<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>O.B465Archon Finding Aid Title O.B465UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:52:16 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    Bettag, Otto (1906-1990): Interview and memoir
    
      Bettag, Otto
    
    
      Immel, Marilyn Huff
    
    O.B465
    820
    
      12.00 items
    
    Dummy Date
    Tapes
    et al
  
  
    Scope and Contents
ILLINOIS STATECRAFT 
Dr. Bettag, former Director of the Illinois Department of Public Welfare, discusses his medical training and experiences combating tuberculosis; experiences at Cincinnati General Hospital and the Veterans' Administration at Hines, Illinois; and as chief surgeon at Whitehaven Sanitorium in Pennsylvania, treating tuberculosis patients and miners with "black lung" disease. He discusses treating tuberculosis at the Pontiac prison; his tenure as the first state tuberculosis medical official and as tuberculosis control officer of Chicago; term as Director of the Depart-ment of Public Welfare, relationship with Governor Stratton; organization of state services through the Department of Public Welfare; and changes in the treatment of patients at psychiatric institutions. He discusses allegations of fraud in the Welfare Department; Governor Stratton's trial for income tax evasion; and the use of drugs in the treatment of mental illness. Articles written about and by Bettag are interspersed throughout the memoir and a summary of accomplishments during his tenure with the Department of Public Welfare is also included. 10 tapes, 900 min., 147 pp. 
Interview by Marilyn Huff Immel, 1981 
OPEN 
See collateral file: interviewer's notes, newspaper articles, Welfare Bulletin, summary of activities, and statement made to Illinois legislature.  
  
    Related Materials
Interview and Memoir in Illinois Digital Archives.http://www.idaillinois.org/u?/uis,1021  
  

