<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>P.AdamsArchon Finding Aid Title P.AdamsUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:06:29 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    P/Adams. Nina Adams, Personal Papers (1976-1990) RESTRICTED
    
      Adams, Nina
    
    P.Adams
    611
    
      0.66 Cubic Feet
    
    Date acquired: 11/05/2005
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This collection contains papers from the faculty files of Nina Adams, now retired faculty member, who taught Women's Studies and History in the Liberal Arts and Sciences program from the early 1970s to the early 1990s.  Materials include journals, newsletters, bulletins, and papers concerning Vietnam and Southeast Asia; classroom materials such as syllabus and lists of research resources; pamphlets and flyers advertising feminist guest speakers (Charlotte Bunch), faculty meeting minutes; and a few student papers.
Box II is RESTRICTED. She also dealt with filing grievances and arbitration procedures for the faculty in the early 1990s, and the second box contains the records from those grievance and arbitration files for that time period.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Subject/chronological  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
RESTRICTED  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Nina Adams  
  
    Course Materials
    Newspaper Clippings
    Papers
    Correspondence
    Reports
    Records
    Flyers/Brochures
    Newsletters
  
  Classroom MaterialsBox 115838Scope and ContentsPublications, Flyers, Syllabus, Journals, Newspaper Articles, Relating to History, Women's Studies and Vietnam and Southeast AsiaVietnam Chronology and Coups - Graph – 1939-1969Folder 1158391Women's Studies – History/Southeast Asian Studies, Philippines Information Bulletin Vol. I-II – 1973-74Folder 2158402Classroom Material Files – Bibliography – Women's History Resources - 1976Folder 3158413Women's Studies – Articles, Clippings, Dollars and Sense Bulletin, Classroom Materials - 1976Folder 4158424Women's Studies – History – Vietnam Newsletters/Publications Classroom Materials - 1978Folder 5158435History - Classroom Materials – Indochina Issues – 1980-81Folder 6158446Class Material Files – Indochina Issues Volumes 2-33 – June 1979- Jan. 1983Folder 7158457Charlotte Bunch – Feminist Guest Speaker  - Flyers and Correspondence - 1983Folder 8158468Pat Langley's Syllabus, Reading Guides, and Materials for Law as Literature ClassFolder 9158479School of Arts and Sciences - 1986Folder 101584810Women's Studies – Bylaws, Faculty Meeting Minutes – 1988-90Folder 111584911Teaching Nuclear History - 1990Folder 121585012Women's Studies/History - Vietnam - Class Papers – "The Trung Sisters and Today" – Nguyen Thi Ngoc Thoa – 1976Folder 131585113History – Southeast Asia Papers from Students – "Imperialism and the Philippine Ruling Class" – Jonathan FastFolder 141585214Women's Studies/History – Class Papers – Passover ReadingsFolder 151585315Women's Studies/History – Southeast Asia – Class Papers – " The State of Social Sciences in Vietnam" – David MarrFolder 161585416RESTRICTED - Grievance/Arbitration FilesBox 215855

