<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.01.15/13Archon Finding Aid Title J.01.15/13UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:57:35 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J1/15/13. Intersession Papers "Ill Economic Development Policy: Here Today, Where Tomorrow" 1986
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    J.01.15/13
    403
    
      1.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1986
    Date acquired: 08/29/2005
    All
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Video tape collection of Spring Intersession series held for a one week course, beginning 3/16/1986, and ending 3/21/1986.  Intersession topic was "Illinois Economic Development and Policy: Here Today, Where Tomorrow," which was sponsored by the Department of Academic Affairs.
The faculty involved were: Dr. Mark Erenburg, Director of the Center for Regional Studies; Dr. Michael Ayers, Vice President for Academic Affairs; Dr. Moshe Levine; Dr. John R. Munkirs; Professor Leory Wehrle; Dr. Zultan Acs; Dr. Robert Prmus; and Dr. Durward Long, SSU President.  
Topics covered included the development of small business in Illinois Communities, business and education partnerships, encouraging large businesses such as the Diamond Star plant in Normal, IL to come to Illinois, and government contracts.  
More information on this Intersession can be found in J11/1/2, Box 5.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  Box 1Box 168035Scope and Contents¾ " U-matic cassettesSession 1: Nature, Policies, and ImplicationsVideotape 16803603/16/1986Scope and ContentsTape 1 of the March 16th session featured guest speaker, Phillip R. O'Connor, Chairman and CEO of the Palmer-Bellevue Corporation. His topic theme was "Nature, Policies, and Implications", and dealt with the break-up of energy corporations.Session 1: Nature, Policies, and ImplicationsVideotape 26803703/16/1986Scope and ContentsTape 2 of the March 16th session featured guest speaker, Phillip R. O'Connor, Chairman and CEO of the Palmer-Bellevue Corporation. His topic theme was "Nature, Policies, and Implications", and dealt with the break-up of energy corporations.Session 2: Illinois Economic Development and Policy: Here Today, Where TomorrowVideotape 36803803/17/1986Scope and ContentsTape 1 of the March 17th Intersession topic was again, "Illinois Economic Development and Policy: Here Today, Where Tomorrow" and was hosted by Dr. Michael Ayers, Vice President for Academic Affairs, and featured guest speakers Dr. John R. Munkirs, Professor of Economics at SSU, and Dr. Zultan Acs, Associate Professor of Economics at SSU.  The theme was the development of "home grown" small businesses, and the level at which the U.S. Government should interfere, followed by a question/answer session.Session 2: Illinois Economic Development and Policy: Here Today, Where TomorrowVideotape 46803903/17/1986Scope and ContentsTape 2 of the March 17th Intersession topic was again, "Illinois Economic Development and Policy: Here Today, Where Tomorrow" and was hosted by Dr. Michael Ayers, Vice President for Academic Affairs, and featured guest speakers Dr. John R. Munkirs, Professor of Economics at SSU, and Dr. Zultan Acs, Associate Professor of Economics at SSU.  The theme was the development of "home grown" small businesses, and the level at which the U.S. Government should interfere, followed by a question/answer session.Session 3: Impact of Technological Change, on World Economy, and U.S. Economic Development in the FutureVideotape 56804003/18/1986Scope and ContentsTape 1 of the March 18th, 1986 intersession were hosted by Dr Moshe Levin, Associate Professor of Business Administration.  The guest speakers were Professor Leroy Wehrle, Professor of Economics, SSU, and Professor Stanley Aronowitz, University of the City of New York. The theme of the first tape was by Dr. Leroy Wehrle, and was the "Impact of Technological Change, on World Economy, and U.S. Economic Development in the Future."  Professor Aronowitz's theme for his speech was "My American Dream: The Disappearance of the Middle Class."Session 3: My American Dream: The Disappearance of the Middle ClassVideotape 66804103/18/1986Scope and ContentsTape 2 of the March 18th, 1986 intersession were hosted by Dr Moshe Levin, Associate Professor of Business Administration.  The guest speakers were Professor Leroy Wehrle, Professor of Economics, SSU, and Professor Stanley Aronowitz, University of the City of New York. The theme of the first tape was by Dr. Leroy Wehrle, and was the "Impact of Technological Change, on World Economy, and U.S. Economic Development in the Future."  Professor Aronowitz's theme for his speech was "My American Dream: The Disappearance of the Middle Class."Session 4: Economic Development in Wisconsin as compared with Illinois, and Striving for Educational Objectives in Regards to the Problem of the Growing UnderclassVideotape 76804203/19/1986Scope and ContentsTape 1 of the March 19th, 1986 intersession featured two guest speakers, one of whom was Robert Milbourne, Executive Director of the Greater Milwaukee, WI Committee for Community Development. His topic was "Economic Development in Wisconsin as compared with Illinois, and Striving for Educational Objectives in Regards to the Problem of the Growing Underclass."Session 4: Economic Development in Wisconsin as compared with Illinois, and Striving for Educational Objectives in Regards to the Problem of the Growing UnderclassVideotape 86804303/19/1986Scope and ContentsTape 2 of the March 19th, 1986 intersession featured two guest speakers, one of whom was Robert Milbourne, Executive Director of the Greater Milwaukee, WI Committee for Community Development. His topic was "Economic Development in Wisconsin as compared with Illinois, and Striving for Educational Objectives in Regards to the Problem of the Growing Underclass."Session 5: Positive Policies for the 1980'sVideotape 96804403/20/1986Scope and ContentsTape 1 of the March 20th, 1986 Intersession was hosted by Dr. Mark Erenburg, Director of the Center for Regional Studies. The theme of that day's topic was "Positive Policies for the 1980's."  The featured speakers on tape 1 were Dr. Durward Long, then president of SSU, Peter Johnson, Executive Director for the Illinois Council on Vocational Education, and Billy Rader, Associate Vice Chancellor for the Skills Program Development of the City College of Chicago. On tape 2, the featured speakers were Steven F. Selcke, Assistant Director of the Illinois Department of Commerce and Community Affairs, William Dart, Vice President of Government Affairs, Illinois Manufacturer's Association, and Robert Gibson, President of the Illinois State AFL-CIO.  Dr. Mark Erenburg was also the host.Session 5: Positive Policies for the 1980'sVideotape 106804503/20/1986Scope and ContentsTape 2 of the March 20th, 1986 Intersession was hosted by Dr. Mark Erenburg, Director of the Center for Regional Studies. The theme of that day's topic was "Positive Policies for the 1980's."  The featured speakers on tape 1 were Dr. Durward Long, then president of SSU, Peter Johnson, Executive Director for the Illinois Council on Vocational Education, and Billy Rader, Associate Vice Chancellor for the Skills Program Development of the City College of Chicago. On tape 2, the featured speakers were Steven F. Selcke, Assistant Director of the Illinois Department of Commerce and Community Affairs, William Dart, Vice President of Government Affairs, Illinois Manufacturer's Association, and Robert Gibson, President of the Illinois State AFL-CIO.  Dr. Mark Erenburg was also the host.Session 6: How Technology has changed Illinois Economic DevelopmentVideotape 116804603/21/1986Scope and ContentsTape 1 of the March 21st Intersession featured a variety of speakers on different themes. Tape 1 was hosted by Dr. Mark Erenburg, and was sponsored by Illinois Bell.  Guest speakers included Dr. Robert Premus, and the main theme of the topic was "How Technology has changed Illinois Economic Development."  Other guest speakers included Helen Shumate, Illinois Bell, Hal Smith, Director of Tabulations of the First state Lottery, Administrator of the Illinois "I-Tech" Program, and Dr. Durward Long, SSU President.Session 6: Public and Private partnership in Education and in BusinessVideotape 126804703/21/1986Scope and ContentsTape 2 of the March 21st Intersession was also hosted by Dr. Mark Erenburg, and featured David W. Bowell, from the Department of Education Program for Illinois, Indiana, Wisconsin, Minnesota, and Ohio, and is the Regional Representative of the U.S. Department of Education. Mr. Bowell's presentation was on "Public and Private partnership in Education and in Business." The second presentation involved Labor, Management, and Business Corporation, and featured Sharon Sharp, who was the Deputy Director of Marketing for the Illinois Department of Commerce and Community Affairs.  The main theme was bringing in the Diamond Star automobile manufacturing plant (Mitsubishi and Chrysler), into Normal Illinois.  The other featured speaker was Dave Anderson, City Manager of Normal, IL.Session 6: Implications of bringing the Diamond Star plant to Bloomington/NormalVideotape 136804803/21/1986Scope and ContentsTape 3 continued the discussion of the implications of bringing the Diamond Star plant to Bloomington/Normal, Illinois, and it's impact on the economic growth and it's benefits for the area.  Speakers included Dave Anderson, Sharon Sharp, Eric Pitcher, Senior Industrial Development Specialist, and staff coordinator on the Diamond Star project for the IL Department of Commerce and Community Affairs, Bob Vancil, Economic Development Consultants, and John Penn, Business Manager of Labor International, Local 362.Session 6: Government Investment in EducationVideotape 146804903/21/1986Scope and ContentsTape 4 of the March 21st Intersession was hosted by Dr. Mark Erenburg, and the topic was "Government Investment in Education."  The featured speakers were Democratic State Senator Philip Rock, Cook County, President of the IL. State Senate, and Republican Representative Sam Vinson, Assistant Minority Leader, of the Illinois House of Representatives.Session 6: Government Investment in EducationVideotape 156805003/21/1986Scope and ContentsTape 5 of the final Intersession held on March 21, 1986 featured the continuation of the speech of Representative Sam Vinson on "Government Investment in Education" and also featured as the final speaker, Joe Cappo, Corporate Vice President and Publisher of "Crains Chicago Business."

