<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.01.15/16Archon Finding Aid Title J.01.15/16UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:57:53 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J1/15/16. Intersession Papers "Controversies in Public Health Policy" 1987
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    J.01.15/16
    404
    
      1.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1987
    Date acquired: 08/09/2006
    All
  
  
    Scope and Contents
PAC 487 - Intersession: "Controversies in Public Health Policy"
Michael Quam and Joyce Elliott served as co-chairs. 
Collection of video tapes for the sessions held 3/15/1987 - 3/20/1987.  
The major themes included acces to care, prevention vs. treatment, public health vs. individual freedom, and public health and societyal priorities.  Individual sessions included "Public Health Policy Making in Illinois," "Teenage Pregnancy," "AIDS," "The Drugging of America," "Environmental Toxins," and "Envisioning the Future of Public Health."  
Dr. Victor Sidell was the keynote speaker. Major speakers included  Dr. Mark Hillegas, Dr. Ann Gilman Dawson, Sen. William Marovitz, State Rep. Woods Bowman, Jeff Todd, Dr. Bernard Turnock, Dr. Roger P. Maickel, Dr. Betina Francis, Dr. James D. Wilson, Dr. Nina Adams, Dr. Roy Wehrle, Linda Miller, Father Charles Kyle, Dr. Larry VonBehren, Mary Frances Fagan, and Fletcher Farrar.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  Box 1Box 168018Scope and Contents(Tape numbers T2927 – T2941 in AV db)
15 - ¾ " U-matic cassettes (located in File Room)Session 1: Asklepios, Apollo, and Zeus: Health, Community, and Government, Dr. Victor SidellVideotape 1680193/15/1987Scope and ContentsSession 1, tape 1 of the March 15th Intersession featured keynote speaker, Dr. Victor Sidell, whose theme was "Asklepios, Apollo, and Zeus: Health, Community, and Government."Session 1: Asklepios, Apollo, and Zeus: Health, Community, and Government, Dr. Victor SidellVideotape 2680233/15/1987Scope and ContentsSession 1, tape 2 of the March 15th Intersession featured keynote speaker, Dr. Victor Sidell, whose theme was "Asklepios, Apollo, and Zeus: Health, Community, and Government."Session 2: Public Health Policy Making in IllinoisVideotape 3680213/15/1987Scope and ContentsSession 2, tape 1 of the March 15th Intersession featured the theme of "Public Health Policy Making in Illinois."  The panel consisted of Mickey Beil, IL Nurses Assoc.; State Re. Woods Bowman; Jeff Todd, IL Public Health Assoc.; Dr. Bernard Turnock, Director of IL Dept. of Public Health; and moderator Mary Frances Fagan, legislative correspondent for WSSR radio.Session 2: Public Health Policy Making in IllinoisVideotape 4680223/15/1987Scope and ContentsSession 2, tape 2 of the March 15th Intersession featured the theme of "Public Health Policy Making in Illinois."  The panel consisted of Mickey Beil, IL Nurses Assoc.; State Re. Woods Bowman; Jeff Todd, IL Public Health Assoc.; Dr. Bernard Turnock, Director of IL Dept. of Public Health; and moderator Mary Frances Fagan, legislative correspondent for WSSR radio.Session 3: Teenage PregnancyVideotape 5680243/16/1987Scope and ContentsSession 3, tape 1 of the March 16th Intersession featured the theme of 
"Teenage Pregnancy."  The panel consisted of Dr. Ann Gilman, Dawson, Assoc Dir of The Ounce of Prevention Fund; Father Charles Kyle, Sociology Professor and parish priest; and Linda Miller, Coordinator of IL Parents Too Soon Initiative, IL Dept of Public Health.Session 3: Teenage PregnancyVideotape 6680253/16/1987Scope and ContentsSession 3, tape 2 of the March 16th Intersession featured the theme of 
"Teenage Pregnancy."  The panel consisted of Dr. Ann Gilman, Dawson, Assoc Dir of The Ounce of Prevention Fund; Father Charles Kyle, Sociology Professor and parish priest; and Linda Miller, Coordinator of IL Parents Too Soon Initiative, IL Dept of Public Health.Session 4: AIDSVideotape 7680263/17/1987Scope and ContentsSession 4, tape 1 of the March 17th Intersession featured the theme of "AIDS."  The speakers were State Senator William Marovitz and Renslow Sherer, MD and Chair or the IL AIDS Interdisciplinary Advisory Council.  Panel members included Nancy Ford, Legal Studies Professor at SSU and Dir of the Center for Legal Studies; Chet Kelly, Chicago Dept of Public Health; and Larry VonBehren, MD at SIU School of Medicine.Session 4: AIDSVideotape 8680273/17/1987Scope and ContentsSession 4, tape 2 of the March 17th Intersession featured the theme of "AIDS."  The speakers were State Senator William Marovitz and Renslow Sherer, MD and Chair or the IL AIDS Interdisciplinary Advisory Council.  Panel members included Nancy Ford, Legal Studies Professor at SSU and Dir of the Center for Legal Studies; Chet Kelly, Chicago Dept of Public Health; and Larry VonBehren, MD at SIU School of Medicine.Session 5: The Drugging of AmericaVideotape 9680283/18/1987Scope and ContentsSession 5, tape 1 of the March 18th Intersession featured the theme of "The Drugging of America."  The speaker was Dr. Roger P. Maickel, Professor of Pharmacology and Toxicology, Purdue University.  Panel members included Gary Green, George Deverman, Anthony Renard, Mary Lou Dixon, and others.Session 5: The Drugging of AmericaVideotape 10680293/18/1987Scope and ContentsSession 5, tape 2 of the March 18th Intersession featured the theme of "The Drugging of America."  The speaker was Dr. Roger P. Maickel, Professor of Pharmacology and Toxicology, Purdue University.  Panel members included Gary Green, George Deverman, Anthony Renard, Mary Lou Dixon, and others.Session 5: The Drugging of AmericaVideotape 11680303/18/1987Scope and ContentsSession 5, tape 3 of the March 18th Intersession featured the theme of "The Drugging of America."  The speaker was Dr. Roger P. Maickel, Professor of Pharmacology and Toxicology, Purdue University.  Panel members included Gary Green, George Deverman, Anthony Renard, Mary Lou Dixon, and others.Session 6: Environmental ToxinsVideotape 12680313/19/1987Scope and ContentsSession 6, tape 1 of the March 19th Intersession featured the theme of "Environmental Toxins."  Speakers included Dr. Betina Francis, Environment Studies Professor at UIUC and Dr. James D. Wilson, corporate environmental policy staff, Monsanto Company, St. Louis.  Panel members discussed the issues.Session 6: Environmental ToxinsVideotape 13680323/19/1987Scope and ContentsSession 6, tape 2 of the March 19th Intersession featured the theme of "Environmental Toxins."  Speakers included Dr. Betina Francis, Environment Studies Professor at UIUC and Dr. James D. Wilson, corporate environmental policy staff, Monsanto Company, St. Louis.  Panel members discussed the issues.Session 7: Envisioning the Future of Public HealthVideotape 14680333/20/1987Scope and ContentsSession 7, tape 1 of the March 20th Intersession featured the theme of "Envisioning the Future of Public Health."  Dr. Mark R. Hillegas, Professor Emeritus of English, SIU Carbondale was the featured speaker.  Panel members included Dr. Nina Adams, Assoc Professor of History and Women's Studies at SSU; Fletcher Farrar, Jr., editor and publisher of Illinois Times; and Dr. Roy Wehrle, Professor of Economics, SSU.Session 7: Envisioning the Future of Public HealthVideotape 15680343/20/1987Scope and ContentsSession 7, tape 2 of the March 20th Intersession featured the theme of "Envisioning the Future of Public Health."  Dr. Mark R. Hillegas, Professor Emeritus of English, SIU Carbondale was the featured speaker.  Panel members included Dr. Nina Adams, Assoc Professor of History and Women's Studies at SSU; Fletcher Farrar, Jr., editor and publisher of Illinois Times; and Dr. Roy Wehrle, Professor of Economics, SSU.

