<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.01.15/18Archon Finding Aid Title J.01.15/18UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:57:57 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J1/15/18. Intersession Papers "The Bill of Rights After 200 Years" 1991
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    J.01.15/18
    405
    
      0.66 Cubic Feet
    
    1991
    Date acquired: 02/16/1995
    All
  
  
    Scope and Contents
PAC 491, Intersession: The Bill of Rights after 200 years: Challenges and Controversies (March 10-16, 1991) consists of 12 video tapes that cover all lectures and panel discussions during the Intersession.  Topics  include the meaning and history of the Bill of Rights, controversies on the treatment of the American Flag,  freedom of speech, censorship and civil liberties.  Speakers include Congressman Richard Durbin, artist Dread Scott (whose exhibits desecrate the flag) and Joseph Morris (attorney for opposition of Scott's exhibits).  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  Box 1Box 168004Introduction; Representative DurbinVideotape 168005March 10, 1991Scope and ContentsLarry Golden, Associate Professor SSU, and Wayne Penn, acting President, introduce the opening of Intersession 1991 with  comments concerning the Bill of Rights, its history and the changes it has gone through over the years.  Congressman Richard Durbin delivered the keynote address to Intersession participants.  He also discussed the meaning of the Bill of Rights.
 1 hr 17 min 17 sec, 1/2" color video cassetteNational Security, War and Civil Liberties; Panel Discussion (part 1)Videotape 268006March 10, 1991Scope and Contents"National Security, War and Civil Liberties," a panel discussion concerning the Persian Gulf war, the role of the media and civil liberties.  Introduction by Larry Golden, panelist Paul Minakey, Jim Grimes, Layla Diab, Doug Cambell and Yosh Golden.  1 hr 52 min 5 sec, 1/2" color video cassette.National Security, War and Civil Liberties; Question and Answer (part 2)Videotape 368007March 10, 1991Scope and ContentsPart 2 of "National Security, War and Civil Liberties." This is the question and answer session lead by the audience.  28 min 57 sec, 1/2" color video cassetteFlag Desecration and Censorship at the Chicago Art Institute School; Q &amp; A (part 1)Videotape 468008March 11, 1991Scope and Contents"Flag Desecration and Censorship at the Chicago Art Institute School," a panel discussion concerning censorship and freedom of speech at the Chicago Art Institute.  Introduction by Larry Golden and Nancy Ford.  Panelists include Debra McGregor, Joyce Fernandes, Dread Scott and Joseph Morris. 2 hr 4 min 36 sec, 1/2" video cassette. part 1Flag Desecration and Censorship at the Chicago Art Institute School; Q &amp; A (part 2)Videotape 568009March 11, 1991Scope and ContentsPart 2 of "Flag Desecration and Censorship at the Chicago Art Institute School," question and answer session.  5 min 4 sec, 1/2" video cassettePrivacy, Freedom of Religion, and Personal Lifestyles; Question &amp; Answer (part 1)Videotape 668010March 12, 1991Scope and Contents"Privacy, Freedom of Religion and Personal Lifestyles," a panel discussion focusing on Oregon v. Smith, use of peyote by Native Americans and Bowers v. Hardwick, sodomy in Georgia.  Introduction by  Larry Golden, Nancy Ford and Peter Wenz.  Panelist include Leanne Easton, Rives Kistler and Kathleen Wilde. 2 hr 3 min 58 sec, 1/2" video cassetteBox 2Box 268011Privacy, Freedom of Religion, and Personal Lifestyles; Question &amp; Answer (part 2)Videotape 768012March 12, 1991Scope and ContentsPart 2 of "Privacy, Freedom of Religion and Personal Lifestyles," question and answer session.  16 min 55 sec, 1/2" video cassettePersonal Security and the State; Panel Discussion; Question &amp; Answer (part 1)Videotape 868013March 13, 1991Scope and Contents"Personal Security and the State," a panel discussion concerning the legality of drug testing and personal freedoms.  The discussion focuses on National Treasury Employees Union v. Von Raab  and Michigan v. Sitz.  Introduction by Larry Golden, Nancy Ford and John Squibb.  Panelists include Elaine Kaplan, Robert Zener, Michael Metnick and Steve Emberton.Personal Security and the State; Panel Discussion; Question &amp; Answer (part 2)Videotape 968014March 10-16, 1991Minorities and the Bill of Rights; B. Manning; Panel Discussion; Question &amp; AnswerVideotape 1068015March 10-16, 1991Chief Justice Ben MillerVideotape 1168016March 10-16, 1991Professor Peter WenzVideotape 1268017March 10-16, 1991

