<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.01.15/22Archon Finding Aid Title J.01.15/22UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:58:03 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J1/15/22. Intersession Papers "Preparing for the 21st Century" 1995
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    J.01.15/22
    406
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1995
    Date acquired: 10/18/2001
    All
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Intersession 1995, "Preparing for the 21st Century" took place on March 12 - March 18, 1995.  The collection contains 8 video tapes and 12 cassette tapes covering all evening lectures during the week.  Topics include international political economy, political order and the decline of the nation-state, the environment and the work force of the future.  Also included is a tape of the mock work congress held on March 18.  
Speakers include Congressman Richard Durbin, Dr. Helen Caldicott, Professor Arthur MacEwan, Professor Patricia Fenandez Kelly, Professor Mark Beissinger, Professor Roger Kanet, Don Fitz, Thomas Hoogheem, Barbara Garson, Jane Slaughter, Pat Rosezelle and Doug Kamholz.
Faculty members and staff involved in the planning include: Alex Casella, Kathy DeBarr, Maria Mootry, Steve Schwark, Doh Shinn, Anthony Sisneros, Bill Warren, and Peter Wenez.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  Box 1Box 167990Lectures - 2 cassettesAudiotape 1679991995/03/12Scope and ContentsTape 1 is of very poor qualityLectures - 2 cassettesAudiotape 2680001995/03/13Lectures - 2 cassettesAudiotape 3680011995/03/14Lectures - 2 cassettesAudiotape 4680021995/03/16Lectures - 2 cassettesAudiotape 5680031995/03/17Tape #1 - Intersession 1995Videotape 1679911995/03/12Scope and ContentsAlex Casella, Dean of the School of Public Affairs and Administration and Robert Sipe open Intersession 1995 with comments about the changing world and becoming prepared for the 21st Century.  Congressman Richard Durbin spoke on political decision-making in the 21st Century, and Dr. Helen Caldicott, environmental activist, delivered the keynote address.  Following the speakers, the audience was given the opportunity to ask questionsTape #2 - Intersession 1995Videotape 2679921995/03/12Scope and ContentsContinuation of the question and answer period from Congressman Durbin and Dr. Caldicott's lecturesTape #3 - Intersession 1995Videotape 3679931995/03/13Scope and Contents"Markets Unbound: The Heavy Price of Globalization" delivered by Arthur MacEwan from the University of Massachusetts at Boston and "NAFTA, GATT, and Global Economy: Who Wins, Who Loses?" delivered by M. Patricia Fernandez Kelly from Johns Hopkins University.  Audience question and answerTape #4 - Intersession 1995Videotape 4679941995/03/14Scope and Contents"State and Empire Building in Post Soviet Politics" delivered by Professor Mark Beissinger of the University of Wisconsin at Madison and "The Triple Transition' in Post-Communist Europe" delivered by professor Roger Kanet of the University of Illinois at Urbana/Champaign.  Audience question and answerTape #5 - Intersession 1995Videotape 5679951995/03/15Scope and Contents"The Environmental State of the World" delivered by Roger Kanerva from the Illinois Environmental Protection Agency, "Reasons to Fear Chemical Contributions" delivered by Don Fitz of Gateway Green Alliance, and "Human Improvement through Chemical Innovation" delivered by Thomas Hoogheem of the Monsanto Corporation.  Audience question and answerTape #6 - Intersession 1995Videotape 6679961995/03/16Scope and Contents"The Electronic Sweatshop: How Computers are Transforming the Office of the Future into the Factory of the Past" delivered by Barbara Garson, New York City playwright, author and social activist, and "Workplace of the Future" delivered by Jane Slaughter specialist in auto industry and labor-management participation programs.  Audience question and answerTape #7 - Intersession 1995Videotape 7679971995/03/17Scope and Contents"Organizing Around Cultural and Racial Diversity" delivered by Pat Rosezelle of Chicago and "(Sm)all Power to the People!" delivered by Doug Kamholz of the Heartland Peace Center.  Audience question and answerTape #8 - Intersession 1995Videotape 8679981995/03/18Scope and ContentsStudents participating in a mock world Congress

