<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.49.05Archon Finding Aid Title J.49.05UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:06:35 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J49/5. Sangamon State Faculty Union Records
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    
      Faculty Union (Sangamon State Faculty Union (SSFU))
    
    J.49.05
    614
    
      5.28 Cubic Feet
    
    1970-1995
    Date acquired: 00/00/1983
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Records of Sangamon State Faculty Union, including Council minutes, memos and correspondence; material of the Collective Bargaining, American Federation of Teachers and Illinois Federation of Teachers; Legal cases and publications of  "Mushroom Garden", "The Blue Memo," and  "SSFU News."This material is divided into four series. Series I includes Council Minutes (1973-82); Memos (1973-82); Correspondence (1973-79); University Assembly: Governance (1973-79); Presidential Review (1977); SSFU Constitutions (1973-76) and Evaluations of Faculty and Administrative Members. It also includes SSFU Fund and The Bruce A. Magidsohn Fund material and material concerning collective bargaining (1973-82).Series II includes the material of the American Federation of Teachers (1974-80) and the material of the Illinois State Federation of Teachers (1974-80). It also includes the Executive Director's Reports (1975-76) and the Agendas, Minutes and Reports of the Board of Regents.Series III includes the publications Mushroom Garden (1973-76); The Blue Memo (1975-76) and Sangamon State Faculty News (1976-83). It also includes some publications related to collective bargaining.Series IV includes several legal cases: "Faculty Six" (1974-75), "Ettinger Case" (1975), "Redge Ranyand Tenure Case" (1973-78), "Walter Kimmel Case" (1973-77) and "Brookens Auditorium Case" (1977). It includes the material of Prof. Robert Crowley concerning the Sangamon Chapter of the Illinois Federation of Teachers, 1979-82, and financial records of SSFU. It also includes the material of Prof. Ron Ettinger concerning the Sangamon State Faculty Union and University Professionals of Illinois (1974-1995).  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  
    Accruals and Additions
Ron Ettinger materials (Series 4, box 16) were added by donation of creator on May 22, 2017.  
  
    Custodial History
A button "INO the Unprogram" was transferred from Ron Ettinger material to Individual Option Program Records J11/5/1.  
  Series 1Series 163415Scope and ContentsIncludes Council Minutes (1973-82); Memos (1973-82); Correspondence (1973-79); University Assembly: Governance (1973-79); Presidential Review (1977); SSFU Constitutions (1973-76) and Evaluations of Faculty and Administrative Members. It also includes SSFU Fund and The Bruce A. Magidsohn Fund material and material concerning collective bargaining (1973-82).Box 1Box 163430Council MinutesFolder 16342019731Council MinutesFolder 26342119742Council MinutesFolder 36342219753Council MinutesFolder 46342319764Council MinutesFolder 56342419775Council MinutesFolder 66342519786Council MinutesFolder 76342619797Council MinutesFolder 86342719808Council MinutesFolder 96342819819Council MinutesFolder 1063429198210Box 2Box 263431MemosFolder 16343219731MemosFolder 26343319742MemosFolder 36343419753MemosFolder 46343519764MemosFolder 56343619775MemosFolder 6634371978-796MemosFolder 7634381981-827MemosFolder 863439n.d.8Box 3Box 363440CorrespondenceFolder 16344119731CorrespondenceFolder 26344219742CorrespondenceFolder 36344319753CorrespondenceFolder 46344419764CorrespondenceFolder 56344519775CorrespondenceFolder 66344619786CorrespondenceFolder 7634471979-817Correspondence, Board of RegentsFolder 8634481974-768Correspondence with AFTFolder 9634491974-799Correspondence with IFTFolder 10634501973-7910Box 4Box 463451Affiliation to AFT and IFTFolder 1634521973-751Ballots, Questionnaire, Memos and Summary on MergerFolder 26345319802Benefits: Dental, Travel, etc.Folder 3634541974-763Brochures and FlyersFolder 4634551975-804ConstitutionsFolder 5634561973-765Evaluation of Faculty Members and Administrative MembersFolder 6634571971-746Salary Survey FormsFolder 7634587MeritsFolder 86345919748Petitions, Polls and BallotsFolder 9634601973-779Presidential ReviewFolder 1063461197710SSU Students Union: Flyers, Newspapers, Memos and StatementsFolder 11634621975-7611Box 5Box 563463Membership Meetings (Minutes, Memos and Drafts)Folder 1634641972-761NCA (Reports, Memos, Survey Results and Newsclippings)Folder 2634651973-752Planning Conference (Agenda and Minutes)Folder 3634661976-793Personnel Policy (Memos, Reports and Statements)Folder 4634671973-764University Assembly: GovernanceFolder 56346819735University Assembly: GovernanceFolder 66346919746University Assembly: GovernanceFolder 76347019757University Assembly: GovernanceFolder 86347119768University Assembly: GovernanceFolder 96347219779University Assembly: GovernanceFolder 1063473197810University Assembly: GovernanceFolder 1163474197911Box 6Box 663475The Bruce A. Magidsohn Fund: ApplicationsFolder 1634761975-771The Bruce A. Magidsohn Fund: CorrespondenceFolder 2634771975-802The Bruce A. Magidsohn Fund: Correspondence with ContributorsFolder 3634781977-813The Bruce A. Magidsohn Fund: Correspondence with Eliot A. MagidsohnFolder 4634791975-814The Bruce A. Magidsohn Fund: Invitations, Committee Members, Receipts, Cards, Newsletters and News  clippingsFolder 5634801976-805Scholarship Fund: Applications and RecommendationsFolder 6634811974-816Scholarship Fund: Correspondence and Blank Application FormsFolder 7634821974-807Scholarship Fund: Releases, Newsclippings, Brochures and StatementsFolder 8634831974-808Box 7Box 763484Collective Bargaining: AgreementsFolder 1634851970-741Collective Bargaining: AgreementsFolder 2634861977-822Scope and ContentsBetween Board of Governors of State Colleges and Universities and AFTCollective Bargaining: AgreementsFolder 3634871973-773Scope and ContentsBetween the Board of Trustees of Community CollegeCollective Bargaining: AgreementsFolder 4634881974-764Scope and ContentsBetween Fairleigh Dickinson UniversityCollective Bargaining: AgreementsFolder 5634891972-755Scope and ContentsOakland University and City University of New YorkCollective Bargaining: Notes and Steps in Agent ElectionFolder 66349019756Collective Bargaining: ContractsFolder 76349119737Collective Bargaining: Flyers, Newsclippings, Memos, Brochures and QuestionnaireFolder 8634921974-778Collective Bargaining: Information BulletinFolder 963493n.d.9Collective Bargaining: Outline for Board of Regents PresentationFolder 1063494197610Collective Bargaining: RegulationsFolder 1163495n.d.11Collective Bargaining: Releases and StatementsFolder 12634961974-7712Reports, Meetings and Poll ResultsFolder 13634971975-7613Collective Bargaining: Research on CB and ResolutionFolder 1463498197614Series 2Series 263417Scope and ContentsIncludes the material of the American Federation of Teachers (1974-80) and the material of the Illinois State Federation of Teachers (1974-80). It also includes the Executive Director's Reports (1975-76) and the Agendas, Minutes and Reports of the Board of Regents.Box 8Box 863499Assoc. of American University Professors: Policy Documents and ReportsFolder 16350019711AFL-CIO: ConstitutionFolder 2635011958, 19732Scope and ContentsCorporate Management Invades AcademeAFL-CIO: Newsletters of EIU and SIUFolder 36350219743American Federation of Teachers: Colleges and Universities DirectoryFolder 46350319744American Federation of Teachers: Flyers, Brochures and QuestionnaireFolder 5635041975-795American Federation of Teachers: A Guideline for Treasurers and Financial Officers of Local UnionsFolder 66350519726American Federation of Teachers: Memos, Applications Forms, News Releases, Newsletters and Loan PolicyFolder 7635061974-797American Federation of Teachers: News from Other Branches, Forms of Assistance Loan and Tuition Tex CreditFolder 8635071977-798American Federation of Teachers: Newspapers, News clippings and ResultsFolder 9635081977-799American Federation of Teachers: PublicationsFolder 10635091974-7510American Federation of Teachers: Rep Report NewslettersFolder 11635101978-8011Board of Governors: Newsletters, Reports and FlyersFolder 12635111976-7712Coalition of University Professors: Newsletters, News clippings, Flyers, Memos, Agendas, Petitions, Brochures, Bulletins and StatementsFolder 13635121975-8013Box 9Box 963513Illinois Board of Higher Education: Statements, Drafts and ReportsFolder 16351419791Illinois Education Association: Petition to Seek ClarificationFolder 26351519772Illinois Federation of Teachers: NewsFolder 3635161977-793Illinois Federation of Teachers: News clippingsFolder 4635171978-794Illinois Federation of Teachers: Newsletters and Status of LocalsFolder 5635181973-795Illinois Federation of Teachers: News ReleasesFolder 6635191973, 19796Illinois Federation of Teachers: Recognition, Agreement, Unresolved Issues and BrochuresFolder 7635201977-797Illinois Federation of Teachers: Status of LocalsFolder 8635211974-758Illinois Federation of Teachers University Council: CorrespondenceFolder 9635221977-799Illinois Federation of Teachers University Council: Drafts, Statements, Tentative Constitution and QuestionnaireFolder 10635231978-8010Illinois Federation of Teachers University Council: MemosFolder 11635241978-8011Illinois Federation of Teachers University Council: MinutesFolder 12635251978-8012Box 10Box 1063526Executive Director's Reports (1-16, 2-20, 3-18, 3-20)Folder 16352719751Executive Director's Reports (5-21, 6-19, 8-28)Folder 26352819752Executive Director's Reports (4-15, 5-20, 6-17)Folder 36352919763Executive Director's Reports (7-29, 9-16, 10-28, 12-16)Folder 46353019764Agendas: The Meetings of Board of RegentsFolder 56353119755Minutes: The Meetings of Board of RegentsFolder 66353219756Final Report of the Affirmative Action Committee: The Board of RegentsFolder 76353319757President's Reports: The Board of RegentsFolder 8635348Scope and Contents1974 (5-16); 1975 (1-16, 2-20, 3-20, 5-21, 8-28)Annual Report of Bank of SpringfieldFolder 96353519809State of Illinois Budget and Fiscal ReportsFolder 10635361979-8110Series 3Series 363418Scope and ContentsIncludes the publications Mushroom Garden (1973-76); The Blue Memo (1975-76) and Sangamon State Faculty News (1976-83). It also includes some publications related to collective bargaining.Box 11Box 1163537Illustrations and CartoonsFolder 1635381978-791Mushroom Garden NewslettersFolder 2635391973-742Mushroom Garden Newsletters (Originals)Folder 3635401973-743Mushroom Garden NewslettersFolder 4635411975-764Mushroom Garden Newsletters (Originals)Folder 5635421975-765Box 12Box 1263543The Blue MemoFolder 1635441974-751Faculty ActionFolder 2635451975-832On CampusFolder 36354619743Sangamon State Faculty NewsFolder 4635471976-834Sangamon State Faculty News (Originals)Folder 5635481976-805SSFU NewslettersFolder 6635491975-766Box 13Box 1363550Bibliography on Professionalization and Collective BargainingFolder 16355119741Consumer Guide to Doctors for Sangamon CountyFolder 26355319742For Your Information Newsletter, #1 - #5Folder 3635543Guide for Legislative Action and State Collective Bargaining LawsFolder 46355519744Industrial Relations: A Journal of Economy and SocietyFolder 56355619745Report Executive BoardFolder 66355719776Title VII Litigation Against College and University DefendantsFolder 763558n.d.7Publications and Faculty Issues on Collective BargainingFolder 8635591972-778Publications on Employers and EmployeesFolder 96356019739Reaction to Labor Law Reform Act: News clippings, Newsletters, Reports and FlyersFolder 10635611976-7810Series 4Series 463419Scope and ContentsIncludes several legal cases: "Faculty Six" (1974-75), "Ettinger Case" (1975), "Redge Ranyand Tenure Case" (1973-78), "Walter Kimmel Case" (1973-77) and "Brookens Auditorium Case" (1977). It includes the material of Prof. Robert Crowley concerning the Sangamon Chapter of the Illinois Federation of Teachers, 1979-82, and financial records of SSFU. It also includes the material of Prof. Ron Ettinger concerning the Sangamon State Faculty Union and University Professionals of Illinois (1974-1995).Box 14Box 1463562Walter Kimmel Tenure Case: Excerpt of TranscriptsFolder 163563April-June 19751Walter Kimmel Tenure Case: MemosFolder 2635641973-742Walter Kimmel Tenure Case: MemosFolder 36356519753Walter Kimmel Tenure Case: MemosFolder 4635661976-774Walter Kimmel Tenure Case: Newsclippings and Check BookFolder 56356719755Posters Against Spencer - KeiserFolder 663568n.d.6Redge Ranyard Tenure Case: Clippings and QuestionsFolder 763569n.d.7Redge Ranyard Tenure Case: CorrespondenceFolder 8635701973-788Redge Ranyard Tenure Case: Drafts and MinutesFolder 9635711976-779Redge Ranyard Tenure Case: MemosFolder 10635721973-7710Redge Ranyard Tenure Case: Memos and Correspondence of Larry GoldenFolder 11635731973-7711Tapes: Walter Kimmel CaseFolder 12636404/24/197412Scope and ContentsFact Finding Hearings for tenure appeals of Andy Edwards, David Sanford and William Sellyey, ca.1980 (3 tapes)Box 15Box 1563641Appeal and Hearing Boards: Memos and DraftsFolder 1636431974-761Bob Crowley Material: Brochures and FlyersFolder 2636441981-822Bob Crowley Material: Constitutions, Tentative Settlements and StatementFolder 3636451979-823Bob Crowley Material: Financial Exigency and ReportsFolder 4636461980-824Bob Crowley Material: Sangamon Chapter Agendas, Corres. and NewslettersFolder 5636471981-835Bob Crowley Material: Sangamon Chapter Memos and Member ListsFolder 6636481980-836Bob Crowley Material: University Professionals of Illinois Memos, Correspondence and DraftsFolder 7636491981-827Brookens Auditorium Case: Memos and ReportsFolder 86365019778Ron Ettinger Case: Memos and CorrespondenceFolder 96365119759Faculty Six Case: Memos and News clippingsFolder 10636521974-7510Legal Defense: Correspondence, Memos and ReportsFolder 11636531973-8011Pay Raise and Sokolik-Walsh Case: Correspondence, Memos and News clippingsFolder 12636541973-7512Tenure Crisis: Memos, News clippings, Newsletters and Poll ResultsFolder 13636551973-7613Tenure Decision: Memos and News clippingsFolder 1463656197414Box 16Box 1663642Calendar and Plain StationeryFolder 16365719781ExpendituresFolder 2636581974-782Financial DocumentsFolder 3636591972-733Financial ExigencyFolder 4636601972-754Group Insurance PlansFolder 5636611974-795Membership Rosters and Payee RecordsFolder 6636621974-806Ron Ettinger material: union buttons, union charter, and collective bargaining documentsFolder 7821981974-19957Ron Ettinger material: copies of union documents and ephemeraFolder 8822021973-19958Scope and ContentsThese are items either scanned or photocopied from the originals owned by Prof. Ettinger. The scanned items are also stored in Box.

