<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.03.01/06Archon Finding Aid Title J.03.01/06UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:59:20 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J3/1/6. Academic Planning Project, 1972-1973
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    J.03.01/06
    418
    
      3.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1972-1973
    Date acquired: 07/16/1974
    1
    2
    3
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Records and papers of the Academic Planning Project (1972-1973) which prepared program proposals and statements for the Director of Academic Planning for submission to the Board of Regents.  Program planning includes Social Justice Professions, Physical Sciences, Management, Public Affairs, Nursing, Community Arts Management, Creative Arts, Human Development Counseling and Midwest Studies; includes card catalog of resource collection and bibliography compiled by  the project in education, governance, and the program areas.  
  
    Arrangement Note
As received from agency  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Florence Lewis  
  Box 1Box 140416IBM punch card data pack: listing of published sources by title for the AAP libraryFolder 1404171Scope and ContentsThis was a resource collection of articles, publications, books, etc. compiled by Florence Lewis for research use by the Academic Planning Project.Computer printout of IBM punch card data packFolder 2404182Shelf list of the AAP card catalog, arranged by a classification numberFolder 3404193Scope and ContentsNote: only a small part of the numerical collection was kept by the Archives, as much of it was 	copies, etc., and already owned by SSU in microfilm, books, etc.Card Catalog of title, author, and subject cards: A-Higher EducationFolder 4404204Card Catalog of title, author, and subject cards: H-ZFolder 5404215Box 2Box 2404220-10: Reform within a University Department, or, What to do While Waiting for the RevolutionFolder 14048219691Scope and Contentsby Sarah A. Robinson, University of Florida0-19: Pittsburgh: The Rocky Road to Academic ExcellenceFolder 24048319662Scope and Contentsby D.S. Greenberg. Science, 151: 549-552, 658-662, 799-801, 799-801;0-20: Development of Higher Education in IllinoisFolder 3404843Scope and ContentsG. Robert Darnes memorandum regarding book manuscript by Ernest G. Palola on the historical development of public junior colleges in Illinois0-23: Recent committee reports relating to Master Plan Phase III, of the Illinois Board of Higher Education (a listing)Folder 44048540-26: Report on New Senior InstitutionsFolder 540486February 19685Scope and ContentsChapter 1--The Task.  Illinois Board of Higher Education0-27: Report on New Senior InstitutionsFolder 640487February 19686Scope and ContentsChapter 3--Functions. Illinois Board of 	Higher Education0-28: Report on New Senior InstitutionsFolder 740488February 19687Scope and ContentsChapter 5--Governance. Illinois Board of 	Higher Education0-53: Journal Holdings in the SSU Library on Higher EducationFolder 840489Fall 197280-62: Governance of the University: A Selected BibliographyFolder 94049019719Scope and ContentsCompiled by Evelyn J. Harris. San Diego State College1-17: Illinois Board of Higher Education, Executive Directors' Report #109 on ManpowerFolder 1040491September 1972101-22: Giesecke, Ernest and Breiseth, Chris. Memo to facultyFolder 11404921972-10-0911Scope and ContentsWhat is to be learned from the current University Week devoted to Careers for the Seventies and Eighties?1-33: Governors State University, Planning DocumentsFolder 12404931970-03-1612Scope and Contentsincludes Prospectus of GSU Needs Survey, Educational Planning GuidelinesGovernors State University. Abstract Progress Report to the Board of Governors (2 copies)Folder 1340494June 9-10, 197113Sangamon State University.  Academic Programs Status Report (condensed reprint) (2 copies)Folder 1440495197114Academic Master Plan Through 1980Folder 1540496152-6:  Lambertsen, Eleanor. The Role of the Nurse in the Health Care of Today and TomorrowFolder 16404971972-05-1916Scope and ContentsSpeech given at first Conference on Health Education, Sangamon State University3-5:  Wandel, David. Career Center of the Illinois Department of Labor. Allied Health ProfessionsFolder 17404981972-05-1917Scope and ContentsSummary of a talk, at the first Health Education Conference, Sangamon State University3-7:  Weil, Thomas P. The Future Education of the Health ProfessionsFolder 18404991972-05-1918Scope and ContentsFirst Health Conference, Sangamon State University5-1:  Crane, Dr. Robert M. Social Justice and Higher Education in IllinoisFolder 1940500October 197019Scope and ContentsA Summary Report. Illinois Board of Higher Education, Report, Item #75-4:  Journal Holdings in SSU Library Related to Criminal JusticeFolder 2040501Fall 1972207.2-2: Markland, Dr. Robert E., University of Missouri, St. LouisFolder 2140502December 197021Scope and ContentsAnalyzing Physical Distribution Systems by Simulating Application Seminar, SSU class presentationAdministrative Center: Ranyard proposal and reactionsFolder 2240503197122Business Program PlanningFolder 2340504197223Computer Science Task Force: Including final reportFolder 244050524Conflict Studies ProposalFolder 254050625Continuing Education: Chico State College, Chico, CA ProjectFolder 264050726Early Childhood Development: Includes Guidance and Counseling as well as Re-Ed proposalFolder 274050827Environment and Aesthetics: Including Cohen Language proposalFolder 284050928Environmental ChemistryFolder 294051029Environmental DesignFolder 304051130External Degrees: Includes materials on the University Without WallsFolder 314051231Family Studies Program Task Force ReportFolder 324051332Health AdministrationFolder 334051433Helping ProfessionsFolder 344051534Human DevelopmentFolder 354051635Internship Task ForceFolder 364051736Law and Health SciencesFolder 374051837Law EnforcementFolder 384051938Library ScienceFolder 394052039Management SequenceFolder 404052140Midwest StudiesFolder 414052241Public Affairs InternshipFolder 424052342Public Affairs Program Information From Internship Task Force (1 of 2)Folder 434052443Public Affairs Program Information From Internship Task Force (2 of 2)Folder 444052544Box 3Box 340423Public Affairs ReportingFolder 1404241Public ArtsFolder 2404252Public Values and PhilosophyFolder 3404263Rural Life Center PlanningFolder 4404274Urban PlanningFolder 5404285Adams, Judd: Evaluations of program proposalsFolder 6404296Alam, Sterling: Family StudiesFolder 7404307Allison, Bob: Health PlanningFolder 8404318Crane, Robert M.: JSO-CriminologyFolder 9404329Conference on Education in Health ProfessionsFolder 104043310Griffin, Joyce: NursingFolder 114043411Hawes, Ed: Rural Life CenterFolder 124043512Don Klett: Computer ServicesFolder 134043613Lewis, Florence: Library Development for AAPFolder 144043714Midwest StudiesFolder 154043815Leader/SupportFolder 164043916CatalogsFolder 174044017Materials ObtainedFolder 184044118Schedules: January 1973Folder 194044219Schedules: December 1972Folder 204044320Schedules: November 1972Folder 214044421Schedules: October 1972Folder 224044522Schedules: September 1972Folder 234044623Schedules: August 1972Folder 244044724Schedules: July 1972Folder 254044825Lewis--Proposals/Re LibraryFolder 264044926RaukhorstFolder 274045027Larry ShinerFolder 284045128Wilshusen, JohnFolder 294045229Zeller, RobertFolder 304045330Academic Program, Board of Regents RegulationsFolder 314045431Academic Planning Program SpaceFolder 324045532Academic Planning Project OrganizationFolder 334045633Format for Program StatementsFolder 344045734Orientation Program LibraryFolder 354045835Requests for Materials to SSUFolder 364045936Tentative Calendar--first Conference on Education in the Health ProfessionsFolder 3740460May 197237Child, Family and Community ServicesFolder 384046138Computer ScienceFolder 394046239Creative ArtsFolder 404046340Health Services ManagementFolder 414046441Human Development CounselingFolder 424046542ManagementFolder 434046643MathematicsFolder 444046744Medical TechnologyFolder 454046845NursingFolder 464046946Operations ResearchFolder 474047047Physical SciencesFolder 484047148Social Justice ProfessionsFolder 494047249PersonnelFolder 504047350Program Proposals, ExamplesFolder 514047451Proposals--summariesFolder 524047552Crane, Robert M.  Social Justice and Higher Education in Illinois:  A Summary Report, Board of Higher EducationFolder 5340476September 197053Resource Analysis.  School of Criminal Justice, Michigan State UniversityFolder 5440477Fall 197154Proposal for Doctor of Philosophy Degree in MathematicsFolder 5540478August 197155Scope and ContentsPresented for approval to the Board of Regents by Northern Illinois UniversityProposal for Doctor of Philosophy Degree in Biological SciencesFolder 5640479August 197156Scope and ContentsPresented for approval to the Board of Regents by Northern Illinois UniversityComputer printout "Academic Planning Project" BibliographyFolder 57404801972-10-2657Computer Science Task Force ReportFolder 584048158

