<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.03.01/07Archon Finding Aid Title J.03.01/07UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:59:22 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J3/1/7. Academic Planning Program, 1970-1974
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    J.03.01/07
    419
    
      2.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1970-1974
    Date acquired: 10/04/1973
    1
    2
    3
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Program statements prepared  for the 1972 Academic Program Status Report and program proposals prepared for the Board of  Regents including the first drafts and edited versions,  prepared by  the Academic Planning Project, 1972-73.  
Programs include Administration, Biology, Children, Families &amp; Community Services, Communications in a Technological Society, Community Arts Management, Community Planning &amp; Area Development, Creative Arts, Economics, Environments and People, Experienced  teachers,  Health Services Administration, History,  Human Development Counseling, Individual Option,  Justice and the Social Order, Literature, Management,  Mathematical Systems,  Mathematics, Medical Technology, Nursing Physical Sciences, Political Studies, Psychology,  Public Affairs,  Public Affairs Reporting,  Social Justice Professions, Sociology/Anthropology, Teacher Preparation, and Work/Culture/Society.

Program Statements 1972-1973 from Box 1:
These are statements prepared by each program detailing its purpose, future plans, what the program has accomplished, etc.; these were prepared for the 1972 Academic Programs Status Report.  
Statements of the following programs are included:

Administration			   
Biology				        
Comm. in Tech. Soc.            
Economics			     
Environments and People    
History					
Human Development Counseling	   
Individual Option	
Justice and the Social Order
Literature
Mathematics
Political Studies
Psychology
Public Affairs Reporting
Sociology/Anthropology
Teacher Preparation
Work/Culture/Society  
  
    Arrangement Note
Program statements alphabetical, then program proposals in alphabetical order  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Florence Lewis, Bob Zeller, and Doug Kindschi  
  Box 1Box 140911Children, Families and Community Services, B.A and M.A.Folder 14089619731Scope and ContentsProgram statement: Master of Arts in Child Care Services.  
Minutes of Early Childhood Development study committee, October 17, 1972 when Child Care Services was presented.  
Child Care Services, Task Force review and recommendations, Oct. 23, 1972.  
Copy of suggestions for Childhood Studies Program from Marj VanderScheer. Dated Nov. 3, 1972 and sent to Bob Zeller.  
Proposal for a new unit of instruction: Family Studies Program, B.A. and M.A.  
Minutes of Family Study Committee, October 11, 1972 regarding review of Family Studies program proposal.  
"Mental Health Worker: Career Series" April 1970.  State of Illinois: Springfield, Department of Mental Health, 24 pp.  
Proposal for a Bachelor's Program in Community Service Careers. (John Nolte) copy and original. Rough Draft of Children, Families and Community Services program proposal including written revisions and paste-ups.  The CFCS proposal incorporates the previously Early Childhood Development Studies, the Family Studies, and the Community Services proposals.  
Proposal for a B.A. Degree and a M.A. Degree in children, Families and Community Services; presented for approval to the Board of Regents by SSU, Nov. 1972.  (Sophie Zimmerman copy with edited notes)  
Another copy of November 1972 proposal.  
Recommendations of the Program Review Task Force, Nov. 16, 1972.  
Final November 1972 proposal (same as Zimmerman copy).  
New Program: Children, Families, and Community Services, March 1973.Community Arts Management, M.A.Folder 2408972Scope and ContentsCAM Proposal 2 pp.
Community Arts Management:  Program Description
Proposal for a M.A. in Community Arts Management, October 1972. (2 copies)
Proposal for a M.A. in Community Arts Management, presented for approval to the Board of Regents, by SSU, Nov. 1972 (2 copies)Community Planning and Area Development, B.A. and M.A.Folder 3408983Scope and ContentsProposal for the Establishment of State and Local Planning and Policy Program Offering the B.A. and M.A. Degrees, Sangamon State University, Oct. 1972 (2 copies)
Program Review Task Force, State and Local Planning, recommendations and general comment, Oct. 23, 1972
Edited Proposal.
Another annotated and edited proposal--by Robert C. Spencer, Nov. 29, 1972
Proposal for a B.A. and M.A. Degree in Community Planning and Area Development, Presented for Approval to the Board of Regents by SSU, Nov. 1972.Creative Arts, B.A.Folder 4408994Scope and ContentsProposal for a B.A. in Interdisciplinary Arts, SSU, Oct.1972 (2 copies)
Edited Proposal.
Program Review Task Force, recommendations and general comment, Oct. 24, 1972
Proposal for a B.A. Degree in Creative Arts, Presented to the Board of Regents by SSU, Nov. 1972 (2 copies)
New Program: Creative Arts, March 1973Experienced Teachers Program (not approved)Folder 5409005Scope and ContentsProposal for the Establishment of a M.A. for Experienced Teachers Program, SSU, Oct. 1972Health Services Administration, B.A.; Health Administration and Planning, M.A.Folder 6409016Scope and ContentsProgram proposal for Health Services Administration by Robert F. Allison, Aug. 24, 1972
Sangamon State University, Programs in Allied Health.
Recommendations and general comments of Program Review Task Force, Dec. 7, 1972
Draft copy, Proposal for a B.A. in Health Services Administration and a M.A. in Health Administration and Planning, presented to the Board of Regents, SSU, Nov. 1972
Same as above, Nov. 1972 (2 copies) not labelled "Draft copy"
New Program: Health Services Administration, March 1973Management, B.A.Folder 7409027Scope and ContentsProposal for the Establishment of a two year Program Leading to a B.A. Degree in Management, Sept. 1972
Same as above, edited draft.
Program Review Task Force, general comments and recommendations, Oct. 23, 1972
Proposal for a B.A. Degree in Management, presented for approval to the Board of Regents, SSU, Nov. 1972 (2 copies)
A Bachelor of Arts Degree in Management at SSU for Fall Quarter 1973, a Brief and General Description, Jan. 10, 1973
A Bachelor of Arts Degree in Management, presented for Approval to the Board of Higher Education by the Board of Regents, March 1973Mathematical Systems, B.A. and M.A.Folder 8409038Scope and ContentsFirst Draft of proposal, Aug. 25, 1972
Second Draft of proposal, Sept. 25, 1972
Proposal for the Establishment of a Computer Science Program offering the B.A. and M.A. Degrees, SSU, Oct. 1, 1972 (2 copies)
Minutes of Computer Science Program and Operations Research/System Analysis committee, Oct. 10, 1972
Program Review Task Force, Computer Science, comments and recommendations, Oct. 10, 1972
Proposal for a B.A. and M.A. in Computer Science Option in Mathematical Systems, presented for approval to the Board of Regents by SSU, Nov. 1972. (edited version)
Proposal for the Establishment of B.A. and M.A. programs in Operations Research/Systems Analysis, Sept. 25, 1972. (2 copies)
Mathematics Program: description and statement of 	purpose.
Program Review Task Force, comment and recommendations, Operations Research/Systems Analysis, Oct. 24, 1972
Proposal for a B.A. and M.A. Degree for Program Options in Operations Research/Systems Analysis in the Mathematical Systems Program, presented for approval to the Board of Regents by SSU, Nov. 1972.
Proposal for a B.A. and M.A. in Mathematical Systems and Expansion of the Mathematics Program to Include Options in: Computer Science and Operations Research/Systems Analysis, presented for approval to the Board of Regents by SSU, Nov. 1972.Medical Technology, M.A.Folder 9409049Scope and ContentsMedical Technology Program (2 copies)
Description of the Program, Nov. 20, 1972 (marked OLD)
Program Review Task Force, comments and recommendations, Medical Technology, Nov. 16, 1972.
Proposal for a B.A. and a M.A. in Medical Technology, presented for approval to the Board of Regents by SSU, Nov. 1972.
Proposal for a B.A. and a M.A. in Medical Technology, presented for approval to the BOR by SSU, March 1973.
New Program: Medical Technology, March 1973Nursing, B.A. and M.A.Folder 104090510Scope and ContentsProgram Proposed for a Baccalaureate Program in Nursing submitted to Director of Academic Planning, Draft 2, September, 25, 1972 by Joyce Z. Griffin, Project Director.
Proposal for a Baccalaureate and Masters Degree Program in Nursing submitted by Project Director, Joyce Z. Griffin.
Same as above, edited version, of President Robert C. Spencer with comments and notes.
Report on Hearing of Nursing Program Proposal, Oct. 16, 1972 (Florence Lewis minutes)
Report on Hearings of the nursing program proposal, Oct. 16, 1972 (Joyce Griffin version)
Program Review Task Force, comments and recommendations, Nov. 14, 1972
Proposal for a B.A. and M.A. Degree Program in Nursing, presented for approval to the Board of Regents by SSU, Nov 1972.Physical Sciences, B.A.Folder 114090611Scope and ContentsProposal for the Establishment of a Physical Sciences Program Leading to a B.A. Degree at SSU, Sept. 1972 (2 copies)
Edited copy of proposal.
Program Review Task force, Physical Sciences, General Comments and Recommendations, Oct. 23, 1972.
Physical Sciences Program Hearing, Oct. 9, 1972
Proposal for a B.A. in Physical Sciences, presented for approval to the Board of Regents by SSU, Nov. 1972. (2 copies)Public Affairs, B.A. and M.A.Folder 124090712Scope and ContentsProposal for a Bachelor's Program in Values and Public Affairs. (3 copies)
Proposal for the Establishment of an Undergraduate and a Graduate Degree in Public Affairs, Oct. 1972. (2 copies)
Public Affairs Degree, program meeting, Oct. 13, 1972
Program Review Task Force, general comments and recommendations, Oct. 13, 1972
Memorandum of Nov. 3, 1972 from Phil Kendall accepting appointment to the Public Affairs Program Committee by Doug Kindschi.
Proposal for and Undergraduate and a Graduate Degree in Public Affairs, presented for approval to the Board of Regents by SSU, Nov. 1972.
Proposal for a B.A. and a M.A. in Public Affairs, presented for approval to the Board of Regents, Nov. 1972.Social Justice Professions, B.A. and M.A.Folder 134090813Scope and ContentsProposal for a Bachelor's and Master's Program in Social and Criminal Justice at SSU.
Program Review Task Force, general comment and recommendations, Oct. 24, 1972.
Social and Criminal Justice Committee meeting, Oct. 9, 1972.
Proposal for a B.A. and a M.A. in Social Justice Professions, presented for approval to the Board of Regents by SSU, Nov. 1972.Program StatementsFolder 14409091972-7314Memo: Comments and recommendations from Program Review Task Force on the 13 Program ProposalsFolder 1540910October 197215Box 2Box 240912Child Care Services; Community Service CareersFolder 140913ca. 19721Management; Accounting and AuditingFolder 2409141972-732Business and Accounting ProgramsFolder 34091519723Community Arts Management; Interdisciplinary ArtsFolder 44091619724ArtsFolder 5409171972-735Allied HealthFolder 64091819726Planning FormsFolder 740919ca. 19737Planning Project Orientation ProgramFolder 84092019728Related ArticlesFolder 9409211970-719Status ReportFolder 1040922197210Rural Life CenterFolder 1140923197211Social and Criminal JusticeFolder 1240924197212Values and Public AffairsFolder 1340925197213Program Development InformationFolder 1440926197214Academic Program Reports BORFolder 1540927197215Checklist for Program ProposalsFolder 1640928ca. 197216Format for DocumentsFolder 17409291972-7317Guidelines for the Review of New Programs from Senior InstitutionsFolder 18409301972-03-0718Correspondence to Dr. Ralph Lundgren, BHEFolder 19409311973-01-1219Program Revisions: GeneralFolder 20409321971-05-2420Program StatementsFolder 2140933197221Academic Policy GuideFolder 2240934Summer 197222Program for Experienced TeachersFolder 23409351972-7323General Studies ProgramFolder 24409361972-7324Health Services AdministrationFolder 25409371972-7325Mental Health; Helping ProfessionsFolder 2640938ca. 197226The Helping Professions of Community ServicesFolder 2740939197227Midwest Studies Task ForceFolder 2840940197228Computer Science Program ProposalFolder 29409411970-10-0129Computer ScienceFolder 3040942197230Sangamon State University New Academic Program ProposalsFolder 3140943March 197331Scope and Contents(1 of 11) New Academic Programs for Fall 1973Sangamon State University New Academic Program ProposalsFolder 3240944March 197332Scope and Contents(2 of 11) proposal #4 Nursing B.A. and M.A.Sangamon State University New Academic Program ProposalsFolder 3340945March 197333Scope and Contents(3 of 11) proposal #5 Medical Technology B.A. &amp; M.A.Sangamon State University New Academic Program ProposalsFolder 3440946March 197334Scope and Contents(4 of 11) proposal #6 Health Services Administration B.A; Health Administration and Planning M.A.Sangamon State University New Academic Program ProposalsFolder 3540947March 197335Scope and Contents(5 of 11) proposal #7 Management B.A.Sangamon State University New Academic Program ProposalsFolder 3640948March 197336Scope and Contents(6 of 11) proposal #8 Mathematical Systems B.A &amp; M.A.Sangamon State University New Academic Program ProposalsFolder 3740949March 197337Scope and Contents(7 of 11) proposal #9 Social Justice Professions B.A. and M.A.Sangamon State University New Academic Program ProposalsFolder 3840950March 197338Scope and Contents(8 of 11) proposal #10 Public Affairs B.A. and M.A.Sangamon State University New Academic Program ProposalsFolder 3940951March 197339Scope and Contents(9 of 11) proposal #11 Community Planning and Area Development B.A. and M.A.Sangamon State University New Academic Program ProposalsFolder 4040952March 197340Scope and Contents(10 of 11) proposal #12 Children, Families and Community Services B.A. and M.A.Sangamon State University New Academic Program ProposalsFolder 4140953March 197341Scope and Contents(11 of 11) proposal #13 Creative Arts B.A.Proposal for B.A. in Creative ArtsFolder 4240954197242Proposal for M.A. in Community Arts ManagementFolder 4340955November 197243Proposal for B.A. in Health Services AdministrationFolder 4440956Nov. 197244Proposal for B.A. in ManagementFolder 4540957Nov. 197245Proposal for B.B in Medical TechnologyFolder 4640958Nov. 197246Public AffairsFolder 4740959Nov. 197247Proposal for B.A. in Physical SciencesFolder 4840960Nov. 197248AdministrationFolder 49409611972, 197449Communications in Technological Society, n.d.Folder 504096250History ProgramFolder 5140963197551Literature Program, n.d.Folder 524096452Teacher PreparationFolder 5340965Sept. 197253North Central Association Report of a VisitFolder 54409661972, Nov. 6-854Operations Research and Computer ScienceFolder 55409671972-7355Proposal for the William Chamberlain Memorial School of LawFolder 5640968Dec. 197456Box 3Box 340969NursingFolder 140970Jan. 19731Nursing (1 of 2)Folder 2409711972-732Nursing (2 of 2)Folder 3409721972-733Community Planning (1 of 2)Folder 4409731971-734Community Planning (2 of 2)Folder 5409741971-735Community Planning and Area DevelopmentFolder 640975Nov. 19726Information--Zeller's Office: Research for CFCS ProgramFolder 740976ca. 19727Children, Families, and Community ServicesFolder 84097719728

