<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.05.01/05Archon Finding Aid Title J.05.01/05UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:59:38 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J5/1/5. Dean of Public Affairs Grant Project File, 1973-1980
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    J.05.01/05
    427
    
      0.66 Cubic Feet
    
    1973-1980
    Date acquired: 02/28/1991
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The Dean of Public Affairs-Grant Project File, 1973-80, contains grant proposals, budgets, and other documents concerning Pre-College Teacher Training Program, CETA Inquiry Center, Advanced Management Study, SSU Young People's Theatre, "Reading, Writing and Radios", workshops, educational policy Fellows Programs and Career/Education Information Center.  The file also contains Public Services External Education, Illinois State Theatre, Improvement of Post Secondary Education, and the Exxon Impact Program.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Philip W. Kendall  
  Box 1Box 136851Public Services: Capital Career CenterFolder 13685219731PA: Title VIII DevelopmentFolder 236853AY77-19762PA: Pre-College Teacher Training Program (NSF)Folder 33685419763Public Services: External education Ill. Offices of Education "Right to Read" effortFolder 4368551974-764AP'S PS: Streetside Booster Project (SPFLD Community Dev. Program; Michael Townsend)Folder 5368561977-795Non-PA: Springboard: Springfield Arts Study (P.Gregg),Folder 6368571978-796Project Propos¬als: Illinois Humanities Council (Lynda Toth)Folder 73685819777A.P. Grants: Nimh: M.A. in Gerontology/Mental Health of the Aging (H.J. Berman)Folder 83685919778P.A.: Non-Public Affairs Projects: Lincoln &amp; American Public (Illinois Humanities Council. Breiseth)Folder 93686019799Projects: CETA Youth craft (SPFLD/Sang county community action agency   E.L.Hawes)Folder 1036861197810PA: CETA Inquiry Center (Richard Mckenzie)Folder 1136862197811PA: Non-DPA Grants: Central Illinois Arts ConsortiumFolder 1236863197812PA: Advanced Management Study (Corp. Public Broadcasting) (Dale Ouzts)Folder 1336864197713DPA: Proposals/Grants for Academic Programs' ActivitiesFolder 1436865197614PA: Theatre of the UnemployedFolder 15368661977-7815PA: SSU Young People's TheatreFolder 1636867197716Public Service: Illinois State TheatreFolder 17368681975-7917PA Theatre: CETA, Sangamon-Cass ConsortiumFolder 18368691978-7918Public Affairs: The Arts-Springfield Area Youth OrchestraFolder 19368701975-7619PA: Science and Illinois Executive Branch (Dick Sames- Institute for Environmental Quality)Folder 2036871197720Public: Rauckhorst NSF Grant: Chemical, physics of molecular, Atomic &amp; Ionic ProcessesFolder 2136872197521Box 2Box 236873PA: "Reading, Writing, and Radio" Jacqueline JacksonFolder 1368741978-801Public Services: Improvement of Post Secondary EducationFolder 2368751972-742Public Affairs: Illinois Humanities CouncilFolder 33687619763PA: Workshop: Retirement Ill. Dept. on Aging (Lesnoff-Caravaglia)Folder 43687719774PA: Practicum for older people Ill. Dept. on Aging (Lesnoff-Caravaglia)Folder 53687819785PA: Early Retirement Study, Fiat-Allis Employees: Harry Berman, GerontologyFolder 63687919786Public Services: Exxon Impact Program Grant: Guided Design Project-CrowleyFolder 7368801975-777PA: Education Policy Fellows Program (IBHE)Folder 8368811976-788PA: Education Policy Fellows Program (IOE)Folder 93688219769PA: Education Policy Fellows-IOEFolder 10368839/1/1977-8/31/197810PA: Education Policy Fellows-IBHEFolder 11368849/1/1977-8/31/197811Public Affairs: Education Policy Fellowship Program (Formerly Washington Interns)Folder 12368851973-7712Public Services: Educational Information and Services Center  (Joint SSU-LLCC)Folder 1336886197413PA: Career/Education Information Center (FIPSE)Folder 1436887197714

