<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.05.01/15Archon Finding Aid Title J.05.01/15UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:59:45 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J5/1/15. Continuing Education Conference Programs
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    
      Continuing Education
    
    J.05.01/15
    429
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1980-1999
    1980-1988
    Date acquired: 10/01/1999
    1
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This file contains brochures, publicity releases, and programs on conferences sponsored by the Office of Continuing Education.  Topics include vegetarianism, tenure, nursing, money, astronomy, energy, international economics, and race relations.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Sherral Clark, OCE  
  
    Custodial History
After obtaining permission from Conference Services (formerly Continuing Ed.) archives staff weeded this collection: we retained pamphlets/brochures, programs, and publicity and we destroyed financial records, planning correspondence, and evaluation materials. Chris Schnell, December 15, 2017.  
  
    Press Releases
    Programs
    Flyers/Brochures
  
  Box 1Box 137460Continuing Education Conference ProgramsFolder 13746119801Sixth Annual Gerontology InstituteItem 186866March-April 198011Illinois Department of Corrections, School District #428 Annual Teachers Institute: "Working Together in the 80's"Item 286871August 19-21, 198012Crossroads 80: Conference on Illinois Government and PoliticsItem 386876October 2-4, 198013Law and the Handicapped: A ConferenceItem 486881October 24-25, 198014Scope and ContentsIncludes a document in braille.Continuing Education Conference ProgramsFolder 23746219812Therapeutic Drug Monitoring: A Laboratory ApproachItem 186886January 30, 198121Passage to Professionalism: A Conference for Secretaries and Support StaffItem 286891February 7, 198122Conference on Legislative ProcessItem 386896February 20, 198123The 1980 Presidential Election (lecture series): "Interpreting the Illinois Elections of 1980"Item 486901February 25, 198124Scope and ContentsSpeakers: Peter Colby and Paul GreenExploring Vegetarianism: A WorkshopItem 586906March 5-6, 1981251981 Intercession: Public Affairs Colloquium: The Energy DecadeItem 686911March 14-21, 198126Busing to Improve CommunicationItem 786916March-April 198127Scope and ContentsCommunication skills in pupil transportion workshop; includes photos of participants and speaker.Seventh Annual Gerontology InstituteItem 886921March-April 198128Realms of Inquiry: The Scholarly Quest, an Enrichment Program for high school juniors and seniorsItem 986926March-April 198129Conference on Computers: Privacy and Public InterestItem 1086931April 3, 1981210Women in Higher Education AdaministrationItem 1186936April 3, 1981211Third Annual Institute on Teaching the Illinois State ConstitutionItem 1286941May 15-16, 1981212Vital Spirits of the 20th Century: Molders of the Modern MoodItem 1386946April-June 1981213The Indochinese Patient: Understanding and Assessing NeedsItem 1486951June 2, 1981214Management workshop: Ways to SucceedItem 1586956August 20-21, 1981215Successful Funding in the 80s: How to Compete for Federal and Private GrantsItem 1686961July 27-28, 1981216The Electronic Classroom: Sharing Media-based Instructional MaterialsItem 1786966September 25, 1981217Microcomputers in Elementary and Secondary EducationFolder 1886971September-October 1981218How to Succeed in Business by Really Trying: A Conference for Women in Small BusinessItem 1986976October 3, 1981219Small Business Workshop SeriesItem 2086981October-November 1981220Scope and ContentsIncludes program for "Getting Started: Basic Information Starting your own Business"Public Relations Society of America Professional Development WorkshopsItem 2186986October 30, 1981221Preventing and Coping with BurnoutItem 2286991November 5-6, 1981222Women's Studies 1981 Fall Workshop SeriesItem 2386996September-November 1981223Illinois CPA Foundation: Economic Recovery Tax Act SeminarsItem 2487001December 10, 1981224Operations Research Techniques in Local and State Government: An Intensive WorkshopItem 2587006December 2-3, 1981225SSU International Studies Committee: The Middle East ConferenceItem 2687011December 4-5, 1981226Continuing Education Conference ProgramsFolder 33746319823Operations Research WorkshopItem 187016January 27-28, 198231Network Intervention Strategies: Alternative Methods of Human Services DeliveryItem 287021March 4, 198232Seminar on Legislative ProcessItem 387026March 26, 198233Problem Solving for Managers and Administrators: A Workshop in Developing and Applying Planning SkillsItem 487031April-May 198234Elderly Abuse and Neglect ConferenceItem 587036April 29, 198235Coronary Artery Disease: State of the ArtItem 687041May 5, 198236Dermatology Workshop for Primary Care NursesItem 787046May 14, 198237Eighth Annual Gerontology InstituteItem 887051April 2-3, 198238Clinical Supervision WorkshopItem 987056June 1-3, 198239Issues in Adult Development SeminarItem 1087061June 11-13, 1982310Tenure WorkshopItem 1187066September 24, 1982311First Annual State Evaluation Network ConferenceItem 1287071September 30, 1982312Economic Data: Practical Application, A ConferenceItem 1387076October 22, 1982313Energy Strategies for Illinois Local Governments and Communities (a conference)Item 1487081November 8-9, 1982314The Social Service Executive and the LawItem 1587086November 17-18, 1982315Scope and ContentsThe Illinois Association of Community Action Agencies and SSU Center for Community and Regional StudiesContinuing Education Conference ProgramsFolder 43746419834Explaining the Economy: A WorkshopItem 187126February 26, 198341Price/Risk Management in AgricultureItem 287091March 198342The Professional Development of the Individual Nurse: A ConferenceItem 387096March 12, 198343Time Management Workshop for LibrariansItem 487101March 17, 198344Seminar on Legislative ProcessItem 587106March 18, 198345Adding Herstory to HistoryItem 687111March 18, 198346Illinois Oral History ConferenceItem 787116April 15, 198347Peeks, Pokes, and Pointers: A Two-Day Conference for Teachers and AdministratorsItem 887121April 14-15, 198348Arbitration: A Workshop for ProfessionalsItem 987131April 28-30, 198349Grantsmanship WorkshopItem 1087136April 30, 1983410Commuity Support Programs for the Chronically Mentally IllItem 1187141May 16, 1983411Using Your Camera Effectively: Mechanics, Materials, &amp; Creative CompositionItem 1287146June-July 1983412Literature Through Women's EyesItem 1387151October 13, 1983413First IDEA ConferenceItem 1487156October 14-15, 1983414Scope and ContentsIDEA: Illinois Drug Education AllianceTeaching Techniques for Health ProfessionalsItem 1587161October 23-25, 1983(?)415Current Legal Issues for Public Administrators and OfficialsItem 1687166October 1983-April 1984416Grievance and Arbitration WorkshopsItem 1787171October 29, 1983417Pathways to a New Future: Alternative Admissions, Credit for Prior Learning, Success Skills Series, CLEPItem 18871761983418Cardiovascular Nursing Update: Assessment, Treatment, and Nursing InterventionItem 1987181Fall 1983-Spring 1984419Continuing Education Conference ProgramsFolder 53746519845Agricultural Price Risk Management SeminarItem 187186February-March 198451Illinios Women in GovernmentItem 287191April 6-8, 198452Third Annual Operations Research Applications ConferenceItem 387196April 25, 198453Microcomputer Management for School Administrators: Microcomputers: Harnessing Their PotentialItem 487201March-May 198454SSU Computer CampsItem 587206July 198455Scope and ContentsSummer camps for children 9-12 years in age.A Training Breakfast for the Working Community on Stress ManagementItem 687211June-July 198456The Sangamon Institute on Arts AdministrationItem 787216July 16-27, 198457Illinois Senior Citizen Advocacy ConferenceItem 887221August 1-3, 198458Special Skills, Special Knowledge (public relations workshops)Item 987226November 2, 198459Micro-Computer Applications Training Program (MAT): Making Computers Work for Non-Profit OrganizationsItem 1087231November 14-15, 1984510Micro-Computer Applications Training Program (MAT): Computer Basics for Non-EnthusiastsItem 1187236November-December 1984511Agricultural Price Risk Management Seminar: A New Dimension: Futures, Options, Forward PricingItem 1287241November-December 1984512How to Cut Your Home Energy BillItem 1387246November-December 1984513Continuing Education Conference ProgramsFolder 63746619856Beginning PotteryItem 187251February-March 198561Managing to Write: A Workshop for Busy Poeple who have an Unscratched Writing ItchItem 287256February 23, 198562Collective Bargaining Skills Workshop for Public Sector Personnel: Labor and ManagementItem 387261February-March 198563Seminar on Legislative ProcessItem 487266March 15, 198564Business and Technical Writing WorkshopItem 587271March-April 198565Business and Technical Writing (Workshops) I &amp; IIItem 687276April-May 198566Micro-Computer Applications Training Program (MAT): Micro-Computer Application in Management and Data ProcessingItem 787281April 2-4, 198567A Symposium: The Economics of Defense: Defense Spending, How Much is Enough?Item 887286April 19, 198568Micro-Computer Applications Training Program (MAT): Computer Basics for Non-EnthusiastsItem 987291April-May 198569Clinical Oncology Update: Pathophysiology of CancerItem 1087296April 24, 1985610Scope and ContentsSSU Nursing Continuing Education (?)Counseling the Gifted: A Practical Approach for ParentsItem 1187301June 13-14, 1985611SSU Computer CampItem 1287306July-August 1985612Scope and ContentsSummer camp for children 9-12 years old. Photos transferred to S1/1/3 under "Computer Camp."Seek and Ye Shall Find: An Archaeological View of Old Testament DiscoveriesItem 1387311September-October 1985613Management Skills for Women DoctorsItem 1487316September 21, 1985614StART New Waves to Learning (conference on art education)Item 1587321November 7, 1985615Comets for EveryoneItem 1687326October-December 1985616Scope and ContentsCharles Schweighauser and Halley's Comet. Includes a copy of Certificate of AchievementLeadership Skills for the Staff NurseItem 1787331Fall 1985 to Spring 1986617Micro-Computer Application Training at SSUItem 1887336Fall 1985-Spring 1986618Continuing Education Conference ProgramsFolder 73746719867The Rights of Victims: Intimidation and Threatened Violence (A Statewide Working Symposium)Item 187341February 20-21, 198671Public Sector Collective BargainingItem 287346March 1, 198672Teaching the Adult Learner in Higher EducationItem 387351March 12-14, 198673Second Annual SSU StoryfestItem 487356April 10-11, 198674Scope and ContentsFeatured Elizabeth Ellis, Jim May, Dan Keding, and Dr. Cricket (SSU professor David Hilligoss).Public Speaking: An Eight Week "on your feet" CourseItem 587361April-May 198675Patient Teaching: Bridging the GapsItem 687366April 10, 198676Scope and ContentsIncludes nursing continuing education certificate.CPA Review Course (Person-Wolinsky CPA Review Courses of New York)Item 787371August-November 198677Scope and ContentsProgram put on by Professional Development Associates (Peoria, IL) and SSU.The Second Illinois Senior Citizen Leadership ConferenceItem 887376August 198678Scope and ContentsSponsored by SSU Gerontology Dept., Continuing Ed., and Senior Citizen Advocacy Division, Office of the Illinois Attorney General, Neil F. HartiganFood, Fun, &amp; Chef Luis ("SSU's first gourmet cooking class!")Item 987381September-October 198679Scope and ContentsLuis Villamonte was Chief Executive Chef at Maldaner's among other places.Food, Fun, &amp; Chef Luis: A World Tour in Gourmet CookingItem 1087386September-October 1986710Continuing Education Conference ProgramsFolder 83746819878Changing Roles of Early Childhood and Special Education Personnel: A New PartnerhsipItem 187391March 6-7, 198781Scope and ContentsIncludes the program for the Chicago conference schedule (March 27-28, 1987).Using Freudian and Jungian Dream Interpretation with your Clients: A Workshop for Mental Health ProfessionialsItem 287396April 21, 198782Public Information Officers and the News MediaItem 387401June 5, 198783Scope and ContentsCo-sponsored by Illinois Department of Central Management ServicesContinuing Education Conference ProgramsFolder 9374691988-19999Internal Organizing: Membership Strategies for Local UnionsItem 187406February-March 198891Scope and ContentsTeleconference with a Chicago site. Co-sponsored by the Illinois AFL-CIO and SSU Department of Labor RelationsAdministrative Rulemaking Policies &amp; Politics in Illinois (An Intensive Workshop)Item 287411May 23-24, 198892Helping Clients Deal With LossItem 387416May 23, 199693Scope and ContentsInteractive video conference also involving sites in Bloomington/Normal, Peoria, and Oglesby.The Global Economy: Promises and Perils (A Conference)Item 487421October 23, 199794Scope and ContentsPresenters included: James Tobin, Robert Z. Aliber, Edwin M. Truman, and SSU economics professor Roy Wehrle.Volunteer Fire Service: Illinois SummitItem 587426November 9-10, 199995Scope and ContentsOffice of the Illinois State Fire Marshal and Fire Service Institute, University of Illinois.LCPC Examination Preparation CourseItem 687431March 199996Scope and ContentsThe National Clinical Mental Health Counseling Exam.Therapy with African American Families: A Live Session with Dr. Kenneth V. HardyItem 787436November 12, 199997Continuing Education: miscellaneous documents, memos, brochuresFolder 1037470c. 1982-198610Scope and ContentsIncudes two packets of information about Continuing Ed. for clients.Continuing Education: Publicity and handsouts for "Crossroads 82" (A Conference on Illinois Government and Politics)Folder 1137471c. 198211Publicity and Handouts for "If Not Now, When?" (a conference on race relations in Illinois)Folder 1237472March 198412Scope and ContentsIncludes poster with registration cards, 8"x10" headshots of participants. Conference included civil rights leader Mary Berry.

