<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.08.06/200Archon Finding Aid Title J.08.06/200UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:01:22 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J8/6/200. Health Services Administration, Student Papers, 1972-1984
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    J.08.06/200
    438
    
      1.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1972-1984
    Date acquired: 00/00/1989
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Student papers written for class in Health Services Administration program, 1972-84; primarily residency report and other research papers dealing with aspects of the Adminisration of hospitals, nursing homes, health departments, and other health care facilities.  For problem solving papers and master's theses from the Health Services Admin program, see J54/45.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  Box 1Box 166570Akinwunmi, Ganiyu. A Study On How A 100 Bed Voluntary Hospital Could Achieve The Best Quality CareFolder 16657119761Allison, Sue. A Study of Home Health Care for St. John HospitalFolder 26657219832Allison, Sue. A Study of Medicaid as It Effects The Community Health Improvement CenterFolder 36657319823Allison, Sue. Marketing Concepts for HospitalsFolder 46657419834Behrens, Gregory. An Evaluative Study to Determine If New Antibiotics Offer Significant Advantages In Patient Care That Justify Their Higher Costs To The Patients Treated At St. Mary HospitalFolder 566575August 19815Behrens, Gregory. A Study To Evaluate The Quality Of The Centralized Intravenous Admixture Service At St Mary Hospital, Quincy, Illinois &amp; To Assess Its Measure Of Quality Against Similar HospitalsFolder 666576May 19816Clark, Cynthia. Early Detection of Infectious AgentsFolder 7665771977/05/027Cole, Betty. Management by Objective in a Nursing Service DepartmentFolder 866578April 19758Cole, Teawana M. Unit Dose: A Drug Distribution System That Has Been Cost Containing for the State of Illinois Department of Mental Health &amp; Developmental DisabilitiesFolder 966579Spring 19869Colgan, Kevin John. Computer Committee Galesburg Cottage Hospital: The Committee ProcessFolder 10665801984/05/1110Dronsfield, John. Daily Journal &amp; Residency ProposalFolder 1166581198011Dronsfield, John. Development of an Effective Staff Orientation Program at Springfield Community HospitalFolder 1266582198012Dunn, Randy. Materials, Managements as it Relates to Hospital CostFolder 1366583197513Dunn, Randy. The Foundation for Medical Care of Central Illinois: its effect on the attitude of a portion of Sangamon County residents concerning present and proposed methods of Medical Insurance coverageFolder 1466584197414Easley, Jerilynn. A Critical Analysis of the Nursing Management Practices in the Lewisville Area Hospital, Lewisville, IllinoisFolder 1566585198015Edordu, Paul A. Cost of Catastrophic Illiness - The U.S. Health IndustryFolder 16665861979/03/1616Edordu, Paul A. National Health InsuranceFolder 17665871979/04/0217Frandsen, Viola M. Mental Health Belongs in a Comprehensive Nationa Health Care SystemFolder 186658818Frandsen, Viola M. Behavior Modification - Personal Behavioral Problem - Self-control &amp; Weight Loss - Eating &amp; Exercise ControlFolder 19665891974/02/2619Frandsen, Viola M.  Behavior Modification - Public Affairs Project - CarpoolsFolder 206659020Frandsen, Viola M. Mental Health Management Belongs in a Comprehensive National-health Care SystemFolder 2166591197621Frandsen, Viola M. Organizational Behavior - The Presentation of Self in Everyday LifeFolder 226659222Frandsen, Viola M. Organizational Behavior - The TrialFolder 236659323Frandsen, Viola M.  Sweden - Health SystemFolder 246659424Fraser, Karen. A Comparison of Hospital Responses to Continuing Education Needs of EmployeesFolder 2566595197925Fraser, Karen. A Small Group Analysis for Organizational DynamicsFolder 2666596197926Box 2Box 266597Gifford, Donna L. Workbook on Library Usage – Community Health OrganizationsFolder 1665991Gilmer, Robert. Life and Times at Nesset Health Center Park Ridge ILFolder 2666002Gilmer, Robert. Overview of the Effects a Prospective Pricing System will have on the Budgeting ProcessFolder 3666013Gilmer, Robert. Transformation Residency ReportFolder 4666021985/11/254Grant, Gilbert. Operation Review of the Cook County Hospital and Recommendations for ImprovementFolder 56660319805Gutzman, Charles. Health Services in AustraliaFolder 66660419806Gutzman, Charles. Licensure &amp; Credentialing of Health PersonnelFolder 76660519727Gutzman, Charles. The Interoganizational Environment as Influenced by Role Sets and Organization InterdependenceFolder 8666068Hawley, Helen M. Health Care Facilities Involvement in Professional Employee Education,Folder 9666071974/05/029Iguodaia, Frank. A New Career Model in a City Public Health DepartmentFolder 1066608197910Jenkins, Morris. Administration of School Health Programs: East St Louis Senior High SchoolFolder 11666091983/11/2811Jenkins, Morris. Children and DeathFolder 12666101982/03/1012Jenkins, Morris. Death and DyingFolder 13666111981/04/1813Jenkins, Morris. Medical EthicsFolder 14666121982/09/2914Jenkins, Morris. Nutrition In Nursing HomesFolder 15666131982-12-0115Jenkins, Morris. People Are Very PreciousFolder 16666141983/08/0116Jenkins, Morris. Policy Argument Proposal Paper: National Health InsuranceFolder 17666151983/03/0317Jenkins, Morris. Prestige of Health Education Within the Health Care System &amp; Does Man Have A FutureFolder 18666161983/01/2418Jenkins, Morris. The British Hospice ConceptFolder 19666171982/12/0119Jenkins, Morris. The Legal Foundation of Food Additives - Research ProjectFolder 20666181983/03/0720King, Dale George. AccountingFolder 21666191983/10/3121King, Dale George. A Study to Examine the Recruitment Program of the United States Army Medical DepartmentFolder 2266620December 198322Kuyoro, Olabisi A.  A Research Papers to Fulfil a Requirement for Master's Degree in Health AdministrationFolder 236662123Kuyoro, Olabisi A.  An Outlook on Nursing Home OrganizationFolder 246662224Kuyoro, Olabisi A. Critique of Book: Hospital &amp; Nursing Home ManagementFolder 256662325Kuyoro, Olabisi A. To Examine the Over-Utilization of the Emergency Room by Patients at Cook County Hospital in ChicagoFolder 266662426Law, Gerald. Hypertension - The Silent KillerFolder 2766625Summer 197627Lehn, John P. A Study of Immunization Levels in Kindergarten Children in Macon County: Where Provider Services May Be NeededFolder 28666261979/04/1128Lehn, John P. Program EvaluationFolder 29666271979/05/0229Manju, Jenveja. Turnover and Productivity in Nursing HomesFolder 306662830Box 3Box 366598Medlin, Robert L.  Tutorial Accounting for Health AdministrationFolder 1666291979/04/161Miskowice, Donald P.  LeadershipFolder 2666301979/12/072Momoh, Anthony John. A Commentary on Environmental Problems in MedicineFolder 3666313Momoh, Anthony John. An Outline on Public Health Administration and PracticeFolder 466632Summer 19794Mulcahy, William E. Admin. &amp; Org. Grp. Processes - Conflict in Reorg. &amp; Eval. Account &amp; Open SystemFolder 5666335Mull, Robert L. Trauma and the HospitalFolder 6666346Petnuch, Claudia. Application of Administration ConceptFolder 7666357Portues, Robert. Factor Governing the Requirement of Physicians in the Rural CommunityFolder 8666368Rather, Sister Mary Elizabeth. Evaluation of a Course in Clinical Pastoral Education in Health MinistryFolder 9666371973/07/139Rudis, George. Critique of: A Spy In the House of MedicineFolder 10666381977/03/0110Sago, Glen. Recommendation for Assisting with Physicians Placement in Ashland, Il By Springfield's Community HospitalFolder 116663911Schoening, Karen. A Case In Defense of Free Enterprise MedicineFolder 126664012Schoening, Karen. Book Report: The Road to RecoveryFolder 136664113Schoening, Karen. How Does Our System of Wealth &amp; Power Maintain Itself?  What Are Its Mechanisms &amp; Ideology?Folder 146664214Schoening, Karen. Rural Hospitals - Problems in PerspectiveFolder 156664315Schoening, Karen. The Cooperate Liability of a Hospital for Physicians on Its StaffFolder 166664416Schoening, Karen. The Health Insurance Industry &amp; Its Role in the Health Care SystemFolder 176664517Schuerman, Mariann. Employee Performance Apraisal at Memorial Medical CenterFolder 186664618Skaggs, George R. Humana Incorporated Growth PoliciesFolder 196664719Skaggs, George R. Management Care 111Folder 206664820Skaggs, George R. System Philosophy - Managaement Core 303Folder 216664921Speck, Richard.  A Comparison of Two Health Care Systems-Argentina &amp; FinlandFolder 2266650August 197722Speck, Richard. An Analysis of Leading Health Issues As Seen by Influential Community LeadersFolder 23666511977-11-0123Speck, Richard. Environmental Services at Brookwood Hospital - A Case StudyFolder 24666521977-03-0124Speck, Richard. Feasibility Study for Pulmonary Rehabilitation Program at Baptist Medical Center - MontclairFolder 256665325Speck, Richard. Social Service Departments: An Annotated BibliographyFolder 26666541977/08/0126Steinhauser, J.R. Worker Alienation, Communications, &amp; the Development of TeamworkFolder 27666551973/08/1327Strom, Lois. A Case Study of Grants Administration at Southern Il. UniversityFolder 286665628Thompson, Phillip. Health Care in SwedenFolder 296665729Thomson, Clifford S. Quality Assurance in Rural Health SettingFolder 30666581980/12/1030Williams, Lawrence E. A Case Study in Health Planning" A Third General Hospital in Springfield?Folder 3166659Summer 197431Williams, Lawrence E. An Analysis &amp; Perspective on the Health System of IcelandFolder 3266660 October 197432Williams, Lawrence E. Program Analysis of Human System Technique Unit Payment System - Dept. of Mental Health &amp; Development DisabilitiesFolder 3366661Summer 197533Williams, Lawrence E. Springfield Dept. of Public Health: A Report on the Programs of the Division of Environmental HealthFolder 346666234Williams, Lawrence E. The U.S. Health Services Systems: What's Right and What's WrongFolder 356666335

