<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.50.Cornog, G.Archon Finding Aid Title J.50.Cornog, G.UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:07:04 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J50/Cornog, G. Faculty Projects, "Illinois Dept of Personnel" Videotapes, 1973
    
      Cornog, Geoffrey Y.
    
    J.50.Cornog, G.
    617
    
      2.00 Cubic Feet
    
    Date acquired: 02/19/1975
    1&amp;2
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Videotapes of the "Development of Classifiers Training Project"  developed by Geoffrey Y. Cornog for the Illinois Department of Personnel under a contract between Sangamon State University and the Department.  Sessions covered organization planning and design, task  and job analysis,  position management,  manpower planning,  work simplification,  work measurement,  systems analysis, and program evaluation.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Geoffrey Cornog, Media  
  
    Videotapes
  
  Box 1Box 163265Cornog, Geoffrey Y. Evaluation of the Development of Classifier Training Project:Folder 163267October 15, 19731Scope and ContentsThe Classifier Organizations Analysis and Review Training Program. Sangamon State University, Springfield, Illinois:Overall Process and Organization Analysis, 2 tapes, 60 min. eachVideotape 163268February 26, 1973Organizations Planning, 2 tapes, 60 min. eachVideotape 263269March 6, 1973Task Analysis, 2 tapes, 60 min. eachVideotape 363270March 13, 1973Position Management, 2 tapes, tape 1 is 60 min. and tape 2 is 15 min.Videotape 463271March 20, 1973Manpower Forecast and Planning, 3 tapes, 60 min. eachVideotape 563272March 27, 1973Work Simplification, 3 tapes, tape 1 is 60 min. and tapes 2 and 3 are 15 min.Videotape 663273April 17, 1973Systems Analysis with Jack Stanley, 2 tapes, tape 1 is 60 min. and tape 2 is 15 min.Videotape 763274April 24, 1973Box 2Box 263266Management Information Systems (MIS), 3 tapes, tapes 1 and 3 are 60 min. and tape 2 is 15 min.Videotape 163275May 1, 1973Program Evaluation, 2 tapes, tape 1 is 60 min. and tape 2 is 15 min.Videotape 263276May 8, 1973Changes, 5 tapes, 15 min. eachVideotape 363277May 15, 1973Work Management, 3 tapes, tape 1 is 60 min. and tapes 2 and 3 are 15 min.Videotape 463278n.d.

