<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.09.05/08Archon Finding Aid Title J.09.05/08UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:02:27 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J9/5/8. History Program, "Contemporary Perspectives on Abraham Lincoln" Intersession, 1976
    J.09.05/08
    454
    
      1.80 Cubic Feet
    
    Date acquired: 02/00/1997
  
  
    Scope and Contents
"Contemporary Perspectives on Abraham Lincoln"  was originally presented as the 1976 Lincoln Intersession at Sangamon State University.  Fourteen scholars discussed themes in American History addressed by Lincoln and his contemporaries.  The Intersession served as the basis for the 1978 course, "Contemporary Perspectives on Abraham Lincoln."  Used re-edited audio cassette tapes have frequently been used as the basis for a media or self-study course.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Audio Tapes
    Lincoln, Abraham
  
  Box 1Box 142801Syllabus and tape scriptsFolder 1428051Early manuscripts (1 of 2)Folder 2428062Early manuscripts (2 of 2)Folder 3428073Box 2Box 242802Tape 1: Charles B. Strozier, The Search for Love and Identity in the Young LincolnItem 1428081Tape 2: Roy P. Basler, Lincoln, Blacks and WomenItem 2428092Tape 3: Katharine Kish Sklar, Female Strategies in Victorian AmericaItem 3428103Tape 4: Roundtable DiscussionItem 4428114Tape 5: Arthur Margon, Does the Self-Made Image Have Any Relevance Today?Item 5428125Tape 6: George Fredrickson, Lincoln and the Search for Order and Community in 19th Century AmericaItem 6428136Tape 7: Norman Graeber, Lincoln and the Idea of ProgressItem 7428147Tape 8: Gabor Boritt, Lincoln and the Right to RiseItem 8428158Scope and ContentsRead by Michael Graver of SSUTape 9: John Keiser, Lincoln and Politics: Vandalia to ChicagoItem 9428169Tape 10: Douglas Morgan, [A New Pillar to the Old Temple of Liberty]Item 104281710Scope and ContentsRead by Dale Coleman of SSUTape 11: Robert Johannsen, The Lincoln-Douglas Debates in National PerspectiveItem 114281811Tape 12: Christopher Breiseth, Lincoln and Douglas in SpringfieldItem 124281912Tape 13: Discussion Session.Item 134282013Tape 14: Roger Bridges, Lincoln Reacts to the Civil WarItem 144282114Tape 15: Don Fehrenbacher, Lincoln and the ConstitutionItem 154282215Tape 16: Richard Current, Lincoln and America's MissionItem 164282316Box 3Box 342803Scope and ContentsContains original raw footage 10 in. reel-to-reel audio tapes with large hubs from the 1976 Lincoln IntersessionTapes 1-16Item 1428241Box 4Box 442804Scope and ContentsContains original raw footage 10 in. reel-to-reel audio tapes with large hubs from the 1976 Lincoln IntersessionTapes 17-20Item 1428251

