<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.09.05/30Archon Finding Aid Title J.09.05/30UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:08:38 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J9/5/30. History Program, Psychohistory Review Articles (Unpublished), 1972-1982
    J.09.05/30
    463
    
      1.66 Cubic Feet
    
    1972-1982
    Date acquired: 12/00/1988
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This series contains articles submitted to Psychohistory Review and not accepted for publication.  Chronological/Alphabetical order is artificial.  Topics include the history of Psychohistory, womens'  histories, and psychobiographies of Marx and Hitler.  Correspondence relating to the rejection of each paper is included.  There are brief biographies of most of the authors.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological/Alphabetical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  Box 1Box 143227Contributions of PsychobiographyFolder 14323019721Lloyd de Mause, Ed., The New PsychohistoryFolder 2432312John J. Fitzpatrick, Psychoanalysis and HistoryFolder 3432323William J. Gilmore, Critical BibliographyFolder 4432334William J. Gilmore, The Development of John Brown's Personality SystemFolder 5432345William J. Gilmore, The Methodology of Psychohistory: An Annotated BibliographyFolder 6432356Raimund E. Goerler, Family, Psychology, and HistoryFolder 7432367Barbara Kellerman, On Methodological Strategies of Political Biography: A PrecisFolder 8432378George Kren, The Psychodynamics of NazismFolder 9432381919-19339Jacqueline S. Reinier, Attitudes Toward and Practices of Child RearingFolder 104323910Robert Robins, HypersuspiciounessFolder 114324011Carroll Smith Rosenberg, The New Woman and the Psychohistorian: A Modest ProposalFolder 124324112Rough DraftsFolder 134324213J. Lee Schneidman and Conalee Levine-SchneidmanFolder 144324314The Story of Adam and EveFolder 154324415Rough DraftsFolder 16432451973-7616D. Luck, Biography on Applied PsychologyFolder 1743246197417Box 2Box 243228Congratulatory RemarksFolder 1432471974-791William J. Gilmore, Toward Multidisciplinary History: The Myth of Interdisciplinary HistoryFolder 24324819752Council for the Advancement of Psychoanalytic EducationFolder 34324919753The Psycho PathFolder 44325019754Judith Wellman, Culture and Character: Some Perspectives from Psychological Anthropology for PsychohistoriansFolder 54325119755ArticlesFolder 6432521975-766Hugh Lloyd-Jones, Females of the Species: Semonides on WomenFolder 7432531975-767CorrespondenceFolder 8432541975-778BiographyFolder 94325519769Draft of Volume 5 #3Folder 1043256197610William J. Gilmore, Psychohistory ConferenceFolder 1143257197611Mark J. Heuman, GravidaFolder 1243258197612Journal of PsychohistoryFolder 1343259197613R. Gerald McMurtry, Lincoln HeraldFolder 1443260197614Minutes of the Vienna Psychohistory SocietyFolder 1543261197615Summer Institute on the New HistoryFolder 1643262197616CorrespondenceFolder 17432631976-8117American Historical AssociationFolder 1843264197718Dona Artz, The Self-Made Character of Charlotte Perkins GilmanFolder 1943265197719Phyllis Palmer, From Service to Submission: Women's Dilemma in the Nineteenth CenturyFolder 204326620Louis W. Potts, Toward a Denatured American RevolutionFolder 2143267197721Psychoanalytic PsychologyFolder 2243268197722Special Issue on Family History, vol. 6 #2Folder 2343269197723Paul Monaco and Harvey J. Graff, Toward a RestatementFolder 24432701977-7924Box 3Box 343229Ralph Colp, Jr., A Force Like a Hundred Thousand WedgesFolder 1432711977-781James William AndersonFolder 24327219782Scope and ContentsDifficulties in the Writing of Psychobiography and Psychobiographical Treatments of Woodrow WilsonDonald Buzinkai, Sasha's BrotherFolder 34327319783Patrick ChaseFolder 44327419784Scope and ContentsPolitical Science and the Psychohistorical Approach: A Methodological AppraisalLloyd EtheredgeFolder 54327519785Scope and ContentsMetaphysics and Power: An MRW Model for Understanding Social and Political AttitudesJames P. Johnson, Nixon's Use of MetaphorFolder 64327619786Quin McLoughlin, History, Science, and PsychohistoryFolder 74327719787Michael Selzer, The Journey to Pretoria: Psychological Roots of Gandhi's Political CareerFolder 84327819788Sue Zschoche, The Use and Abuse of WomenFolder 94327919789Lawrence H. ClimoFolder 10432801978-7910Scope and ContentsIdentity Crisis: Window on a Family's Past and a Generation's CharacterGeoffrey Cocks, Hitler and Death: A Rankian ViewFolder 11432811978-7911D. Wilfred Abse and Richard Ulman, Charisma and RegressionFolder 1243282197912Edmund H. Dickerman, Chicot and Henry III: The Jester Was No HeroFolder 1343283197913Edmund H. Dickerman, Chicot and Henry III, and the Psychodynamics of a JestFolder 1443284197914Martha G. Duncan, Radical Activism and the Defense Against DespairFolder 1543285197915Hattenhauer, The Early Works of PsychohistoryFolder 1643286197916Joseph E. Illich, John Adams: The Early YearsFolder 1743287197917Institute for Research in HistoryFolder 1843288197918Thomas T. LewisFolder 1943289197919Scope and ContentsThe Rational-Humanistic Perspective of Psychological History: An Alternative ParadigmJoel Markowitz, The Group-Mind Influence in History: A Psychohistorical HypothesisFolder 2043290197920Dan McAdams, Fantasy and Reality in the Death of Yukio Mishima: Perspectives From Freud, Fairbairn, Sullivan, and BakanFolder 2143291197921Char Miller, Dreamy Madness: The Abolitionist Cancer of Elizur Wright, Jr.Folder 2243292197922Salvatore Prisco, Richard Nixon's Other CrisesFolder 2343293197923Molly TownsendFolder 2443294197924Scope and ContentsMy Dear Kind Good Child: Cobbet The Champion of Family LifeKenneth F. woods, Psychomarxism: The Ideology of PracticeFolder 25432951979-8025John Marshall CarterFolder 2643296198026Scope and ContentsGuibert of Nogent and Psychohistory: An Evaluation of the Validity of Psychoanalytical StudyEdmund Dickerman, Henry IV, Jeanne D'Albert and the Making of a HeroFolder 2743297198027Donald Dietrich, The Psychodynamics of Nazism, 1919-1933Folder 2843298198028David Felix, The Revolutionary Personality MarxFolder 2943299198029Marvin GoldwertFolder 3043300198030Scope and ContentsHuitzilopochtil and Freud's Primal Crime: An Essay in Speculative HistoryH.C. Greisman, Social Structure, Psychoanalysis, and Collective AggressionFolder 3143301198031Natalie Isser, Minority Self-Hatred: A Psychohistorical Case StudyFolder 3243302198032Jerrold M. Post, M.D., The Seasons of a Leader's LifeFolder 3343303198033Leo Sveikauskas, The Psychological Appeal of MarxismFolder 3443304198034Don R. SwansonFolder 3543305198035Marleen Barr, Tudor Women Martyrs: Sexual Roles and Aggressive BehaviorFolder 36433061980-8136Harvey Asher, Hitler's Decision to Declare War on the U.S.Folder 3743307198137Joseph A. Bongiorno, Woodrow Wilson Revisited: The Pre-Political YearsFolder 3843308198038Abraham Gilam, The Idea of Loving in the Romanticist TraditionFolder 3943309198139Marvin Goldwert, The Conquest of Mexico as Kairos: A Fruedian ViewFolder 4043310198140Haim Gordon, The Child Among the BooksFolder 4143311198141Peter Hoffer, The Demon at the Door: Sectional Strife in American HistoryFolder 4243312198142Alexander Lipskiki, A.J. Toynbee's Frantic Quest for SurvivalFolder 4343313198143Graham Little, The Liminal CharacterFolder 4443314198144Richard D. LoganFolder 4543315198145Scope and ContentsFrom Subject to Object: A Proposed Eriksonian Model for the Historical Development of the SelfJesus MendezFolder 4643316198146Scope and ContentsThe Personality of Hipolito Yrigoyen and It's Import on the Intransigence of the Radical Party and Argentinian Foreign Policy, 1880-1930Leon Rappaport, Marx's Fate: The Shape of a LifeFolder 4743317198147William McKinley Runyen, Why Did Van Gogh Cut Off His Ear?Folder 4843318198148R. L. SchnellFolder 4943319198149Scope and ContentsIn Service of the Betters: Custody and Control of Dependent Child Life in British North America/Canada, 1800-1950Thomas Thale, Career, Character, and DiseaseFolder 5043320198250Philip Utley, Multicausal Explanation in PsychohistoryFolder 5143321198151Lee Wilkins, Wayne Morse: An American AdamFolder 5243322198152Anton F. de Man, Autonomy-Control Variation in Child Rearing: Past and PresentFolder 5343323198253Maureen Slatter, A Socio-Psychoanalytic AnalysisFolder 5443324198254Neil Wallman, Freud vs. Jung: Influences of Their Lives Upon Their TheoriesFolder 5543325198255

