<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.09.05/35Archon Finding Aid Title J.09.05/35UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:08:48 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J9/5/35. History Program, Oral History "Illinois General Assembly" Research Project, 1935-1981
    
      Camp, Dennis
    
    
      Waggoner, Horace Q.
    
    J.09.05/35
    465
    
      1.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1935-1981
    Date acquired: 11/00/1989
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Oral History Illinois General Assembly Research Project consisting of alphabetical index of legislative deliberations, 1935-81, bibliographies, legislative rosters, research notes, and state publications regarding the history, membership and procedures of the Illinois General Assembly.  
The file was assembled by Horace Q. Waggoner as background material for the Oral History office's project to interview current and former members of the General Assembly.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Linda Jett  
  
    General Assembly
  
  Box 1Box 143749IGAOHP Indexing Guidelines: Index through ConstitutionFolder 1437501Index continued: Consumer Rights through EducationFolder 2437512Index continued: Elections and ReapportionmentFolder 3437523Index continued: Ethics &amp; Conflict of InterestFolder 4437534Index continued: Gambling through Judicial ReformFolder 5437545Index continued: Legislative ReformFolder 6437556Index continued: Licensing &amp; Regulations through Public Aid, Health, Welfare &amp; SafetyFolder 7437567Index continued: Public Employees through TransportationFolder 8437578Chronology of State GovernmentFolder 9437581966-19779Manual of the Procedures of the House of Representatives of the State of IllinoisFolder 1043759December 198010General Assembly History Legislative SummaryFolder 11437601961-196911Illinois Council Research Memorandum FilesFolder 12437611934-1964 &amp; 1957-197912State &amp; Local Government in Illinois, A BibliographyFolder 134376213Legislative RosterFolder 14437631818-1978141970 Illinois Constitution AnnotatedFolder 154376415Birdwhistell, Terry L.Folder 164376516Scope and ContentsThe Elite Speak: Political Oral History at the University of Kentucky LibraryCampbell, Ballard: The State Legislature in American History: A Review EssayFolder 174376617Davis, Cullom: The General Assembly: Tradition &amp; Change in Illinois PoliticsFolder 184376718Davis, Cullom: Voices from the StatehouseFolder 194376819Davis, Cullom: Voices of the General AssemblyFolder 2043769198220Scope and Contentswith comments by Howard W. Allen - Crossroads ConferenceDavis, Cullom: Word Processors &amp; Oral HistoryFolder 214377021Day, William L.: Prelude to Legislative ModernizationFolder 224377122Van Der Slik, Jack: Echoes from the Rotunda, plus Research MaterialFolder 234377223Waggoner, Horace Q.:Folder 244377324Scope and ContentsThe Illinois General Assembly Oral History Program, Some Oral History Program Essentials, &amp; Illinois Legislative Change, 1950-1970Annual Report of the Auditor GeneralFolder 2543774197825Scope and ContentsBound VolumeBill Drafting ManualFolder 2643775April 197226Scope and ContentsBound VolumeChicago's Politics &amp; SocietyFolder 274377627Scope and ContentsBound VolumeConference on the Research Use &amp; Disposition of Senators' PapersFolder 2843777September 197828Scope and ContentsBound VolumeCOOGA: 10 Years LaterFolder 2943778May 197729Scope and ContentsBound VolumeFinal Report of the Assembly on Legislative Oversight in IllinoisFolder 3043779August 198230Scope and ContentsBound VolumeGuide to Research Collections of Former United States SenatorsFolder 31437801789-198231Scope and ContentsBound VolumeIllinois Constitution Annotated for LegislatorsFolder 3243781197032Scope and ContentsBound VolumeIllinois Legislative District Data BookFolder 334378233Scope and ContentsBound VolumeIllinois RosterFolder 3443783198134Scope and ContentsBound VolumeIllinois RosterFolder 3543784198335Scope and ContentsBound VolumeMr. Speaker: Presiding Officers of the Illinois House of RepresentativesFolder 36437851818-198036Scope and ContentsBound VolumeState &amp; Local Government in IllinoisFolder 37437861954-196437Scope and ContentsBound VolumeState of Illinois Report &amp; Recommendations to Illinois Budgetary CommissionFolder 3843787December 195638Scope and ContentsBound VolumeIllinois General Assembly, Oral History Program Master IndexItem 39786841980-198539

