<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.09.05/50Archon Finding Aid Title J.09.05/50UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:08:52 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J9/5/50. History Program, Oral History, Tapes &amp; Memoirs, 1972-
    
      Oral History Office
    
    J.09.05/50
    466
    
      37.60 Cubic Feet
    
    Date acquired: 10/00/1989
    1
    Memoir Files/Tapes
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Oral History Tapes &amp; Memoirs, consisting of oral history interviews recorded on cassette tapes and conducted by the the Oral History staff and others since 1972.  The memoirs are edited typed transcripts of the taped interviews.  
The master copies of the tapes and memoirs are stored in the Oral History Master Manuscript and Collateral file (file cabinets).  
Most typed memoirs are open for research, but some are closed and a few others may not be copied.
The collateral files contain memorabilia in relation to the individuals and may contain photographs, certificates, newspaper articles, etc.

Interviews and memoirs are available online in the Illinois Digital Archives.  
Browse O - Oral History Collection in Archon to see a full list of all items available in the collection.  Click on Show Administrative Information to display the link to the memoir/transcript in the Illinois Digital Archives (www.idaillinois.org).  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
Various  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Oral History Office  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Additional memoirs and more copies located on shelving.

Legal Releases and Data Sheets stored in separate Box on shelves.  
  
    Audio Tapes
    Audio CDs
    Memorabilia
    Newspaper Clippings
    Letters
    Photographs
    Photocopies
  
  Box 1Box 173994A - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 1739951B - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 2739962C - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 3739973D - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 4739984E - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 5739995F - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 6740006G - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 7740017H - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 8740028I - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 9740039J - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 107400410K - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 117400511L - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 127400612M - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 137400713N - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 147400814O - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 157400915P - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 167401016R - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 177401117S - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 187401218T - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 197401319U - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 207401420V - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 217401521W - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 227401622Y - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 237401723Z - Oral History Data Sheets - Completed MemoirsFolder 247401824A,B,C - Oral History Memoirs in ProgressFolder 257401925D,E - Oral History Memoirs in ProgressFolder 267402026F,G,H - Oral History Memoirs in ProgressFolder 277402127I,J,K - Oral History Memoirs in ProgressFolder 287402228L,M,N,O - Oral History Memoirs in ProgressFolder 297402329P,R,S,T - Oral History Memoirs in ProgressFolder 307402430U-Z - Oral History Memoirs in ProgressFolder 317402531Oral History Class PermissionsFolder 3274026200732Scope and ContentsCharles &amp; Benjamin Harmony, Henry Horner, J. Michael Houston, George Kitterman, Warren Musch, Bill Schimm, Gustav Speder, Bond Tarr, James Marc WadeA - Oral History ReleasesFolder 337402733B - Oral History ReleasesFolder 347402834C - Oral History ReleasesFolder 357402935D - Oral History ReleasesFolder 367403036E - Oral History ReleasesFolder 377403137F - Oral History ReleasesFolder 387403238G - Oral History ReleasesFolder 397403339H - Oral History ReleasesFolder 407403440I - Oral History ReleasesFolder 417403541J - Oral History ReleasesFolder 427403642K - Oral History ReleasesFolder 437403743L - Oral History ReleasesFolder 447403844M - Oral History ReleasesFolder 457403945N - Oral History ReleasesFolder 467404046O - Oral History ReleasesFolder 477404147P - Oral History ReleasesFolder 487404248R - Oral History ReleasesFolder 497404349Sm - Oral History ReleasesFolder 507404450S-Si - Oral History ReleasesFolder 517404551T - Oral History ReleasesFolder 527404652U - Oral History ReleasesFolder 537404753V - Oral History ReleasesFolder 547404854W - Oral History ReleasesFolder 557404955X,Y,Z - Oral History ReleasesFolder 567405056

