<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.09.05/200Archon Finding Aid Title J.09.05/200UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:09:06 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J9/5/200. History Program, Student Papers, 1972-1984
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    J.09.05/200
    468
    
      0.66 Cubic Feet
    
    1972-1984
    Date acquired: 00/00/1989
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This series includes papers by undergraduate and graduate students.  Some are similar to or identical with master's theses (record series J54)  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
History Department  
  Box 1Box 143899Bean, Stephen M.Folder 1439001Scope and ContentsThe First Presidential Campaign of Adlai E. Stevenson II:  The Springfield Connection (nd)Boyer, PeggyFolder 2439012Scope and ContentsToward an Oral History of the Illinois Coal Miner (nd)Boyer, PeggyFolder 34390219843Scope and ContentsOral History Report, Illinois House of Representatives 1935-1956Carroll, TimothyFolder 4439034Scope and ContentsGovernment and Human Nature: The Philosophy of the Founding Fathers (nd)Caughlin, CathyFolder 543904April 19825Scope and ContentsWomen's Changing Role in United States and Great BritainCorley, KevinFolder 6439056Scope and ContentsAn Interpretation of Ethnicity by Central Illinois Mining Communities (nd)Creed, Roland P.Folder 743906Summer 19817Scope and ContentsComparing the Modernization of China, 1949-Present, to the Modernization of the United States, 1850-1890Creed, Roland P.Folder 843907August 19778Scope and ContentsBook Review Essay [Copperheads]Creed, Roland P.Folder 943908August 19789Scope and ContentsThe Chautauqua MovementCreed, Roland P.Folder 1043909July 198010Scope and ContentsUlysses S. Grant: The Presidential Years, ReconsideredGardiner, Gerald C.Folder 1143910Summer 197711Scope and Contents1968 and the Emergence of Richard NixonHarner, Jo Anna LynnFolder 1243911198512Scope and ContentsIndustrial Wage Earning Women in America: 1890-1927Hatton, David H.Folder 13439121973-11-1813Scope and ContentsBoliviaHatton, David H.Folder 14439131973-11-2914Scope and ContentsKarl Marx -- The Discovery of Social TheoristsHatton, David H.Folder 15439141973-12-1015Scope and ContentsThe Antifederalists and John C. CalhounHatton, David H.Folder 16439151973-10-2716Scope and ContentsThe Federalist PapersHatton, David H.Folder 17439161971-12-0217Scope and ContentsMoot Court Opinion -- Lemmon vs. the U. S., 5 Wal. 57 (1867)Haynes, Judith A.Folder 18439171980-05-0618Scope and ContentsThe Condition of Rural Women in the 19th-Century MidwestHaynes, Judith A.Folder 194391819Scope and ContentsA Comparison of the Woman's Suffrage Movements in the United States and England (nd)Haynes, Judith A.Folder 2043919May 198020Scope and ContentsIs a Fourth Agricultural Revolution Imminent?Haynes, Judith A.Folder 2143920198421Scope and ContentsPortrait of a Woman Legislator:  Bernice T. van der Vries, Illinois House of Representatives 1935-1956Hegg, Pauline F.Folder 2243921Summer 197622Scope and ContentsThe Status of Women in the Swedish SocietyHerndon, Calista T.Folder 234392223Scope and ContentsThe Brown Family (nd)Herndon, Calista T.Folder 244392324Scope and ContentsThe Bunn Family (nd)Herndon, Calista T.Folder 254392425Scope and ContentsElijah Iles (nd)Herndon, Calista T.Folder 264392526Scope and ContentsThe Pasfield Family (nd)Hicks, Leo B. Jr., (A.S.T.)Folder 274392627Hicks, Leo B. Jr.Folder 28439271977-12-1628Scope and ContentsStuds Terkel: WorkingHicks, Leo B. Jr.Folder 294392829Scope and ContentsWhat Price Individuality? (nd)Hicks, Leo B. Jr.Folder 30439291977-12-1630Scope and ContentsA System in TroubleHinrichs, PennyFolder 314393031Scope and ContentsThe Aztec Warrior of the 16th Century and the Sioux Warrior of the 18th Century (nd)Hinrichs, PennyFolder 324393132Scope and ContentsThe Indians Discovered America:  Government Policies, Past and Present (nd)Hinrichs, PennyFolder 3343932Summer 197733Scope and ContentsAmerindians of the U.S.Hinrichs, PennyFolder 344393334Scope and ContentsThe 16th-Century Aztec Culture (nd)Box 2Box 243934Hopkins, DottieFolder 1439351980-05-051Scope and ContentsFamily Life: A Comparison -- 19th-Century Sioux to 20th-Century WhitesJohnston, WesleyFolder 2439371978-12-082Scope and ContentsThe Flavor of Family Life: The Koutecky, Subert and Johnston Families --1878-1978Johnston, WesleyFolder 3439381980-06-233Scope and ContentsMexican Life in Chicago: Two FamiliesKoos, Greg (principal author)Folder 443939December 19854Scope and ContentsEast Grove Street Architectural/Historical SurveyKurrasch, Evan L.Folder 5439401983-10-145Scope and ContentsThe DeCrastos Cottage, Historic PreservationMarkwell, Merle K.Folder 643941May 19836Scope and ContentsFamily Size and Structure in Central Illinois 1850 1880:  A Census StudyMichael, Patrick J.Folder 7439421977-05-097Scope and ContentsNorthern IrelandPearson, JacquiFolder 8439431980-05-068Scope and ContentsThe Production Role of Middle Class Women:  Unchanged in a Changing Society 1880 1920Penn, Wallace A.Folder 9439441977-04-219Scope and ContentsIllinois: A History of the Prairie State:  A Book ReviewPenn, Wallace A.Folder 10439451977-04-2810Scope and ContentsA Short History of Labor Unions in IllinoisPenn, Wallace A.Folder 114394611Scope and ContentsA Walk with Melancholia: Self Understanding Through Soren Kierkegaard (nd)Penn, Wallace A.Folder 124394712Scope and ContentsIntroduction &amp; Appendixes to the Assessment of Understanding Self (The Historical Personage of Soren Kierkegaard) As A Means of Understanding Others (nd)Penn, Wallace A.Folder 134394813Scope and ContentsUnderstanding the Contemporary World in Historical Perspective:  The Role of Ideology in the Modernization of the United States and the Soviet Union (nd)Ransom, Carter, The Individual and SocietyFolder 1443949198414Reynolds, David, Sports, America, and the American Character (nd)Folder 154395015Saner, Marca Polo, Will The Real China Please Stand Up (nd)Folder 164395116Sarff, MegFolder 17439521972-12-0517Scope and ContentsExecutive Control of Foreign Policy:  The Gulf of Tonkin Resolution in Historical PerspectiveSarff, MegFolder 18439531972-11-0218Scope and ContentsSuppression and Censorship:  The Velikovsky Controversy in the McCarthy EraSchnirring, CherylFolder 194395419Scope and ContentsA True Picture of Emigration by Rebecca Burlend (nd)Schnirring, CherylFolder 20439551977-08-1120Scope and ContentsTextbooks and Auxiliary Services in Nonpublic SchoolsSchnirring, CherylFolder 214395621Scope and ContentsBibliography of Midwestern Experimental Communities: Illinois (nd)Sherbenou, BrendaFolder 22439571976-05-0622Scope and ContentsSexism in the Language: Application of Whorfian HypothesisStrell, PennyFolder 23439581980-04-3023Scope and ContentsA Comparison of the Economic Forces and Sexual Mores Affecting the Formation of American Slave Families with English and French Families, 1760-1860Talbott, TimFolder 24439591984-04-3024Scope and ContentsRobert Owen: His Socialism and CommunitarianismTalmant, RonFolder 25439601982-05-0125Scope and ContentsEducation in Japan Vs United StatesTippit, JeanFolder 264396126Scope and ContentsHow Dress Reflects Class Differences in Jacksonian America (nd)Towery, MargieFolder 2743962198627Scope and ContentsFrontier Women: Images of ThemselvesTripp, Charles T.Folder 28439631977-07-3128Scope and ContentsThe Madonna and Child: A Transitional Model of Child-Mother RelationsWilliams, PeggyFolder 2943964May 198329Scope and ContentsDomestic Service in Springfield, 1840 1860Wilson, Clifford KeithFolder 304396530Scope and ContentsIran and Ante-Bellum America: Modernization, Identity and RevolutionWright, KarenFolder 31439661981-05-2931Scope and ContentsThe Development of Elementary Education for the Public:  A Look at England and the United StatesStudents' Education PlansFolder 32439671984-8832Problem Solving Projects (M. A. Students)Folder 33439681982 &amp; 198833Student Research ProposalsFolder 34439691977 8734

