<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.05.05/10Archon Finding Aid Title J.05.05/10UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:09:58 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J5/5/10. "The Lincolns of Springfield, IL," Documentary Production Videotapes, 1986-1992
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    
      Lennon, Mike
    
    
      Television Office
    
    J.05.05/10
    474
    
      1.16 Cubic Feet
    
    1986-1992
    Date acquired: 02/00/2006
  
  
    Scope and Contents
"The Lincolns of Springfield, Illinois" Television Documentary was a project initiated by J. Michael Lennon, director of the Office of Public Affairs Communication (OPAC) in 1987 to record the restoration of the Lincoln Home.  "The Lincolns of Springfield" documented the restoration work and featured interviews with experts.  The goal of the hour-long documentary was to present for a general audience the details of the home's restoration and give insight to the homelife of the Lincolns.
"The Lincolns of Springfield, Illinois" collection contains over 25 interviews conducted by Mike Lennon, rough drafts/scripts for the documentary, manuals of other historic homes and catalogs containing hardware from the 1860s, papers from the Annual Lincoln Colloquium (1986-88, 1990), and newsletters from Lincoln organizations.  Also included are programs for the reopening of the Lincoln home, articles on the Lincoln family and their home, photographs and postcards from the Todd home in Lexington, Kentucky, and six audiocassettes of interviews.  Of special interest are copies of blueprints of the Lincoln home from the late 19th century, copies of the letters found in the wall of the Lincoln home during restoration, and a copy of "Mr. Lincoln's Neighborhood:  A Self-Guiding Experience" by George L. Painter. 
The documentary was aired on PBS can be found in the Archives Audio and Video Collection - Call Number T-2911 and T-2603.  
  
    Accruals and Additions
Lincoln Home drawings (Item 3) added by Dave Antoine, March 18, 2009. Chris Schnell (Sept. 13, 2017)  
  Box 1Box 136954List of Participants in Lincoln Home RestorationFolder 1369551Grant Application for Lincoln DocumentaryFolder 2369562Tape Logs for Lincoln DocumentaryFolder 3369573Interview with James HickeyFolder 4369584Interview with Ed HawesFolder 5369595Interview with Emilie TariFolder 6369606Interview with Sue MonroeFolder 7369617Interview with Ed Hawes and Emilie TariFolder 8369628Interview with Chuck StrozierFolder 9369639Interview with Jim O'TooleFolder 103696410Interview with Jean BakerFolder 113696511Interview with Virgil NobleFolder 123696612Interview with Jean Baker and Chuck StrozierFolder 133696713Interview with Lou HoldenFolder 143696814Interview at Harper's Ferry CenterFolder 153696915Interview with Vance KaminskiFolder 163697016Interview with Gentry DavisFolder 173697117Interview with John SimonFolder 183697218Interview with Scott MayerFolder 193697319Interview with Jeff, Project Supervisor for Contractor, River City RestorationFolder 203697420Interview with George PainterFolder 213697521Interview with Francis KrupkaFolder 223697622Interview with Dick TaylorFolder 233697723Interview with Tom SchwartzFolder 243697824Interviews with Unknown SourcesFolder 253697925Rough Drafts of Script/Outline for DocumentaryFolder 263698026Notes for Lincoln DocumentaryFolder 273698127The David Davis Mansion Volunteer ManualFolder 283698228Illustrated Catalogue of American Hardware of the Russell &amp; Erwin Manufacturing CompanyFolder 2936983186529Furnishings Plan Section A through E:  The Lincoln Home National Historic SiteFolder 303698430Scope and ContentsSpringfield, IllinoisHistoric Structure Report of the Lincoln HomeFolder 313698531Programs and Papers for the Annual Lincoln ColloquiumFolder 32369861986-1988, 199032Scope and ContentsPapers include the following items:"Temples of Justice: County Courthouses in Mid-Nineteenth Century Illinois" by Albert J. LarsonItem 136987321"Lincoln and the Eighth Circuit" by Richard N. CurrentItem 236988322"Creating a Video Documentary on the Lincoln Home Preservation Project" by Marilyn A. HuffItem 336989323"Lincoln's Political Principles" by Thomas F. SchwartzItem 436990324"Lincoln's Early Experience with the Constitution" by Harlington Wood, Jr.Item 536991325"Lincoln and the U.S. Constitution" by George L. PainterItem 636992326"Lincoln on Democracy:  The Privilege and Peril of Translating Lincoln for Poland" by Harold HolzerItem 736993327"Abraham Lincoln and the Universal Yankee Nation" by Robert W. JohannsenItem 836994328"The Lincoln Family Album" by Mark E. Neely, Jr. and Harold HolzerItem 936995329"Abraham Lincoln and American Political Culture" by William E. GienappItem 10369963210"Abraham Lincoln and Jefferson Davis:  Drifting Responses to Similar Environments" by Edwin C. BearssItem 11369983211"I have labored hard to find the law:  Abraham Lincoln for the Alton and Sangamon Railroad" by William D. BeardItem 12369973212"Marriage and Divorce in Menard County:  A Preliminary Report from Lincoln's Law Practice" by James R.  WalrothItem 13369993213The Lincoln Legacy – A Quarterly Publication of the Lincoln Group of IllinoisFolder 33370001987-9133Scope and ContentsIncluded are:Vol. 1, No. 1Item 137001331Vol. 2, No. 1, 2, 4Item 237002332Vol. 3, No. 1, 3Item 337003333Vol. 4, No. 3, 4Item 437004334Vol. 5, No. 1Item 537005335The Lincoln ChronicleFolder 34370061987-9134Scope and ContentsIncluded are:Vol. VII, No. 1, 3, 4Item 137007341Vol. VIII, No. 1, 2, 3Item 237008342Vol. IX, No. 2, 3Item 337009343The Lincoln Group of IllinoisFolder 353701035Lincoln Legal Papers – Newsletters and Annual ReportFolder 36370111989-9136Lincoln Newsletter – Vol. VII, No. 7Folder 3737012Spring 198837"Dispatch" from the Illinois State Historical SocietyFolder 38370131987-9238Scope and ContentsIncluded are:Series 9, Vol. 3Item 137014381Series 10, Vol. 2, 4, 5Item 237015382Series 11, Vol. 2, 5-6Item 337016383Series 12, Vol. 2, 3Item 437017384Series 13, Vol. 1, 2, 3, 6Item 537018385Series 14, Vol. 2Item 637019386Articles/Reviews on Charles Strozier and his book Lincoln's Quest for Union: Public and Private MeetingsFolder 393702039Abraham Lincoln and Others at the St. Nicholas by Wayne C. TempleFolder 403702140The Lincoln Home Reopening and Activities ProgramsFolder 4137022June 15 &amp; 16, 198841Articles on Mary Todd LincolnFolder 423702442Scope and ContentsIncluded are:"Trials of Mrs. Lincoln is a Trial in itself" by Tamara Browning (Book Review)Item 1370251987-06-28421Scope and ContentsThe State-Journal Register"The Liberation of Mary Lincoln" by James Krohe Jr.Item 23702610/1-7/1987422Scope and ContentsIllinois Times"Victorian Women and Domestic Life:  Mary Todd Lincoln, Elizabeth Cady Stanton, and Harriet Beecher Stowe" by Kathryn Kish SklarItem 337027423"Meet Mary Todd Lincoln" portrayed by Karen Lee LynnItem 437028424"Mary Todd Lincoln:  Her Life and Letters" by Justin G. Turner and Linda Levitt TurnerItem 537029425Articles on Abraham LincolnFolder 433703043Scope and ContentsIncluded are:"Looking for Lincoln in the 1980's" by Gabor S. BorittItem 1370311987-02-08431Scope and ContentsThe New York Times Book Review"Follow Lincoln's Example, officials urge" by Anthony HebronItem 2370321989-02-13432Scope and ContentsThe State-Journal Register"Now he belongs to the historians" by James Krohe, Jr. (Book Review), Illinois TimesItem 3370332/16-22/1989433"What Jefferson and Lincoln Read" by Douglas L. Wilson, The Atlantic MonthlyItem 4370341-1991434"The Missing Lincoln:  The Lincoln Legal Papers is Looking for an Honest Lawyer" by Bill Furry, Illinois TimesItem 5370351991-03-21435Articles on Lincoln HomeFolder 443703644Scope and ContentsIncluded are:"Envelope, letters discovered inside Lincoln Home wall" by Doug Pokorski, The State Journal RegisterItem 1370371987-10-08441"Rebuilding History:  Lincoln Home restoration yields a lot of work – and a few surprises" by Doug PokorskiItem 2370381987-11-27442Scope and ContentsThe State-Journal Register Weekend Journal"Tippecanoe and Baseball, Too" by William Serrin New York TimesItem 3370391988-06-05443"Shades of Lexington in Springfield" The State-Journal RegisterItem 4370401989-01-13444Miscellaneous ArticlesFolder 453704145"Scott County home tour set for Sunday" The State-Journal RegisterItem 13704211987-10-15451"The House at Hyde Park" by Geoffrey C. WardItem 237043452"History of The House of Representatives" by George B. Galloway (excerpt, copy)Item 337044453"American Interior Design" by Meyric R. Rogers (excerpt, copy)Item 437045454Copies of Letters found at Lincoln HomeFolder 463704646Copies of 19th Century Newspaper articles about LincolnFolder 473704747"House Divided:  Lincoln and His Father" by John Y. SimonFolder 483704848Chapters 2 &amp; 5 for Unknown Source (about Mary Lincoln)Folder 493704949"Mary and Abraham Lincoln:  Portrait of a Marriage" by Charles B. StrozierFolder 503705050Scope and ContentsPresented at Symposium, "Understanding Mary:  Recent Scholarship on the Life of Mary Todd Lincoln"Announcements about Lincoln events sponsored by the Illinois State MuseumFolder 513705151"Thoughts on Mary and Abraham's Home:  One Morning in May" by Ed HawesFolder 523705252Specifications:  Phase II – Restore Lincoln HomeFolder 533705353Box 2Box 237054Illinois Historic Preservation Agency – Map of Historic Illinois Places and Announcements from the AgencyFolder 1370551News Releases from the U.S. Postal Service and the Governor of IllinoisFolder 2370562"Finding Mrs. Lincoln:  A Dramatized Interview with Mary Todd Lincoln's Older Sister, Mrs. Elizabeth Todd EdwardsFolder 3370573"Mr. Lincoln's Neighborhood:  A Self-Guiding Experience" by George L. PainterFolder 4370584Lincoln CatalogFolder 5370595Photographs/PostcardsFolder 6370606Scope and ContentsIncludes:3 Postcards of Mary Todd Lincoln House in Lexington, KentuckyItem 13706161Photograph of home in Lexington, KentuckyItem 23706262Charles Strozier talking with Lincoln impersonator (Mike Lennon in background)Item 33706363Copy of Lincoln's copy of the contract between Abraham Lincoln and Charles Dresser for purchase of the house at Eighth and JacksonItem 43706464Abstract of Social Status and Diet:  Archeological Excavations at the Lincoln Home National Historic Site (Springfield)Folder 7370657Scope and Contentsand the Galena State Historic Site (Galena) by 	Floyd Monsberger and Terrance MartinSpringfield Civil War Round Table – Vol. I, No. 3Folder 8370661988-11-108Project Schedule – Restore Lincoln Home for the weeks of 10/19 to 10/30/1987Folder 9370679A Collection of Documents Relating to the Ownership by Abraham LincolnFolder 103706810Scope and Contentsof the House Located on the Northeast Corner of Eighth and Jackson Streets, Springfield, IllinoisPage from "Philosophy in Stone: The Marker of Martin P. Jenners" by James C. JewellFolder 113706911Brochure for "Mr. Lincoln in Illinois" – A Video DocumentaryFolder 123707012Lincoln Home Chronology DrawingsFolder 13370711839-198613Lincoln Home Restoration Meeting with Jean BakerAudiotape 1370721987-06-29Lincoln Home Project LHR 8Audiotape 237073Lincoln Home Project LHR 14 &amp; 15AAudiotape 337074Lincoln Home Project LHR 15B &amp; 15CAudiotape 437075Lincoln Home Project LHR 49 &amp; 50Audiotape 537076Lincoln Home Project LHR 76 &amp; 77Audiotape 637077Drawings of Lincoln HomeItem 383511n.d.3

