<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.05.05/11Archon Finding Aid Title J.05.05/11UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:10:05 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J5/5/11. Abraham Lincoln Association (ALA), Publication Committee Records, 1984-1988
    
      Office of Public Affairs Communication
    
    
      Davis, G. Cullom
    
    
      Immel, Marilyn Huff
    
    J.05.05/11
    475
    
      0.50 Cubic Feet
    
    1986-1992
    Date acquired: 02/00/2006
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Cullom Davis, a history faculty member at SSU, and Marilyn Huff Immel, assistant to the director of the Office of Public Affairs Communication, were members of the publications committee of the Abraham Lincoln Association during the 1980s.  The publication committee provided general editorial advice and assistance in the preparation of volumes.  

The collection includes original and edited manuscripts that were published in the ALA journal and presented at the annual ALA Symposia from 1984-1988.  The authors include noted Lincoln historians Frank J. Williams, John Y. Simon, Charles B. Strozier, Joel H. Silbey, and Tom Schwartz. Also included are Symposium programs, manuscript evaluations, correspondence, lists of ALA members and donors from 1984-1986, printing information, copyright forms, and publication agreements. 

The Abraham Lincoln Association was organized in 1908 as the Lincoln Centennial Association. The Journal of the ALA  is the only journal devoted exclusively  to the legacy of Abraham Lincoln.  
  Box 1Box 139462ALA List of Members and DonorsFolder 1394641984-861ALA SymposiumFolder 23946519842Papers of the Abraham Lincoln Association, Volume VIItem 139466198421Lincolniana in 1984Item 23946722Scope and Contentsby Frank J. WilliamsThe Oregon Connection of Abraham LincolnItem 33946823Scope and Contentsby Mark O. Hatfield, U.S. Senator from OregonLincoln After 175 Years: The Myth of the Jealous SonItem 43946924Scope and Contentsby Richard N. CurrentCommentary at the 10th Annual Lincoln SymposiumItem 53947025Scope and Contentsby John Y. SimonAddress Before the Young Men's Lyceum of Springfield, IllinoisItem 6394711838-01-2726ALA Original ManuscriptsFolder 33947219853The Use and Misuse of the Lincoln LegacyItem 13947331Scope and Contentsby John Hope FranklinLincoln and America WritersItem 23947432Scope and Contentsby Roy D. Basler (2 copies)Presidential Use of Lincoln's Military ExampleItem 33947533Scope and Contentsby Herman Hattaway (2 copies)CommentsItem 43947634Scope and Contentsby Charles B. Strozier (2 copies)Lincolniana in 1985Item 53947735Scope and Contentsby Frank J. WilliamsPapers of the Abraham Lincoln Association, Volume VIIItem 639478198536ALA Printing InformationFolder 43947919854ALA Manuscript EvaluationsFolder 53948019855Publications Committee CorrespondenceFolder 63948119856Publication AgreementsFolder 73948219857Contributors to ALA SymposiumFolder 83948319868Manuscripts for the ALA SymposiumFolder 93948419869Always A Whig in Politics: The Partisan Life of Abraham LincolnItem 13948591Scope and Contentsby Joel H. SilbeyAbraham Lincoln Association PrayerItem 2394861986-02-1292An Egregious Political Blunder: Justin Butterfield, Lincoln, and Illinois WhiggeryItem 33948793Scope and Contentsby Tom SchwartzAbraham Lincoln and Our Unfinished WorkItem 43948894Scope and Contentsby Governor Mario M. Cuomo (2 copies)ALA Edited ManuscriptsFolder 1039489198610Always a Whig in Politics:" The Partisan Life of Abraham LincolnItem 139490101Scope and Contentsby Joel H. SilbeyAbraham Lincoln Association PrayerItem 2394911986-02-12102An Egregious Political Blunder: Justin Butterfield, Lincoln, and Illinois WhiggeryItem 339492103Scope and Contentsby Tom SchwartzAbraham Lincoln and Our Unfinished WorkItem 439493104Scope and Contentsby Governor Mario M. Cuomo (2 copies)ALA Printing InformationFolder 1139494198611ALA Manuscript EvaluationsFolder 1239495198612ALA CorrespondenceFolder 1339496198613Publication AgreementsFolder 1439497198614Manuscripts for the 1987 ALA SymposiumFolder 153949815Lincolniana in 1987Item 139499151Scope and Contentsby Frank J. WilliamsThe Case of the Missing DocumentsItem 239500152Scope and ContentsAddition to 1987 LincolnianaLincoln's Wartime Leadership:  The First Hundred DaysItem 339501153Scope and Contentsby Donald E. FrehrenbacherBox 2Box 239463Publication AgreementsFolder 13950219871ALA CorrespondenceFolder 23950319872ALA SymposiumFolder 33950419873ALA SymposiumFolder 43950519884Journal of the Abraham Lincoln Association Vol. 9Folder 53950619875Lincoln's Wartime Leadership:  The First Hundred DaysItem 13950751Scope and Contentsby Don E. FehrenbacherLincoln's Published Writings:  A History and SupplementItem 23950852Scope and Contentsby Thomas F. 	SchwartzLincolniana in 1987Item 33950953Scope and Contentsby Frank J. WilliamsMembers of the Abraham Lincoln AssociationItem 439510198754Papers of the Abraham Lincoln Association:  Plan for Direct Mail Promotion to LibrariesFolder 6395116ALA EnvelopesFolder 7395127Manuscript Evaluation FormsFolder 8395138Lincoln's Gettysburg AddressFolder 9395149Scope and ContentsAs Written by His Military Staff, Before Translation to Common-Sense EnglishAbraham Lincoln Association Copyright FormsFolder 103951510Mary Todd Lincoln:  A Final Judgment? (Reprint)Folder 113951611Scope and Contentsby Irving Stone's

