<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.05.05/22Archon Finding Aid Title J.05.05/22UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:10:24 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J5/5/22. Office of Electronic Media/TV Office SCAN 17/Access 4 Miscellaneous Tapes, 1985-2001
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    
      Electronic Media, Office of
    
    
      Institute for Public Affairs
    
    
      Television Office
    
    J.05.05/22
    478
    
      2.00 Cubic Feet
    
    Date acquired: 05/05/2003
    1
    2
  
  
    Scope and Contents
SCAN 17 or Springfield Community Access Network first aired on cable channel 17 in 1985; in 1994 the station name was changed to Access 4 and began airing on cable channel 4.  The community access channel allows any member of the Springfield Community the opportunity to produce and air television shows on a variety of different topics, including religion, cultural events, art, fitness and health.  Local community events and performances are also aired on the station.  
This collection of 3/4" and VHS tapes primarily consists of compilations of programming on SCAN 17/Access 4.  
The majority of the tapes were used as entries for the Hometown Video Festival.  Of particular interest is the Ribbon Cutting Ceremony for the new station, the first broadcast for SCAN 17.  The broadcast features Dr. Durward Long, President of SSU, Ray Schroeder, director of SCAN 17, Mayor Mike Houston, and Senator John Davidson.  
In addition to the compilation tapes, there are four tapes featuring entire segments of Jazzfield Illinois, Artbeat, and Helping Place.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronologically  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Television Office  
  PROGRAMSSeries 139664Scope and Contents* All tapes are ¾" unless otherwise notedBox 1Box 139667T3185 Jazzfield Illinois with host Dave HoffmanVideotape 139668Scope and Contents#57 Dave's Super Duper Mid Season All Star Break Sampler, 30:02, ndT3186 Artbeat with host Elaine Birtch of the Springfield Area Arts CouncilVideotape 2396691994Scope and Contents#192 Interview with actor Cal Shrum, 29:08T3187 Helping Place with host Rev. Bill PeckhamVideotape 339670Scope and Contents#12 St. John's Breadline, 26:45, nd
#13 Innercity Mission, 29:30, ndT3188 Helping Place with host Rev. Bill PeckhamVideotape 439671Scope and Contents#45 Gateway Foundation, 29:30
#46 SCAN 17 (interview with Ray Schroeder, director of SCAN 17) 28:11SPECIAL VIDEOS PRODUCED FOR EVENTSSeries 239665Scope and Contents* All tapes are ¾" unless otherwise notedBox 1Box 139672T3189 SCAN 17 Ribbon Cutting CeremonyVideotape 5396731985Scope and ContentsSpeakers include J. Michael Lennon of SSU, Mayor Mike Houston, John Gill of Dimension Cable Services, President of SSU Dr. Durward Long, Senator John Davidson, and Ray Schroeder director of SCAN 17T3190 SCAN 17 Rewinding Five YearsVideotape 6396741990Scope and ContentsProduced for the 5 year anniversary party.
A compilation tape featuring the clips of the following programming aired on the station:
. Mike's Music World, host Mike Anderson
. On the Spot with…Very Special People, host Dr. Benn
. Pets are People Too, Animal Protection League
. Boardgaming, Miniatures and Role-playing, host John Herriken
. Christmas at Clayville, with Mike Anderson
. Fitness Focus, hosts Jeff Sunderlin and Kim Munn
. Artbeat, host Debbie Ellerman
. Christians in Action, host Pastor James     Hailey
. Move to Keep Fit, host Alice Markwood
. Jazzfield Illinois, host Dave Hoffman
. Reflections, host Carol L. Gaston
. Ken and his Guitar, with Ken Ellis
. Yourshow, hosts Keith Chambers and Steven Richie
. Illinois Veterans Forum, host Jim Hall
. Works in Progress, hosts Peg Knoepfle and Rosie Richmond
. Illinois in Flight, host Joe Angermeier
. Jugglestuff ShowT3191 Footage from the 1990 GalaVideotape 739675Scope and ContentsSpeakers at the event which took place in Brookens Auditorium include director of the station, Ray Schroeder, President Long, Mayor Ozzie Langfelder, and several hosts of SCAN 17 programming.  The evening concluded with awards for service to the station.T3192 SCAN 17/Acces 4 File Footage (VHS)Videotape 839676Scope and ContentsTape contains several episodes of Today on Twenty when Ray Schroeder of Jan Morrow were interviewed.
. 5/20/85 guest Ray Schroeder – discussing history of the station
. 6/23/86 guest Ray Schroeder – discussing history of the station
. 4/11/88 guest Jan Morrow – discussing 3rd birthday of SCAN 17
. 6/23/89 guest Jan Morrow – SCAN 17 update
. 3/19/90 guest Jan Morrow – 5th birthday of SCAN 17T3193 Access 10 Year CelebrationVideotape 939677Scope and ContentsA compilation tape depicting the variety of programming on the station.
The shows included on the tape were:
. C-TV Peases Candy by Springfield Chamber of Commerce
. Capital Commentary by Raymond Poe
. AIDS in Springfield
. Committed to Serving by Junior League
. Backstreet Journal
. Mode-B
. Celebrate Diversity, Lincoln Library
. Marcellus and Friends
. Real Estate and You
. The Word of Power
. Artbeat, host Elaine Birtch
. Oh No Its Nyles Royce Again, host Nyles Royce
. The Shooting Sport
. Reflections, Carol Gaston
. Jazzfield Illinois, Dave Hoffman
. Biblical Poetry
. Inside Out
. On the Spot…With Very Special People, Dr. Benn
. Grapevine Harvest
. Contending for the Faith, Lois HayesT3194 Access 15 Year CelebrationVideotape 1039694T3195 SCAN 17 Video SamplerVideotape 1139678Scope and ContentsA compilation video of programming on SCAN 17.
. Jazzfield Illinois, host Dave Hoffman
. Catholic Schools, Dr. Donald Graham
. Contending the Faith, host Lois Hayes
. Illinois Veteran's Forum, host Jim Hall
. Crime Stopper, host Neil Williamson
. Artbeat, host Elaine Birtch
. Start Talking
. Puppies of the Forgotten Kind, Sangamon County Animal Pound
. Crisis NurseryT3196 Sangamon State Custom MusicVideotape 1239679Scope and ContentsTape of custom vocal and instrumental music for Sangamon State University.  Probably used as the background to commercialsHOMETOWN VIDEO FESTIVAL ENTRIESSeries 339666Scope and Contents* All tapes are ¾" unless otherwise notedThe following tapes were all submitted to the Hometown Video Festival in the category of Overall Excellence in Public ProgrammingBox 1Box 139680T3197Videotape 1339681Spring 1987Scope and ContentsCompilation tape showing excerpts of the following programming:
. Lincoln Festival Parade July 4, 1986
. Union of Concerned Scientists: A View of Star Wars, panel discussion lead by Alexander Casella
. Highlights on the 1986 State Fair, contains portion of opening remarks by Gov. Thompson as well as a brief interview
. Clayville Fall Crafts Festival, 1986
. Yourshow, hosts Keith Chambers and Steven Richie
. The Soldier's Chorus of the US Army Field Band, performance at SSU
. Aydin Gonulsen's Sports Show
. After the Summit: A Discussion with Lin Ackland
. Fitness Focus, host Jim Liston
. Kids Talk Sex, original play by Kevin PurcellT3198Videotape 14396821988-03-08Scope and ContentsCompilation tape showing excerpts of the following programming:
. Artbeat, host Debbie Ellerman
. Fitness Focus, hosts Jim Sunderlin and Kim Munn
. Signs of Silence, host Kate Steigerwald
. Aydin Gonulsen's Sports Show
. Yourshow, hosts Keith Chambers and Steve Richie
. Illinois Media, host Scott Ealy
. About the Bible, host Clark Stine
. Pets are People Too, Springfield Animal Pound
. Family Perspectives on Hydrocephalus
. Electrical Power Generation: Fossil to Fission, host Alex Cassela
. Boardgamming, Miniatures, and Roleplaying, John Henrikesen
. Finding Mrs. Lincoln: A dramatized interview with Mary Todd Lincoln's older sister Mrs. Edwards, National Park Service
. God and Country Concert, by Christian Elementary School
. A Musical Christmas Card, by Central Baptist Church
. Springfield New City Government, sponsored by Spfld League of Women Voters
. Highlights from 1987 Illinois State Fair Twilight ParadeT3199 1988 (VHS)Videotape 1539683Scope and ContentsVHS duplicate of the above mentioned tapeT3200Videotape 16396841989Scope and ContentsPublic Access: A Capital Idea, 12:03
Compilation tape showing excerpts of the following programming:
. ArtBeat, host Lib Granzeau
. Disability Digest, host Chuck Graham
. Public Announcement
. United Way Rap, performed by Southeast High School Students
. Signs of Silence, host Kate Scheigerwald
. Aerobics
. Religious Programming
. Fitness Programming
. Interview Programming
. Community Music Performances
. Alternative Music in Springfield
. Illinois Media, host Scott Ealy
. Yourshow, hosts Keith Chambers and Steven Richie
. On the Spot…with Very Special People, host Dr. BennBox 2Box 239685T3201Videotape 17396861990Scope and ContentsPublic Access in Mr. Lincoln's Hometown: Shiny as a New Penny, 28:51
Compilation tape showing excerpts of the following programming:
. Artbeat, host Elaine Birtch
. Veterans Forum host Jim Hall
. Move to Keep Kit
. Fitness Formula, host Sue May
. Fitness Focus, hosts Jim Sunderlin and Kim Munn
. Aydin Gonulsen's Sports Show
. Jazzfield Illinois, host Dave Hoffman
. Heartbeat, host Mark Putman
. The Jugglestuff Show
. Community Music Performance
. The Space Scene
. Yourshow, hosts Keith Chambers and Steven Richie
. Reflections, host Carol Gastone
. On the Spot…with Very Special People, host Dr. Benn
. Contending for the Faith, host Lois Hayes
. Lincoln at the Bar 
. RecreationT3202Videotape 18396871991Scope and ContentsPublic Access in Mr. Lincoln's Hometown: Shiny as a New Penny, 28:51
Compilation tape showing excerpts of the following programming:
. Artbeat, host Elaine Birtch
. Veterans Forum, host Jim Hall
. Move to Keep Kit
. Fitness Formula, host Sue May
. Fitness Focus, hosts Jim Sunderlin and Kim Munn
. Aydin Gonulsen's Sports Show
. Jazzfield Illinois, host Dave Hoffman
. Heartbeat, host Mark Putman
. The Jugglestuff Show
. Community Music Performance
. The Space Scene
. Yourshow, hosts Keith Chambers and Steven Richie
. Reflections, host Carol Gastone
. On the Spot…with Very Special People, host Dr. Benn
. Contending for the Faith, host Lois Hayes
. Lincoln at the Bar
. RecreationT3203Videotape 19396881992Scope and ContentsEveryday People, 11:29
Compilation tape showing excerpts of the following programming:
. Artbeat, host Elaine Birtch
. Dollarwise, host Greg Curran
. Oh No Its Nyles Royce Again, host Nyles Royce
. Hooked on Boxing, host Chris Oliea
. Do It Now: Prosper
. Backstreet Journal
. The Space Scene
. Biblical Poetry, host James Willis
. Works in Progress, Peg Knopfle and Rosie Richmond
. Community Response
. What's my Job?
. Jazzfield Illinois, host Dave HoffmanT3204Videotape 20396891993Scope and ContentsOverall Excellence in Public Access, 11:29
Compilation tape showing excerpts of the following programming:
. Jazzfield Illinois, host Dave Hoffman
. St. Monica's
. Fair Housing, host Dolores Brookins
. Artbeat, host Elaine Birtch
. Veterans' Forum, host Jim Hall
. Oh the Animals
. Contending for the Faith, host Lois Hayes
. Oh No Its Nyles Royce Again
. Start Talking, Game Show
. Escape from Domestic Violence
. Fitness Focus, hosts Jim Sunderlin and Kim MunnT3205Videotape 21396901994Scope and ContentsEveryday People, 29:30
Compilation tape showing excerpts of the following programming:
. Lets Ride the Bus, Springfield Mass Transit
. Shooting Sport, Springfield Sportsman Association
. Lincoln Library Stories for African American History Month
. Mode B
. Illinois Flood Update, Illinois National Guard
. Crisis Nursery
. The Magic Pizza
. The Space Scene
. Do It Now, host Rev. Geri Comstock
. Black Street Journal
. Artbeat host Elaine Birtch
. Grapevine Harvest
. Town Meeting on Health Care, speaker Don Moss
. Contact Ministries Tour
. Jazzfield Illinois host Dave Hoffman
. Inside Out, Aime Meneghetti
. Discovering the Bah'i Faith
. What Black History Means to Me
. Over 60 But Not Over the HillT3206Videotape 22396911996Scope and ContentsOnly brief vocal introduction and nothing else on this tape.  It may have been erased.T3207Videotape 23396921997Scope and Contents19:51
Compilation tape showing excerpts of the following programming:
Different intro but same clips of shows on tape T3193T3208Videotape 24396932001Scope and ContentsCommunity Voices, 19:25
Compilation tape showing excerpts of the following programming:
. Skys the Limit, Youth Outreach
. Child Safety Seat Demonstration
. Marcus Garvey
. Sports Highlights
. Karel Keldermans playing the Carillon
. Marvelous Marcellus Leonard reading poetry
. Women's Group	
. Last Hour Message with Bishop Clarke
. Entertainment Showcase

