<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.09.06/04Archon Finding Aid Title J.09.06/04UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:11:02 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J9/6/4. Literature Program, Sangamon Poets Collection, 1973-1980
    
      Literature Program
    
    
      Knoepfle, John
    
    J.09.06/04
    488
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1973-1980
    Date acquired: 02/00/1979
    2 Items
    1
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Sangamon Poets, a group of poets and artists associated with SSU, published a series of chapbooks and a magazine, "The Village Magazine", under the leadership of John Knoepfle.  Money for  these publications came from a a grant by the Venture Fund.  The collection includes copies of the chapbooks and the magazine, as well as financial ledger pages, correspondence, and a report to the Venture Fund Committee.
The Literature Program became the English program in the 1987-88 school year.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
John Knoepfle  
  Box 1Box 144082Amezquita, Ricardo Mario.  Eating StonesFolder 14408319771Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois:  Sangamon Poets, Sangamon State University. 16 pp. [Eighth in a series of chapbooks, in an edition of 500 copies] 2 copies, #373 and #471.  Autographed by author.Dolgin, Steven Alfred.  Between Lunatic EarsFolder 24408419742Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois: Sangamon Poets, Sangamon State University,  n.p.  2 copies.Gardner, Eve.  Morning SighsFolder 34408519753Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois: Sangamon Poets, Sangamon State 	University.  n.p.  [Fifth in an series of chapbooks, in an edition of 500 	copies] 2 copies, #199 and #220. Autographed by author.Hanrahan, Janne.  Light From New SteelFolder 44408619744Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois: Sangamon Poets, Sangamon State University. 24 pp. [Edition of 500 copies] 2 copies.Hilton, Pat.  The Museum Is ClosedFolder 54408719795Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois:  Sangamon Poets, Sangamon State University.  16 pp. [Twelfth in a series of chapbooks, in an edition of 500 copies]  2 copies, #293 and #294.  Autographed by author.Kallas, Anthony C.  Rock River SuiteFolder 64408819776Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois: Sangamon Poets, Sangamon State University.  n.p.  [Tenth in a series of chapbooks, in an edition of 500 	copies] 2 copies, #78 and #477.  Autographed by author.Knoepfle, Peg.  Sparks from Your HoofsFolder 74408919767Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois: Sangamon Poets, Sangamon State University.  28 pp. [Edition of 500 copies] 2 copies, #21 and #347.  Autographed by author.Morrel, Jane.  Wordings Like LoveFolder 84409019758Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois:  Sangamon Poets, Sangamon State University.  24 pp.  [Edition of 700 copies] 2 copies, #164 and #469.  	Autographed by author.Osburn, Timothy.  OuttakesFolder 94409119749Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois: Sangamon Poets, Sangamon State University.  n.p.  2 copies. Autographed by author.Ranyard, John.   Dog's BreakfastFolder 1044092197610Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois: Sangamon Poets, Sangamon State University.  18 pp.  [Seventh in a series of chapbooks, in an edition of 500 	copies]	2 copies, #284 and #306.  Autographed by author.Riseman, Sandra.  The Infected EyeFolder 1144093197711Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois: Sangamon Poets, Sangamon State University.  n.p. [Eleventh in a series of chapbooks, in an edition of 500 copies] 2 copies, #131 and #469.  Autographed by author.Winning, Rebecca.  Cure for Backache &amp; Other PoemsFolder 1244094197712Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois: Sangamon Poets, 	Sangamon State University. n.p. [Ninth in a series of chapbooks, in	an edition of 500 copies] 2 copies, #49 and #347.  Autographed by author.The Village MagazineFolder 1344095197913Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois: Sangamon Poets, Sangamon State University, 1979.  50 pp.  [Edition of 700 copies] 2 copies.Financial papers for Sangamon PoetsFolder 14440961973-198014Letters regarding Sangamon PoetsFolder 15440971974-197715Notebook concerning Sangamon PoetsFolder 164409816Review of 2 chapbooks: Wording Like Love and Morning SighsFolder 174409917John Knoepfle Self Statement, Descriptions of Sangamon Poets and SSUFolder 1844100197518Scope and ContentsNational Book 	Award application for Janne HanrahanMy Mother by Victor Farwell, poster, 18" x 14"Folder 194410119Scope and ContentsLocated in Oversize Cabinet 1, Drawer 1Illinois Poets: An Exhibit, poster, 22" x 17", 2 copiesFolder 204410220Scope and ContentsLocated in Oversize Cabinet 1, Drawer 1OVERSIZE cabinet 1OVERSIZE cabinet 150207Drawer 1Drawer 150208Illinois Poets: An ExhibitFolder 1502091Scope and ContentsMy Mother
2 folders

