<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>G.01/01/06Archon Finding Aid Title G.01/01/06Sandra LongenUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:11:21 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    G1/1/6. University Relations, Subject File, 1981-2005
    
      University Relations
    
    
      Peck, Cheryl
    
    G.01/01/06
    1709
    
      1.86 Cubic Feet
    
    1981-2005
    Date acquired: 03/11/2009
    1
    2
    3
    4
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The University Relations subject File, 1981-2001 consists of memos, correspondence, reports, speeches, meeting notes, news clippings, and other material between the UIS campus community and internal and external entities.  
This file contains recruitment reports, including the search for a new Chancellor when Naomi Lynn retired and Richard Ringeisen was selected; the expansion of the campus with the construction of the Health and Sciences Building; the implementation of the Capital Scholars program for undergraduates; and the conversion to being part of the University of Illinois community.
This file also contains President's reports, Board of Regents reports, Institutional Self-Study Report (1997), and other varied information about the campus, such as the UIS fight song written by student Phillip Snow.
The main source is the Director of Public Relations, Cheryl Peck, who retired from UIS in 2009.
Box 4 contains the entire Marketing and Promotional Plan for UIS for the Fall enrollment of 1999, includes proof sheets and final copies for ads, promotions and recruitment pieces.  Files obtained from the notebook of Cheryl Peck.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Cheryl Peck.  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Additional material obtained from Cheryl Peck May 2013; includes 1999 UIS Marketing and Promotional Plan  
  
    Correspondence
    Speeches
    Flyers/Brochures
    Videotapes
    Sheet Music
    Scrapbook
    Newspaper Clippings
    Press Releases
    Photographs
    Letters
    Newspapers
    Reports
    Records
    Programs
    Proof sheets
  
  Box 1Box 144123Union MattersFolder 2441241993-972Capital ScholarsFolder 3441251997-993Alum NewslettersFolder 4441261998-994SSU Presidential SearchFolder 54412719915SSU News and UIS JournalFolder 6441701991-986Scope and ContentsSSU News - Anniversary Issue, April 10, 1991
UIS Journal:
Vol 15, Issue 9, 1998/10/21
Vol 15, Issue 10, 1998/10/28
Vol 15, Issue 11, 1998/11/04
Vol 15, Issue 12, 1998/11/11
Vol 15, Issue 13, 1998/11/18
Vol 15, Issue 14, 1998/12/09
Vol 15, Issue 15, 1999/01/27
Vol 15, Issue 16, 1999/02/03
Vol 15, Issue 19, 1999/02/24
Vol 15, Issue 21, 1999/03/10Hillary Rodham Clinton Visits UISFolder 744171April 19967Scope and Contentsnews clippingsBill Miller, PAR Director, RetiresFolder 84417219938Impermanent Columns Sculpture DedicationFolder 94417319939A. Lincoln Honors College ProposalFolder 1044174199310Scope and ContentsLower division college at UISJames Jones SymposiumFolder 11441751991-11-0111Matt Hale Visits UISFolder 1244176200012Lincoln Home RestorationFolder 1344177199813Scope and ContentsState Journal Register Special EditionSSU to UIS, Transition Steering CommitteeFolder 1444178199514Streamlining University CurriculumFolder 15441791998-9915SSU Four Year Status RestructuringFolder 16441801992-9516Peoria CampusFolder 17441811990-9217Sailing ClubFolder 18441821989-9118Public Affairs DoctorateFolder 1944183199219SSU Advertising CampaignFolder 2044184199720SSU Advertising Campaign; Bunn SeriesFolder 2144185199721Scope and ContentsEducation Can Make a World of DifferenceUniversity Hall, New Classroom BuildingFolder 22441861999-200422Scope and ContentsGround breaking 2002
Dedication service 2004Doctor of Public Administration DegreeFolder 23441871997-9823Campus Safety and Police ForceFolder 24441881991-200024Campus Crime Awareness and Campus Security Act of 1990Folder 25441891990-200025Campus PoliciesFolder 26441901994-200126Fox, Sakolsky IncidentFolder 2744191199527Campus Entrance markerFolder 28441921998-200028Strategic Planning, University RelationsFolder 29441931993-199629UIS Fight SongFolder 3044194200030Scope and Contentswritten by Phillip SnowStudent CenterFolder 3144195198531New Chancellor Chosen - Richard RingheisenFolder 3244196200132Scope and ContentsNews clippings and correspondenceUIS Alumni InterviewsDVD 145101October 2006Scope and ContentsLocated in Video Collection T#3217
Diane Rutledge, 
Kevin Purcell, 
Michael SchwartzUIS Online Students - In Their Own Words (2 copies)DVD 245102Scope and ContentsLocated in Video Collection T#3218
Sonia Moritz, 
Carla Ross, 
Amy Turasky, 
Vera Garrett, 
Robert Schultz, 
Jeff Miller, 
Myron HighfieldMatt Hale visit to UISVideotape 1442742000-02-17Scope and ContentsLocated in Video Collection T#3214
Local channel 20 news report on visit of Hale to UIS.Cable Access 4: Brian Henderson ShowVideotape 245099Scope and ContentsLocated in Video Collection T#3215
Variety Show Premiere: Pressures of being a college student and dating in the campus scene.Cable Access 4: The Shooting Sport with Tom ShaferVideotape 345100Scope and ContentsLocated in Video Collection T#3216
State Journal-Register on the firing line; Copley press, the elite press.Box 2Box 244201Naomi Lynn, Chancellor FileFolder 1441971991-991New Program Request: Abraham Lincoln Honors College at SSUFolder 2441981991/07/052Proposal for the Abraham Lincoln College at UISFolder 344199April 19963Capital Scholars ChronologyFolder 4442001999/09/284Sangamon StateFolder 5442021989-19925Scope and ContentsMiscellaneous file includes: 
SSU Self-study report (1986); 
Patton Park dedication (1990); 
President's Convocation (1990 and 1991); 
SSU Homecoming and Fall Festival (1992); 
SSU 20th Anniversary (1990); 
Organization Charts for Full-Time Employees (1991)Clayville Rural Life CenterFolder 6442031973-756Naomi Lynn, SSU President - Speeches and News ClippingsFolder 7442041991-20017Health Sciences BuildingFolder 844205FY 19928Thank You Card to Naomi Lynn, undatedFolder 9537949Commencement Procedure card w/notesFolder 1053795199610Bill Clinton's vist to UIUCFolder 1153796199511Scope and ContentsContact sheets and notesBox 3Box 345103Durward LongFolder 1442061988-891UIS 2001: A Space Odyssey, Board of Trustees MeetingFolder 2442071997/09/112Institutional Self-Study ReportFolder 34420819973Scope and ContentsSubmitted to the Commission on Institutions of Higher Education of the North Central Association of Colleges and SchoolsPhysical Development of Sangamon State UniversityFolder 4442091969-19954Scope and Contentsby Richard R. WilliamsSSU at 15, What is that place for?Folder 544210March 28 - April 3, 19855Scope and ContentsIllinois Times Edition (Vol 10, No. 30)Record of Achievement, A Promise for the Future 1969-1992Folder 644211July 24, 19916Scope and ContentsCompiled by Sharon Helding - An Index to Faculty and Administration at Sangamon State UniversitySSU at 20 and a Look AheadFolder 7442121990/06/137SSU - Rebirth of the University - 25 yearsFolder 8442131985/03/218Scope and ContentsState Journal Register Special EditionPublic Affairs Research Centers - SSUFolder 9442149UIS: A Capital IdeaFolder 104421510SSU Recruitment PlanFolder 11442161985-8611Toward 2000: A Strategic Plan for SSU, Phase IFolder 1244217March, 199212SSU ResurgenceFolder 13442181984-199013The Campus Land Purchase and the McClelland StoryFolder 1444219January 200614Scope and Contentsby Richard R. WilliamsLincoln's Sangamon County: The Strawbridge-Shepherd Farm SiteFolder 1544220200715Scope and ContentsRichard E. Hart
Cotton Hill on Sugar Creek Series
Copyright 2007 by Elijah Iles House Foundation
Springfield, ILSpring Commencement Ceremony ScrapbookFolder 1644221200116Scope and ContentsPictures of graduates, no names attachedBox 4Box 477137Marketing &amp; Promotional Plan for Fall Enrollment at UISFolder 17713819991Promotional Material for Individual UIS ProgramsFolder 27713919992Scope and ContentsIncludes ads for these programs:
Business Administration, English, Public Affairs, Political or Legal Studies, Accounting, Communication, Teacher &amp; Leadership, Psychology, Management Information, Environmental Health, Social Work, Human Services, and Criminal JusticeAdvertisement for Specific Courses or ProgramsFolder 37714019993Scope and ContentsSingle page ads listing courses available for Fall 1999:
Online, College of Business &amp; Management, Political Studies at Night, Social Work, Broadcast Television, Classes at Capital City Center, Elementary &amp; Secondary Education, Masters of Arts in Educational Admin or Human Services or Human Development Counseling, and Graduate Certificates in Public Management Practices of Public Sector Labor Relations or Management of Nonprofit Organizations2 + Two Program: Business Administration Degree from LLCC &amp; UISFolder 47714119994Scope and ContentsReceive Associate in Science in BA at Lincoln Land Community College in two years and continue two  more years at UIS to finish a Bachelor in BA.Program BrochuresFolder 57714219995Scope and ContentsIncludes: Nursing, Environmental Studies, Environmental Risk Assessment, Health Services Administration, Clinical Laboratory Science, Chemistry, Biology, Liberal Studies, Credit for Prior Learning, and Doctor of Public AdministrationUIS ReportsFolder 67714319996Scope and ContentsInstitute for Public Affairs, University of Illinois Engine of Economic Development, Executive Summary of the Institutional Self-Study Report (1997), and UIS Vision StatementCapital Campaign Brochure and NewslettersFolder 77714419997Scope and ContentsUIS Campaign - A Defining Moment
Investing in Illinois-Newsletter of the U of I Foundation, Special UIS Edition; Winter 1999 Issue 26. Fundraising Campaign for Springfield Campus.
Capital Investment-Newsletter, Winter 1999 Issue 1. National City Bank Endows First Professorship at UIS.UIS BrochuresFolder 87714519998Scope and ContentsIncludes:
. Impact Illinois-13 Ways the University of Illinois Benefits the State
.UIS-A Capital Idea
. Capital Outreach: UIS-Serving the Community and the State
. UIS Campus Housing
. UIS-Office of Enrollment Services
. University of Illinois Springfield - In Brief
. University of Illinois Springfield - At a Glance, 1999-2000UIS Advertisements in NewspapersFolder 97715620019Scope and ContentsState Journal-Register, Senior News &amp; Times, and The Journal [UIS newspaper]Proof SheetsFolder 107715710Scope and Contentsfor brochures and newspaper advertisementsProof Sheets (oversize)Folder 117715811Scope and Contentsfor brochures and newspaper advertisementsMatted Proof SheetsFolder 127715912Scope and ContentsProbably used at presentations

