<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>P.DickermanArchon Finding Aid Title P.DickermanNicole L. LouisUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:11:24 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    P/Dickerman. Barbara Dickerman, Personal Papers
    
      Dickerman, Barbara
    
    P.Dickerman
    1708
    
      3.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1968-2009
    Date acquired: 06/25/2009
    1
    2
    3
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Papers of Barbara Dickerman, SSU/UIS student, UIS admissions councilor, and Springfield housing and equal rights activist. Collection contains correspondence, reports, notes, newspaper clippings, and other memorabilia from Dickerman's work with such organizations as the League of Women Voters, YWCA, Springfield Housing Authority, NAACP, United Way, MOVE, Inc. and various other groups.  Of note is Dickerman's work to desegregate Springfield School District #186, achieve fair housing for low-income families, and a voting rights lawsuit that eventually led to Springfield changing its form of city government from council to aldermanic. Some files contain written notations from Dickerman regarding their contents.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Topical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Donated by Barbara Dickerman  
  
    Agendas
    Awards
    Contact Sheets
    Correspondence
    Course Materials
    Flyers/Brochures
    Journal Articles
    Letters
    Maps
    Memorabilia
    Minutes
    Newsletters
    Newspaper Clippings
    Papers
    Photocopies
    Photographs
    Posters
    Press Releases
    Programs
    Records
    Reports
    Resolutions
    Sheet Music
    Speeches
    Statistics
    Surveys
    Transcripts
  
  Box 1Box 140101NAACPFolder 1401022008-20091Scope and ContentsPrograms, flyersPublic Hearing on Public HousingFolder 24010319932Scope and ContentsNewspaper clippings, testimony, contact lists, correspondence, notesNAACPFolder 34010419973Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, newspaper clippingsCelebration - Brown v. Board of EducationFolder 4402642004-5-114Scope and ContentsNewspaper clippings, correspondence, notes, programsNAACPFolder 5402652000-20015Scope and ContentsNotes, programs, correspondence, newspaper clippingsNAACP - HousingFolder 64026619946Scope and ContentsPrograms, notes, correspondence, contact listsYouth Honors Program/Lincoln InstituteFolder 7402671979-19857Scope and ContentsNotes, programs, correspondence, budgetsSchool District #186 Desegregation LawsuitFolder 84026820048Scope and ContentsNewspaper clippings, notes, correspondence, programsSpringfield School District #186 Desecration LawsuitFolder 94026919769Scope and ContentsNewspaper clipping, copy of lawsuit (filed on 1974-04-11).Planning for School DesegregationFolder 1040270197410Scope and ContentsNotes, correspondence, bookletsLeague of Women Voters - Urban CrisisFolder 11402711978-197911Scope and ContentsNewspaper clippings, brochures, notes, correspondenceIllinois League of Women VotersFolder 1240272199412Scope and ContentsBrochures, pamphlets, notes, agendasPublications and Clippings re: Illinois LegislatureFolder 1340273ca. 1980-198313Scope and ContentsBrochures, flyers, newslettersLeague of Women VotersFolder 14402741981-198214Scope and ContentsMemos, correspondence, brochureLeague of Women Voters - ReportsFolder 1540275197015Scope and ContentsAgenda, magazine articleLeague of Women Voters - CorrespondenceFolder 1640276197316Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, pamphlets, agendasNews Clippings re: Illinois LegislatureFolder 17402771981-198217Scope and ContentsNewspaper clippingsAbortion DebateFolder 18402781981-198218Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, notes, newspaper clippings, brochures, flyersLobbying Activities for Social PolicyFolder 19402791981-198319Scope and ContentsFlyers, notes, reports, correspondenceLeague of Women Voters - CorrespondenceFolder 2040280198220Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, agendas, notesUnited Way ProjectFolder 2140281198221Scope and ContentsNotes, brochures, newspaper clippings, correspondenceEqual Rights AmendmentFolder 2240282198222Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, newspaper clippings, memos, notesLobbyingFolder 23402831980-198223Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, notes, memos, agendasBox 2Box 240404Lobbying Illinois LegislatureFolder 24404051981-198324Scope and ContentsNotes, newsletters, newspaper clippings, press releasesLobbying Illinois LegislatureFolder 25404061979-198225Scope and ContentsNotes, minutes, correspondence, newsletters, newspaper clippingsLeague of Women Voters - TaxesFolder 26404071993-199426Scope and ContentsNotes, speech outlines, transparencies, political cartoonsYWCA Board TrainingFolder 2740408199527Scope and ContentsNotes, correspondence, flyers, newslettersYWCAFolder 2840409199628Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, invitations, notes, budgets, contact lists, newspaper clippingsYWCA Blanket DriveFolder 2940410199929Scope and ContentsPress releases, flyers, correspondence, newspaper clippingsYWCA MemoiresFolder 30404111980-199430Scope and ContentsNewspaper clippings, photographs (photocopies), notes, contact lists, press releasesChildren's Supper Hour at Asbury Methodist ChurchFolder 3140412199631Scope and ContentsPrograms, memos, minutes, notes, budgetsClass in City Government (taught by Dickerman)Folder 32404131977-198132Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, thank-you notes, newspaper clippings, notes, brochures"Making a Difference"Folder 33404141988-199233Scope and ContentsNewspaper clippings, notes, programs, brochruesSpringfield Housing DevelopmentFolder 34404151970-197534Scope and ContentsNotes, correspondence, Illinois constitutional amendment drafts, transcripts, budgets, brochures, memos, minutesHUD CorrespondenceFolder 35407281980-198235Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, memosHousing AuthorityFolder 3640729196936Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, agendas, surveys, newspaper clippingsHousing Task ForceFolder 37407301968-197237Scope and ContentsNewspaper clippings, correspondence, memos, agendas, chartsFair Housing - Programs/BrochuresFolder 38407311969-200338Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, reports, tourist brochuresFair Housing - NotebooksFolder 39407321969-197439Scope and ContentsNotesAccess to HousingFolder 40407331979-198440Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, memosCommunity Housing Resource BoardFolder 41407341991-199941Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, agendas, handbookFairfax County Department of HousingFolder 42407351991-199442Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, memos, articlesAccess to HousingFolder 43407361980-198243Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, memos, agendas, reports, brochures, newspaper clippingsLeague of Women VotersFolder 44409781969-198244Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, newspaper clippings, notes, brochureLeague of Women Voters - Housing for MinoritiesFolder 45409791968-196945Scope and ContentsNewspaper clippings, correspondence, reports, agendasFair Housing Studies by League of Women VotersFolder 4640980197646Scope and ContentsNewspaper clippings, correspondence, reports, memos, transcriptsLeague of Women Voters - Fair HousingFolder 47409811971-197247Scope and ContentsBrochures, notes, correspondence, memosReport on Racial Discrimination in Springfield, IllinoisFolder 4840982198648Scope and ContentsReportWICS Television Show Produced by the League of Women VotersFolder 4940984197049Scope and ContentsMemos, correspondence, scripts, sheet musicLeague of Women Voters - MiscellaneousFolder 50409851972-197650Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, interviews, annual reportsLocal CorrespondenceFolder 51409861970-197251Scope and ContentsContact lists, brochures, correspondence, reports, agendas, newsletters, newspaper clippingsBox 3Box 340983League of Women Voters in the United States and Illinois - BulletinsFolder 52409871980-199552Scope and ContentsBrochures, bulletins, annual reports, pamphlets"Springfield Magical" Event for WSEC-TVFolder 5340988199253Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, poster"Springfield Magical" InvitationsFolder 5440989199254Scope and ContentsPrograms, memos, notes, brochures, agendas, budgetsSpringfield Area Neighborhood OrganizationFolder 55409901973-197455Scope and ContentsNewspaper clippings, correspondence, reports, photographs, brochures, contact lists, notesSpringfield Area Neighborhood OrganizationFolder 56409911973-197456Scope and ContentsPress releases, newspaper clippings, photographs, flyers, memos, notes, correspondence, contact lists,MOVE, Inc.Folder 57413521973-198957Scope and ContentsNewspaper clippings, notes, correspondence, agendas, charts, budgetsMOVE, Inc. Minutes and Treasurer's ReportsFolder 58413531977-198058Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, minutes, agendas, correspondence, contact lists, budgets, newspaper clippingsStudent PortfolioFolder 59413541984-198659Scope and ContentsCredit request forms, school schedules, notes, personal statements/narratives, class papersPersonal File - SSU and WSEC-TVFolder 60413551983-200460Scope and ContentsArticles, newsletters, programs, newspaper clippings, correspondence, vita, cards, transcripts, calendarsYorkettes - Frontier's InternationalFolder 61413561996-200161Scope and ContentsPrograms, newsletters, correspondence. agendas, contact lists, notesProject Area Council of the Urban Renewal Project - SpringfieldFolder 6241357197262Scope and ContentsNotes, essays, land use plansVoting Rights LawsuitFolder 63417851978-198763Scope and ContentsCopy of lawsuit, correspondence, newspaper clippings, reportsFair HousingFolder 64417861978-200164Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, editorials, reports, agendas, newspaper clippings, notes, copies of ordinances, brochuresNewspapers Clippings Regarding Voting Rights Lawsuit/Change in Springfield City GovernmentFolder 65417871986-198765Scope and ContentsNewspaper clippingsOVERSIZE cabinet 1OVERSIZE cabinet 174284SSU Poster located in Drawer 12 of OVERSIZEItem 174283ca. 1980s1Scope and ContentsFull size poster with styrofoam backing. 
"The step beyond the community college is at SSU.
2+2= SSU"
2 years at Community College
+ 2 years at SSU
= 4 year Bachelor Degree Program

