<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>P.HaylerArchon Finding Aid Title P.HaylerNicole L. LouisUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:11:37 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    P/Hayler. Barbara Hayler, Personal Papers
    
      Hayler, Barbara J.
    
    P.Hayler
    1704
    
      0.50 Cubic Feet
    
    1966-1982
    Date acquired: 00/00/2009
    1
    2
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Papers of Barbara Hayler,  Professor Emerita of Criminal Justice at UIS.  
Contains  reports, articles, flyers, newspaper clippings, and collected publications pertaining to women's rights, the 1970s women's liberation movement, and sexual harassment within the workplace. 
Includes articles, notes, correspondence, and other material related to a 1980 survey conducted by Hayler regarding sexual harassment of female Illinois state government employees.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Hayler, Barbara J.  
  
    Contact Sheets
    Correspondence
    Flyers/Brochures
    Journal Articles
    Letters
    Minutes
    Newspaper Clippings
    Papers
    Photocopies
    Press Releases
    Reports
    Speeches
    Statistics
    Surveys
    Records
  
  Box 1Box 138243ReportsFolder 1382441979-19811Scope and Contents"Sexual Harassment in the Federal Workplace: Is it a Problem?" (Summary of Findings), 1981
"Sexual Harassment in the Federal 
Workplace: Is it a Problem?" (Full Report), 1981
"Sexual Harassment in the Federal Government: Hearings Before the Subcommittee on Investigations of the Committee on Post Office and Civil Service," 1979
"Sexual Harassment in the Federal Government: Subcommittee on Investigations of the Committee on Post Office and Civil Service," 1980
"Summary of Preliminary Findings on Sexual Harassment in the Federal Workplace given before the Subcommittee on Investigations Committee on Post Office and Civil Service," 1980
"Sexual Harassment: A Report on the Sexual Harassment of Students," 1980Sexual Harassment: Illinois State StudyFolder 2382451979-19802Scope and ContentsCopies of 1980 sexual harassment survey, letters, memos, newspaper clippings, cartoons, and Hayler's testimony before the Illinois House Judiciary Committee (1980-03-04)Sexual Harassment: Articles, Misc. MaterialFolder 3382461979-19803Scope and ContentsFlyers, newspaper clippings, correspondence, memosInformation Requests re: Sexual Harassment StudyFolder 43824719804Scope and ContentsNotes, correspondence, contact sheets, timelinesSexual Harassment - based on SSU studyFolder 5382481980-055Scope and Contents"Sexual Harassment in the Workplace," by Ronda Robinson-BeemanSexual Harassment ReportFolder 63824919806Scope and ContentsCopies of 1980 sexual harassment survey, memos, meeting minutes, data, notes[Sexual Harassment Literature]Folder 7382501971-19827Scope and Contents"Sexual Harassment: On the Job Sexual Harassment: What the Union Can Do." (American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees, 1980)
"Sexual Harassment on the Job: A Guide for Employers." (U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, 1982)
"Sexual Harassment: How to Recognize and Deal with It." (What Would Happen If...Inc., 1979)
"Sexual Harassment on the Job: A Guide for Employers." (U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, 1982)
"Sexual and Gender Harassment in the Academy: A Guide for Faculty, Students, and Administrators." (Commission on the Status of Women in the Profession, 1981)
"Stopping Sexual Harassment: A Handbook." (Labor and Education Research Project, 1980)
"Fighting Sexual Harassment: An Advocacy Handbook." (Alliance Against Sexual Coercion, 1979)
"Our Bodies Our Selves: A Course by and for Women." (Boston Women's Health Course Collective, 1971)
"A Book About Sexual Harassment." (Montreal Health Press, 1979)
5.25" floppy disk, "SPSS Work, SSU Sexual Harassment Survey Dataset"Box 2Box 238251Women: GeneralFolder 8382521966-19768Scope and Contents"Women: The Longest Revolution," by Juliet Mitchell, 1966
"Kinder, Kuche Kirche as Scientific Law: Psychology Constructs the Female," by Naomi Weisstein, ca. 1970
"Toward a Female Liberation Movement," by Beverly Jones and Judith Brown, 1968
"Female Liberation: As the Basis for Social Revolution," by Roxanne Dunbar
"The Myth of Women's Inferiorty [sic]," by Evelyn Reed, originally published 1954 (reprint)
"The Atlantic," 1970-03
"Women of the Year," TIME Magazine, 1976-01-05
"Special Issue: The American Woman," TIME Magazine, 1972-03-20
"Current History: Women in America," 1976-05[Feminist Literature]Folder 9382531968-19759Scope and Contents"Notes from the First Year." (New York Radical Women, 1968-06)
"Notes from the Second Year: Women's Liberation, Major Writings of the Radical Feminists." (New York Radical Women, 1970)
"Notes from the Third Year: Women's Liberation." (New York Radical Women, 1970)
"Feminist Revolution." (Redstockings, 1975)

