<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>K.08.02/03Archon Finding Aid Title K.08.02/03Nicole L. LouisUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:11:39 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    K8/2/3. International Festival Records, 1979-2014
    
      International Studies Office
    
    K.08.02/03
    1703
    
      2.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1979-2014
    Date acquired: 09/16/2008
    1
    2
    3
    4
    Poster
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The International Festival is an annual program that highlights the cultural diversity at Sangamon State University/University of Illinois at Springfield.  Organized by the International Student Organization, the festival features exhibits, food, and entertainment provided by international students and featuring their home countries.  Each yearly festival is centered on a theme that explores the unique differences between the featured countries.  Examples of themes include wedding traditions, toys and games, and clothing.  There is also a "world market" where visitors can purchase items from other nations.  Originally started as a simple potluck get-together, the festival has been celebrated every year since 1977.The collection contains correspondence, programs, budgets, posters, recipes, videos, photos, music, and other organizational material from the festivals held between 1979 and 2014.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
International Studies Office  
  
    Accruals and Additions
Box 4: Videos, music, photographs, and document files (on floppy disc), 1993-2009, added to collection, June 7, 2017. Chris Schnell.  
  
    Agendas
    Awards
    Contact Sheets
    Correspondence
    Flyers/Brochures
    Letters
    Memorabilia
    Minutes
    Newspaper Clippings
    Newspapers
    Papers
    Photocopies
    Posters
    Press Releases
    Programs
    Records
    Reports
    Sheet Music
    Surveys
    Audio Tapes
    Videotapes
  
  Box 1Box 136469International FestivalFolder 13650620001Scope and ContentsPrograms, request forms, correspondence, newspaper clippingsInternational Student AssociationFolder 23651120002Scope and ContentsNotes, programs, newspaper clippings, correspondence, request forms, diagramsInternational FestivalFolder 33651320003Scope and ContentsDiagrams, meeting minutes, correspondence, request forms, notesLertmahawong, AmornratFolder 43651219994Scope and ContentsRequest forms, budget, meeting minutesInternational FestivalFolder 53650719995Scope and ContentsPrograms, correspondence, budgets, request forms, invoices, pictureInternational FestivalFolder 63650819986Scope and ContentsPrograms, notes, mailing lists, correspondence, request forms, budgets, invoices, diagrams, newspaper clippingsInternational Student Association ActivitiesFolder 73650919987Scope and ContentsMeeting minutes, notes, correspondence, request forms, flyersInternational FestivalFolder 83651019978Scope and ContentsPosters, programs, notes, budgetsReserved Tickets/ComplementaryFolder 93651419979Scope and ContentsNotes, tickets, correspondenceEntertainmentFolder 1036516199710Scope and ContentsNotes, correspondence, flyersPrinting/DuplicatingFolder 1136517199711Scope and ContentsTickets, flyerInternational CelebrationFolder 1236518199712Scope and ContentsNotes, posters, newspaper clippings, correspondence, flyers, request formsGeneralFolder 1336519199713Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, notes, diagramsHistorical ExhibitFolder 1436520199714Scope and ContentsNotes, posters, photographDuBois/Bamboo DanceFolder 1536521199715Scope and ContentsInstructions, notesStageFolder 1636522199716Scope and ContentsDiagrams, notes, picturesReserved Tickets/ComplementaryFolder 1736515199617Scope and ContentsTickets, budgets, correspondenceGeneralFolder 1836523199618Scope and ContentsRequest forms, notes, meeting minutes19th International FestivalFolder 19365241996-11-1019Scope and ContentsRequest forms, song lyrics, recipes, programs, diagrams, program script, notesBudgetFolder 2036525199620Scope and ContentsBudgets, correspondence, programs, notesEntertainmentFolder 2136526199621Scope and ContentsProgram script, correspondence, song lyrics, notesCorrespondenceFolder 2236527199622Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, newspaper clippingsPublicity/Program/ScriptFolder 2336528199623Scope and ContentsPrograms, newspaper clippings, program script, notes, flyersInternational FestivalFolder 2436530199624Scope and ContentsPrograms, notes, newspaper clippings, correspondence, budgets, invoices, purchase orders, request formsMenus/FoodFolder 2536531199625Scope and ContentsNotes, recipes, programsInternational Buffet RecipesFolder 2636532199526Scope and ContentsPrograms, recipesInternational FestivalFolder 2736533199527Scope and ContentsFlyers, correspondence, diagrams, notesCorrespondenceFolder 2836534199528Scope and ContentsFlyers, notes, correspondenceMenus/FoodFolder 2936535199529Scope and ContentsNotes, menusEntertainmentFolder 3036536199530Scope and ContentsNotes, correspondence, flyersPublicity/Program/ScriptFolder 3136537199531Scope and ContentsProgram script, flyers, programsGeneralFolder 3236538199532Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, notes, purchase ordersPrinting/DuplicatingFolder 3336539199533Scope and ContentsFlyers, notesBudgetFolder 3436540199534Scope and ContentsBudgets, request forms, correspondenceReserved Tickets/ComplimentaryFolder 3536541199535Scope and ContentsInvoices, notes, correspondence, ticketsBudgetFolder 3636548199536Scope and ContentsBudgets, correspondence, notes, flyersInternational FestivalFolder 3736542199437Scope and ContentsPrograms, request forms, invoices, notes, recipes. Budgets, correspondenceInternational FestivalFolder 3836543199438Scope and ContentsPosters, flyers, notes, programs, correspondence, newspaper clippingsEntertainmentFolder 3936576199439Scope and ContentsProgram scripts, notes, correspondenceGeneralFolder 4036546199440Scope and ContentsNotes, request forms, correspondenceBazaarFolder 4136547199441Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, notesCorrespondenceFolder 4236549199442Scope and ContentsNotes, correspondenceMenus/FoodFolder 4336550199443Scope and ContentsRecipes, notesMailing ListFolder 4436551199444Scope and ContentsMailing ListExhibitsFolder 4536552199445Scope and ContentsRequest forms, notes, diagramsPrinting/DuplicatingFolder 4636553199446Scope and ContentsPrograms, postersTicketsFolder 4736554199447Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, notes, ticketsInternational FestivalFolder 4836555199348Scope and ContentsBudgets, invoices, notes, programsMenus/FoodFolder 4936556199349Scope and ContentsRecipesISA ArchivesFolder 5036557199350Scope and ContentsMeeting minutes, notes, correspondence, flyersGeneralFolder 5136558199351Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, request forms, notesBazaarFolder 5236559199352Scope and ContentsCatalogs, correspondence, notesCorrespondenceFolder 5336560199353Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, notesMailing ListFolder 5436561199354Scope and ContentsMailing ListPrinting/DuplicatingFolder 5536562199355Scope and ContentsRecipesExhibitsFolder 5636563199356Scope and ContentsNotesTicketsFolder 5736564199357Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, invoices, ticketsBox 2Box 236529PublicityFolder 5836565199358Scope and ContentsNewspaper clippings, programs, notes, program scriptBudgetFolder 5936566199359Scope and ContentsRequest forms, budgets, correspondence, notesEntertainmentFolder 6036567199360Scope and ContentsProgram, program script, notes, newspaper clippings, song lyrics, posters, purchase orders, request formsExhibits/EntertainmentFolder 6136470199261Scope and ContentsMeeting minutes, letters, notes, signsInternational BazaarFolder 6236471199262Scope and ContentsCatalogs, order forms, letters, notesPublicity/ProgramFolder 6336472199263Scope and ContentsPress releases, programs, lettersMenus/Food ListFolder 6436473199264Scope and ContentsMenus, recipes, meeting minutesGeneralFolder 6536474199265Scope and ContentsProgram scripts, request forms, diagrams, letters, notesCorrespondenceFolder 6636475199266Scope and ContentsLettersTicketsFolder 6736476199267Scope and ContentsTickets, lettersMailing ListFolder 6836477199268Scope and ContentsMailing listBudgetFolder 6936478199269Scope and ContentsFinancial statements, invoices, purchase orders, notes, postersInternational T-Shirt Order FormsFolder 7036501199270Scope and ContentsForms, notesCorrespondenceFolder 7136479199171Scope and ContentsLetters, notes, programsExhibits/Entertainment/BazaarFolder 7236480199172Scope and ContentsLetters, programs, music, catalogsRecipesFolder 7336481199173Scope and ContentsRecipesMenus/Food ListFolder 7436482199174Scope and ContentsRecipes, menus, programs, notesBox 3Box 336545PublicityFolder 7536483199175Scope and ContentsNewspaper clippings, press releases, posters, recipes, notesPrinting/Duplicating (Posters, Flyers)Folder 7636484199176Scope and ContentsTickets, notes, newspaper articles, flyers, diagrams, recipesTicketsFolder 7736485199177Scope and ContentsTickets, notesBudgetFolder 7836486199178Scope and ContentsFinancial statements, invoices, purchase orders, notesGeneralFolder 7936489199179Scope and ContentsLists, notes, correspondence, posterMenusFolder 8036487199080Scope and ContentsFood listsComplimentary TicketsFolder 8136488199081Scope and ContentsTickets, lists, lettersTicketsFolder 8236490199082Scope and ContentsTickets, notes, request formsBudgetFolder 8336491199083Scope and ContentsFinancial statements, invoices, purchase orders, notesLetters of Thanks to International Students and CommunityFolder 8436492199084Scope and ContentsLetters, lists, invoiceMailing ListFolder 8536493199085Scope and ContentsMailing ListPrograms and PublicityFolder 8636494199086Scope and ContentsPrograms, newspaper clippings, recipes, program scriptProgram CoverFolder 8736495199087Scope and ContentsPrograms, notes, listsGeneralFolder 8836496199088Scope and ContentsPrograms, notes, request formsExhibits/EntertainmentFolder 8936497199089Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, recipes, program scripts, request formsInternational FestivalFolder 9036498198890Scope and ContentsPrograms, flyers, invoices, notes, recipesInternational FestivalFolder 9136499198791Scope and ContentsPrograms, tickets, recipesInternational FestivalFolder 9236500198692Scope and ContentsPrograms, tickets, newspaper clippings, pictures, recipes, notes, postersInternational FestivalFolder 9336502198593Scope and ContentsProgramsInternational FestivalFolder 9436503198494Scope and ContentsPrograms, tickets, posterInternational FestivalFolder 9536504198395Scope and ContentsPrograms, program scripts, flyersInternational FestivalFolder 96365051979-198296Scope and ContentsPrograms, flyers, ticketsVideos, music, and photosBox 4819731993-2009Sangamon State University 1993 International Festival - musicAudiotape 1819771993International Festival, November 2002Videotape 181981UIS International Festival (Edited Version)Videotape 281985November 2, 2003UIS International Festival (unedited version)Videotape 381989November 2, 2003UIS International Festival (unedited version)Videotape 481993November 2, 2003UIS International FestivalVideotape 58199720043.5" floppy disc: International Festival mailing list (access database)Item 18200120041International Festival photosCD 182005200529th Annual International FestivalDVD 182009January 28, 200729th Annual International FestivalDVD 282013January 28, 20072008 UIS International Festival, "Highlights"DVD 382017November 16, 20082008 International FestivalDVD 482021January 27, 20082008 International FestivalDVD 582025January 27, 20083.5" floppy disc: various documents for planning 2008 International FestivalItem 282029200822009 UIS International FestivalDVD 682033October 25, 20092009 UIS International FestivalDVD 782037October 25, 2009International Festival, photosCD 2820412009Arabic music by Saudi production company Funoon Al JazeeraAudiotape 282045n. d.Arabic musicAudiotape 382049n. d.37th Annual International Festival PosterDrawer 2791192014

