<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.42/6Archon Finding Aid Title MC.42/6Sandra LongenUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:12:33 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC42/6. James Jones Literary Society Papers, 1978-2008
    
      James Jones Literary Society
    
    MC.42/6
    1715
    
      0.88 Cubic Feet
    
    1978-2008
    Date acquired: 00/00/2009
    1
    2
    Scrapbook
  
  
    Scope and Contents
James Jones Literary Society, founded in 1991, became a national organization devoted to promoting the general and academic interests in the literary works and life of Robinson, Illinois native - James Jones, author of From Here to Eternity,The Thin Red Line, and others.

This collection consists of the James Jones Literary Society records including board meeting minutes, membership rolls, event programs, newspaper articles, photographs of members and events, and copies of the James Jones Society Newsletter.
A scrapbook is included; it is oversized and unboxed but located with the boxed collection.  
  
    Letters
    Newspaper Clippings
    Correspondence
    Flyers/Brochures
    Minutes
    Agendas
    Workshop Materials
    Papers
    Photographs
    Newsletters
  
  ScrapbookItem 1486541Scope and ContentsPhotographs and Newspaper ArticlesBox 1Box 148625Board CommuniquesFolder 1486262000-20011Board EmailsFolder 24862720022Board EmailsFolder 34862820033Board CorrespondenceFolder 4486291997-20004Board CorrespondenceFolder 5486301992-19945Letters Sent RE: MembershipFolder 6486311993-956MinutesFolder 7486321996-20017HandoutsFolder 8486332000-20018Event in ParisFolder 948634June 20029Handouts, MinutesFolder 1048635200310Minutes, ReportsFolder 1148636200411Minutes, ReportsFolder 1248637200512RecordsFolder 1348638200613RecordsFolder 1448639200714Board Meeting &amp; Strategic Planning MeetingFolder 1548640October 200815Box 2Box 248641News Articles &amp; CorrespondenceFolder 14864219921News Articles &amp; CorrespondenceFolder 2486431992-942Membership Report and ListFolder 34864420003First Novel Fellowship WinnersFolder 4486451993-20014Business PapersFolder 5486461995-20015Membership Packet and Society MeetingFolder 6486491996-976Scope and ContentsIncludes membership listJames Jones Society NewsletterFolder 7486501993-947Scope and ContentsVol. 3, No. 1
Vol. 3, No. 2Robinson Argus newspaper articlesFolder 8486471993-948Scope and Contents1993-11-18 - Support for James Jones Society by Helen Howe
1994-10-13 - James Jones Symposium / Conference held in Robinson, IL
Also House Tour program in Marshall, IL (1994-10-09)Newspaper ArticlesFolder 9486481994-959Scope and ContentsFrom Tri-State, Robinson Argus, Robinson Daily News, Evansville CourierNewspaper and Magazine ArticlesFolder 10486511978-200710Scope and ContentsFrom The Robinson Argus, Robinson Daily News, Chicago Daily News (1978), Playboy Magazine article (1991)
Includes some photographs and copies of photographs of James JonesPhotographs (copies) and MiscellanousFolder 114865211Scope and ContentsIncludes some photographs and copies of photographs of James Jones, as well as a program from 1994 event - a tour of the home James Jones built when he was at the Handy ColonyNewspaper ArticleFolder 124865312Scope and ContentsUndated article titled, Symposium returns to focus on Jones's stories, from Robinson Daily NewsBoard of Directors MeetingFolder 135174311-10-200613Scope and ContentsIncludes brochure on the 16th annual James Jones Literary Society Symposium, held at Virginia Theatre, Champaign, IL, on this date.

