<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>K.05.01/05Archon Finding Aid Title K.05.01/05Sandra Longen &amp; Scott JohnsonUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:14:13 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    K5/1/5. Athletics &amp; Recreation Office Records &amp; Photographs
    
      Student Services
    
    K.05.01/05
    1713
    
      2.66 Cubic Feet
    
    1977-2007
    Date acquired: 07/05/2009
    1
    2
    3
    4
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The collection consists of documents, guides, and photographs pertaining to the SSU/UIS Athletic Department ranging from the 1970's into 2005.  The documents include but are not limited to: resolutions, sports guides, record books, NAIA eligibility certificates, brochures, news articles, statistics and score sheets.

The pictures in the collection consist of action photos from various university sport games and events, team photos, player profile pictures, coaching staff, and various candid pictures of the Athletic Department.  
The majority of the photographs in the collection are 4X6 colored photographs, with other pictures in black and white.  Some files also include photo negatives, photo CD's, and diskettes.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Photographs are in chronological order according to sport.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Scott Reed  
  Box 1Box 145259Project Manual for Recreational Building Addition at SSUFolder 1452601984-08-231Scope and ContentsBoard of Regents
Allied Design Consultants, Inc.House Joint Resolution 63: UIS Soccer 2nd place in National ChampionshipFolder 2452611987-04-302Guide: Celebration of the Elders Match between SSU and Purdue UniverstiyFolder 3452671981-09-203Soccer: The Umbero Senior BowlFolder 4452661992-934Scope and ContentsOfficial Tournament Program from the tournaments held at SSU in Springfield, ILWorld Collegiate Soccer Championships, 4th annualFolder 545265April 19875Scope and ContentsOfficial Program book, ticket, and program from tournament at Las Cruces, New MexicoWorld Collegiate Soccer Championships, 7th annualFolder 64527619906Scope and ContentsOfficial ProgramNAIA: Men's Soccer National ChampionshipFolder 745264November 19807Scope and ContentsOfficial Tournament Program, team rosters, tournament results at the Championship in Springfield, ILNAIA: Men's Soccer National ChampionshipFolder 845268November 19858Scope and ContentsOfficial Tournament Program at the University of South CarolinaNAIA: Men's Soccer National ChampionshipFolder 945263November 19889Scope and ContentsOfficial Tournament Program, team rosters, tournament results at the Championship in Ft. Lauderdale, FLNAIA: Men's Soccer National ChampionshipFolder 1045269November 198910Scope and ContentsOfficial Tournament Program at Las Cruces, New MexicoNAIA: Men's Soccer National ChampionshipFolder 1145270November 199411Scope and ContentsOfficial Tournament Program at the University of MobileNAIA: Men's Soccer National ChampionshipFolder 1245271November 199612Scope and ContentsOfficial Tournament Program at Birmingham, ALNAIA: Men's Soccer National ChampionshipFolder 1345262November 199713Scope and ContentsNews Releases as well as team and individual statistics at the championship in Birmingham, ALNAIA: Men's Soccer National ChampionshipFolder 1445272November 199814Scope and ContentsOfficial Tournament Program at the championship in Birmingham, ALNAIA: Men's Soccer National ChampionshipFolder 1545273November 199915Scope and ContentsOfficial Tournament Program at the championship in Albuquerque, New MexicoNAIA: Men's Soccer National ChampionshipFolder 1645274November 200016Scope and ContentsOfficial Tournament Program at the championship in Albuquerque, New MexicoNAIA: Men's Soccer National ChampionshipFolder 1745275November 200217Scope and ContentsOfficial Tournament Program at the championship in Bowling Green, KYNAIA Fall Sports Media GuideFolder 1845277199718NAIA Winter Sports Media GuideFolder 19452781997-9819NAIA Spring Sports Media GuideFolder 2045279199820NAIA Winter Sports Media GuideFolder 21452801998-9921NAIA Spring Sports Media GuideFolder 2245281199922NAIA Fall Sports Media GuideFolder 2345282199923NAIA Winter Sports Media GuideFolder 24452831999-200024NAIA Spring Sports Media GuideFolder 2545284200025NAIA Fall Sports Media GuideFolder 2645285200026NAIA Winter Sports Media GuideFolder 27452862001-200227NAIA Senior Bowl 2nd AnnualFolder 28452871990-04-2228Scope and ContentsOfficial Tournament Program from the tournament in Las Cruces, New MexicoNAIA Basketball Championships History and Records BookFolder 2945288199729NAIA Division II Women's Basketball National TournamentFolder 3045289199830Scope and ContentsOfficial Tournament Program from Sioux City, IANAIA Champions of Character Report &amp; Enhancement MaterialsFolder 31452902000-200231NAIA Sports Information Directors ManualFolder 32452912002-200332Soccer America, Volume 13 No. 24Folder 33452921977-12-1333Scope and ContentsArticle: Sangamon's Soccer Formula adds up to Success by Dale ColemanSoccer America, Vol. 31 No. 26 &amp; Vol. 32 No. 2Folder 34452931986-12-18 and 1987-01-2234Tennis USTA (Supplement to Tennis magazine)Folder 3545301August 199435Scope and ContentsArticle about Don Giacomini, SSU Girls Tennis coach entitled Longetime Player/Coach Relationship Bears FruitNAIA Eligibility Certificate - Women's VolleyballFolder 36452941989-200236NAIA Eligibility Certificate - Women's BasketballFolder 37452951995-20037SSU/UIS Sports News ClippingsFolder 38452961986-200438Aydin Gonulson Retirement BrochureFolder 3945297200139American Midwest Conference Constitution and BylawsFolder 40452982006-0740Women's Basketball Season Roster &amp; BrochureFolder 41452991998-200141Sport AwardsFolder 42453001983, 1988, 199442Scope and Contents1983 - SSU Soccer champion of the NAIA District 20
1988 - SR 1420 honoring SSU soccer team for winning the NAIA National Soccer Championship
1994 - SSU Soccer players picked as Grand Marshals of IL State Fair ParadeDom Giacomini article in Tennis USTAFolder 4345302August 199443Scope and ContentsArticle about Dom Giacomini, SSU Tennis Coach, in Tennis USTA (Supplement to Tennis magazine) entitled Longtime Player/Coach Relationship Bears FruitDom Giacomini RetirementFolder 4445303May 200744Scope and ContentsLetter of retirement by long-time SSU tennis coachTennis - Women &amp; MenFolder 45462982003-200445Tennis - WomenFolder 46462992003-200546Women's Basketball Score SheetsFolder 47463002000-200147Year by Year Men's Soccer vs All OpponentsFolder 48463011977-199648UIS Athletics - Student Athlete Information Form &amp; Player Release LettersFolder 49463022000-200249NAIA Eligibility Certificates - Men's SoccerFolder 5046303200150NAIA Verification of Academic StandingFolder 5146304199951CREW System for Basketball StatisticsFolder 5246305199852Soccer Score SheetFolder 53463061996 Season53Soccer Schedule and RosterFolder 5446307198954Academic All-American StatisticsFolder 5546308199755NAIA Documents for UIS SportsFolder 56463091997-200256UIS Coach InformationFolder 57463102003-200557Scope and ContentsJoe Fisher
Paul MacDonnaPrairie Stars and Surrounding Area SchoolsFolder 584631158Thank You cards and Post cardsFolder 594631259Correspondence, Receipts and FormsFolder 60463132001-200760CREW softwareFolder 614631461Focus on Capital Scholars (includes Athletics information)Folder 6246992200062CD-ROM: Correspondence, photos, rosters, team statistics, etc.(Digital formats)Folder 63465212001-200663Scope and ContentsFiles copied from 3 1/2" floppies to CD. MS Word, Excel, HTML formats.Box 2Box 246165UIS Athletics Administration and Staff PhotosFolder 1461661UIS Athletics with Bill Cosby PhotosFolder 2461672UIS Athletics Recruitment Signing PhotosFolder 34616820033UIS Special Events Photos and TicketsFolder 4461694Scope and ContentsEvents include but are not limited to "Walk/Run for Women's Athletics," Awards Ceremonies, and youth soccer campUIS Athletics Sponsor Signs and BillboardsFolder 5461705UIS Athletics Unidentified Photos and NegativesFolder 6461716Scope and ContentsAssorted pictures and negatives of unnamed athletes and staff of UIS AthleticsUIS Men's Basketball Photos, UIS vs. Goshen CollegeFolder 74617211/01/20027UIS Men's Basketball Photos, UIS Vs. Cardinal StritchFolder 84617311/09/20028UIS Men's Basketball Photos, UIS vs. Oakland CityFolder 94617401-06-20039UIS Men's Basketball Photos, Coach Kevin Gamble - Operation SnowflakeFolder 1046175200310UIS Men's Basketball PhotosFolder 11461762003-200411UIS Men's Basketball PhotodFolder 12463152006-200712Scope and ContentsCDUIS Men's Basketball, undated photos/ ticketsFolder 134617713SSU Soccer CampFolder 1446178Circa 1977-7814Scope and ContentsPictures of SSU Youth Soccer CampSSU Men's Soccer PhotosFolder 15461791992-199315Scope and ContentsAssorted Pictures of the 1992-1993 season. Pictures include: Mike Hanson, B.J. Moore, Rene Montero, Jerod Fry, Bora Esenlet, as well as others.UIS Men's Soccer PhotosFolder 1646180199416UIS Men's Soccer, 1996-1997 NAIA National Championship TournamentsFolder 17461811996-199717Scope and ContentsPictures associated with UIS going to the NAIA National Championship Tournament in both 1996 and 1997. Pictures include: Scott Bork, Milt Tennant, Bob Kellum, as well as others.UIS Men's Soccer PhotosFolder 1846182199818UIS Men's Soccer PhotosFolder 1946183199919UIS Men's Soccer PhotosFolder 2046184200020UIS Men's Soccer PhotosFolder 2146185200321Scope and ContentsPictures associated with the 2003 season.  Pictures include: Ryan Raschke, Daniel Flynn, Javid Ferguson, Mercio Lora, Yonas Kutlu, Berk Guler, Ross Pagliara, Andres Barcenas, Zach Hoette, Ryan Leach, Paul Pianezza, Andy Simmons, Curt Miller, Alexander Cruz, Todd Pierce, Marcus Rodriguez, Ivec Halic, Jamie Doerfler, as well as others.UIS Men's Soccer Photos, Coaching Staff and Assorted Player ProfilesFolder 22461861986-199922Scope and ContentsPhotos of coaching staff: Aydin Gonulsen, Joe Eck, Milt Tennant, and Naomi Lynn (SSU President).  Photos of players include: Bob Kellum, Jason Vleck, Rob Fox, Doug Curtner, Jamie Hemingway, Alfonso Donyen, Gurel Turkel, Chad Formeg, Cory Formeg, Denis Dergelev, Jose Corona, Rene Montero, Russ Bagdanovich, and Chris OwsleyUIS Men's Soccer Action PhotosFolder 234618723Scope and ContentsAction Photos from various undated gamesUIS Men's Soccer Action PhotosFolder 244618824Scope and ContentsAction photos taken from various undated UIS men's soccer gamesUIS Men's Soccer Photos, Assorted Pictures/TicketsFolder 254618925Scope and ContentsAssorted unnamed and undated pictures concerning UIS men's soccer.UIS Men's Soccer Film NegativesFolder 264619026UIS Men's Tennis Photos, The San-San Tennis CupFolder 2746191199227Scope and ContentsPictures taken of SSU's Men's Tennis Participation in the 'San-San Tennis Cup" held in Mexico in 1992SSU TennisFolder 2880222July 199328UIS Men's Tennis Photos, Men's RegionalFolder 2946192199829Scope and ContentsPictures of UIS Tennis during the 1998 Spring RegionalsUIS Men's Tennis PhotosFolder 3046193200230UIS Men's TennisFolder 3146194200331UIS Men's Tennis, Coach Manny VelascoFolder 324619532Scope and ContentsAssorted pictures of Coach Manny VelascoSSU/UIS Men's Tennis Photos, undatedFolder 334619633Scope and ContentsUndated photos associated with Men's TennisUIS Men's Tennis Photos, UndatedFolder 344619734Scope and ContentsUndated/ Unnnamed Tennis Photos Assocaited with UIS Men's TennisUIS Men's Tennis Photos, UndatedFolder 354619835Scope and ContentsUndated/ Unnnamed Tennis Photos Assocaited with UIS Men's TennisBox 3Box 346199UIS Women's Basketball Photos, Alumni GameFolder 14620020031UIS Women's Basketball, UIS vs. ColumbiaFolder 2462012UIS Women's Basketball Photos, UIS vs. BenedictineFolder 3462023UIS Women's Basketball Action PhotosFolder 4462034Scope and ContentsAction pictures taken of the UIS women's Basketball team from 1995-2004UIS Women's Basketball Team PhotosFolder 5462045Scope and ContentsTeams photos and profile pictures taken from 1995 to 2004 of teams fielded by UIS.  The 2004 profile pictures include: Audrone Sulskyte, Tamika Reeves, Melanie Cain, LaToya Jackson, Myeshia Jones, Ashley Barton, Chikayla Moss, Kelly Beyer, Jessica Lay, Zabrina Harper, and Nicole Elkins.UIS Women's Basketball Photos, Event at Springfield Urban LeagueFolder 6462056Scope and ContentsEvent took place while Wanda Nettles was the coach of the UIS Women's Basketball team.UIS Women's Basketball Assorted PhotosFolder 7462067Scope and ContentsVarious unnamed and undated photos concerning the UIS women's backetball teamUIS Women's Basketball Photo CDs and NegativesFolder 8462078UIS Women's Softball PhotosFolder 9462082003-20049Scope and ContentsPictures include: Angela Becker, Kayla Moss, Sara Abu-Tayeh, Rebekah Bandy, Katie McBride, Katie Kuschell, Grazia Silvestro, Laura Fager, Candace Welch, as well as others.UIS Women's Softball, UndatedFolder 104620910Scope and ContentsCd and DisketteSSU Recreational SoftballFolder 1146210Circa 1970's11Box 4Box 446211SSU Women's Tennis PhotosFolder 14621219841UIS Women's Tennis PhotosFolder 2462131993-19942UIS Women's Tennis PhotosFolder 34621419953UIS Women's Tennis PhotosFolder 4462151998-19994UIS Women's Tennis PhotosFolder 54621620035Scope and ContentsPictures include: Christine Tabayoyong, Georgina Wulfers, Katie Popp, Jennifer Poss, Samantha Drews, Nicole Frkol, Criss Cuervo, Anna Dow, Erin SibleyUIS Women's Tennis Photos, Undated SeasonFolder 6462176Scope and ContentsPictures focusing on a single undated season of UIS Women's Tennis.UIS Women's Tennis Photos, UndatedFolder 7462187Scope and ContentsAssorted undated/ unnamed photos associated with UIS Women's TennisSSU Women's Volleyball PhotosFolder 8462191993-19948UIS Women's Volleyball PhotosFolder 9462201994-19959UIS Women's Volleyball PhotosFolder 10462211995-199710UIS Women's Volleyball PhotosFolder 11462221998-199911UIS Women's Volleyball PhotosFolder 12462232000-200112Scope and ContentsPictures include: Sarah Henkelman, Lori Claybraugh, Kristie Henkelman, Jayne Schulte, Eva Becker, Jenni Sergent, Marcelle Merchat, Amanda Starman, Jill Stinebaker, Jackie Adkins, Jamie Miller, Kristen Knapp.UIS Women's Volleyball PhotosFolder 1346224200213UIS Women's Volleyball PhotosFolder 1446225200314Scope and ContentsPhotos include: Abby Kuntz, Chris Burton, Carrie Bauer, Chrisa Potthast, Sarah Stratton, Megan Leonard, Ashley Crow, Lindsey Lambrecht, Ashley Wade, Audra Roach, Maria RayUIS Women's Volleyball Photos, UndatedFolder 154622615Scope and ContentsAssorted undated/unnamed pictures associated with the SSU/UIS Women's Volleyball team

