<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>P.TownsendArchon Finding Aid Title P.TownsendRochelle M. Joseph; Chris SchnellUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:15:35 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    P/Townsend. Mike Townsend, Personal Papers
    
      Townsend, Mike (Townsend, Michael Patrick)
    
    P.Townsend
    1739
    
      1.16 Cubic Feet
    
    1955-2013
    1979-1995
    Date acquired: 05/15/2009
    1
    2
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This series contains personal correspondence, memos, course materials, lecture notes, syllabuses, student papers and examinations, press releases, sociology articles, photographs, videotape and audiocassette recordings. This collection also contains material from the Chicago Area Project, the nation's first community-based delinquency prevention program; Ron Sakolsky's Free Speech Case; United Students for Africa; Citizens Against Prostitution, a Springfield-based community organization; and The Alternative, a student newspaper. Of special interest are the collected articles, early publications and correspondence composed by Dr. Sidney M. Willhelm, a Political Science Professor in the Department of Sociology at the State University of New York, Buffalo, regarding racism.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Mike Townsend  
  
    Accruals and Additions
05/27/2009, 06/09/2010, 10/3/2013.  
  
    Custodial History
A number of additions (box 2) were collected piecemeal and added to the collection at one time. Chris Schnell 7/24/2017.  
  
    Papers
    Audio Tapes
    Photographs
    Videotapes
  
  Box 1Box 151107Correspondence and News Clippings, Chicago Area/Quincy Area ProjectFolder 1511081983-11-16 - 1990-02-081Scope and ContentsIncludes Chicago Area Project booklet about the nation's first community-based delinquency prevention program.Quincy Neighborhood Committee/Federation Newsletters, Chicago Area/Quincy Area ProjectFolder 2511091983-19902Articles on Juvenile Delinquency and Behavior, Chicago Area/Quincy Area ProjectFolder 3511101955-19853Cressey, Donald R.  Changing Criminals:  The Application of the Theory of Differential AssociationItem 1511111955-0931Scope and ContentsPublished in the American Journal of Sociology, Vol. 61.McKay, Henry D.  Basic Considerations in Delinquency PreventionItem 2511131959-0432Summary of Social Factors in Juvenile Delinquency, Illinois Youth Commission Division of Community Services and Chicago Area ProjectItem 3511121959-1133Kobrin, Sol.  Sociological and Cultural Foundations of the Youth Employment ProblemItem 4511141961-02-2434McKay, Henry D.  Research Bulletins, Department of Research Institute for Juvenile Research:  Social Influences on Adolescent BehaviorItem 5511151962-0635Scope and ContentsPublished by State of Illinois, Department of Mental Health, Vol. 1, No. 2 (2 copies).Bolosky, W. A.   Position Paper:  Casework is Limited in Working with DelinquentsItem 6511161964-04-0936Scope and ContentsWest Virginia University, Department of Social Work, SW 361 Seminar.Cressey, Donald R.   Organized Crime and Inner-City Youth, ndItem 75111737Liazos, Alexander.  Class Oppression:  The Functions of Juvenile Justice, ndItem 85111838Scope and ContentsRegis College.Turbak, Gary.  Children in Jail:  A Shocking CrimeItem 9511191985-0139Scope and ContentsPublished in Kiwanis Magazine/January 1985.Knoepple, Peg.  Oral History Transcript of George Parsons InterviewFolder 4511201988-11-054Scope and ContentsChicago Area/Quincy Area Project.Student PapersFolder 5511211979-19845Kubota, Eiko.  The State Journal-RegisterItem 1511221979-12-1751Scope and ContentsPAC 444.Brookens, Brenda and McCall, Mary.  WICS, Channel 20 Research PaperItem 2511231979-12-1952Scope and ContentsSocial Change and Alternative Media.Murray, Kevin G.  The Black Power Structure in SpringfieldItem 4511251983-01-0154Mahoney, Mary Beth.  Eastside Politics:  Blacks in the City of SpringfieldItem 551126Fall 198455Scope and ContentsCFC 492 - Community Outreach.Syllabus and Student Papers, PAC 417, Cities and the PoorFolder 6511281980-19816SyllabusItem 151129Summer 198061Khosho, Fadhic.  Untitled Reaction PaperItem 25113062Collins, Mary.  Reaction Paper to Summer of Rage:  The Springfield Race Riot of 1908 by James Krohe, Jr.Item 351131Summer 198063McGlennon, Barb.  Reaction Paper to Summer of Rage:  The Springfield Race Riot of 1908 by James Krohe, Jr.Item 451132Summer 198064Burgio, Charles.  Reaction PapersItem 5511331980-07-2265Strohan, Gary.  Reaction Paper to Summer of Rage: The Springfield Race Riot of 1908 by James Krohe, Jr., ndItem 65113466Strohan, Gary.  Welfare in America, ndItem 75113567Budin, Razidah.  Reaction Paper to Summer of Rage: The Springfield Race Riot of 1908 by James Krohe, Jr.Item 8511361980-07-1868Holmes, James.  Reaction Paper to Summer of Rage: The Springfield Race Riot by James Krohe, Jr., ndItem 95113769Dale, Lillie Mae.  Reaction Paper to Summer of Rage: The Springfield Race Riot by James Krohe, Jr., ndItem 1051138610Dangpradub, Wijitra.  Reaction Paper to Summer of Rage: The Springfield Race Riot by James Krohe, Jr., ndItem 1151139611Buins, Robin.  Reaction Paper to Summer of Rage: The Springfield Race Riot by James Krohe, Jr., ndItem 1251140612Khosho, Fadhic.  Reaction Paper to Summer of Rage: The Springfield Race Riot by James Krohe, Jr., ndItem 1351141613Mulrooney, Mary.  Reaction Paper to Summer of Rage: The Springfield Race Riot by James Krohe, Jr.Item 14511421980-06-16614Rawlings, Barbara.  Reaction Paper to Summer of Rage: The Springfield Race Riot by James Krohe, Jr., ndItem 1551143615O'Brien, Mary.  Reaction Paper to Summer of Rage: The Springfield Race Riot by James Krohe, Jr., ndItem 1651144616Sczurko, Margie.  Reaction Paper to Summer of Rage: The Springfield Race Riot by James Krohe, Jr., ndItem 1751145617Wyatt, Debbie.  Reaction Paper to Summer of Rage: The Springfield Race Riot by James Krohe, Jr.Item 1851146Summer 1980618Muncy, Dolores.  The Trip to Chicago for class, Cities and the Poor, ndItem 1951127619Stevens, Alusaine.  Economics of Racism U.S.A.:  A Reaction Paper on the Roots of Black Inequality by Victor Perlo, ndItem 2051147620Kerwin, David.  Chicago Trip Reaction Paper Number TwoItem 21511241981-07-19621Time Magazine, "The American Underclass: Destitute and desparate in the land of plenty"Item 22511481977-08-29622Syllabus and Lecture Notes, CFC 506, History and Philosophy of Social WorkFolder 751149Spring 19827Syllabus and Lecture Notes, CFC 576, Community Organization: Theory and ModelsFolder 851151Spring 19858Syllabus, CFC 447, Streetwork with AdolescentsFolder 951152Fall 19859Syllabus and Lecture Notes, CFC 513, Social Action and the Helping ProfessionsFolder 1051153Spring 199010Professional Training Series No. 1, Human Rights and Social Work: A Manual for Schools of Social Work and the Social Work ProfessionFolder 1151154199411Scope and ContentsCentre for Human Rights, Geneva (United Nations, New York and Geneva, 1994) drafted by Terry Bamford, Paul Dolan, Eilis Envall, Nigel Hall, Harriet Jakobsson, Vera D. Mehta, Maria Lorena Molina-Molina, Ellen Mouravieff-Apostol, Evelyne Serrano-Balais, and Dorothy Van Soest.Syllabus and Responses to Student Reaction Papers re: Savage Inequalities by Jonathan Kozol, CFC 513, Social Action and the Helping ProfessionsFolder 1251155200012Johnson, Nancy K. and Tucker, Suella I.  The Impact of the Policies of the German National Socialists' Party on the Role of the Social WorkerFolder 13511562000-0713Scope and ContentsStudent Master's Project.Student Papers and Class Notes, SWK 420, Social WorkFolder 1451157200414Hunt, Renee.  Class notes for SWK 420, ndItem 151158141Harvill, Amy.  Reaction Paper to "Toward an American Revolution" by Gerald John Fresia, ndItem 251159142Lanier, Heidi.  "Toward an American Revolution" by Gerald John Fresia, ndItem 351160143Lewis, Dara.  "Toward an American Revolution" by Gerald John Fresia, ndItem 451161144Miller, Laura.  "Toward an American Revolution" by Gerald John Fresia, ndItem 551162145Newberry, Rhonda.  "Toward an American Revolution" by Gerald John Fresia, ndItem 651163146Porter, Debbie.  "Toward an American Revolution" by Gerald John Fresia, ndItem 751164147Smith, Perry.  "Toward an American Revolution" by Gerald John Fresia, ndItem 851165148Smith, Larry.  "Toward an American Revolution" by Gerald John FresiaItem 9511662004-04-28149Wells, Wendy.  "Toward an American Revolution" by Gerald John Fresia, ndItem 10511671410Kuschell, Katie.  Teenage Mothers on WelfareItem 11511682004-05-051411Informational biographical brochure re: Jerry Fresia, ndItem 12511691412Social Work Club (UIS), Minutes, Correspondence, Agendas, Roster, Flyers, By-Laws and NewsletterFolder 15511702000-200315Student Paper, HMS 501Folder 1651171Spring 200416Scope and ContentsMiller, Laura Anne.  Untitled manuscript.Social Work Club (UIS), Minutes, Meetings, and Email CorrespondenceFolder 17511722005-08/0917Scope and ContentsContains email sign-up sheets from SWK classes for hurricane relief aid.Sidney M. Willhelm, Publications and ArticlesFolder 18511821958-196918The Social Characteristics of EntertainersItem 1511831958-10181Scope and ContentsCo-author Gideon Sjoberg.  Reprinted from Social Forces, Vol. 37, No. 1, October 1985, pp 71-76.Economic vs. Protective Values in Urban Land Use ChangeItem 2511841960-01182Scope and ContentsCo-author G. Sjoberg.  Published in The American Journal of Economics and Sociology, Vol. 19, No. 2, pp 151-160.Concept of the 'Ecological Complex'Item 3511851964-07183Scope and ContentsPublished in The American Journal of Economics and Sociology, Vol. 23, No. 3, pp 241-248.Elites, Scholars, and SociologistsItem 451186Summer 1966184Scope and ContentsReprinted from Catalyst No. 2 (Summer 1966), pp 1-10.Reformulation of Social Action TheoryItem 5511871967-01185Scope and ContentsPublished in The American Journal of Economics and Sociology, Vol. 26, No. 1, pp 23-32.Red Man, Black Man and White AmericaItem 651188Spring 1969186Scope and ContentsPublished in Catalyst, Number Four, pp 1-62.Red Man, Black Man and White AmericaItem 7511891973187Scope and ContentsPublished by Reprint 166 (A Warner Modular Publication) with permission from Catalyst, Spring 1969, Number Four, pp 1-62.Sidney M. Willhelm, Publications and ArticlesFolder 19511731977-198719The Rise of State Rule:  An Exploratory and Interpretative EssayItem 1511741977191Scope and ContentsPublished in Catalyst (Trent University), Number 9, Issue Theme: "State and Capital", pp 1-58.Can Marxism Explain America's Racism?Item 2511751980-12192Scope and ContentsPublished in Social Problems, Official Journal of the Society for the Study of Social Problems, Vol. 28, No. 2, pp 98-112.Black-White Equality: An Economic Doctrine for White Supremacy, Part IItem 3511761981193Scope and ContentsPublished in Journal of Black Studies (Sage Publications), Vol. 12, No. 2, December 1981, pp 142-165.The Supreme Court:  A Citadel for White SupremacyItem 4511771981-03194Scope and ContentsWillhelm's review of Derrick A. Bell, Jr.'s, "Race, Racism and American Law", published in the Michigan Law Review, March 1981, Vol. 79, No. 4, pp 847-855.Black/White Equality:  The Socioeconomic Conditions of Blacks in America, Part IIItem 5511781983-12195Scope and ContentsPublished in Journal of Black Studies (Sage Publications), Vol. 14, No. 2, pp 151-184.IntroductionItem 6511791986-12196Scope and ContentsPublished in Journal of Black Studies (Sage Publications), Vol. 17, No. 2, pp 139-147.The Economic Demise of Blacks in America: A Prelude to Genocide?Item 7511801987197Scope and ContentsOriginally published in Journal of Black Studies (Sage Publications), Vol. 17, No. 2, pp 201-254.Sidney M. Willhelm, Commemorative Lecture, "Race in America Today:  A Tribute to Sidney Willhelm"Folder 20511811989-12-820Scope and ContentsIncludes Willhelm's Vitae and Bob Blauner's Draft of Buffalo Talk on Sidney Willhelm.Sidney M. Willhelm, Publications and ArticlesFolder 2151190199221Racism and America's Rapacious EliteItem 1511911992211Scope and ContentsReview of Andrew Hacker's "Two Nations:  Black and White, Separate, Hostile, Unequal" (Charles Scribner &amp; Sons, 1992), pp 1-18.Black in a White AmericaItem 251192212Scope and ContentsDraft.Sidney M. Willhelm, Correspondence and News ArticlesFolder 22511931992-03-26 - 12-0422Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 1511941992-03-26221Letter from Mike Townsend to Sidney WillhelmItem 2511951992-04-17222Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 3511961992-05-05223Starr, John R.  "No real solutions offered as Los Angeles smolders", AR Democrat GazetteItem 4511971992-05-05224Letter from Mike Townsend to Sidney WillhelmItem 5511981992-05-15225Purchase Order, Sangamon State University Board of Regents, to Sidney WillhelmItem 6511991992-05-18226Scope and ContentsRe: Serving as presenter for meeting with students and faculty on June 4 and 5, 1992, includes a draft of Mr. Willhelm's presentation.Davis, Mike.  "Urban America Sees its Future:  In L.A., Burning all Illusions", The NationItem 7512001992-06-01227Memorandum from Mike Townsend to Students, Colleagues and Community FriendsItem 8512011992-06228Scope and ContentsRe: Lecture and Discussion Session "From L.A. to John Hay: The Black Counterattack Against Genocide" featuring Professor and Author Sidney Willhelm and Human Rights Activist Mbanna Kantako.Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 9512021992-07-01229"From L.A. to John Hay", Illinois TimesItem 10512031992-07-16 - 07-222210Scope and ContentsTelevision Cable Access Channel 4 to air video of Willhelm's and Kantako's recent lecture at SSU on 7/18 and 7/24.Letter from Mike Townsend to C. Hunter-Gault of the MacNeil/Lehrer NewshourItem 11512051992-07-272211Letter to Mike Townsend from Charlayne Hunter-Gault of the MacNeil/Lehrer NewshourItem 12512041992-09-302212Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 13512061992-08-282213Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 14512071992-09-092214Anderson, Jack.  "Low interest rates robbing savers", AR Democrat GazetteItem 15512081992-09-292215Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 16512091992-09-142216Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 17512101992-10-032217Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 18512111992-10-152218Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 19512121992-11-062219Scope and ContentsIncluding two news articles, "In Omaha, the Other Shoe Drops on Job Creation" by Frank Swoboda, and "Connecting the Wires for Technology: Which philosophy is best suited for our future?" by Dan Southerland, both printed in the Washington Post National Weekly Edition, 11/2-8-1992.Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 20512131992-11-072220Scope and ContentsIncludes an Order Form for items from Black Liberation Radio.Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 21512141992-11-092221Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 22512151992-11-132222Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Derrick ?Item 23512161992-12-032223Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 24512171992-12-042224Sidney M. Willhelm, Correspondence and News ArticlesFolder 23512181993-01-18 - 12-0923Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 1512191993-01-18231Scope and ContentsIncludes a copy of JoAnn Wypijewski's news article in The Nation, 12/21/92.Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 2512201993-02-13232Scope and ContentsIncludes several news articles and a political cartoon.Letter from Mike Townsend to Sidney WillhelmItem 3512211993-03-05233Childs, John Brown.  Toward Trans-Communality, the Highest Stage of Multiculturalism:  Notes on the Future of African-AmericansItem 451222Spring - Summer 1993234Scope and ContentsPublished in Social Justice, Vol. 20, Nos. 1-2, pp 35-51.Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 5512231993-03-16235Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 6512241993-04-18236Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 7512251993-04-23237Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 8512261993-05-01238Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 9512271993-05-26239Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 10512281993-08-042310Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 11512291993-10-202311Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 12512301993-11-092312Scope and ContentsIncludes various news articles.Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 13512311993-12-012313Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 14512321993-12-092314Sidney M. Willhelm, Correspondence and News ArticlesFolder 24512331994-01-19 - 1998-03-1624Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Professor John Brown Childs, Dept. of Sociology, University of CaliforniaItem 1512341994-01-19241Letter from Mike Townsend to Sidney WillhelmItem 2512351994-03-31242Scope and ContentsIncludes "Extra!" Press Release flyer.Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 3512361994-06-28243Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 4512371994244Scope and ContentsIncludes various news articles.Letter from Mike Townsend to Sidney WillhelmItem 5512381995-01-12245Letter from Mike Townsend to Sidney WillhelmItem 6512391995-03-12246Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 7512401995-04-05247Letter from Mike Townsend and Mbanna Kantako to Ms. Lynn Lu and the Editorial Collective, South End Press, Boston, MAItem 8512411996-01-04248Scope and ContentsRe: Requesting that Ms. Lu publish Dr. Sidney Willhelm's new manuscript entitled "Racial Separation in an Equal America".Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 9512421997-03-18249Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 10512431997-04-172410Scope and ContentsIncludes copy of the cover Willhelm's "Who Needs the Negro?" book.Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 11512441997-05-132411Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 12512451997-05-262412Letter from Sidney Willhelm to Mike TownsendItem 13512461997-05-262413Scope and ContentsRe: A P.S. letter Willhelm wrote to another friend.Letter from Mike Townsend to Sidney WillhelmItem 14512471998-03-162414School District #186 Desegregation LawsuitFolder 25512481973-198125Carstens, Caryl.  "School Integration Gets Attention of Committee", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 1512491973-02-24251Long, Joanne.  "Lawyer sees no objection to crosstown busing now", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 2512501974-08-08252Long, Joanne.  "Palmer School closing", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 3512511975-12-02253Long, Joanne.  "City gets extension to comply with state desegregation rules", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 4512521976-04-08254News articles, "District 186 desegregation deliberations start next week" and "Integration suit cost schools $33,817", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 5512531976-04-16255News articles, "Board files integration plan" and "Wood won't rule in desegregation suit", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 6512541976-06-05 and 05-26256Long, Joanne.  "Board attitude better on integration-expert", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 7512551976-07-27257Summary of the Court in Case S-Civ-74-44Item 8512561976-12-07258Scope and ContentsResidents v. School District #186, Springfield, IL; The Board of Education, School District #186, Springfield, Illinois, et al."Linda Brown goes back to court", Civil LibertiesItem 9512571980-02259Newsletter from Illinois Education AssociationItem 10512581981-07-102510Newsletter from Illinois Education AssociationItem 11512591981-07/152511Singleton Ruling Summary, U.S. Federal Court, Jackson, MississippiItem 1251260ca. 19702512Political handbill, "Who Speaks for You?", ndItem 13512612513Scope and ContentsRe: Supporting the proposition to change School Board Elections."The Alternative", Student newspaperFolder 26512621989-199126Announcement, Constitution and By-LawsItem 1512631989-10-07261The Alternative: Headlines you can Remember!Item 2512641989-11-25262Scope and ContentsVol. 1, Issue #1The Alternative: Headlines you can Remember!Item 3512651989-12-10263Scope and ContentsVol. 1, Issue #2The Alternative: Headlines you can Remember!Item 4512661990-02-20264Scope and ContentsVol. 2, Issue #1The Alternative: Headlines you can Remember!Item 5512671990-03-20265Scope and ContentsVol. 2, Issue #2The Alternative: Headlines you can Remember!Item 6512681990-04-20266Scope and ContentsVol. 2, Issue #3The Alternative: We Print What you SayItem 7512691991-02267Scope and ContentsVol. 3, Issue #2The AlternativeItem 8512701991-09268Scope and ContentsVol. 3, Issue #5The AlternativeItem 9512711991-10/11269Scope and ContentsVol. 3, Issue #6Booklets of programs sponsored by Sangamon State UniversityFolder 275127227Scope and ContentsStudies in Social Change booklet, Individual Option Program, and "Cope:  A Child Advocacy Program" outline.Miscellaneous Lecture Notes, ndFolder 285127328Miscellaneous Articles and Publications used in various classesFolder 29512741975-200329Gelper, Jeffry.  Social Welfare in Capitalist Society: A Socialist AnalysisItem 1512751979291Scope and ContentsThis article, printed in Catalyst, was later revised and published in Jeffry Galper's book entitled "Social Work Practice: A Radical Perspective", Prentice-Hall Inc., 1979.De Maria, Dr. William.  Alive on the Street, Dead in the Classroom:  The Return of Radical Social Work and the Manufacture of Activism, ndItem 251276ca. 1990292Scope and ContentsPublished in Journal of Sociology &amp; Social Welfare, Vol. ?, No. ?, pp 137-158.Moore, Richard K.  Beyond Left &amp; Right: Escaping the MatrixItem 3512772000-09-16293Scope and ContentsArticle published in New Dawn magazine, a journal of Alternative News &amp; Information.
Printed from www.newdawnmagazine.com.au.Swift, Deanna.  Globalization: Leaked Memo Reveals WTO PlanItem 4512782001-07-23294Scope and ContentsPrinted from http://schoolsnotjails.com.Pilger, John.  Hidden Agenda Behind War on TerrorItem 5512792001-10-29295Scope and ContentsArticle from Mirror.co.uk.
Printed from http://mirror.icnetwork.co.uk.McMurty, John.  The FTAA and the WTO:  The Meta-Program for Global Corporate Rule, ndItem 651280ca. 2001296Scope and ContentsPublisher unknown.Monthly Review, an Independent Socialist Magazine, "Terror Crisis in Context"Item 7512812001-11297Scope and ContentsVol. 53, No. 6, pp 1-27.Sklar, Holly.  Imagine a Country - Life in the new milleniumItem 8512822003-05298Scope and ContentsCrossCurrents section, Z Magazine.Correspondence, News Articles and EmailsFolder 30512831976-03-30 - 200530United Students for Africa, Correspondence, Project Funded Programs, Reports and ActivitiesFolder 31512841993-199631United Students for Africa, Photographs, undatedFolder 325128532Scope and ContentsPhotographs are labeled on back.Correspondence, News Articles, and Policies re: Ron Sakolsky's Free Speech CaseFolder 3351286199533Bush, Bill.  "Curran on offensive in debate:  Hasara says it's because he's behind", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 1512891995-03-16331"Campus Free Speech Action Alert!" from Dennis FoxItem 251290ca. 1995332Faculty Senate Meeting AY 94/95 MinutesItem 3512911995-03-24333Faculty Senate Meeting AY 94/95 MinutesItem 4512921995-04-07334Faculty Senate Resolution 24-5, DraftItem 5512931995-04-07335McClelland, Stephanie.  Senate votes on bylaw violationsItem 6512941995-04-12336Scope and ContentsArticle published in the Sangamon Star, Sangamon State University, Vol. 11, No. 20.Fox, Dennis.  "Radical University" Celebrates 25th Year and DiesItem 7512951995-04337Scope and ContentsReprinted from RadPsyNews #8/April 1995, the Newsletter of the Radical Psychology Network.Cartoon, "Rawn Barri and Barbie", ndItem 851296338Letter from Phillip Gregg of SSU to Naomi Lynn, President, SSU, and Doug Anderson, University Legal Counsel, SSUItem 9512971995-04-14339Viewpoints: Editorial and Letters to the Editor, The Sangamon StarItem 10512981995-04-193310"Sangamon Police State?  Arrests of two professors raise old questions about armed police and their training", Illinois TimesItem 11512991995-04-20 -04-263311Faculty Senate Meeting AY 94/95 MinutesItem 12513001995-05-053312Flyer, "Free Speech Defense Fund"Item 13513013313Sakolsky/Fox Free Speech Update #2, Email Response, ndItem 14513023314Campus Committee for Free Speech informational packet, ndItem 15513033315Beaven, Stephen.  "Harsara names team to help with transition", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 16513041995-04-243316Faculty Senate Resolution 24-6, SubstituteItem 17513051995-04-283317Student Senate Resolution: Professor Dennis Fox ResolutionItem 18513061995-04-303318Scope and ContentsIntroduced by Senator Reinholtz.Ignatius, Jeff.  "SSU admissions department:  Naomi Lynn says university made mistakes in arresting professors", Illinois TimesItem 19513071995-04-27 - 05-033319Letter from Monica McFarland to Doug AndersonItem 20513091995-05-053320Scope and ContentsRe: Freedom of Information Act RequestAdministrative Policies Bulletin from the President, SSUItem 21513101995-05-123321Scope and ContentsRe: Time, Manner, and Place Rules for Speech Activities, Bulletin #42.Ignatius, Jeff.  "SSU drops case against profs:  University 'regrets' one arrest, admits lack of policies", Illinois TimesItem 22513111995-06-08 - 06-143322Memorandum from Office of University Relations to the University CommunityItem 23513121995-06-143323Memorandum from Ron Sakolsky to SSU CommunityItem 24513131995-06-153324Scope and ContentsRe: Illinois State Police Report.Letter from Ron Sakolsky, the Alliance for Cultural Democracy to Artist/FriendItem 25513141995-09-263325Free Expression Art Show flyerItem 26513151995-123326Miscellaneous notes and cartoonsItem 27513163327Response to Ikenberry's Statement by Dennis Fox and Ron SakolskyItem 28513081999-05-043328Campus Free Speech Packet and Email Responses to arrests re: Ron Sakolsky's Free Speech CaseFolder 3451287199534Ron Sakolsky's Free Speech Case, RESTRICTEDFolder 3551288199535PublicationsFolder 365131836The Power Game:  Who Rules Springfield, a publication of the People's Institute, 3rd Edition, ndItem 151319361Sakolsky, Ron.  "Surviving Springfield", The Last Mushroom Garden, Vol. 3Item 2513201975-09362Richard Cloward, Brookens Auditorium, SSUFolder 37513311992-11-2337Scope and ContentsTape 2Jesse Jackson Part 1Folder 3875530198438Scope and ContentsFliers and papers related to Jesse Jackson's presidential campaign in 1984.Jesse Jackson Part 2Folder 3975531198439Scope and ContentsNewspapers and clippings related to Jesse Jackson's 1984 presidential election.Miscellaneous MaterialsFolder 4075532?-201240Scope and ContentsA collection of materials donated after the original accession date. Included are two small posters, one which announces the Social Action Class taught by Townsend, the other an announcement for the 3rd Annual Faculty Scholarship Auction. Also included: a copy of human rights principles taught by Townsend, and a copy of a newspaper article detailing a look at the Dickson Mounds area after 20 years.Mimi Abramovitz, ndAudiotape 151324Daryl Maigher Referrals, ndAudiotape 251325Holly SklarAudiotape 3513261996-06-13Independent Freedom and the State (PAC)Audiotape 4513271978-01-09Scope and Contents(60 min.) Tape 1 - Introduction, Frances Fox Diven.Independent Freedom and the State (PAC)Audiotape 5513281978-01-09Scope and Contents(60 min.) Tape 2 - Q &amp; A with Frances Fox Diven.Independent Freedom and the State (PAC)Audiotape 6513331978-01-09Scope and Contents(60 min.) Tape 3 - Q &amp; A with Frances Fox Diven and Russell Kirk.Radical Social Work, ndAudiotape 751329Richard Cloward, Brookens Auditorium, SSUAudiotape 8513301992-11-23Scope and ContentsTape 1Richard Cloward, Brookens Auditorium, SSUAudiotape 9513321992-11-23Scope and ContentsTape 2Richard Cloward, Brookens Auditorium, SSUVideotape 1513211992-11-23CFC 513: Silent VigilVideotape 2513221992-12-14"Norman Mailer:  The Sanction to Write", a film by Jeff Davis, ndVideotape 351323Box 2Box 282536Citizens Against Prostitution: Meeting minutes, notes, reports, membership and mailing listsFolder 18254119851Citizens Against Prostitution: Newspaper clippingsFolder 2825461984-19852Student  Project, CFC 506, "Springfield, Illinois: A Haven for Immigrants, 1830-1930"Folder 38255119833Student Project, "Photo Essay of Delapidated or Condemned Housing from East Springfield"Folder 48255619844Student Project, "Pictures of Substandard Housing ... Posted by the City Disallowing Occupancy"Folder 58256119875Student Project, INO 580, "Radio Activism"Folder 68256620006Essay, "Breaching the Matrix: Why Human Rights Radio Had to Go"Folder 78257120137Michael Townsend's Obituary by the State Journal-RegisterFolder 8834312017-08-188OVERSIZE cabinet 1OVERSIZE cabinet 151334Poster, United Students for Africa, War Against A.I.D.S., ndItem 1513441Scope and ContentsLocated in Drawer 5Occupy Movement AdvertsItem 2755212Scope and ContentsFive newspaper foldouts containing poster-sized messages advocating the Occupy Movement of 2011. Located in Oversize Cabinet, Drawer 5.Poster, Studies in Social Change Film SeriesItem 3755283Scope and ContentsLocated in Drawer 5Poster, El Salvador, Another Vietnam?: A Teach-In on Central AmericaItem 47552919814Scope and ContentsLocated in Drawer 5

