<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.50.Langley, P.Archon Finding Aid Title J.50.Langley, P.UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:07:12 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J50/Langley, P. Faculty Projects, Pay Equity Study, 1963-1985
    
      Langley, Patricia
    
    J.50.Langley, P.
    620
    
      1.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1983-1985
    Date acquired: 09/10/2001
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Faculty Project conducted by Patricia Langley on the subject of pay equity contains court cases, studies of comparatable worth from Indiana, Michigan, Wisconsin, Illinois, and Washington states, national and state legislative information and bibliographies.  Files also contain news clippings, journal articles, and statistical figures relation to comparatable worth.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Patricia Langley  
  
    Newspaper Clippings
    Statistics
    Journal Articles
  
  Box 1Box 163292Equity CasesFolder 1632931973-841CasesFolder 2632941970-842CasesFolder 3632951970-833Job Discrimination – sexual harassment and wageFolder 4632964Articles – comparable worth overviewsFolder 5632975News clippingsFolder 6632981983-846Langley textFolder 7632997Testimony against pay equity comparable worthFolder 8633008Journal articlesFolder 9633019Illinois legislative council studyFolder 106330210Newsletters/pamphletsFolder 116330311Testimony for pay equity comparable worthFolder 126330412Illinois pilot studyFolder 136330513A preliminary study of comparable worth – Michigan Department of LaborFolder 146330614Understanding the program 10 pointsFolder 156330715Before the Illinois Human Rights Commission and Illinois Department of Human RightsFolder 166330804/04/198316Written comments on proposed interpretive rules under the Illinois Human Rights Act on discrimination in employment on the basis of sex and marital statusFolder 176330904/04/198317Final report of the Compensation Task Force – State of IndianaFolder 1863310198518Comparable worth study – State of WashingtonFolder 1963311197419Preliminary Report – Wisconsin's Task Force on Comparable WorthFolder 2063312198420Management Science Associates Report – Sections I-V, samples, appendix BFolder 216331321Comments of the National Public Employer Labor Relations AssociationFolder 226331422Scope and ContentsOn job segregation and wage discrimination and the concept of "comparable worth" under Title VIIPay Equity and Comparable Worth:  A BNA Special ReportFolder 236331523Bibliography cards (handwritten)Folder 246331624Charts, graphs, and compilationsFolder 256331725Photo copies of Executive Orders 1135 and 11246Folder 266331826Illinois Legislative ActivityFolder 276331927Hay groupsFolder 286332028United NationsFolder 296332129Bibliographies on Comparable WorthFolder 306332230American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees AFL-CIO v. State of WashingtonFolder 316332331

