<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>K.01.01/08Archon Finding Aid Title K.01.01/08Sandra LongenUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:16:10 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    K1/1/8. Student Affairs, Assistant Vice-Chancellor for Student Affairs Stephen Chrans Files
    
      Chrans, Stephen R. (Steve)
    
    K.01.01/08
    1743
    
      1.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1975-2007
    Date acquired: 12/21/2010
    1
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Assistant Vice-Chancellor of Student Affairs, Steve Chrans was directly responsible for the Student Affairs and Housing and Residential Life. This series contains site plans, cost estimates, and program documents for the residence halls and recreational building on the UIS/SSU campus.  Also included are loan applications and request for solar energy grants from the federal government for building these units.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Steve Chrans  
  
    Blueprints
    Letters
    Ledgers
    Maps
    Memorabilia
    Papers
    Press Releases
    Surveys
    Reports
    Records
  
  Box 1Box 153773WTW Architects BookletFolder 153774n.d.1Bond Indentures SSU/UISFolder 25377519792Scope and ContentsHousing and revenue bondsCollege Housing Direct Loan Development HandbookFolder 3537761976-03-143Student Housing Program DocumentsFolder 4537771978-04-144Student Housing Site Plan Phase IIFolder 5537781980-04-115SSU Project Manual for Recreational Building &amp; SSU Buildings D&amp;EFolder 65377908-23-19846College Housing Program Application for AssistanceFolder 7537801985-06-077College Housing Program Application for AssistanceFolder 8537811985-05-028College Housing Loan ProgramFolder 95378219859SSU Financial ReportFolder 10537831985-06-3010College Housing Loan- Enrollment DataFolder 1153784198511UIS Residence Hall Design Brochure (Founders Hall)Folder 12537852007-0312UIS Residence Hall Schematic Design Phase (Founders Hall)Folder 13537862007-0213BOR SSU Recreational Facilities Revenue Bonds- Gymnasium ProjectFolder 1453787198414Scope and ContentsCopy 1BOR SSU Recreational Facilities Revenue Bonds- Gymnasium ProjectFolder 1553788198415Scope and ContentsCopy 2SSU Housing Loan Agreement &amp; Financial ReportsFolder 1653789197516College Housing Program Application for Assistance Under Title IV of the HousingFolder 1753790197717College Housing Program Application for Assistance Under Title IV of the Housing Act Part IIIFolder 18541831978-9-1418Request for Grant, Solar Energy Program, Residential Integrated ProjectFolder 19537911978-7-3119Housing- Construction DocumentsFolder 20537921978-198420College Housing Loan Program- Application for AssistanceFolder 2153793198521

