<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>P.Catchpole, Series IArchon Finding Aid Title P.Catchpole, Series IRoss RachelleUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:17:15 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    P/Catchpole. Mattilou Catchpole, Personal Papers
    
      Catchpole, Mattilou
    
    P.Catchpole, Series I
    1750
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1946-2010
    Date acquired: 08/18/2010
    1
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Papers of Mattilou Catchpole, Professor Emeritus at UIS. Catchpole served as director of Sangamon State's Nurse Anesthesia and Nurse Anesthesia Completion programs (1978-1991), within the School of Health and Human Services. Catchpole was employed as associate professor in the School of Liberal Arts and Sciences (1991-1994) and later as an adjunct instructor, teaching courses in the Women's Studies program (WMS). Materials include documents related to Catchpole's military service during the Second World War, personal photographs and correspondence, copies of publications which she authored, employment records and course material from the Nurse Anesthesia Program. The collection includes two oral history transcripts (conducted in 2002 &amp; 2010) and one audio CD containing an oral history interview. Reports written by Catchpole documenting her work in developing countries where she taught basic courses on Anesthesia are also included. Due to sensitive personal information, some of these records are RESTRICTED.  
  
    Arrangement Note
By Subject  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
RESTRICTED  
  
    Audio CDs
    Transcripts
    Course Materials
    Correspondence
    Photographs
    Journal Articles
    Letters
    Newspaper Clippings
  
  Box 1Box 168714Personal RecordsFolder 1688851Transcripts and Curriculum VitaeFolder 2688862Army Records (photocopies, see oversize for originals)Folder 3688871945-19463Correspondence and PhotographsFolder 4688884Articles and Newspaper ClippingsFolder 5688895Awards and CertificatesFolder 6688906SSU Nurse Anesthesia ProgramFolder 7688917Other UIS Courses Taught as adjunctFolder 8688928University Employment Records, RESTRICTEDFolder 9688939Publications/Written WorksFolder 106889410Overseas Trips and ReportsFolder 116889511Berhana Ghebremedhin ProjectFolder 126889612Oral History DocumentsFolder 136889713

