<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.50.02Archon Finding Aid Title J.50.02Sean BruceUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:17:17 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J50/2.  SSU/UIS Faculty Publications
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    J.50.02
    1759
    
      4.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1959-2012
    Date acquired: 02/23/2012
    1
    2
    3
    4
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The materials collected here include works written, edited, contributed to, and arranged by Sangamon State University and University of Illinois at Springfield faculty, and are composed of books, journal articles, forewords for books, and music arrangements. These items include textbooks, journals, photocopied writings, sheet music, University informational handouts, and conference and committee publications.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical by faculty member  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Faculty File Office  
  
    Book
    Newsletters
    Sheet Music
  
  Box 1Box 174295Anderson, C.J.Item 17429619811Scope and ContentsFact book: For academic administrators. Washington, D.C. American Council on Education.Anderson, Stuart A.Item 28275119922Scope and ContentsCommunity Colleges / Four-Year Colleges and Universities CooperationAtkin, M.J. (Eds.).Item 37429719813Scope and ContentsDaedalus: Journal of the American academy of arts and sciences: America's schools: Public and private. Richmond, VA. American Academy of Arts of Sciences.Austin, A.E., Gamson, Z.F.Item 47429819834Scope and ContentsAcademic workplace: New demands, heightened tensions. Washington, D.C. Association for the Study of Higher Education.Baldridge, J.V., Kemerer, F.R.Item 57478419815Scope and ContentsAssessing the Impact of Faculty Bargaining. Washington, D.C. American Association for Higher EducationBarnes, I.J., Seely, H.W., VanDemark, P.J.Item 67478519746Scope and ContentsMicrobes and Man: A Laborartory Manual for Students in the Health Sciences. San Francisco, CA. W.H. Freeman and Company.Baughman, M.D., Haraway, C.W., Richards, B.F. (Eds)Item 77478619747Scope and ContentsContemporary Education: Early Childhood Education: A Search for Understanding and Maturity. Terre Haute, IN. School of Education Indiana State University.Bonjean, C.M.Item 87478719868Scope and ContentsSocial Science Quarterly: Black America. Austin, TX. The Southwestern Social Science Association.Bragg, A.K.Item 97478819769Scope and ContentsThe Socialization Process in Higher Education. Washington, D.C. The American Association for Higher Education.Breland, H.M., Wilder, G., Robertson, N.J.Item 1074789198610Scope and ContentsDemographics, Standards, and Equity: Challenges in College Admissions. Washington, D.C. The American Association of Collegiate Registrars and Admissions Officers.Brookes, M.C.T., German, K.L.Item 1174790198311Scope and ContentsMeeting the Challenges: Developing Faculty Careers. Washington, D.C. Association for the Study of Higher Education.Caravaglia, G.L.Item 1274791197212Scope and ContentsEducation as Existential Possibility. New York, NY. Philosophical Library, Inc.Caravaglia, G.L.Item 1374792197713Scope and ContentsPerspectives on Aging. Wheeling, IL. Whitehall Company/Publishers.Caravaglia, G.L.Item 1474793198014Scope and ContentsHealth Care of the Elderly: Strategies for Prevention and Intervention. New York, NY. Human Sciences Press.Caravaglia, G.L.Item 1574794198215Scope and ContentsAging and the Human Condition. New York, NY. Human Sciences Press.Caravaglia, G.L.Item 1674795197316Scope and ContentsJournal of Thought: An Interdisciplinary Journal. Fayettville, AK. Journal of Thought.Caravaglia, G.L.Item 1774796197417Scope and ContentsThe Gerontologist. Vol 14, No. 2. Guest Editorial: Senescence and Adolescence: Middle-Age Inventions. Washington, D.C.The Carnegie Council on Higher EducationItem 1874797198018Scope and ContentsThree Thousand Futures: The Next Twenty Years of Higher Education. San Francisco, CA. Jossey-Bass Inc., Publishers.Carnes, G. (Eds)Item 1974798198619Scope and ContentsThe Alchemist Review: A Literary Magazine. Springfield, IL Sangamon State University.Cell, E. (Eds.)Item 2074799196720Scope and ContentsLanguage Existence and God. Nashville, TN. Abingdon Press.Cell, E. (Eds.)Item 2174800196721Scope and ContentsReligion and Contemporary Western Culture: Selected Readings. Nashville, TN. Abingdon Press.Chesky, J.A.Item 2274801197822Scope and ContentsComparative Aspects of Declining Muscle Function. New York, NY. Raven Press.Chesky, J.A., LaFollette, S., Travis, M., Fortado, C.Item 2374802198323Scope and ContentsEffects of Physical Training on Myocardial Enzyme Activities in Aging Rats. Washington, D.C. American Physiological Society.Chesky, J.A., Rockstein, M., Lopez, T.Item 2474803197924Scope and ContentsMechanisms of Ageing and Development: Changes With Age of Myocardial Creatine Phosphokinsase in the Male Fischer Rat, 12, 237-243.Chesky, J.A., Rockstein, M.Item 2574804197725Scope and ContentsCardovascular Research: Reduced Myocardial Actomyosin Adenosine Triphosphatase Activity in the Ageing Male Fischer Rat, 11 (3), 242-246.Corriveau, D.M., Fritsma, G.A.Item 2674805198826Scope and ContentsHemostasis and Thrombosis in the Clinical Laboratory. Philadelphia, P.A. J.B. Lippincott Company.Crampon, W.J.Item 2774807197527Scope and ContentsA Guide to Statistical Analysis. Springfield, IL. Sangamon State University.Cranston, M. (Eds.)Item 2874808198328Scope and ContentsDaedalus: Journal of American Arts and Sciences: Human Rights. Richmond, VA. American Academy of Arts and Sciences.Cribett, J.Item 2974809198229Scope and ContentsForeign Students and Institutional Policy Toward and Agenda for Action. Washington, D.C. American Council on Education.Crosson, P.H.Item 3074810198330Scope and ContentsPublic Service in Higher Education: Practices and Priorities. Washington, D.C. Association for the Study of Higher Education.Crouse, J.S., Cobb, D.C., Harris, B.B., Kopecky, F.J., Poertner, J.Item 3174811198131Scope and ContentsAbuse and Neglect of the Elderly: Incidence and Characteristics, Legislation and Policy Recommendations. Springfield, IL. Sangamon State University.Davis, C.G.Item 3274812196232Scope and ContentsThe Mississippi Valley Historical Review: The Transformation of the Federal Trade Commission, 1914-1929, 49 (3). 438-455.Delon, F.G.Item 3374813197733Scope and ContentsLegal Controls on Teacher Conduct: Teacher Discipline. Topeka, KS. National Organization on Legal Problems of Education.Dickmeyer, N., Wessels, J., Goldren, S.L.Item 3474814198134Scope and ContentsInstitutionally Funded Student Financial Aid. Washington, D.C. American Council on Education.Dungey, KeenanItem 3579293200435Scope and ContentsCD with four publications by Keenan Dungey from 2004. One is a book review, and the other three are slide deck presentations. PDF format. Also available online. Please contact UIS Archives for access to online files.Eble, K.E.Item 3674815198036Scope and ContentsNew Directions for Teaching and Learning: Improved Teaching Styles. San Francisco, CA. Jossey-Bass Inc.Edgar, J.Item 3774816198437Scope and ContentsHandbook of Illinois Government. Springfield, IL. State of Illinois.Education Commission of the StatesItem 3874817198638Scope and ContentsTransforming the State Role in Undergraduate Education: Time for a Different View. Denver, CO. Education Commission of the States.Eibl, J.F., Pancrazio, J.J.Item 3974818n.d.39Scope and ContentsStudent Personnel Work in General Education. Springfield, IL. Charles C Thomas.Eurich, N.P., Boyer, E.L.Item 4074819198540Scope and ContentsCorporate Classrooms: The Learning Business. Lawrenceville, NJ. Princeton University Press.Box 2Box 274820Everson, D.H.Item 17482119811Scope and ContentsThe Effects of Initiatives on Voter Turnout: A Comparative State Analysis. Salt Lake City, UT. University of Utah.Everson, D.H.Item 27482219842Scope and ContentsThe Decline of Political Parties. New York, NY. the Academy of Political Science.Everson, D.H. (Eds.)Item 37482319743Scope and ContentsPublic Institutions and Public Trust: Crisis in Confidence. Springfield, IL. Sangamon State University.Ferrell, O.C., Gardiner, G.Item 47482419914Scope and ContentsIn Pursuit of Ethics: Tough Choices in the World of Work. Springfield, IL. Smith Collins Company.Fleming, B.A., Collins, J.N., Gerson, D.Item 57482519815Scope and ContentsHousing Issues in Illinois. Springfield, IL. Sangamon State University.Floyd, C.E.Item 67482619856Scope and ContentsFaculty Participation in Decision Making: Necessity or Luxury? Washington, D.C. Association for the Study of Higher Education.Freeman, R.J., Shoulders, C.D.Item 77482719997Scope and ContentsGovernment and Nonprofit Accounting: Theory and Practice. Upper Saddle River, NJ. Prentice-Hall, Inc.Fritsche, J.M.Item 87482819848Scope and ContentsToward Excellence and Equity: The Scholarship on Women as a Catalyst for Change in the University. Orono, ME. University of Maine at Orono.Furniss, T.W.Item 97482919849Scope and ContentsThe Self-Reliant Academic. Washington, D.C. The American Council on Education.Furniss, T.W., Garder, D.P.Item 1074830197910Scope and ContentsHigher Education and Government. Washington, D.C. American Council on Education.Gappa, J.M.Item 1174831198411Scope and ContentsPart-Time Faculty: Higher Education at a Crossroads. Washington D.C., Association for the Study of Higher Education.Gardiner,G.Item 1274832199012Scope and ContentsTough-Minded Management of Problem Employees: Don't Be a Gutless Nice Guy! Springfield, IL. Smith Collins Company.Geiger, L.G.Item 1374833197113Scope and ContentsVoluntary Acceditation: A History of the North Central Association. Menasha, WI. George Banta Company.Gherardini, C.A., Lennon, J.M., Shereikis, R.J., Smith, L.R. (Eds.)Item 1474834198214Scope and ContentsIllinois Election. Springfield, IL. Illinois Issues: Sangamon State University.Gorton, R.A.Item 1574835198315Scope and ContentsSchool Administration and Supervision. Dubuque, IA. WM. C. Brown Company PublishersGross, R., Gross, B.Item 1674836198316Scope and ContentsIndependent Scholarship: Promise, Problems, and Prospects. New York, NY. College Board Publications.Hadidi, R.Item 1774837198217Scope and ContentsJustifications for the Use of Utility Ratio Approach in Group Decision Making. Springfield, IL. Sangamon State University.Hadidi, R.Item 1874838198218Scope and ContentsOperations Research Techniques in Local and State Government. Springfield, IL. Sangamon State University.Hadidi, R., Leonard, M.S., Ashton, W.B.Item 1974839198219Scope and ContentsA Quantitative Method for the Selection of Hospital Information Systems Components. Maryland Heights, MO. Academic Press, Inc.Hall, L.Item 2074840197420Scope and ContentsNew Colleges for New Students. San Francisco, CA. Jossey-Bass, Inc., Publishers.Hardin, C.M.Item 2174841197721Scope and ContentsThe Case for Party Government Revisited. Thousand Oaks, CA. Sage Publications, Inc.Heide, W.S.Item 2274842197122Scope and ContentsWhat's Wrong with Male-Dominated Society. Washington, D.C. Impact of Science on Society.Heide, W.S.Item 2374843197223Scope and ContentsTestimony on S. 1889 in the Senate of the United States to Establish the United States Academy of Peace, and for Other Purposes. Framingham, MA.Heide, W.S.Item 2474844197324Scope and ContentsRevolution: Tomorrow is Now. Washington, D.C. Vital Speeches of the Day.Heide, W.S.Item 2574845197425Scope and ContentsFeminism and the Fallen Woman. Washington, D.C. American Association of Correctional Psychologists.Heide, W.S.Item 2674846197526Scope and ContentsOccasional Papers in Gerontology. Detroit, MI. Wayne State University.Heide, W.S.Item 2774847197627Scope and ContentsSmith College School of Social Work Journal: The Community Project: A Long Story. Northhampton, MA. Smith College.Heide, W.S.Item 2874848197828Scope and ContentsAbstract of Detailed Testimony of Wilma Scott Heide. Framingham, MA.Hendrickson, R.M., Lee, B.A.Item 2974849198329Scope and ContentsAcademic Employment and Retrenchment: Judicial Review and Administrative Action. Washington, D.C. Association for the Study of Higher Education.Hill, B.A.Item 3074850198130Scope and ContentsLiberal Education: Spring 1981. Washington, D.C. Association of American Colleges.Hill, B.A.Item 3174851198331Scope and ContentsLiberal Education: Spring 1983. Washington, D.C. Association of American Colleges.Hill, B.A., Hager, J.W., Berk, P. (Eds.)Item 3274852198432Scope and ContentsLiberal Education. Washington, D.C. Association of American Colleges.Hill, B.A., Hager, J.W., Berk, P. (Eds.)Item 3374853198633Scope and ContentsLiberal Education. Washington, D.C. Association of American Colleges.Hopkins, B.R.Item 3474854198034Scope and ContentsA Tax Guide for University and College Presidents. Washington, D.C. American Council on Education.Huckshorn, R.J., Spencer, R.C.Item 3574855197135Scope and ContentsThe Politics of Defeat. Amherst, MA. University of Massachusetts Press.Janardan, K.G.Item 3674856198236Scope and ContentsCorrelation Between the Numbers of Two Types of Children in a Family, Using the Markov-Polya Model. New York, NY. Elsevier Science Publishing, Co., Inc.Janardan, K.G., Schaeffer, D.J., Grave, W.R.Item 3774857198237Scope and ContentsMultivariate Statistical Methods in Toxicology III Specifying Joint Toxic Interaction Using Multiple Regression Analysis. Washington, D.C. Hemisphere Publishing Corporation.Johnson, L.G.Item 3874858198438Scope and ContentsThe High-Technology Connection: Academci/ Industrail Cooperation for Economic Growth. Washington, D.C. Association for the Study of Higher Education.Johnson, W.Item 3974859197739Scope and ContentsWomen's Studes: Awakening Academe. Washington, D.C. The Western Social Science Association.Judd, R., Wright, S. (Eds.)Item 4074860198740Scope and ContentsHealth Administration Track. Springfield, IL Sangamon State University.Judd, R.J. (Eds.)Item 4174861198241Scope and ContentsNational Directors' Conference: Reviewing the First Decade, Developing Strategies for the Second. Springfield, IL. Sangamon State University.Keimig, R.T.Item 4274862198342Scope and ContentsRaising Academic Standards: A Guide to Learning Improvement. Washington, D.C. Association for the Study of Higher Education.Kenney, D., Van Der Slik, J.R., Pernacciaro, S.J.Item 4374863197543Scope and ContentsRoll Call! Patterns of Voting in the Sixth Illinois Constitutional Convention. Champaign, IL. The University of Illinois Board of Trustees.Kopecky, F.J. (Eds.)Item 4474864197844Scope and ContentsCurrent Illinois Legal Issues: A Classroom Supplement. Springfield, IL Sangamon State University.Krohe, J.Item 4574865198245Scope and ContentsBreadbasket or Dust Bowl: The Future of Illinois Farmland. Springfield, IL. Sangamon State University.Box 3Box 374866Ladd, D.R.Item 17486719701Scope and ContentsChange in Educational Policy: Self-Studies in Selected Colleges and Universities. Berkeley, CA. The Carnegie Commission on Higher Education.Lang, P.H. (Eds.)Item 27486819642Scope and ContentsThe Musical Quarterly. New York, NY. G. Schmirmer, Inc.Laska, J.A., Hackett, P. (Eds.)Item 37486919723Scope and ContentsEducational Studies: A Journal of Book Reviews in the Foundations of Education. Austin, TX. American Educational Studies Association.Lennon, J.M.Item 47487019764Scope and ContentsModern Language Studies. Battleboro, VT. Northeast Modern Language Association.Lennon, J.M.Item 57487119775Scope and ContentsMailer's Radical Bridge. The Journal of Narrative Technique.Lennon, J.M.Item 67487219786Scope and ContentsModern Fiction Studies: Miscellaneous. West Lafayette, IN. Purdue University Press.Lennon, J.M.Item 77487319777Scope and ContentsModern Fiction Studies: Mailer's Sarcophagus: The Artist, The Media, and the "Wad". West Lafayette, IN. Purdue University Press.Lennon, J.M.Item 87487419828Scope and ContentsMailer's Cosmology. New York, NY. Modern Language Association.Lennon, J.M., Gheradini, C.A.Item 97487519829Scope and ContentsIllinois Issues Special Report: The Cutback Amendment. Springfield, IL. Sangamon State University.Lennon, J.M., Stroizer, C.B.Item 1074876198110Scope and ContentsThe Psychohistory Review: Empathy and Detachment in the Narratives of Erickson and Mailer. Human Sciences Press.Litten, L.H., Sullivan, D., Brodigan, D.L.Item 1174877198311Scope and ContentsApplying Market Research in College Admissions. New York, NY. College Board Publications.Lobrasbi, A. (Eds.)Item 1274878198512Scope and ContentsProduction and Operations Management Proceedings. Springfield, IL. Sangamon State University.Meisinger, R.J., Bubeck, L.W.Item 1374879198413Scope and ContentsCollege and University Budgeting: An Introduction for Faculty and Academic Administrators. Washington, D.C. National Association of College and University Business Officers.Melendez, W.A., de Guzman, R.M.Item 1474880198314Scope and ContentsBurnout: The New Academic Disease. Washington, D.C. Association for the Study of Higher Education.Menke, P.G.Item 1574881198615Scope and ContentsDivision on Education Programs. Washington, D.C. National Endowment for the Humanities.Miller, M.B.Item 1674882197216Scope and ContentsIssues in Criminology. Berkeley, CA. University of California.Miller, M.B.Item 1774883197617Scope and ContentsTime-As-Punishment: How Prisoners Do Time Under an Indeterminate Sentence. Sacramento, CA. Lambda Alpha Epsilon American Criminal Justice Association.Miller, M.B.Item 1874884197818Scope and ContentsReadings in Criminal Justice: An Introduction to the System. Santa Monica, CA. Goodyear Publishing Company.Miller, M.B.Item 1974885198219Scope and ContentsCrime and Social Justice: Meeting the Challenge of the 1980s. San Francisco, CA. Crime and Social Justice Associates.Millett, J.D.Item 2074886197420Scope and ContentsStrengthening Community in Higher Education. Washington, D.C. The Academy for Educational Development.Morrison, J.L., Renfro, W.L., Boucher, W.I.Item 2174887198421Scope and ContentsFutures Research and the Strategic Planning Process: Implications for Higher Education. Washington, D.C. Association for the Study of Higher Education.Mortimer, K.P., Bagshaw, M., Masland, A.T.Item 2274888198522Scope and ContentsFlexibility in Academic Staffing: Effective Policies and Practices. Washington, D.C. Association for the Study of Higher Education.Nandi, P.K.Item 2374889197723Scope and ContentsCultural Constraints on Professionalization: The Case of Nursing in India. Waltham, MA. Perfamon Press (Elsevier).Nandi, P.K.Item 2474890198024Scope and ContentsThe Sociology of Heckling. New York, NY. Thomson Reuters.Nandi, P.K.Item 2574891198025Scope and ContentsThe World of Invisible Minority: Pakistanis in America. CA. California Sociologist.Nandi, P.K., Gursslin, O.R.Item 2674892197326Scope and ContentsGemeinschaft and Gesellschaft in Higher Education. Darya Ganj, New Delhi. Serials Publications.Nandi, P.K., Loomis, C.P.Item 2774893197727Scope and ContentsProfessionalization of Nursing in India: Deterring and Facilitating Aspects of the Culture. Thousand Oaks, CA. Sage Publications.National Council for Accreditation of Teacher EducationItem 2874894197828Scope and Contents25th Annual List 78-79. Washington, D.C. National Accreditation of Teacher Education.Ostar, A.W., Horn, S.Item 2974895198629Scope and ContentsReport of the National Commission on the Role and Future of State Colleges and Universities: To Secure our Blessings of Liberty. Washington, D.C. American Association of State Colleges and Universities.Ottinger, C.A.Item 3074896198430Scope and Contents1984-85 Fact Book on Higher Education. New York, NY. Macmillan Publishing Company.Pancrazio, J.J.Item 3174897n.d.31Scope and ContentsIt's Your Life. Westchester, IL. Benefic Press.Pancrazio, J.J.Item 3274898197032Scope and ContentsSpate: A Group Experience - For What? Alexandria, VA. Student Personnel Association for Teacher Education.Pancrazio, J.J.Item 3374899197133Scope and ContentsThe Counselor as a Human Relations Consultant, 81-87.Pancrazio, J.J.Item 3474900197534Scope and ContentsHuman Concerns for the Offender. Honolulu, HI. Education Research and Development Center, University of Hawaii.Pancrazio, J.J., Cody, J.J.Item 3574901196735Scope and ContentsA Comparison of Role-Playing and Lecture-Discussion: Instructional Methods in a Beginning Course in Counseling Theory. Cincinnati, OH. Association for Counselor Education and Supervision.Pancrazio, J.J., Zeller, R., Metzger, Grenier, W.Item 3674902197936Scope and ContentsFoster Parent Training Curriculum. Springfield, IL. Department of Children and Family Services.Pancrazio, J.J., Zeller, R.H.Item 3774903198137Scope and ContentsCommunication to Improve Pupil Transportation. Springfield, IL. Illinois State Board of Education.Parker, J.A.Item 3874904198438Scope and ContentsThe Illinois Tax Increase of 1983: Summit and Resolution. Springfield, IL. Sangamon State University.Payne, K.Item 3974905197739Scope and ContentsThe Browning of the Mississippi: Human Activity has Made North America's Largest River Dirtier, Narrower, Slower, Deeper, Lockier, and Dammier. Biologists Say Enlarging Locks and Dam 26 Will Make it More So. Illinois times, pp. 4-7.Postman, N.Item 4074906198540Scope and ContentsEtc. A Review of General Semantics: Etcetera a Journal Devoted to the Role of Symbols in Human Behavior. San Fracisco, CA. International Society of General Semantics.Preer, J.L.Item 4174907198341Scope and ContentsCompetence, Admissions, and Articulation: Returning to the Basics in Higher Education. Washington, D.C. Association for the Study of Higher Education.Rao, B.R., Janardan, K.G.Item 4274908198242Scope and ContentsCharacterization of Generalized Markov-Polya and Generalized Polya-Eggenberger Distributions. Philadelphia, PA. Marcel Dekker Inc.Rao, B.R., Janardan, K.G.Item 4374909198243Scope and ContentsOn the Moments of Multivariate Discrete Distributions Using Finite Difference Operators. Alexandria, VA. The American Statistician.Richards, M.D., Sherratt, G.R.Item 4474910198144Scope and ContentsInstitutional Advancement Strategies in Hard Times. Washington, D.C. Association for the Study of Higher Education.Rivers, W.M., Louise, H.A., Savignon, S.J., Scalan, R.T.Item 4574911197245Scope and ContentsChanging Patterns in Foreign Language Programs: Report of the Illinois Conference on Foreign Languages in Junior and Community Colleges, 1972. Rowley, MA. Newbury House Publishers, Inc.Rockstein, M. Chesky, J.A., Levy, M.H., Yore, L.Item 4674912198146Scope and ContentsGerontology. Effects of Population Density on Life Expectancy and Wing Retention in the Common House Fly, Musca Domestica l, 27, 13-19.Rockstein, M., Chesky, J.A., Lopez, T.Item 4774913198147Scope and ContentsJournal of Gerontology. Effects of Exercise on the Biochemical Aging of Mammalian Myocardium. I. Actomyosin Atpase, 36 (3), 294-297.Sangamon State UniversityItem 4874914197048Scope and ContentsGraduate Public Service Internship. Springfield, IL Sangamon State University.Sangamon State UniversityItem 4974915197049Scope and ContentsUpper-Division Center Located at Illinois Central College: A Handbook for Prospective and Continuing Students. Springfield, IL. Sangamon State University.Schaeffer, D.J., Janardan, K.G., Rao, B.R.Item 5074916198250Scope and ContentsEstimating the Proportion of Mutagenic Compounds in Environmental Samples. Washington, D.C. Hemisphere Publishing Corporation.Schaeffer, D.J., Janardan, K.G., Rao, B.R.Item 5174917198251Scope and ContentsIs There a Correlation Between the Number of Mutagens and the Number of Nonmutagens in an Environmental Sample? Waltham, MA. Pergamon Press.Schroeder, R.Item 5274918198152Scope and ContentsComputer Conferencing: Exploding the Classroom Walls. Action, MA. Information Synergy, Inc.Schuster, M.R., Van Dyne, S.R.Item 5374919198553Scope and ContentsWomen's Place in the Academy: Transforming the Liberal Arts Curriculum. New Jersey. Rowman and Allanheld.Schweighauser, C.A.Item 5474920197954Scope and ContentsAstronomy from A to Z: A Dictionary of Celestial and Ideas. Springfield, IL. Sangamon State University.Shiner, L.Item 5574921198255Scope and ContentsHistory and Theory: Studies in the Philosophy of History. Middletown, CT. Wesleyan University Press.Shiner, L. (Eds.)Item 5674922198856Scope and ContentsThe Psychohistory Review: Studies of Motivation in History and Culture. Springfield, IL. Sangamon State University. Volume 1.Shiner, L. (Eds.)Item 5774923198957Scope and ContentsThe Psychohistory Review: Studies of Motivation in History and Culture. Springfield, IL. Sangamon State University. Volume 2.Siebert, F.M.Item 5874924198258Scope and ContentsPerformance Problems in Fifteenth-Century Organ Music. Andover, MA. Organ Institute.Soble, L.Item 5974925196959Scope and ContentsUCLA Graduate Journal. Los Angeles, CA. Associated University of California.Box 4Box 474926Spurr, S.H.Item 17492719701Scope and ContentsAcademic Degree Structures: Innovative Approaches: Principles of Reform in Degree Structures in the United States. Berkley, CA. Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching.Stauffer, T.M.Item 27492819812Scope and ContentsCompetition and Cooperation in American Higher Education. Washington, D.C. American Council on Education.Sterns, H.L., Ansello, E.F., Sprouse, B.M., Layfield-Faux, R.Item 37492919793Scope and ContentsGerontology in Higher Education: Developing Institutional and Community Strength. Belmont, CA. Wadsworth Publishing Company.Stuart, J., Kearney, M.Item 47493019814Scope and ContentsCauses and Effects of Agricultural Labor Migration from the Mixteca of Oaxaca to California. San Diego, CA. University of California.Szabo, D., Katzenelson, S. (Eds.)Item 57493119785Scope and ContentsOffenders and Corrections. New York, NY. Praeger Publishers.Tickton, S.G.Item 67493219806Scope and ContentsThe Energy Conservation Handbook. Washington, D.C. American Council on Education.Timko, M., Kaplan, F., Guilian, E.Item 77493319947Scope and ContentsDickens Studies Annual: Essays on Victorian Fiction. New York, NY. AMS Press, Inc.Tinsley, A., Secor, C., Kaplan, S. (Eds.)Item 87493419848Scope and ContentsNew Directions for Higher Education: Women in Higher Education Administration. San Francisco, CA. Jossey-Bass Inc.Tipsword, R.F.Item 97493519919Scope and ContentsIllinois General Assembly Oral History Program: Rolland F. Tipsword Volume I. Springfield, IL Sangamon State University. Volume 1.Tipsword, R.F.Item 1074936199110Scope and ContentsIllinois General Assembly Oral History Program: Rolland F. Tipsword Volume II. Springfield, IL. Sangamon State University. Volume 2.Tressel, N., Parson, J., Hennelly, M.Item 1174937197511Scope and ContentsSponsored Research of the Carnegie Commission on Higher Education. Berkley, CA. The Carnegie Foundation of the Advancement of Teaching.Troxell, J. Bach, J.S.Item 1274938196512Scope and ContentsFlute Quartet. Westbury, NY Pro Art Publications, Inc.Trocell, J., Hayden, J.Item 1374939196513Scope and ContentsClarinet Choir. Westbury, NY. Pro Art Publications, Inc.Troxell, J. Hayden, J.Item 1474940196514Scope and ContentsClarinet Trio. Westbury, NY Pro Art Publications, Inc.Troxell, J., Norris, B. (Eds.)Item 1574941196315Scope and ContentsThe Iowa Music Educator: Convention Issue. Missouri Valley, IA. The Iowa Music Educator Association.Toxell, J., Norris, B. (Eds.)Item 1674942196316Scope and ContentsThe Iowa Music Educator: Music Session Program of ISEA Convention. Missouri Valley, IA.  The Iowa Music Educator Association.Toxell, J., Norris, B. (Eds.)Item 1774943196417Scope and ContentsThe Iowa Music Educator: SIU's Hawkeye Marching Band. Missouri Valley, IA. The Iowa Music Educator Association.Toxell, J., Norris, B. (Eds.)Item 1874944196418Scope and ContentsThe Iowa Music Educator: State Convention Performing Groups from Fairfield and Manson City. Missouri Valley, IA. The Iowa Music Educator Association.Toxell, J., Norris, B. (Eds.)Item 1974945196419Scope and ContentsThe Iowa Music Educator: Summer Camp and Workshop Issue. Missouri Valley, IA. The Iowa Music Educator Association.Toxell, J., Norris, B. (Eds.)Item 2074946196420Scope and ContentsThe Iowa Music Educator: The Dimensions of Music in 1964. Missouri Valley, IA. The Iowa Music Educator Association.Toxell, J., Norris, B. (Eds.)Item 2174947196521Scope and ContentsThe Iowa Music Educator: New Iowa State Center to be Constructed Soon. Missouri Valley, IA. The Iowa Music Educator Association.Toxell, J., Norris, B. (Eds.)Item 2274948196522Scope and ContentsThe Iowa Music Educator: SCI Music Education Building at Night...MENC North Central Convention Features Missouri Valley, IA. The Iowa Music Educator Association.The University of IllinoisItem 2374949198523Scope and ContentsCode on Campus Affairs and Regulations Applying to All Students. Champaign, IL. University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign Office of Admission and Records.Van Der Silk, J.R., Stenger, T.C.Item 2474950197724Scope and ContentsCitizen Witness Before Congressional Committees. New York, NY. The Academy of Political Science.Van Der Silk, J.R., Pernacciaro, S.J.Item 2574951197925Scope and ContentsOffice Ambitions and Voting Behavior in the U.S. Senate. Thousand Oaks, CA. Sage Publications, Inc.Van Der Silk, J.R., Pernacciaro, S.J. Kenny, D.Item 2674952197426Scope and ContentsPatterns of Partnership in a Nonpartisan Representational Setting: The Illinois Constitutional Convention. Carbondale, IL. American Journal of Political Science.Waggaman, J.S.Item 2774953198327Scope and ContentsFaculty Recruitment, Retention, and Fair Employment: Obligations and Opportunities. Washington, D.C. Association for the Study of Higher Education.Waterhouse, JanettaItem 27.1077842October 201227.10Scope and Contents"Computer Libraries" October 2012 volume, Page 6
"How to Ensure our Library Systems are Horse-High, Bull-Strong, and Pig-Tight"Worthy, J.C.Item 2874954195928Scope and ContentsBig Business and Free Men. New York, NY. Harper and Brothers.Worthy, J.C.Item 2974955197529Scope and ContentsCrisis in Confidence II: Corporate America. Springfield, IL. Sangamon State University.Young, C.Item 3074956198730Scope and ContentsThe Alchemist Review 1986-87. Springfield, IL. Sangamon State University.Zemsky, R., Oedel, P.Item 3174957198331Scope and ContentsThe Structure of College Choice. New York, NY. College Entrance Examination Board.Zhongguo, J.G., Yu, F.L.Item 3274958200432Scope and ContentsThe Grand Secretary Number One. Guangming Daily Press.

