<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>P.CampArchon Finding Aid Title P.CampSandra LongenUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:17:24 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    P/Camp. Dennis Camp, Personal Papers
    
      Camp, Dennis
    
    P.Camp
    1758
    
      0.16 Cubic Feet
    
    1966-1986
    Date acquired: 05/03/2012
    1
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Personal papers of Dennis Camp,  Assoc. Dean of Arts &amp; Sciences program and professor of Literature/English (later Faculty Emeritus of English), and noted Vachel Lindsay scholar.  Includes Academic Achievement Award Camp received in 1985; "Illinois Historical Journal," Autumn 1987 &amp; Winter 1986; "The Personalist," Summer 1966; 1970-71 Sangamon State University Catalog; "Sangamon" Spring 1973; "The Book-Mart" Sept. 1979; "Prairie State" 2/14/1983, noting Camp as Commencement speaker in 1983; invitation to join SSU staff as Asst. Professor of English dated 1970.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Chris Ryan  
  
    Memorabilia
    Newspaper Clippings
    Newspapers
    Flyers/Brochures
    Awards
    Correspondence
    Lindsay, Vachel, 1879-1931
  
  Box 1Box 176395Announcement to Interested FacultyFolder 10176406ca 1970101Scope and ContentsCall for faculty for the opening of newly created Upper Division University - Sangamon State.  Directs inquireies to SSU located at that time in the Myers Building in downtown Springfield.Letter inviting Dennis Camp to join SSU as Asst. Prof. of EnglishFolder 10276407June 3, 1970102Scope and ContentsYearly salary of $12, 780Programs Celebrating Life in Lincoln CountyFolder 103764051981103Scope and ContentsThis program is conjunction with Intersession: The Energy DecadePrairie Star; Sangamon State University, Vol 5, No. 7Folder 10476404February 14, 1983104Scope and ContentsAnnounces Dennis Camp as faculty speaker at 1983 commencementBook-Mart: Monthly Journal for Book Buyers, Sellers and CollectorsFolder 10576403September 1979105Scope and ContentsIncludes article about Vachel Lindsay, reprinted from the Vachel Lindsay Association newsletter, with additional information from Dennis CampCamp to give lecture on Vachel Lindsay; State Journal RegisterFolder 10676408October 1972106Illinois Fields in Summer; Sangamon Poets No. 13Folder 10776401107Scope and ContentsLinked poem by three authors:
Harris Hatcher
John Knoepfle
Deborah NewboldSangamon, Vol 1, No. 1Folder 10876400Spring 1973108Scope and ContentsMagazine about SSU: its programs, plans, buildings, and people. Intended to be published quarterly and primarily for former students.Sangamon State University Course CatalogFolder 109763991970-1971109Academic Achievement Award, SSUFolder 11076402December 10, 1985110Scope and ContentsSpecial award to Dennis Camp "who has enriched the academic life of the university through truly significant academic and scholarly accomplishment."The PersonalistFolder 11176396Summer 1966111Scope and ContentsArticle by Dennis Camp, "Browning's Pompilia and the Truth"Illinois Historical JournalFolder 11276397Winter 1986112Scope and ContentsBook review of "Poetry of Vachel Lindsay" edited by Dennis CampIllinois Historical JournalFolder 11376398August 1987113

