<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.09.05/06Archon Finding Aid Title J.09.05/06Sean BruceUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:17:29 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J9/5/6. History Program, Lincoln Sites Project, Rebecca Veach New Salem Research
    J.09.05/06
    1770
    
      1.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1975-1978
    Date acquired: 03/05/2012
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This collection contains a variety of materials donated by Rebecca Veach that deal with Lincoln Sties project. Specifically this collection contains research, records, scripts, correspondences, and manuscripts from the New Salem historical site acquired by Veach during her time as the assistant to the Lincoln Sites Project.

Notable materials include several article manuscripts that were proposed as inclusions to a book about Lincoln, collections of research (both primary and secondary) about New Salem and Lincoln, correspondences between Veach and others concerning the material, and scripts of historical reenactments done at New Salem. Much of this material is composed of photocopies of journal articles, re-printed primary source documents, and newspapers.

The Lincoln Sites Project, also know as "Lincoln's Thought and the Present," was funded and maintained by the National Endowment for the Humanities. It was and attempt to unify the historical perspectives presented at the Lincoln home, Old State Capitol, Lincoln's Tomb, Lincoln Law Office, Lincoln Depot and New Salem Park.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Rebecca Veach  
  
    Correspondence
    Journal Articles
    Letters
    Photocopies
    Records
    Lincoln, Abraham
  
  Box 1Box 175039Law Office: Data: Lincoln's AssociatesFolder 1750401975-19761Scope and ContentsCollection of photocopied articles and published works dealing with Abraham Lincoln's law associates. Also contained correspondences specifically mentioning the topic.Law Office: Data: GeneralFolder 2750412Scope and ContentsA collection of primary and secondary source research on Abraham Lincoln's time as a lawyer.Law Office: Data: Descriptions of Lawyer LincolnFolder 3750423Scope and ContentsA collection of primary and secondary source research about descriptions of Lincoln during his time as a lawyer.Law Office: Data: Legal EducationFolder 4750434Scope and ContentsA collection of primary and secondary source research about Abraham Lincoln's legal education.Law Office: Data: 8th CircuitFolder 5750445Scope and ContentsA collection of secondary source research on Lincoln's time working on the 8th circuit court.Law Office: Data: StuartFolder 6750456Scope and ContentsA collection of secondary source research about Lincoln's time and experiences working with John T. Stuart.Law Office: Data: LoganFolder 7750467Scope and ContentsA collection of secondary source research about Lincoln's relations with Stephan T. Logan.Law Office: Data: HerndonFolder 8750478Scope and ContentsA collection of secondary source research about Lincoln's experiences with William Herndon.Law Office: Data: Federal CourtFolder 97504819769Scope and ContentsA collection of primary and secondary source research on Lincoln's time working with federal courts. Also contains some correspondences and material index lists.Law Office: Data: Law/PoliticsFolder 107504910Scope and ContentsA collection of secondary source research on Lincoln's time as both a lawyer and a politician.Law Office: Data: The PracticeFolder 117505011Scope and ContentsA collection of secondary source research on Lincoln's time spent in private practice.Law Office: Data: Higher Court PrecedentFolder 127505112Scope and ContentsTwo pieces of secondary source research detailing Lincoln's uses of higher court precedents.Law Office: Data: "Judge" LincolnFolder 137505213Scope and ContentsAn article dealing with Lincoln's occasional standing in for Judge Davis during court appearances.Law Office: Data: Misc.Folder 147505314Scope and ContentsA collection of primary and secondary source research dealing with various topics about Lincoln's time as a lawyer.ScriptsFolder 1575054May 197615Scope and ContentsA collection of firsts drafts of scripts of presentations and shows dealing with Lincoln during his time as a lawyer.New Salem Data: General DescriptionFolder 167505516Scope and ContentsA collection of secondary source research which serves to give a general description of New Salem during Lincoln's time.New Salem Data: FarmingFolder 177505617Scope and ContentsA collection of primary source research dealing with the farming of New Salem during Lincoln's time.New Salem Data: ReligionFolder 187505718Scope and ContentsA collection of primary source research on the religion at New Salem during Lincoln's time.New Salem Data: SchoolsFolder 197505819Scope and ContentsA collection  of primary source research on schools in New Salem during Lincoln's time.New Salem Data: TemperanceFolder 207505920Scope and ContentsA collection of primary source research on the temperance movement in New Salem during Lincoln's time.Box 2Box 275060New Salem Data: PetersburgFolder 1750611Scope and ContentsA collection of primary source research on the town of Petersburg, IL during Lincoln's time.New Salem Data: Intellectual Life, Literature SocietyFolder 2750622Scope and ContentsA collection of primary source research on the intellectual life in New Salem during Lincoln's time.New Salem Data: Misc.Folder 3750633Scope and ContentsA collection of primary source research on New Salem dealing with a variety of topics.New Salem Data: FinanceFolder 4750644Scope and ContentsA collection of secondary source research detailing Lincoln's personal finances while living in New Salem.New Salem Data: Post OfficeFolder 5750655Scope and ContentsA collection of secondary source research on Lincoln's time as a postmaster in New Salem.New Salem Data: BlackFolder 6750666Scope and ContentsA collection of primary source research on African Americans in New Salem during Lincoln's time.New Salem Data: MillsFolder 7750677Scope and ContentsA collection of primary source research on mills in Sangamon County during Lincoln's time.New Salem Data: Land HoldingsFolder 8750698Scope and ContentsA collection of research detailing the ownership of land plots in New Salem during Lincoln's time.New Salem Data: AnecdotesFolder 9750709Scope and ContentsA collection of primary source anecdotes about Lincoln during his time at New Salem.New Salem Data: Black Hawk WarFolder 107507110Scope and ContentsA collection of statistical data about and an account of the Black Hawk War.New Salem Data: CabinsFolder 117507211Scope and ContentsA description of cabins at New Salem during the early 1830s, as well as a list of the residences of prominent members of the community.New Salem Data: ElectionsFolder 127507312Scope and ContentsA collection of primary source accounts of elections in New Salem that involved Lincoln.New Salem Data: Deep SnowFolder 137507413Scope and ContentsA secondary source article written about two important weather events that occurred during Lincoln's time at New Salem, "The Deep Snow," and "The Sudden Change."New Salem Characters: MiscFolder 147507514Scope and ContentsA collection of miscellaneous documents found at the beginning of this binder.New Salem Characters: CastFolder 157507615Scope and ContentsA collection of lists and general descriptions of New Salem historical figures.New Salem Characters: Jack ArmstrongFolder 167507716Scope and ContentsA collection of research and documents about Jack Armstrong and his time at New Salem.New Salem Characters: BerryFolder 177507817Scope and ContentsA collection of research concerning John Berry and his time ate New Salem.New Salem Characters: ClaryFolder 187507918Scope and ContentsA collection of research about John Clary and his time at New Salem.New Salem Characters: GrahmFolder 197508019Scope and ContentsA collection of research about Mentor Grahm and his time in New Salem.New Salem Characters: HillFolder 207508120Scope and ContentsA collection of research about Samuel Hill and his time at New Salem.New Salem Characters: KelsoFolder 217508221Scope and ContentsA collection of research about Jack Kelso and his time at New Salem.New Salem Characters: McNeilFolder 227508322Scope and ContentsA collection of research about John McNeil and his time in New Salem.New Salem Characters: OffuttFolder 237508423Scope and ContentsA collection of research about Denton Offutt and his time at New Salem.New Salem Characters: RutledgeFolder 247508524Scope and ContentsA collection of research about James Rutledge and his time in New Salem.News Salem Characters: WatkinsFolder 257508625Scope and ContentsA collection of research about Tom Watkins and his time in New Salem.New Salem Characters: Minor CharactersFolder 267508726Scope and ContentsA collection of research about a number of other historical individuals who lived in New Salem during Lincoln's time there.Box 3Box 375088Book Manuscript: Introductory InformationFolder 1750891976-19781Scope and ContentsA collection of correspondence and documents concerning the writing of a edited volume of articles dealing with Lincoln's contributions to America.Book Manuscript: MargonFolder 2750902Scope and ContentsA manuscript of the article "The Self-Made Man: The Lincoln Image and American Ideas of Success" by Arthur Margon.Book Manuscript: BorittFolder 3750913Scope and ContentsA manuscript of the article, "Lincoln and the Right to Rise" by G.S. Boritt.Book Manuscript: FerhrenbacherFolder 4750924Scope and ContentsA list of end-notes belonging to Ferhrenbacher's article.Book Manuscript: KeiserFolder 5750935Scope and ContentsA manuscript of the article "Lincoln and Politics: Vandalia to Chicago" by John Keiser.Book Manuscript: MorganFolder 6750946Scope and ContentsA manuscript of the article "Lincoln: Law, Politics and Public Morality" by Douglas Morgan.Book Manuscript: BaslerFolder 7750957Scope and ContentsA manuscript of the article "Lincoln, Blacks, and Women" by Roy P. Basler.Book Manuscript: FredricksonFolder 8750968Scope and ContentsA manuscript of the article "Abraham Lincoln and the Search for Order and Community in Mid-Nineteenth Century America" by George M. Fredrickson.Book Manuscript: SklarFolder 9750979Scope and ContentsA manuscript of the article "Female Strategies in Victorian Families" by Kathryn Kish Sklar.Book Manuscripts: BreisethFolder 107509810Scope and ContentsA manuscript of the article "Lincoln, Douglas and Springfield in the 1858 Campaign" by Christopher N. Breiseth.Book Manuscript: JohansenFolder 117509911Scope and ContentsA copy of the end notes used by Johansen in his article.Book Manuscript: CurrentFolder 127510012Scope and ContentsThe end notes used by Current in his article.Book Manuscript: BridgesFolder 137510113Scope and ContentsA manuscript of the article "Lincoln Reacts to the Civil War" by Roger D. Bridges.Book Manuscript: StroizerFolder 147510214Scope and ContentsA collection of photocopied pages from a book detailing the proper format in which to list notes and sources in an academic paper.

