<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.102/3Archon Finding Aid Title MC.102/3Sean BruceUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:17:31 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC102/3. Recycling Archives: Recycling Enterprises Inc. Collection
    MC.102/3
    1767
    
      1.00 folders
    
    1970-1979
    Date acquired: 04/23/2012
    1 folder
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Collection of materials related to the operations of Recycling Enterprises Inc. during the 1970s in Oxford, MA. This group is primarily composed of brochures and booklets advertising various aspects of recycling. Specific materials include a written correspondence, a recycling booklet directed at children, a flyer advocating for glass recycling, and a brochure dedicated to the house made of recycled materials.Dan Knapp and the Institute for Local Self Reliance are responsible for coordinating the collections of material related to recycling for donation to the UIS Archives.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Murray J. Fox  
  
    Correspondence
    Flyers/Brochures
    Photographs
  
  Recycling Enterprises Inc. Materials and DocumentsFolder 1749901970s1Letter from Murray J. Fox to Neil SeldmanItem 17499111Play: 30 Toys and Activities to MakeItem 274992197712Scope and ContentsA copy of a booklet designed to teach children how to make toys and activities out of recycled materials.Scrap Glass has Value!Item 37499313Scope and ContentsFlyer advocating for the recycling of glass. Also contains architectural diagrams of Recycling Enterprises, Inc.'s drop off stations and flyers meant to raise public awareness about recycling.Photo of Recycling Enterprises, Inc. Members at a ConventionItem 4749941970s14The Home that Recycling BuiltItem 5749951970s15Scope and ContentsBrochure on the methods used to build a home using recycled materials.

