<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.102/2Archon Finding Aid Title MC.102/2Sean BruceUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:17:33 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC102/2. Recycling Archives: Saratoga County Recycling Collection
    MC.102/2
    1766
    
      1.00 folders
    
    1988-1995
    Date acquired: 04/23/2012
    1 folder
  
  
    Scope and Contents
A collection of materials related to recycling projects in Saratoga County, NY during the late 1980s and 1990s. The contents serve to provide historical background on the recycling movement and its implementation in the county. Included are newspaper clippings, e-mail correspondences, a brochure, a mouse-pad, and a book cover.Dan Knapp and the Institute for Local Self Reliance are responsible for coordinating the collections of material related to recycling for donation to the UIS Archives.  
  
    Arrangement Note
By Subject  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Sally J. Sheldon  
  
    Newspaper Clippings
    Flyers/Brochures
    Correspondence
  
  Saratoga County Recycling Materials and DocumentsFolder 1749891988-19951Letter from Sally J. Sheldon to Neil SeldmanItem 17499611Scope and ContentsLetter containing a brief history of recycling in Saratoga County.Newspaper Clipping: County Starts Recycling Scrap MetalItem 2749972/25/198812Newspaper Clipping: County Residents Must Begin RecyclingItem 3749984/20/198813Newspaper Clipping: Saratoga Co. Recycling Off to Energetic StartItem 474999March 198914Newspaper Clipping: Spa County Has New Outles for Recycled NewspapersItem 57500011/6/198915Newspaper Clipping: Recycling Efforts put Saratoga Co. at Leading EdgeItem 67500111/19/198916Newspaper Clipping: Waste WatchersItem 7750024/2/199217Newspaper Clipping: Recycling Programs Vary Based on Community MakeupItem 8750034/6/199218Newspaper Clipping: Recycling of Tin Cans Has Long, Productive HistoryItem 9750044/13/199219Newspaper Clipping: Solid Waste and Recycling Education a Community EffortItem 107500510/25/1993110Newspaper Clipping: Lighten Up on Waste During this Holiday SeasonItem 117500611/22/1993111Newspaper Clipping: Saratoga County Could Adopt a Can-Do AttitudeItem 12750071/24/1994112Newspaper Clipping: Plastic Bottles by Any Other Name Can't Be Recycled in County - YetItem 13750082/28/1994113Newspaper Clipping: Hard Working Wroms, Junk Mail, and SafetyItem 14750096/6/1994114Newspaper Clipping: Race Course a Winner at RecyclingItem 15750107/25/1994115Newspaper Clipping: Programs Uses Worms to Teach CompostingItem 16750119/26/1994116Newspaper Clipping: Shredding Misconceptions About Disposal of Sensitive DocumentsItem 177501211/28/1994117Newspaper Clipping: Don't Just Chuck Your TreeItem 187501312/27/1994118Newspaper Clipping: County Can Now Recycle Office PaperItem 19750142/27/1995119Flyer: The Saratoga County Glass Pulverizing Facility, a.k.a. "Glassosaurus-Rex"Item 2075015120Book JacketItem 2175016121Scope and ContentsA book jacket advocating recycling. Tagline "Save Mother Earth, Recycle!" appears on front.Flyer: This is a Bunch of GarbageItem 2275017122Scope and ContentsFlyer identifying potentially recyclable materials.Mouse-padItem 2375018123Scope and ContentsA mouse-pad featuring Saratoga County's mascot for the glass pulverizing machine.

