<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.102/1Archon Finding Aid Title MC.102/1UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:17:36 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC102/1. Recycling Archives: Blue Mountain Center Interviews
    MC.102/1
    1765
    
      0.16 Cubic Feet
    
    2007
    Date acquired: 06/05/2011
    3 folders
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This disk contains a collection of interviews of recycling activists who met at the Blue Mountain Center at Blue Mountain Lake, New York on June 1-3, 2007. The interviews were held in a chain format with each interviewer/ interviewee pair switching roles and performing a second interview after the first. The participants include 14 prominent members of the recycling field with discussions held in 22 separate audio tracks. Each participant is asked a series of questions from an established list (a copy of the list is included in the inventory folder).The audio tracks contain extensive descriptions about the lives and careers of the participants. Specific focus is made on their involvement with a number of key topics in recycling, which include recycling as a social movement, the organization of recycling, landfills, waste energy and incineration, and personal opinions about the field and its future. Most participants also took the opportunity to relate a number of personal anecdotes about recycling and their involvement with it.The 22 digital recordings on the DVD are in both .MP3 and .DVF formats.Dan Knapp and the Institute for Local Self Reliance are responsible for coordinating the collections of material related to recycling for donation to the UIS Archives.Located in Audio/Visual Collection: #AV3293  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetically by first name of interviewee.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Neil Seldman  
  
    Audio CDs
    Correspondence
    Reports
  
  Box 1Box 174988Proposal: Oral History of RecyclingItem 274986May 31-June 4, 20072Scope and ContentsThe Gathering at Blue Mountain Center in the AdirondacksLetter from Neil SeldmanItem 374987June 5, 20113Scope and ContentsDetailing the Contents of the DVDRecycling Archives Interviews, Blue Mountain Center, NYDVD 174962June 1-3, 2007Interview, Armen Stepanian, by Dan KnappItem 174963June 1, 20071Scope and ContentsThis is an account of Stepanian's life with an emphasis on his involvement in the recycling industry. The majority of the interview deals with the challenges he faced while founding and running one of the first curb-side pick-up recycling programs in the US. It also includes a large number of details about his personal life and the difficulties he suffered through as a result of his life-long dedication to environmentalism. Play time: 1:16:42.Interview, Bert Ball, by Maurice Sampson (Part 1)Item 274965June 20072Scope and ContentsThis interview details Ball's experiences in starting and running material reuse programs in the Los Angeles area. It includes details about his current company LA Shares, which focuses on obtaining donated material to redistribute to other organizations for profit. The length of the track is peppered with personal insight from Ball detailing his personal opinions and observations about the field of recycling and reuse. Play time: 23:08.Interview, Bert Ball, by Maurice Sampson (Part 2)Item 374966June 20073Scope and ContentsThe second portion of the original interview. Includes mention of Ball's major contributions to the recycling field. The track concludes with his predictions on the future of both his own business and the industry in general. Play time: 7:19.Interview, Brenda Platt, by Jon Michael HulsItem 474967June 20074Scope and ContentsThis track details the career of Platt, who served as the co-director of the Institute for Local Self-Reliance in Washington, D.C. at the time of the interview. It includes an explanation of how she was inspired to enter the field and it covers her various experiences while working in recycling. One of the most unifying aspects of her account is her lifelong battle against waste energy (a.k.a. garbage incineration as a form of energy production.) Play time 1:03:21.Interview, Dan Knapp, by Armen StepanianItem 574968June 1, 20075Scope and ContentsHere Knapp describes his early experiences in environmentalism, his work teaching at Sangamon State University, and his reasons for pursuing a career in recycling. Much of the track is dedicated to his work founding and running Urban Ore, a materials salvage and reuse company, which later also became a second-hand store for recovered goods. Play time: 1:41:49.Interview, David Tam, by Rick Anthony (Part 1)Item 674969June 20076Scope and ContentsTam explores his volatile life in recycling and his involvement with the socialist movement in America. It covers, in great depth, his focus on instituting policies for and pushing through legislation on recycling and recycling programs. Play time: 1:27:08.Interview, David Tam, by Rick Anthony (Part 2)Item 774970June 20077Scope and ContentsCreated as a supplement to the original interview. This section primarily deals with Tam's most important mentor, Michael Harrington, writer of "The Other America." Also he explores his involvement with the establishment and management of local recycling-related organizations. Play time: 27:15.Interview, David Tam, by Rick Anthony (Part 3)Item 874971June 20078Scope and ContentsCreated as a supplement to the supplement of the original interview. Tam explains the inner workings of and his involvement with the Alameda County Recycling Board, www.stopwaste.org, and Waste Management Initiative. Play time: 25:46.Interview, Gary Liss, by Tanya Levy (Part 1)Item 974972June 3, 20079Scope and ContentsDetails of Liss's early experiences in recycling following Earth Day 1970 and how he first got into recycling. He focuses on his involvement with a number of zero waste and sustainability programs. Play time: 8:05.Interview, Gary Liss, by Tanya Levy (Part 2)Item 1074973June 3, 200710Scope and ContentsCovers Liss's major experiences in his career in recycling and his involvement with the policy and programmatic side of the movement. Here he explains his major contributions to the field, including the founding of a large number of organizations. He concludes by restating his current advocacy for zero-waste initiatives. Play time: 21:53.Interview, Gary Liss, by Tanya Levy (Part 3)Item 1174974June 3, 200711Scope and ContentsThis section primarily details Liss's foreign travels and his involvement with landfills. Here he expresses his personal beliefs on the practice of landfilling and his predictions about the future of the industry. Play time: 8:12.Interview, Gary Liss, by Tanya Levy (Part 4)Item 1274975June 3, 200712Scope and ContentsLiss details his experiences with incinerators, the problems of recycling programs, and solid waste management programs. Also includes a discussion of his experiences with organized crime when dealing with waste management. He concludes with his predictions on the future. Play time: 37:55.Interview, Gretchen Brewer, by Linda KnappItem 1374976June 200713Scope and ContentsBrewer describes her experiences in recycling and her involvement on the regulatory side of the industry as a regional planner for the Massachusetts Department of Environmental Protection. She also explains her personal beliefs on a number of recycling-related topics, such as incinerators, zero-waste, composting, environmental planning, and recycling legislation. Play time: 57:39.Interview, Jon Michael Huls, by Brenda PlattItem 1474977June 200714Scope and ContentsHuls recounts his recycling work in Southern California and his advocacy for zero waste initiatives. Includes mention of work done for the Institute for Local Self-Reliance and Atlantic City. Also details the organizations he helped found and the travelling he has done while working in the field. Play time: 1:02:50.Interview, Laura Anthony, by Penny HansenItem 1574978June 200715Scope and ContentsAnthony describes her involvement in environmental volunteer groups and her work in recycling education. This account includes details of Anthony's life prior to her relatively recent decision to pursue recycling as her career. Play time 21:19.Interview, Linda Knapp, by Gretchen BrewerItem 1674979June 200716Scope and ContentsThe recounting of Knapp's work in recycling, sustainability, alternative energy, and energy conservation. Also included is an account of her time as a Senior Program Manager for the Institute for Local Self Reliance, her work in building materials recovery in Philadelphia, PA, and her experience in organizing and connecting disparate recycling groups. Play time: 51:47.Interview, Maurice Sampson, by Bert BallItem 1774980June 200717Scope and ContentsDetails of Sampson's work as owner of the Mitch Recycling Company, first recycling coordinator for the city of Philadelphia, and founder of numerous recycling organizations. Sampson, a self-described "enabler," recounts how much of his career was spent aiding recycling organizations and travelling for the purpose of information dissemination and research. Play time: 30:44.Interview, Penny Hansen, by Laura AnthonyItem 1874981June 200718Scope and ContentsHansen, now retired, details her experiences working in environmentalism with specific emphasis on the 8 years she served as the recycling coordinator for the Environmental Protection Agency. Included are accounts of her work establishing recycling programs in over 200 cities, writing the procurement guidelines for recycling producers, and generating motivation and support for recycling initiatives. Play time: 39:35.Interview, Rick Anthony, by David Tam (Part 1)Item 1974982June 200719Scope and ContentsThis section deals with Anthony's start in environmentalism as part of the anti-war movement in the 1960s. It also includes a general description of his work with recycling organizations and on his dealings with local governments. Play time: 26:22.Interview, Rick Anthony, by David Tam (Part 2)Item 2074983June 200720Scope and ContentsThis section includes Anthony's explanation of his stance on a number of recycling related issues, such as incineration, zero waste initiatives, and landfills. The other major foci of this section is Anthony's difficult relationship with local governments, his involvement in the creation of important international recycling organizations like the International Zero Waste Initiative, and his beliefs on the future of recycling. Play time: 1:40:36.Interview, Tanya Levy, by Gary Liss (Part 1)Item 2174984June 200721Scope and ContentsThis section includes the major details of Levy's career in recycling as a recycling programmer for the city of Berkley and recycling specialist for the California Department of Conservation. She goes on to explain her specialization in recycling policy and legislation. It also includes frequent mention of her personal views on waste energy and her efforts to combat its implementation on a number of occasions. Play time: 38:25.Interview, Tanya Levy, by Gary Liss (Part 2)Item 2274985June 200722Scope and ContentsThis section is devoted to Levy's experiences in travel, dealing with intimidation and violence directed at recyclers, and her involvement in indirectly doubling the amount of recycled paper used in North America. It also includes a brief mention of her current work as the owner of Collaborative Consumption, a company dedicated to advancing a low-consumption, resource sharing economy. Play time 1:11:16.

