<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>P.Catchpole, Series IIIArchon Finding Aid Title P.Catchpole, Series IIIUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:17:38 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    P/Catchpole. Mattilou Catchpole, Personal Papers, Series III
    
      Catchpole, Mattilou
    
    P.Catchpole, Series III
    1763
    
      0.66 Cubic Feet
    
    1938-2012
    Date acquired: 08/22/2012
    1
    2
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Papers of Mattilou Catchpole, Professor Emeritus at UIS. Catchpole served as director of Sangamon State's Nurse Anesthesia and Nurse Anesthesia Completion programs (1978-1991), within the School of Health and Human Services. Catchpole was employed as associate professor in the School of Liberal Arts and Sciences (1991-1994) and later as an adjunct instructor, teaching courses in the Women's Studies program (WMS). Materials include educational documents, program surveys, self-authored manuscripts and published papers, international volunteer reports, speaking engagement presentations, correspondences, a thesis proposal, research notes, a dissertation copy, an application for tenure, a photo album, and an obituary. Reports and pictures detailing her work in developing countries and her management of international nursing study programs are included.  
  
    Arrangement Note
By Subject  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Transfer from Lincoln Library-SVC.  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Donated by Floyd and Janine Catchpole.  
  Box 1Box 174736Caps and CapesFolder 17473719481Scope and ContentsNurse Yearbook, Charity Harbor School of NursingEducational Documents and TranscriptsFolder 2747381957-19832Nurse Anesthesia Refresher Program: NARP BusinessFolder 3747391989-19903Nurse Anesthesia Refresher Program: A Survey of Texts for Nurse Anesthesia Programs in 1999Folder 47474019994American Association of Nurse AnesthesistsFolder 5747411989-20025Health Volunteers Overseas ReportsFolder 6747421996-20056Health Volunteers Overseas GuyanaFolder 7747431994-19977LettersFolder 8747441990-19978Papers: Acid Base Balance (NARP)Folder 97474519869Papers: DocumentationFolder 1074746n.d.10Papers: Pharmacodynamics...Folder 1174747199111Papers: Women's Health in ChinaFolder 1274748n.d.12PublicationsFolder 13747491972-200213Research Papers for Publication: Women and Health, "The Differential Treatment…Folder 1474750199514Research Papers for Publication: Journal of Emergency Nursing, "The Differential Treatment…Folder 1574751199615Research Papers for Publication: American Journal of Emergency Medicine, "The Differential Treatment…Folder 16747521994-199516International U.N. Meetings of Women 1995: Survey conducted at 4th International UN conference on Women and DiscussionFolder 17747531995174th International U.N. Meetings of Women 1995: Paper, Twenty Eight Women Plus OneFolder 1874754199518Uganda Women's World Congress, 2002: "The Coming of Age"Folder 1974755200219Uganda Women's World Congress, 2002: UgandaFolder 2074756200220Rotary ClubFolder 21747572003-200821Rotary: EikoFolder 2274758199322Box 2Box 274759Speaking EngagementsFolder 17476019991Speaking EngagementsFolder 274761Oct. 19872Speaking Engagements: Fall Assembly of StatesFolder 374762Nov 8, 20023Speaking Engagements: "Pharmacokinetics and Pharmacodynamics of Intermediate Acting Muscle Relaxants"Folder 47476319874Speaking Engagements: IndianaFolder 574764April 5-6, 19865Speaking Engagements: HIV or "Something" Positive? What Now?Folder 67476519926Speaking Engagements: MissouriFolder 774766Oct. 8, 19887Speaking Engagements: OklahomaFolder 874767Oct. 25-26, 19868Speaking Engagements: Oklahoma Anesthesia Nurse AssociationFolder 974768Nov 11-13, 19889Speaking Engagements: Panel American Association of Nurse Anesthesists, ChicagoFolder 1074769200010Speaking Engagements: Certified Registered Nurse Association ForumFolder 1174770200011University of Illinois Springfield: AwardsFolder 1274771n.d.12University of Illinois Springfield: Misc.Folder 1374772n.d.13Master's Thesis: Research ProposalFolder 1474773n.d.14University of Illinois Springfield: My Ph.D. ResearchFolder 1574774198415Southern Illinois University at Carbondale: Original DissertationFolder 1674775198316Scope and Contents"Evaluation of Methods Used to Reduce Patient Stress as Measured by Plasma Catecholamine Levels Prior to Surgery"Application for TenureFolder 1774776198317ObituaryFolder 1874777201218Photo AlbumFolder 1974778n.d.19Scope and ContentsAlbum containing a series of photos from international trips

