<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.101Archon Finding Aid Title MC.101Sean Bruce, Thomas J WoodUIS Archives/Special Collections12/20/2012Archives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:17:45 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC101. W. Russell Arrington Papers
    
      Arrington, W. Russell
    
    MC.101
    1761
    
      4.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1946-1979
    Date acquired: 05/17/2012
    1
    2
    3
    4
    5
    6
    7
    Scrapbooks
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The W. Russell Arrington gift consists of 21 scrapbooks dating from 1946 to 1979, including original newspaper clippings, photographs, letters, programs, and other documents and memorabilia relating to the career of W. Russell Arrington in the Illinois House of Representatives (1945-1954) and Senate (1955-1972).  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Michael Arrington  
  
    Accruals and Additions
The empty scrapbooks are all boxed separately and located in Room 140C.  
  
    Processing Information
When received, most of the original scrapbooks were in poor condition due to highly acidic and brittle pages. Many of the contents had come loose from the pages. The newspaper clippings were acidic and brittle and the correspondence, photographs and other material in the scrapbooks were suffering from acid migration from the scrapbook pages and newsclippings.We scanned the scrapbooks in their original condition to preserve their original appearance and arrangement. Then, we removed the newspaper clippings that were loose to acid-free envelops and other types of material to acid-free folders and boxes. We kept the original scrapbooks because some newspaper clippings were glued to the pages and could not be removed without damage.  
  
    Illinois--politics and government
    Scrapbook
    Correspondence
    Awards
    Flyers/Brochures
    Journal Articles
    Newspaper Clippings
    Photocopies
    Photographs
    Memorabilia
    Press Releases
    Speeches
  
  Arrington ScrapbooksSeries 174721ScrapbookItem 1746711946-19481Scope and Contents14 1/2" x 12." 54 pages.ScrapbookItem 2746721949-19512Scope and Contents14" x 12." Cover missing. 84 pages.ScrapbookItem 3746731951-19553Scope and Contents15" x 13." Cover missing. 202 pages.ScrapbookItem 4746741956-19574Scope and Contents17" x 18" 119 pages.ScrapbookItem 5746751958-19605Scope and Contents16 1/2" x 18." Labeled "January 16, 1958, to December 31, 1960, Inclusive." 207 pages.ScrapbookItem 6746761961-19626Scope and Contents16 1/2" x 18 1/2." Labeled "January 1, 1961 to December 31, 1962." 162 pages.ScrapbookItem 7746771963-19647Scope and Contents17" x 18 1/2." Labeled "January 1, 1963 to December 31, 1964" 162 pages.ScrapbookItem 87467819658Scope and Contents17" x 18" Labeled "January 1, 1965 to June 30, 1965." 222 pages.ScrapbookItem 97467919659Scope and Contents16 1/2" x 18." Labeled- "July 1, 1965 to December 31, 1965" 122 pages.ScrapbookItem 1074680196610Scope and Contents16 1/2" x 18."Labeled- "January 1, 1966 to December 30, 1966" 284 pages.ScrapbookItem 1174681196711Scope and Contents16 1/2" x 18 1/2." Labeled "Senator W. Russell Arrington Scrapbook January 1, 1967- December 31, 1967" 356 pages.ScrapbookItem 1274682196812Scope and Contents16 1/2" x 18." Labeled- "Senator W. Russell Arrington Scrapbook January 1, 1968- December 31, 1968." 204 pages.ScrapbookItem 1374683196913Scope and Contents16 1/2" x 18." Labeled "January ,1969 to December, 1969." 368 pages.ScrapbookItem 1474684197014Scope and Contents16 1/2" x 18 1/2." Labeled- "January, 1970 to December, 1970." 302 pages.ScrapbookItem 1574685197115Scope and Contents16 1/2" x 18 1/2." Labeled "January, 1971 to December, 1971." 118 pages.ScrapbookItem 1674686197216Scope and Contents16 1/2" x 18 1/2." Labeled "January 1972 to December, 1972." 89 pages.ScrapbookItem 1774687197317Scope and Contents16 1/2" x 18 1/2." Labeled "January 1973 to December 1973." 108 pages.ScrapbookItem 1874688197418Scope and Contents16 1/2" x 18 1/2." Labeled "January 1974 to December 1974." 126 pages.ScrapbookItem 1974689197519Scope and Contents17" x 18 1/2." Labeled "January, 1975 to December, 1975." 116 pages.ScrapbookItem 20746901976-197720Scope and Contents17" x 18 1/2." Labeled "1976 January-December through 1977 January-December." 66 pages.ScrapbookItem 21746911978-197921Scope and Contents17" x 19." Labeled "January-December 1978 and 1979" 35 pages.Arrington Scrapbooks: Boxed MaterialsSeries 275124Scope and ContentsA collection of materials removed from the scrapbooks for preservation.Box 1Box 175125Scrapbook 1, pp. 5-14Folder 175126May-September 19481Scope and ContentsCareer as a representative. Includes news accounts of his election and involvement in the voting process; correspondences between Arrington and supporters, voting guides, and newspaper ads.Scrapbook 1, pp. 16-35Folder 275127December 1946-December 19502Scope and ContentsCareer as a representative. Inclusions: seating plan for the House of Representatives 1945-1946, photographs of Arrington during functions, and a 64th General Assembly member ribbon.Scrapbook 1, pp. 38-54Folder 375128September 1947-March 19483Scope and ContentsCareer as a representative. Inclusions: magazine articles, a report on the 65th General Assembly, a Kwanis International guest speaker certificate, a two printed post cards.Scrapbook 2, pp. ?Folder 475129November 19504Scope and ContentsA letter from Lawrence B. Perkins congratulating Arrington on his victory in the election. Held in separate folder because original location is unknown.Scrapbook 2, pp. 3Folder 575130October 19485Scope and ContentsElection article in which Arrington is shown as a replacement candidate for the position of director. Organization unknown. Held in separate folder to reduce acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 5Folder 675131November 19486Scope and ContentsMagazine articles detailing Arrington's actions as the Vice President and General Counsel of the Combined Insurance Company of America. Kept in separate folder to reduce acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 7Folder 775133February 19497Scope and ContentsLetter to Arrington complementing him on an excellent presentation. Kept in separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 8Folder 875132February 19498Scope and ContentsLetter to Arrington thanking him for his speaking at a meeting in Urbana. Kept in separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 9Folder 975134February 19499Scope and ContentsLetter thanking Arrington for a presentation given at a law school. Kept in separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 2Folder 1075135194910Scope and ContentsPamphlets supporting Arrington for re-election and the program for a spelling bee involving Arrington's daughter. Kept in a separate folder to reduce acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 20Folder 1175136May 194911Scope and ContentsLetter thanking Arrington for the presentation he gave at the League of Women Voters convention. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 25Folder 1275137July 194912Scope and ContentsLetter thanking Arrington for his stand on a House of Representatives bill. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 26Folder 1375138July 194913Scope and ContentsA letter thanking Arrington for his work with an Unemployment bill. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 28Folder 147513914Scope and ContentsPhotograph of Arrington and others watching the Governor sign a bill into law. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 30Folder 1575140July 194915Scope and ContentsLetter thanking Arrington for his work during the 66th General Assembly. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 31Folder 1675141June 194916Scope and ContentsLetter thanking Arrington for his courteous consideration brought up by the Insurance Committee of the House. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 34Folder 1775142194917Scope and ContentsMagazine article detailing the signing of a bill for five-day week for banks in Illinois. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 35Folder 1875143July 194918Scope and ContentsA letter thanking Arrington for his support of the House Bill 663. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 36Folder 1975144194919Scope and ContentsPhoto of Arrington and others posing with golf clubs. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 38Folder 2075145194920Scope and ContentsPostcard inviting property owners of Arrington's district to hear him speak. Kept in separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 39Folder 2175146October 194921Scope and ContentsExcerpt from the Illinois Bar Journal featuring an article written by Arrington. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 41Folder 2275147November 194922Scope and ContentsA letter from the Illinois Bar Journal thanking Arrington for his article. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 42Folder 2375148November 194923Scope and ContentsLetter thanking Arrington for addressing a meeting. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 47Folder 2475149February 195024Scope and ContentsA letter congratulating Arrington on the article he wrote for the University of Illinois Law Forum on Jurisdictional Aspects of Divorce, Annulment and Separate Maintenance. Kept in separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 48Folder 2575150March 195025Scope and ContentsLetter from the Retail Liquor Dealers' Protective Association of Illinois stating their endorsement of Arrington for election. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 50Folder 2675151March 195026Scope and ContentsProgram for the Illinois Youth and Government Pre-Legislative Assembly. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 51Folder 2775152195027Scope and ContentsLetter requesting support for Arrington's election campaign. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 52Folder 2875153April 195028Scope and ContentsLetter stating that the Directors of the Better Government Association recommended Arrington for election. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 53Folder 2975154April 195029Scope and ContentsA letter from the Chicago Crime Commission urging people to vote and supporting Arrington and others for their offices. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 54Folder 3075155March 195030Scope and ContentsA letter from the Chicago Crime Commission to Illinois representatives. Speaks of copies of bills they want passed and the desire for comments on the bills. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 55Folder 3175156March 195031Scope and ContentsA report on the outgoing members of the 66th General Assembly. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 58Folder 3275157April 195032Scope and ContentsA letter from the Interprofessional Committee of Physicians, Dentists and Pharmacists detailing their desire to elect politicians to combat socialism. Supports Arrington and others. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 61Folder 3375158March 195033Scope and ContentsA memorandum from two pharmacists suggesting that other pharmacists support Arrington and other candidates in the election. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 63Folder 3475159March 195034Scope and ContentsLetter from the Interprofessional Committee of Physicians, Dentists, and Pharmacists stating their endorsement of Arrington in the election. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 2, pp. 64-82Folder 3575160May-October 195035Scope and ContentsCampaign for re-election. Inclusions: a name tag, endorsement letters, a photograph of Arrington and others posing on a golf course, and a banquet program.Scrapbook 2, Loose FragmentsFolder 367516136Scope and ContentsLoose clippings and fragments that may have fallen out of Scrapbook 2, in poor condition.Scrapbook 3, pp. 1-39Folder 3775162March-June 195137Scope and ContentsLegislative actions. Inclusions: thank you letters for Arrington's appearance at functions, a photocopy of a plaque in Latin, and copies of The Watchdog, a political newsletter.Scrapbook 3, pp. 40-45Folder 3875163May-July 195138Scope and ContentsInvolvement in a variety of engagements and legislation. Inclusions: several correspondences and program for the Seventh Annual Meeting of the National Association of Independent Insurers.Scrapbook 3, pp. 46-58Folder 3975164August-November 195139Scope and ContentsInclusions: political advertisements, correspondences, a copy of the Illinois Bar Journal form Oct. 1951, and a list of necessary equipment for air raid wardens.Scrapbook 3, pp. 59-74Folder 4075165November 195140Scope and ContentsInvolvement in groups and committees outside of the legislature. Inclusions: an excerpt from the proceedings of the National Association of Independent Insurers annual convention, photographs of the convention, and letters.Scrapbook 3, pp. 75-94Folder 4175166January-March 195241Scope and ContentsInclusions: several correspondences and a voting guide.Scrapbook 3, pp. 91-114Folder 4275167March-October 195242Scope and ContentsPrograms and groups outside of the legislature. Inclusions: re-election ad, a certificate of appreciations from the Boy Scouts of America, and the program for the 34th annual meeting of the Illinois State Chamber of Commerce.Scrapbook 3, pp. 115-128Folder 4375168December 1951-April 195343Scope and ContentsMiscellaneous articles, documents, letters, and photographs. Inclusions: a copy of the proposed revision of Article 9 of the Illinois Constitution, discussion of senatorial redistricting, and correspondences.Scrapbook 3, pp. 131-157Folder 4475169May-October 195344Scope and ContentsLegislative achievements. Inclusions: photographs of Arrington and other legislators, letters recognizing Arrington for activities in the legislature, and an account of the University of Illinois class of 1928's reunion.Scrapbook 3, pp. 158-172Folder 4575170October 1953-September 195445Scope and ContentsEnd of his career as a representative. Inclusions: a letter suggesting that Arrington take a deceased senator's place on the ballot, a number of letters offering support for his senatorial campaign, and a business card from Harry H. Fuller, manager of the mid-western branch of the National Bureau of Casualty Underwriters.Scrapbook 3, p. 174-202Folder 46751711954-195546Scope and ContentsEarly senate career. Inclusions: photograph of Arrington and others at a celebratory dinner, program and materials from the 11th annual meeting of the National Association of Independent Insurers, and a letter from the Northwest Men's Club announcing a speech by Arrington.Scrapbook 3, Loose FragmentsFolder 477517247Scope and ContentsLoose clippings and fragments believed to have come from scrapbook 3Scrapbook 4, pp. 1-7Folder 4875173March 1954-February 195648Scope and ContentsSenate career. Inclusions: a certificate of membership from the American Bar Association, excerpt from a series of speeches given at the National Association of Independent Insurers meeting in 1955 including one by Arrington, and a series of photographs with Arrington and others.Scrapbook 4, pp. 10-21Folder 4975174June-October 195649Scope and ContentsRe- election efforts. Inclusions: a photo of the All Chicago Citizens Committee and correspondences offering support to Arrington in the election.Scrapbook 4, pp. 27-37Folder 5075175November 195650Scope and ContentsVictory in the election. Inclusions: congratulation letters, election advertisements, and articles discussing Arrington's support of a constitutional amendment.Scrapbook 4, pp. 39-55Folder 5175176January-March 195751Scope and ContentsFollowing his re-election into the senate. Inclusions: photo of Arrington addressing the New Members dinner of the General Assembly of Illinois, an invitation to the inaugural ceremonies for the state officers elect, and correspondences thanking Arrington for his appearances.Scrapbook 4, pp. 60-82Folder 5275177April-May 195752Scope and ContentsPresentations given by Arrington. Inclusions: thank you letters for Arrington's presentations, photographs of Arrington at the functions, and an article detailing his work sponsoring a bill.Scrapbook 4, pp. 99Folder 5375178June-July 195753Scope and ContentsLetters and correspondences that thank Arrington for his work in defeating a bill. Inclusion: a journal article that specifically lists a number of Arrington's accomplishments.Scrapbook 4, pp. 94-113Folder 5475179May-September 195754Scope and ContentsSimilar to the previously folder. Letters and articles congratulating/thanking Arrington for his work in resisting a bill. Inclusions: a program for the National Association of Insurance Commissioners Meeting of Zone IV, a program for 39th annual meeting of the Illinois Chamber of Commerce, and highlights of a public address given by Arrington.Scrapbook 4, pp. 115-119Folder 5575180July 195755Scope and ContentsWork in the adoption of a judicial amendment. Inclusions: a letter thanking Arrington for his work, and Taxpayers' Federation Newsletters.Box 2Box 275181Scrapbook 5, pp. 2-18Folder 175182January-May 19581Scope and ContentsInvitation to and participation in a number of private functions. Inclusions: a series of photographs (some of which are candid) of Arrington participating in said functions, invitations to functions, and programs for the activities at the functions.Scrapbook 5, pp. 21-30Folder 275183September-November 19582Scope and ContentsActivities as a legislator during the fall of 1958. Inclusions: political advertisement showing Arrington supporting judicial amendment, a ticket to the St. Clair County Taxpayers Association Trustee-Membership Meeting, and a magazine ad announcing Arrington's speech at the meeting.Scrapbook 5, pp. 31-39Folder 375184November-December 19583Scope and ContentsActivities in the late autumn/early winter of 1958. Inclusions: announcement flier for the Annual Luncheon Meeting of the Insurance Federation of Illinois featuring Arrington as a speaker, a photograph of Arrington at the meeting, and letters thanking Arrington for his actions in the Senate.Scrapbook 5, pp. 54-55Folder 475185April 19594Scope and ContentsLetters congratulating Arrington on opposing the extension of Unemployment Compensation benefits to 39 weeks. Inclusion: a program from the Wilmette Baptist Church.Scrapbook 5, pp. 40-64Folder 575186January-May 19595Scope and ContentsActivities during the early part of 1959. Inclusions: a news bulletin from the Skokie Valley Industrial Association announcing a speech by Arrington, a program for the League Legislative Conference, and a photograph of Arrington endorsing a giant petition on the judicial amendment with a giant pencil.Scrapbook 5, pp. 66-84Folder 675187May-August 19596Scope and ContentsActions as a legislator during the summer of 1959. Inclusions: a certificate of membership from Optimist International, a large number of letters expressing gratitude for Arrington's actions, and an excerpt from the messages to the House of Representatives on June 11, 1959.Scrapbook 5, pp. 85-95Folder 775188July-August 19597Scope and ContentsActivities during the late summer/early autumn of 1959. Inclusions: a formal document from the city of Evanston commending Arrington, a collection of materials relating to Arrington's trip to Hawaii in September, and a congressional ballot for Hawaii.Scrapbook 5, pp. 97-109Folder 875189August-October 19598Scope and ContentsTrip to Hawaii and letters of thanks for activities in the legislature. Inclusions: a certificate of greeting from the County of Hawaii, a photograph of Arrington at a function in Hawaii, an announcement of speech by Arrington at the Union League Club of Chicago.Scrapbook 5, pp. 111-126Folder 975190September-November 19599Scope and ContentsActivities during the fall of 1959. Inclusions: a fall meeting program for the Illinois Canners Association, photographs of Arrington and others, and list of people participating in the luncheon for Honorable James P. Mitchell, Secretary of Labor.Scrapbook 5, pp. 131-138Folder 1075191January 196010Scope and ContentsActions as a legislator. First signs of re-election thoughts show up here. Inclusion: article from Illinois Aviation in which a photo of Arrington appears while at the graduation ceremony for a new class of pilots.Scrapbook 5, pp. 139Folder 1175192January 196011Scope and ContentsMinutes from the Illinois Conference of Legislation from January 9, 1960. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 5, pp. 145Folder 1275193January 196012Scope and ContentsA continuation of the previous folder. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 5, pp. 140-158Folder 1375194January-March 196013Scope and ContentsParticipation in a number of speeches and the beginnings of a re-election campaign. Inclusions: program from the Women's Republican Club of Evanston listing Arrington as a speaker, letters thanking Arrington for his appearances as well as ones offering support in the coming election, and part of newsletter to the General Assembly from the Illinois Legislative Council.Scrapbook 5, pp. 155Folder 1475195March 196014Scope and ContentsCopies of two letters attempting to garner support for Arrington during the election. Kept in a separate folder to reduce acid absorption.Scrapbook 5, pp. 160-172Folder 1575196March-April 196015Scope and ContentsRe-election campaign. Inclusions: a large number of letters offering support for Arrington in the election, a few political ads supporting Arrington, and a Women's Republican Club of Evanston voting guide.Scrapbook 5, pp. 177-189Folder 1675197May-September 196016Scope and ContentsWork as a legislator, specifically focuses involvement with the relief efforts for unemployment. Inclusions: a program for the 13th annual meeting of the National Legislative Conference, a series of letters expressing gratitude to Arrington for his work, and a few letters discussing changes in the re-election campaign.Scrapbook 5, pp. 190-199Folder 1775198August-November 196017Scope and ContentsVariety of topics, most relevant is his continuing re-election campaign, involvement in certain functions, and his legislative work. Inclusions: letters offering support in the coming election, an invitation for Mrs. Arrington (complete with envelope) to a reception honoring Mrs. William G. Stratton, and a program for the Joint Annual Conference of the Illinois Association of Park Districts and the Illinois Recreation Association.Scrapbook 5, pp. 200-207Folder 1875199November-December 196018Scope and ContentsCongratulatory letters for a successful re-election. Inclusions: a Christmas letter from the Executive Committee of the Combined Group of Companies of which Arrington was a part of, and an article in which Arrington describes his personal life.Scrapbook 6, pp. 2-28Folder 1975200January-March 196119Scope and ContentsActivities during the first quarter of 1961. Inclusions: a program for the Palm Sunday service at Trinity Lutheran Church in Evanston, a couple copies of the Illinois Tax Facts newsletter, and an advertisement stating Arrington's opinion on Illinois's financial condition.Scrapbook 6, pp. 34-57Folder 2075201April-May 196120Scope and ContentsActivities as a legislator and his participation in several functions. Inclusions: letters expressing gratitude for Arrington meeting the writers privately, a special bulletin from The Union League Club of Chicago, and an article in which Arrington states his opinion on election law reform.Scrapbook 6, pp. 58-99Folder 2175202June-July 196121Scope and ContentsWork as a legislator, specifically focusing on work with the economy. Inclusions: issues of Heard and Seen featuring blurbs written by Arrington, letters of congratulations and gratitude for the work Arrington did, and a magazine article describing how (legally) June had a 31st day in Illinois.Scrapbook 6, pp. 98-107Folder 2275203June-August 196122Scope and ContentsLetters to Arrington dealing with a number of topics, revolved around praising him in some way.Scrapbook 6, pp. 108-144Folder 2375204December 1961-March 196223Scope and ContentsActions as a legislator during this time period. Inclusions: a letter which stated Arrington's refusal to participate in the national senatorial campaign, an announcement for the Civic League's 19th annual meeting, and a photograph of Arrington and other legislators.Scrapbook 6, pp. 148-162Folder 2475205March-October 196224Scope and ContentsInvolvement in a number of functions during this time period. Inclusions: a copy of the City Club Bulletin announcing a speech made by Arrington, an invitation to a luncheon in which Arrington gave a speech on court reform, and letters thanking Arrington for his appearances.Scrapbook 7, pp. 1-11Folder 2575206February 196325Scope and ContentsSpeeches given in February of 1963. Inclusions: a copy of the Retail News Briefs featuring a section devoted to one of Arrington's speeches, photographs of Arrington participating in speeches, and printed descriptions of the above photographs.Scrapbook 7, pp. 26Folder 2675207March-May 196326Scope and ContentsCopies of two articles written about legislation Arrington was involved in. Kept in a separate folder to reduce acid absorption.Scrapbook 7, pp. 14-31Folder 2775208February-March 196327Scope and ContentsActions as a legislator, specifically revolving around a bill supported by Arrington that would deny pay to striking workers. Inclusions: a published rebuttal to remarks made by Arrington on the proposed bill, letters expressing support and then congratulations for the passing of the bill, and an article on the successful passing of the election board bill.Scrapbook 7, pp. 38Folder 2875209February-March 196328Scope and ContentsNewspaper clippings dealing with a bill proposed by Arrington which would expand protection from uninsured drivers. Kept in a separate folder to reduce acid absorption.Scrapbook 7, pp. 35-74Folder 2975210March-July 196329Scope and ContentsWork as a legislator during this time period. Inclusions: a letter from a Democrat expressing gratitude, a photo of Arrington and others at a dinner function, and a letter mentioning a commemorative pen to celebrate the sign of a bill into law.Scrapbook 7, pp. 78-91Folder 3075211July-December 196330Scope and ContentsActivities in the Senate. Inclusions: several letters expressing gratitude for Arrington's actions, and a copy of the Illinois Political Reporter which named Arrington and two others as the most effective senators.Scrapbook 7, pp. 93Folder 3175212196331Scope and ContentsA card sent by a child named Kurt expressing positive feelings for Arrington. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 7, pp. 105Folder 3275213196332Scope and ContentsBirthday card to Arrington from "The Boys at Camp Blackshare." The card appears to be made of tree bark. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 7, pp. 99-109Folder 3375214December 1963-August 196433Scope and ContentsAppearancec at a number of functions. Inclusions: a religious card featuring a bible passage, photographs of Arrington participating in functions, and letters thanking Arrington for appearing at said functions.Scrapbook 7, pp. 110-117Folder 3475215September-October 196434Scope and ContentsContinued involvement in functions as well as the first few appearances of re-election campaigning documents. Inclusions: a letter confirming Arrington's candidacy, a certificate of appreciation from Kwanis International, and a photograph of Arrington and others hold a sign saying "Jobs."Scrapbook 7, pp. 118-133Folder 3575216November-December 196435Scope and ContentsActivities near the end of 1964. Inclusions: letters congratulating Arrington on his successful election, articles and pamphlets supporting his re-election, and a copy of the December issue of the Illinois Political Reporter.Scrapbook 7, pp. 136-162Folder 3675217December 196436Scope and ContentsActivities as a legislator. Contains a large number of congratulatory letters for his recent re-election. Inclusions: photographs of Arrington at an award ceremony, and press releases on tax legislation.Box 3Box 375218Scrapbook 8, pp. 1-7Folder 175219January 19651Scope and ContentsElection as the President Pro Tem. Inclusions: letters of congratulations on the election, a photograph of Arrington participating in a televised interview, and a letter thanking Arrington for his participation in said interview.Scrapbook 8, pp. 58-105Folder 275220February-March 19652Scope and ContentsInclusions: thank-you letters for his appearances, photographs of him at said functions, and a letter showing signs of difficulties from the reapportionment act.Scrapbook 8, pp. 109-220Folder 375221March-June 19653Scope and ContentsInclusions: letters mentioning the Fair Employment Practices Commission controversy, several photographs of Arrington with other politicians, and an article explaining Arrington's support of tax hikes.Scrapbook 8, Additional MaterialsFolder 475222June 19654Scope and ContentsEnvelopes found in scrapbook 8. Inclusions: handwritten letters with almost illegible handwriting, and photographs of a few politicians (no description provided) giving speeches.Scrapbook 9, pp. 4-33Folder 575223July 19655Scope and ContentsWork as a legislator. Inclusions: a column which suggests that Arrington was "much maligned," a birthday card, and several letters of gratitude and invitation.Scrapbook 9, pp. 45-36Folder 675224July 19656Scope and ContentsA collection of letters congratulating Arrington on his work in the Senate during this time period.Scrapbook 9, pp. 37-55Folder 775225July-Septembr 19657Scope and ContentsInclusions: letters of invitation, photographs of Arrington with and unidentified woman at some function, and several programs from functions.Scrapbook 9, pp. 56-65Folder 875226September-October 19658Scope and ContentsWork as a legislator and success in his position. Inclusions: articles and letters mentioning Arrington's selection as "Most Effective Senator" and "Outstanding Senator," another certificate of appreciation from Kwanis International, a ribbon with Arrington's name, and programs to functions Arrington spoke at or participated in.Scrapbook 9, pp. 71-92Folder 975227October-November 19659Scope and ContentsInclusions: photographs depicting Arrington making a phone call, browsing books, and examining an unusual device.Scrapbook 9, pp. 95-109Folder 1075228November-December 196510Scope and ContentsSpecial attention: his speech before the Chicago Circle Young Republicans. Inclusions: photographs of Arrington making a speech in a classroom, programs for functions, and several name badges/ribbons used by Arrington while attending functions.Scrapbook 9, pp. 110-122Folder 1175229December 1965-January 196611Scope and ContentsInclusions: a photograph of Arrington addressing the January meeting of the Governmental Affairs Council (with attached description), a menu fro the Council of Retail Trade Associations Annual Dinner, and a piece of scrap paper with notes.Scrapbook 10, pp. 1-41Folder 1275230January-March 196612Scope and ContentsInclusions: an article from Market Trends congratulating Arrington and others on a job well done, letters of gratitude for his appearances, and small slip which might have served as a name tag for a reunion at Northern Illinois University.Scrapbook 10, pp. 43-96Folder 1375231March-June 196613Scope and ContentsInclusions: news bulletins concerning speaking appearances of Arrington, congratulatory on his victory in the Senatorial primary, and an invitation and program fro a Testimonial Dinner honoring Senator Arthur R. Gottschalk.Scrapbook 10, pp. 98-123Folder 1475232June- July 196614Scope and ContentsInclusions: more congratulatory letters on his victory in the primary, and a letter mentioning a speech given by Nixon that Arrington went to.Scrapbook 10, pp. 124-147Folder 1575233July-September 196615Scope and ContentsLetters thanking Arrington for his work. Inclusions: several post cards from the Union League Boys' Clubs Camp, a flier giving support from the Better Government Association for the coming election, and a program for the 19th annual National Legislative Conference in Maine.Scrapbook 10, pp. 149-175Folder 1675234September-October 196616Scope and ContentsInclusions: a photograph of Arrington receiving a campaign contribution, a photograph of Arrington and several other politicians with labels next to their images, and an invitation to the 1966 Republican Year Luncheon featuring Richard M. Nixon.Scrapbook 10, pp. 177-199Folder 1775235October-November 196617Scope and ContentsLetters primarily devoted to congratulating Arrington on his re-election.Scrapbook 10, pp. 200-216Folder 1875236November 196618Scope and ContentsLetters congratulating Arrington on his re-election. Also includes photographs of Arrington and others at a function.Scrapbook 10, pp. 217-257Folder 1975237November-December 196619Scope and ContentsSmall number of additional congratulatory letters on Arrington's re-election and re-appointment as the Senate Majority leader. Also features features letters and a press release related to the push for a constitutional convention.Scrapbook 10, pp. 259-284Folder 2075238December 196620Scope and ContentsInclusions: a joke resolution signed by a number of people praising Arrington, a menu from the Council of Retail Trade Associations Twentieth Annual Dinner, and a letter of gratitude for Arrington's accomplishments in the Senate.Scrapbook 11, pp. 1-15Folder 2175239December 1966-February 196721Scope and ContentsInclusions: ribbons and cards from celebratory occasions, photographs of Arrington with other politicians, and a Rotary Club newsletter that featured a blurb about a speech that Arrington gave.Scrapbook 11, pp.16-93Folder 2275240February-April 196722Scope and ContentsLegislator and function-goer. Inclusions: articles and letters that mention an ongoing battle in the senate over a tax bill, letters of invitation and thanks for functions or Arrington's appearance at them, and copies of two broadcasted radio editorials concerning Arrington.Scrapbook 11, pp. 105-241Folder 2375241April-July 196723Scope and ContentsWork as a senator. Inclusions: a "glossy" photograph of Arrington looking over documents with another man and a letter attached to explain the photo, numerous letters expressing gratitude for Arrington's actions in the legislature, and another published radio editorial.Scrapbook 11, pp.260-279Folder 2475242July-August 196724Scope and ContentsInclusions: and Associated Employers of Illinois Comments newsletter featuring an article on Arrington, a belated birthday card, the speaking notes Arrington use for in his response to Harold Smith's introduction (complete with annotation for speaking style), and a program and invitation to the Republican State Senate Gala.Scrapbook 11, pp. 293-318Folder 2575243September 196725Scope and ContentsInclusions: the menu and program for the National Legislative Conference in San Antonio, Texas, programs for other functions, and a certificate of appreciations from the Illinois Local Governmental Law Enforcement Officers Training Board.Scrapbook 11, pp. 323-335Folder 2675244October-November 196726Scope and ContentsWork as a legislator. Inclusions: a program for the National Conference on Legislative Leadership in Washington D.C. as well as the name tag Arrington used while attending as a delegate, letters mentioning some of Arrington's work in the legislature during this time period, and photographs of Arrington at his desk.Scrapbook 11, pp. 337-351Folder 2775245November-December 196727Scope and ContentsInclusions: letters thanking Arrington for his work in the senate, a certificate of merit from the Illinois Association of County Superintendents of Schools, and a program for the National Conference of State Legislative Leaders in San Francisco, CA.Box 4Box 475246Scrapbook 12, pp. 1-10Folder 175247January 19681Scope and ContentsInclusions: a photograph of and story about Arrington explaining the use of the electric typewriter, a page from the program at the Kendall College groundbreaking ceremony for Penny Jane Terra Hall in which Arrington gave a speech, and photographs of Arrington giving speeches.Scrapbook 12, pp. 11-40Folder 275248January-April 19682Scope and ContentsInclusions: a certificate of appreciation from the Institute on Continuing Education of the Illinois Bar, a program for a testimonial dinner honoring William J. Scott, and the speech notes for a speech given by Arrington on Radio.Scrapbook 12, pp. 43-47Folder 375249March-April 19683Scope and ContentsThe folder contains the Union League Mean and Events magazine's March issue. The magazine focuses a great deal on legislation and therefore Arrington features prominently in several articlesScrapbook 12, pp. 50-75Folder 475250April-May 19684Scope and ContentsActivities as a legislator and his participation in functions. Inclusions: Arrington's name tag for The Citizens Conference on State Legislatures, a photograph of Arrington presenting a meritorious service award to Fremont E. Schneider, and a marriage announcement for Arrington's daughter.Scrapbook 12, pp. 75Folder 575251May 19685Scope and ContentsHandwritten letter to Arrington from  Dick. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 12, pp. 76-120Folder 675252June-July 19686Scope and ContentsActivities as a legislator. Inclusions: a letter mentioning a speech by Arrington on the "right to bear arms," a letter describing presidential candidate Richard Nixon as a unifying point for the Republican party, and letters thanking Arrington for his participation in functions.Scrapbook 12, pp. 122-129Folder 775253July-September 19687Scope and ContentsInvolvement in the ongoing presidential campaign. Inclusions: a press release demonstrating the support of Nixon by 104 state legislators, an invitation and program to the Republican National Convention Gala, and a dinner invitation from Nixon and Agnew.Scrapbook 12, pp. 130-141Folder 875254October 19688Scope and ContentsPartially related to Arrington's continued interaction with the Nixon campaign, and partially related to Arrington's work as a legislator. Inclusions: letters from Nixon's campaign thanking Arrington for his support, photographs of Arrington while at a function in Miami, and the program for the Road to Victory Dinner in Chicago.Scrapbook 12, pp. 142-154Folder 975255October 19689Scope and ContentsInclusions: a request for information on Michael B. Arrington for the purposes of membership to the Union League Club of Chicago, a certificate declaring Arrington an Honorary Member of the Grinnell Young Republicans Club, and letters of thanks for his participation in functions.Scrapbook 12, pp. 156Folder 1075256November 196810Scope and ContentsAn unusual publication entitled the Sixth Annual Dinner Dance - contains a number of advertisements and small ads about important Republicans.Scrapbook 12, pp. 154-173Folder 1175257October-November 196811Scope and ContentsInclusions: a letter thanking Arrington for a birthday gift, a program for The Economic Club of Chicago's 165th Dinner Meeting, and letter thanking Arrington for his appearance at functions.Scrapbook 12, pp. 177-197Folder 1275258November-December 196812Scope and ContentsInclusions: a press release mentioning a national conference on state legislation in Hawaii, photographs of Arrington posing with others at a ball, a letter of thanks from Richard Nixon for Arrington's support of the successful campaign.Scrapbook 12, pp. 198-199Folder 1375259December 196813Scope and ContentsInclusions: a press release proposed by Arrington to add a cut-off date for proposed legislation, Christmas letters, and a New Years card from Richard Nixon.Scrapbook 13, pp. 1-17Folder 1475260December 1968-January 196914Scope and ContentsInclusions: the 1969 Republican Legislative Program, a letter with 6 total invitations to the Illinois General Assembly, and a letter of support for Arrington in the face of some rather damaging criticism.Scrapbook 13, pp. 18-22Folder 1575261January 196915Scope and ContentsInclusions: a number of tickets to functions, a large number of invitations and programs to inaugural celebrations, and letters containing further invitations.Scrapbook 13, pp. 23-40Folder 1675262January 196916Scope and ContentsInclusions: letters and photographs documenting Arrington's work with the Citizens Committee on Emotionally disturbed Children of the Mental Health Association of Greater Chicago, letter thanking Arrington for his appearances at functions, and photographs of Arrington participating in functions.Scrapbook 13, pp. 41-56Folder 1775263January-February 196917Scope and ContentsInclusions: a certificate announcing Arrington's status as a RN Associate, a ticket to the 65th annual meeting of the Chicago Association of Commerce and Industry, and articles announcing Arrington's coming speeches.Scrapbook 13, pp. 57-83Folder 1875264February-March 196918Scope and ContentsInclusions: letters thanking Arrington for his participation in functions, photographs of Arrington meeting with other politicians, and a dinner invitation from the governor.Scrapbook 13, pp. 85-101Folder 1975265March 196919Scope and ContentsInclusions: photographs of Arrington meeting with a group of young people, articles and letters referring to Arrington's Mental Health Referendum, and a congratulatory card recognizing Arrington's command of the legislative process.Scrapbook 13, pp. 102-132Folder 2075266March-April 196920Scope and ContentsInclusions: a copy of the 76th General Assembly Senate Resolution No. 63, and letters and articles related to Arrington's participation in a legislative body to fill the gubernatorial vacancy on the Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations.Scrapbook 13, pp. 134-154Folder 2175267April 196921Scope and ContentsInclusions: a letter requesting an autograph on a picture sent to Arrington, several photographs of Arrington at a wide variety of events, and letters of appreciation.Scrapbook 13, pp. 156-184Folder 2275268May 196922Scope and ContentsInclusions: photographs of Arrington and others including one of him while on television, a program for the United Republican Fund's All-Illinois Victory Gala, and a certificate of good standing from the National Society of State Legislators.Scrapbook 13, pp. 188-276Folder 2375269May-July 196923Scope and ContentsInclusions: a Distinguished Public Service Award from the American Society of Public Administration, postcards directed to Arrington's staff, several photographs of Arrington, and cards/letters wishing Arrington a happy birthday.Scrapbook 13, pp. 278-290Folder 2475270July 196924Scope and ContentsInclusions: more letters containing birthday congratulations, letters of thanks for Arrington's appearance at functions, a program for the Republican State Senate Dinner, and a copy of a speech (including speaking notes) given by Arrington.Scrapbook 13, pp. 291-307Folder 2575271July-September 196925Scope and ContentsInclusions: letters of appreciation, a program from the 22nd Annual Meeting of the National Legislative Conference in St. Louis Missouri, and a letter mentioning another letter sent by Arrington to the White House.Scrapbook 13, pp. 309-319Folder 2675272September-October 196926Scope and ContentsInclusions: photographs of Arrington meeting with other politicians, and invitation from the Executives Club of Chicago to sit at the speakers table to hear an address by Vice President Spiro Agnew, and a program from the 5th Annual Meeting of the National Society of State Legislators.Scrapbook 13, pp. 320-336Folder 2775273October-November 196927Scope and ContentsInclusions: letters expressing gratitude to Arrington, photographs of Arrington at a number of functions, two notes from the American Association of University Women, a baseball team roster for the Mets and the Orioles, and an invitation to the Good Shepherd Award Dinner.Scrapbook 13, pp. 337-348Folder 2875274November 196928Scope and ContentsInclusions: tickets to the 35th Anniversary Dinner of the United Republican Fund of Illinois, programs and an invitation to the Tranquility Ball (which Arrington did not attend), and a press release in which Arrington denounces the Democratic opposition.Scrapbook 13, pp. 350-359Folder 2975275November-December 196929Scope and ContentsInclusions: letters thanking Arrington for his appearances at functions, several magazine articles referring to Arrington, a quote from Theodore Roosevelt, and a dinner invitation from the governor.Scrapbook 13, pp. 360-367Folder 3075276December 1969-January 197030Scope and ContentsA small collection of documents including a ticket to the 6th Illinois Constitutional Convention, two invitations to state functions, a newsletter referencing Arrington, and Newsweeks' 1968 Republican Convention Score Card.Box 5Box 575277Scrapbook 14, pp. 4-31Folder 175278January 19701Scope and ContentsInclusions: letters and cards congratulating Arrington on his anniversary, photographs of Arrington meeting politicians and others, and several letters expressing gratitude for a variety of reasons.Scrapbook 14, pp. 32-44Folder 275279January-February 19702Scope and ContentsInclusions: a program for the Salute to Senator Howard R. Mohr, invitations to a number of functions, and a copy of a resolution thanking Arrington from the Illinois Registered Land Surveyors Association.Scrapbook 14, pp. 45-74Folder 375280February-March 19703Scope and ContentsInclusions: a program for the 1970 Lincoln Day Dinner, a letter from the White House expressing gratitude to Arrington, another certificate of appreciation from the Kiwanis International, and a program, invitation, and menu for the Republican Senate-House Majority Dinner.Scrapbook 14, pp. 75-95Folder 475281March-April 19704Scope and ContentsInclusions: three different programs to the 10th Annual Washington Conference on Business-Government Relations, TV broadcast scripts mentioning Arrington, and several letters of appreciation.Scrapbook 14, pp. 106-165Folder 575282April-June 19705Scope and ContentsInclusions: a ticket to the 4th Ward Dinner, a program fro the 10th Annual White Orchid Dinner, a wedding invitation, and editorial published by a TV station urging Arrington to stop his efforts at halting a bill, and photographs of Arrington and other politicians.Scrapbook 14, pp. 165Folder 675283June 19706Scope and ContentsCopies of a letter and an Article related to a perceived lack of leadership on Arrington's part. Kept in a separate folder to prevent acid absorption.Scrapbook 14, pp. 171-196Folder 775284July 19707Scope and ContentsInclusions: tickets to Bill Harris Day, a copy of the 76th General Assembly Senate Resolution No. 145, and several birthday cards.Scrapbook 14, pp. 197-208Folder 875285July 19708Scope and ContentsTwo photographs of Arrington, a program, and a copy of the Illinois Bar Journal's July issue. The first photograph features Arrington in the legislature, the second show him reading the "Heritage Cookbook" with another.Scrapbook 14, pp. 205-214Folder 975286August-September 19709Scope and ContentsInclusions: several postcards, a program for the 56th annual Governmental Research Association conference, a three photographs of Arrington with W. J. Crowley, the Chairman of the Finance Committee.Scrapbook 14, pp. 215-231Folder 1075287September-October 197010Scope and ContentsInclusions: a certificate of membership to The National Register of Prominent Americans, name tag and program for the 6th Annual Meeting National Society of State Legislators, and photographs of Arrington at a variety of meetings.Scrapbook 14, pp. 232-253Folder 1175288October 197011Scope and ContentsInclusions: postcards, the program for a fashion show of sorts put on by the Wayne Township Republican Women's Club entitled "Together for Fun," and a copy of the Illinois Public Official September-October issue.Scrapbook 14, pp. 290-298Folder 1275289November-December 197012Scope and ContentsInclusions: a caucus roll call for the 77th General Assembly, letters congratulating Arrington on a victory in the Senate, and two Christmas cards.Scrapbook 15, pp. 1-23Folder 1375290January-April 197113Scope and ContentsInclusions: letters expressing gratitude for Arrington's work, get well cards, a Distinguished Service Award from the Mental Health Association of Greater Chicago, and a copy of the 77th General Assembly Senate Resolution No. 11 which also wished Arrington a speedy recovery.Scrapbook 15, pp. 24-80Folder 1475291May-November 197114Scope and ContentsExpected and then achieved return to the Senate. Inclusions: an invitation to the Chicago Symphony Orchestra, letters congratulating Arrington on his return to work, and a letter mentioning Arrington's decision to not seek re-election.Scrapbook 15, pp. 89-107Folder 1575292November-December 197115Scope and ContentsArrington's decision to retire from the legislature. Inclusions: editorials consistently singing Arrington's praises, several letters expressing regret on Arrington's retirement, and a petition form for nomination to the Senate.Scrapbook 15, pp. 108-117Folder 1675293December 197116Scope and ContentsInclusions: more letters expressing regret for Arrington's decision to retire, letters announcing Arrington's appointment to the Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations, and two Christmas cards.Scrapbook 16, pp. 1-32Folder 1775294January-April 197217Scope and ContentsInclusions: a letter congratulating Arrington on being selected the "Man of the Year" by the March of Dimes, letters related to Arrington's retirement and his support of another candidate, David E. Brown, in his place, and letters referring to Arrington's recovery.Scrapbook 16, pp. 35-55Folder 1875295June-July 197218Scope and ContentsInclusions: several letters expressing regret over Arrington's retirement, letters and a photograph related to a farewell event, and a copy of the 77th General Assembly Senate Resolution No. 418 calling Arrington "the most outstanding and influential Senator of the century in this body."Scrapbook 16, pp. 56-81Folder 1975296July-December 197219Scope and ContentsInclusions: a program to the Evanston Republican Organization Fifth Annual Picnic, further letters expressing regret over Arrington's retirement, and a letter seeking to explain a Christmas card sent to Arrington.Scrapbook 16, pp. 82-87Folder 2075297December 197220Scope and ContentsInclusions: a copy of the 77th General Assembly Senate Resolution No. 443 and 5 letters over various topics.Scrapbook 17, pp. 1-17Folder 2175298January 197321Scope and ContentsInclusions: several letters concerning and invitations to a number of inaugural celebrations, a large sign saying "Official Car," and further letters expressing regret over Arrington's retirement.Scrapbook 17, pp. 18-49Folder 2275299January-May 197322Scope and ContentsInclusions: a birthday card, letters to and from Arrington mentioning his involvement in a number of functions, a copy of the 77th General Assembly House Resolution No. 902, and documents related to Arrington's award of a degree called Doctor of Letters from Lincoln College.Scrapbook 17, pp. 50-65Folder 2375300May-June 197323Scope and ContentsInclusions: a program for Lincoln College's 106th commencement ceremony, letters discussing Arrington's involvement in state functions, and a copy of the 78th General Assembly Senate Resolution No. 240.Scrapbook 17, pp. 66-87Folder 2475301July-October 197324Scope and ContentsInclusions: a program for the Investment in Leadership Testimonial Dinner, birthday cards, photographs of Arrington, a program fro the 39th Anniversary Dinner of the United Republican Fund of Illinois, and a certificate declaring Arrington a Member of the Board of Managers of the Chicago Boys Club.Scrapbook 17, pp. 88-167Folder 2575302October-December 197325Scope and ContentsInclusions: the October issue of the Union League Men and Events magazine, two photographs of an oil painting of Leo Burnett, and several letters of correspondence.Box 6Box 675306Scrapbook 18, pp. 1-45Folder 175303January-April 19741Scope and ContentsInclusions: letters offering Arrington sympathy for the death of his wife, a certificate from the National Society of State Legislators confirming Arrington's status as a life member, and letters related to Arrington's appearances at functions.Scrapbook 18, pp. 48-58Folder 275304April-May 19742Scope and ContentsInclusions: a program for the Convocation and Investiture of Members of the Lincoln Academy of Illinois, letters congratulating Arrington to his election to the Lincoln Academy of Illinois, a telegram from President Nixon expressing regret for Arrington's retirement, and a program/menu for the 43rd Annual Shakespeare Birthday Program.Scrapbook 18, pp. 59-87Folder 375305May-August 19743Scope and ContentsInclusions: a certificate of membership from the National Police Reserve Officers Association, several letters and cards of congratulations for a large number of awards and honors, and letters and cards expressing gratitude to Arrington for a number of reasons.Scrapbook 18, pp. 88-101Folder 475307August-October 19744Scope and ContentsInclusions: a photo of Arrington posing with a group of younger people, a copy of The Rehab Reporter (The Newsletter of the Rehabilitation Institute of Chicago), and letters of correspondence.Scrapbook 18, pp. 102-116Folder 575308October-November 19745Scope and ContentsInclusions: cards and letters expressing gratitude to Arrington, a program for The United Republican Fund of Illinois in support of the President of the United States, and letters explaining the origins of clippings included in the scrapbook.Scrapbook 18, pp. 118-126Folder 675309November-December 19746Scope and ContentsInclusions: letters thanking Arrington for his time and appearances at functions, thank you and Christmas cards, and correspondences.Scrapbook 19, pp. 1-18Folder 775310January-March 19757Scope and ContentsInclusions: several cards including Valentine's Day, Easter, thank you, and greeting cards, a certificate of Recognition from the John Ericsson Republican League of Illinois, and letters expressing gratitude to Arrington for his work.Scrapbook 19, pp. 21-42Folder 875311April-June 19758Scope and ContentsLetters expressing gratitude towards Arrington for a variety of reason. Inclusions: article on the funding of a new program at the Citizens Conference on State Legislatures for the Study of Educational Lawmaking, and the program for a dinner honoring James S. Kemper Jr.Scrapbook 19, pp. 43-55Folder 975312June-July 19759Scope and ContentsInclusions: a copy of the June issue of The Log, the newsletter for Lincoln College, several birthday cards, and a letter suggesting that Arrington continued to play a role in legislation even in 1975.Scrapbook 19, pp. 56-60Folder 1075313197510Scope and ContentsA collection of birthday cards to Arrington from a variety of sources.Scrapbook 19, pp. 61-81Folder 1175314July 197511Scope and ContentsInclusions: several more birthday cards, a letter from the Speaker of the House of Illinois telling Arrington, "Your wish is my command," and a program for the Republican State Senate Dinner Honoring Illinois Republican State Senators.Scrapbook 19, pp. 83-91Folder 1275315August-September 197512Scope and ContentsInclusions: the program to a symphony event in Chicago, a copy of the Report of the Special Task Force on Nontraditional Education in the Board of Governors System, and a copy of a press release on the Board of Governors Bachelor of Arts Degree Program.Scrapbook 19, pp. 92-116Folder 1375316July-December 197513Scope and ContentsInclusions: cards and letters expressing gratitude towards Arrington, and a Christmas ad from an unknown publication featuring Arrington and others expressing seasonal greetings.Scrapbook 20, pp. 2-19Folder 1475317January-May 197614Scope and ContentsInclusions: a Certificate of High Honor from Jack Harter Helicopters, thank you cards and letters, and a flyer announcing the Senator Bill Harris Testimonial Dinner, the Republican Candidate for Secretary of State.Scrapbook 20, pp. 25-34Folder 1575318July 1976-January 197715Scope and ContentsInclusions: a certificate of life membership from the Evanston Historical Society, a program for the New York Philharmonic Gala Bicentennial Tour, and several invitations to inaugural events.Scrapbook 20, pp. 35-50Folder 1675319January-June 197716Scope and ContentsInclusions: The United Republican Fund of Illinois Lincoln Day Dinner, a copy of Arrington's speech saluting William Harrison Fetridge, and letters and cards expressing gratitude towards Arrington.Scrapbook 20, pp. 51-63Folder 1775320May-July 197717Scope and ContentsInclusions: letters and cards inviting Arrington to a number of functions and events, a program from the 1977 Milestone Anniversary Dinner Dance at the Michigan Shores Club, and a program for the birthday party of Oscar Getz.Scrapbook 20, Additional Materials 1Folder 1875321January-September 197718Scope and ContentsInclusions: a copy of Caring: A Quarterly Publican of Illinois Masonic Medical Center, and several letters and a card related to Arrington's subscription to Illinois Issues.Scrapbook 20, Additional Materials 2Folder 1975322February-March 197719Scope and ContentsInclusions: more letters referring to Illinois Issues, and a letter mentioning a grant made by Arrington to Sangamon State University.Scrapbook 21, pp. 2-19Folder 2075323March-August 197820Scope and ContentsInclusions: a program for the John F. Atkinson Award Dinner in honor of Senator W. Russell Arrington, a program for A Special Saturday in September, and a copy of the Board of Managers Meeting on May 22, 1978.Scrapbook 21, pp. 20-35Folder 2175324March-July 197821Scope and ContentsInclusions: a program for Dance the Night Away by the Ray Graham Association for the Handicapped, letters mentioning Arrington's increasing retreat from the realm of responsibility, and copies of two house resolutions: No. 346 and No. 528.Loose Fragments, 1960-1965Folder 227532522Scope and ContentsA collection of loose newspaper fragments from the time period. Unknown origins.History of the Legislative SeatFolder 2375326194723Scope and ContentsA list of all the occupants to have held the same house seat as Arrington, sent as a memorandum to Arrington. Unknown origins.Letter about seating planFolder 2475327194724Scope and ContentsA letter from Arrington to Lucien D. Levaccare thanking him for a copy of the house seating plan. Unknown origin.Photo of Arrington and OthersFolder 257532825Scope and ContentsA photograph of Arrington and others, presumably during his time as a Representative.House seating plan and letterFolder 2675329194726Scope and ContentsA copy of the 1947 house seating plan with a letter sent by Levacarre indicating that it reflected the seating during one of his uncles terms. Unknown origins.Oversized Items and Removed ClippingsBox 775330Scope and ContentsMany of these contain newspaper clippings removed from a scrapbook.Scrapbook 4, pp. 1, 4-5Folder 1753311Scrapbook 4, pp. 8-9Folder 2753322Scrapbook 4, pp. 14-15Folder 3753333Scrapbook 4, pp. 17Folder 4753344Scrapbook 4, pp. 18-19Folder 5753355Scrapbook 4, pp. 24-25Folder 6753366Scrapbook 4, pp. 28-29Folder 7753377Scrapbook 4, pp. 30-31Folder 8753388Scrapbook 4, pp. 32-33Folder 9753399Scrapbook 4, pp. 34-35Folder 107534010Scrapbook 4, pp. 38-39Folder 117534111Scrapbook 4, pp. 40-41Folder 127534212Scrapbook 4, pp. 44-45Folder 137534313Scrapbook 4, pp. 46-47Folder 147534414Scrapbook 4, pp. 48-49Folder 157534515Scrapbook 4, pp. 48-49Folder 167534616Scrapbook 4, pp. 51-51Folder 177534717Scrapbook 4, pp. 52-53Folder 187534818Scrapbook 4, pp. 54-55Folder 197534919Scrapbook 4, pp. 56-57Folder 207535020Scrapbook 4, pp. 58-59Folder 217535121Scrapbook 4, pp. 60-61Folder 227535222Scrapbook 4, pp. 62-63Folder 237535323Scrapbook 4, pp. 64-65Folder 247535424Scrapbook 4, pp. 66-67Folder 257535525Scrapbook 4, pp. 68-69Folder 267535626Scrapbook 4, pp. 70-71Folder 277535727Scrapbook 4, pp. 72-73Folder 287535828Scrapbook 4, pp. 74-75Folder 297535929Scrapbook 4, pp. 76-77Folder 307536030Scrapbook 4, pp. 78-79Folder 317536131Scrapbook 4, pp. 80-81Folder 327536232Scrapbook 4, pp. 82-83Folder 337536333Scrapbook 4, pp. 84-85Folder 347536434Scrapbook 4, pp. 86-87Folder 357536535Scrapbook 4, pp. 88-89Folder 367536636Scrapbook 4, pp. 90-91Folder 377536737Scrapbook 4, pp. 92-93Folder 387536838Scrapbook 4, pp. 94-95Folder 397536939Scrapbook 4, pp. 96-97Folder 407537040Scrapbook 4, pp. 98-99Folder 417537141Scrapbook 4, pp. 100-101Folder 427537242Scrapbook 4, pp. 102-103Folder 437537343Scrapbook 4, pp. 104-105Folder 447537444Scrapbook 4, pp. 106-107Folder 457537545Scrapbook 4, pp. 108-109Folder 467537646Scrapbook 4, pp. 110-111Folder 477537747Scrapbook 4, pp. 112-113Folder 487537848Scrapbook 4, pp. 114-115Folder 497537949Scrapbook 4, pp. 116-117Folder 507538050Scrapbook 4, pp. 118-119Folder 517538151Scrapbook 4, pp. 120-121Folder 527538252Scrapbook 4, pp. 122-123Folder 537538353Scrapbook 5, pp. 14-15Folder 547538454Scrapbook 5, pp. 18-19Folder 557538555Scrapbook 8, pp. 172Folder 567538656Scope and ContentsA handwritten certificate called The Earl Warren and William O Douglas Reapportionment Victory Plaque, dedicated to Arrington.Oversized Items Folder 1Folder 57753871959-196957Scope and ContentsOversized documents removed from the scrapbooks. Contains a number of certificates, tax clinic meeting minutes, and a photograph.Oversized Item Folder 2Folder 58753881969-197058Scope and ContentsOversized documents removed from the scrapbooks. It contains a certificate, a political handout, tax clinic minutes, a hand-made get well soon card, and the menu for the 1970 Republican Senate House Majority Dinner.Oversized Items Folder 3Folder 59753891970-198059Scope and ContentsOversized documents removed from the scrapbooks. It contains the menu for the National Association for Mental Health Testimonial Dinner, a certificate, the menu for Grassfield's International Restaurant, the minutes for the 80th General Assembly March 23, 1977 regular session, and the menu for a food and wine tasting event.Scrapbook 1 ScansFolder 607539060Scope and ContentsThe photocopied images of scrapbook 1.Scrapbook 2 ScansFolder 617539161Scope and ContentsThe photocopied images of scrapbook 2.Scrapbook 3 ScansFolder 627539262Scope and ContentsThe photocopied images of scrapbook 3.

