<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.102/5Archon Finding Aid Title MC.102/5Sean BruceUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:20:29 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC102/5. Recycling Archives: Abby Walden Collection
    MC.102/5
    1769
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1987-1995
    Date acquired: 07/02/2012
    1
  
  
    Scope and Contents
A collection of reports and newspaper clippings dealing with recycling in Springfield, Sangamon County, and Illinois. Specific materials included clippings from periodicals in Springfield and Sangamon country, reports on recycling and solid waste management, a report on a study of solid waste disposal, and a regulation guide and keyword index for the 1987 Resource Conservation and Recovery Act.Abby Walden is the manager of the Waste and Recycling Division in the Springfield Department of Public Works.Dan Knapp and the Institute for Local Self Reliance are responsible for coordinating the collections of material related to recycling for donation to the UIS Archives.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Abby Walden  
  
    Newspaper Clippings
    Reports
  
  Box 1Box 175034Collection of Newspaper ClippingsItem 1750331989-19951Scope and ContentsA album containing newspaper clippings dealing with recycling and recycling related topics in Sangamon County, IL.Governor's Small Business Environmental Task Force Report &amp; RecommendationsItem 275035April 19942Scope and ContentsReport from the Illinois Environmental Protection Agency and the Illinois Department of Commerce and Community Affairs.Report on Solid Waste Handling Strategies for the City of Springfield, ILItem 375036June 19903RCRA Regulations and Keyword Index, 1987 EditionItem 47503719874Scope and ContentsPublished version of the regulations implemented by the 1987 Resource Conservation and Recovery Act.Solid Waste Disposal Study For Springfield, IL and Sangamon CountyItem 575038September 19885Scope and ContentsA study prepared by Edward J. Long &amp; Associates, Ltd. Consulting Engineers.

