<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.102/4Archon Finding Aid Title MC.102/4Sean BruceUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:20:38 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC102/4. Recycling Archives: Gretchen Brewer Collection
    MC.102/4
    1768
    
      1.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1991-2001
    Date acquired: 01/05/2012
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This collection contains  a variety of materials dealing with recycling policy, technology, and planning. Binders containing slides, photographs, and articles about recycling technologies in North America and Europe make up the majority of this collection. Also included are policy handbooks, a newsletter, program implementation guides, and a recycled products guide.Gretchen Brewer is a former regional planner and recycling coordinator at the Massachusetts Department of Environmental Protection. She is currently a principal at Earth Circle Conservation &amp; Recycling.Dan Knapp and the Institute for Local Self Reliance are responsible for coordinating the collections of material related to recycling for donation to the UIS Archives.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Gretchen Brewer  
  
    Slides
    Photographs
    Reports
  
  Box 1Box 175019Recycling Technology Search Part 1: European Plastics Recycling SystemsItem 1750211986-19901Scope and ContentsBinder containing projector slides from presentations on European plastics recycling systems. Also contains copies of published articles on the topic.Recycling Technology Search Part 2: Plastics Recycling in Europe and the USItem 2750221985-19912Scope and ContentsBinder containing a collection of projector slides of plastics recycling technologies in Europe and the US. Also contains photographs and copies of published articles on the topic.Recycling Technology Search Part 3: Material Recovery Facility (MRF) Designs/ SystemsItem 3750233Scope and ContentsBinder containing projector slides from presentations on material recovery facility designs and systems. Also contains a copy of a journal article, "Denmark's First MRF."Recycling Technology Search Part 4: Recovery Systems for: Paper, Textiles, Organics/Composting, and TiresItem 4750244Scope and ContentsBinder containing projector slides on recovery systems. Also includes copies of published articles on the topic.National Directory of Manufacturers Utilizing Recycled MaterialsItem 575025March 19835Solid Waste Management Plan: Naval Station San DiegoItem 675026November 19966Third World 1981 Administrative Committee: Emmaus International NewletterItem 775027June 19817North American Recycling CommunicationsItem 875028June 19938Scope and ContentsAn Analysis of Outstanding Materials, Campaigns, and Strategies from North America.Plastics Recycling Action Plan for MassachusettsItem 975029July 19889The Official RPG: Recycled Products GuideItem 1075030200110Scope and ContentsA list of companies that sell products using recycled material.Recycling Clip ArtItem 1175031199311Scope and ContentsA collection of clip art and cartoons that feature recycling as their main theme. All work has been done by Lawrence E. Green.Affirmative Procurement Program Strategies: Naval Station San Diego, CAItem 1275032April 199812Scope and ContentsA policy publication of the Southwest Division Naval Facilities Engineering Command. Made in response to legislation concerning the implementation of recycling procedures in naval facilities.

