<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.16.01/00Archon Finding Aid Title J.16.01/00Sandra LongenUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:21:09 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J16/1/0. Reports and Presentations, 1997-2005
    
      Schroeder, Ray
    
    J.16.01/00
    1778
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    Date acquired: 06/01/2013
    1
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Center for Online Learning, Research, and Services (formerly known as Office of Teaching and Enhanced Learning). The Center is the UIS hub for the study and application of online learning pedagogy, technology, and best practices.   COLRS Research Center provides leadership for research on online and blended learning at UIS and beyond. 
This collection contains reports of the University of Illinois Global Campus Initiative, proposals for online/blended programs and classes, and other documents about the Center.  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
No Restrictions  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Ray Schroeder  
  
    Correspondence
    Papers
    Workshop Materials
  
  Box 1Box 177121State Journal-Register article on Ray Schroeder, Director of OTEL/COLRSFolder 1771228/10/19971Scope and Contents"Career Move" discusses online courses at UISStudent Survey Responses "What does Online Classes Mean to You?"Folder 27712320052Blended Learning CoursesFolder 37712420053Sloan Program:  Proposals for Online Programs and ClassesFolder 4771252004-20054University of Illinois Global Campus Initiative Resource DocumentsFolder 577126December 20055University of Illinois Global Campus Initiative Resource DocumentsFolder 677127March 9, 20066University of Illinois Global Campus Initiative Draft Final ReportFolder 777128April 20067University of Illinois Global Campus Initiative Final ReportFolder 877129May20068University of Illinois Global Campus Initiative Alumni Center Workshop Resource DocumentsFolder 977130December 20069University of Illinois Global Campus Initiative President's Retreat Resource DocumentsFolder 1077131January 200710CDs [4]Folder 117713211Scope and Contents. Global Campus Initiative: Greetings from President B. Joseph White (2 copies)
. Online Teaching - Office of Technology-Enhanced Learning
. Transforming Lives - Office of Technology-Enhanced Learning

