<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.102/6Archon Finding Aid Title MC.102/6UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:21:46 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC102/6. Recycling Archives: Tania Levy Papers
    MC.102/6
    1772
    
      2.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1979-2011
    Date acquired: 12/17/2012
    1
    2
    3
    4
    5
    6
  
  
    Scope and Contents
A collection of materials from the personal papers of Tania Levy during her time as a Recycling Analyst for the City of Berkeley, California. These papers range from the late 1980s to her retirement in July of 2011. This collection contains a wide variety of materials including personal correspondence, financial records, contact lists, recycling public relations publications, manuals, training videos, and other assorted documents. The subject matter of the documents primary lies in ares of recycling, solid waste management, public awareness of recycling programs, composting, and the financial responsibilities of a recycling analyst.Dan Knapp and the Institute for Local Self Reliance are responsible for coordinating the collections of material related to recycling for donation to the UIS Archives.  
  
    Arrangement Note
The papers already in folders at the time of accession have been arranged chronologically by latest entry. The remaining loose papers have been arranged chronologically by year.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Dan Knapp  
  
    Correspondence
    Agendas
    Bills
    Films
    Book
    Ledgers
    Records
    Reports
    Statistics
  
  Box 1Box 175397California Integrated Waste Managedment Board, Facility Cost Model Workbook, Version TwoFolder 175398December 19941Scope and ContentsManual designed to help individuals build and operate cost-effective integrated waste management facilities. Also contains a floppy disk copy of the manual and a email detailing this versions changes from the previous one.California Integrated Waste Management Board, Curbside Collection Cost Model, Version 1Folder 275399August 19952Scope and ContentsA cost model on the overhead involved in running a curbside collection business.Used Oil RecyclingFolder 375400June 19973Scope and ContentsA collection of documents related to programs and policies related to the recycling of used oil.Tour-BackgroundFolder 4754011997-19984Scope and ContentsMaterials used in preparation for giving a tour of Berkeley's Solid Waste Management Facility.50% Recycling RateFolder 575402February-September 19995Scope and ContentsMaterials related to the projected achievement of a 50% recycling rate in the city of Berkeley.Bekeley's Best Builders Project Report: 800 Bancroft WayFolder 675403May-July 20016Scope and ContentsMaterials related to the Berkeley's Best Builders Program, an effort to encourage construction companies to used recycling-friendly methods while building.Buy Recycled and Environmentally Preferable Purchasing Materials, Alameda County Wast Management Authority and Recycling BoardFolder 775404July-October 20027Scope and ContentsA collection of strategies and reports relating to the implementation of Environmentally Preferable purchasing practices.Alameda County Waste Management Authority, Disaster Debris WorkshopFolder 875405September-October 20028Scope and ContentsA collection of materials related to a FEMA workshop covering the proper methods of dealing with debris created during a disaster.Load Checking ProceduresFolder 975406January 20039Scope and ContentsA copy of the load checking procedures for the transportation of hazardous materials.Food Waste Subsidy ApplicationsFolder 1075415May 2002-June 200310Scope and ContentsDocuments and applications related to the Commercial Food Waste Subsidy.646-2004Folder 1175407January-June 200411Scope and ContentsA series of receipts and financial documents related to fund 646.Budget 2004-2005Folder 1275408May 2003-July 200412Scope and ContentsDocuments and correspondences related to the budget of the Solid Waste Management Administration for the years of 2004 and 2005.Contract, Applied Compost Consulting, Inc.Folder 1375409August 2004-October 200513Scope and ContentsContracting and interviewing materials related to the hiring of Applied Compost Consulting, Inc. as a contractor for the city of Berkeley.Instructions, Purchasing ManualFolder 1475410November 200514Scope and ContentsA collection of materials related to the purchasing procedures for the Solid Waste Management Administration of the City of Berkeley.Recycled Content and Environmentally Preferable ResourcesFolder 1575411July 2002-March 200615Scope and ContentsMaterials related to a presentation on the usage of recycled content and environmentally preferable resources in business.Recycling Plans and FormsFolder 1675412August 1999-June 200616Scope and ContentsDocuments and forms relating to recycling, including a few plans for implementation of recycling practices.Resourceful Bag and Tag, Inc.Folder 1775413June 200617Scope and ContentsMiscellaneous materials related to the company Resourceful Bag and Tag, Inc. Notable inclusions: a sample bag, a labeled letter opener, and fliers for the company.PR IdeasFolder 1875414200618Scope and ContentsA large collection of fliers, handouts, and brochures related to recycling programs and public awareness of them.Dan Knapp emailFolder 197640912/11/201219Tania Lipshutz. "Garbage to Energy: The False Panacea" (second edition)Folder 2081624197920Scope and Contents"Developed by the Sonoma County Community Recycling Center...September, 1979." Gift of Dan Knapp, 2016.Box 2Box 275416RES FW TonsFolder 175417November 2006-June 20071Scope and ContentsA collection of statistical and financial information on the solid wastes disposal practices of the City of Berkeley.XX7N07, Fiscal Year 2006Folder 275418May 2004-20062Scope and ContentsReports related to project XX7N07, or the Recycled Product Procurement Project.Recycling ProgramsFolder 375419August-December 20073Scope and ContentsDocuments related to recycling programs both in the city of Berkeley and in cities nearby, such as Oakland, CA.Zero Waste Commission, Transfer StationFolder 475420December 20074Scope and ContentsDocuments related to Zero Waste Planning in references to a few specific transfer stations, or places where recycled materials are converted into something reusable.The Reuse People of AmericaFolder 575421November 2007-20085Scope and ContentsDocuments related to the nonprofit consulting company The Reuse People of America.646 Grant 2007Folder 675422March 20086Scope and ContentsFinancial documents related to the 646 grant in the year of 2007.University of California at Berkeley Policy 2008Folder 775423March 2007-April 20087Scope and ContentsPolicy guidelines for the UCB recycling program initiatives.03RB10Folder 875424March 2007-June 20088Scope and ContentsFinancial documents and correspondences related to project 03RB10.Facility Rebuild Request for Proposals 2007-2008Folder 975425July 20089Scope and ContentsDocuments related to the request for proposals concerning the rebuilding of recycling facilities.Statistics for the City of Berkeley 2008Folder 1075426April 2008-May 200910Scope and ContentsStatistical information on the recycling practices of the City of Berkeley.Transfer StationsFolder 1175427May 200911Scope and ContentsDocuments related to the hours of operation and pricing for three transfer stations operating in Alameda County.Multi-Family NumbersFolder 1275428May 200912Scope and ContentsProcedural and statistical documents related to the recycling procedures for residences housing multiple families.Statistics for the City of Berkeley, Part 2Folder 1375429May 200913Scope and ContentsA collection of further statistical information on the City of Berkeley.Move Out, University of California at Berkeley 2009Folder 1475430February-May 200914Scope and ContentsDocuments and correspondences related to a recycling and reuse program centered on the move out period at UCB.Manditory Recycling OrdinanceFolder 1575431June 200915Scope and ContentsA copy of the ordinance instituting mandatory recycling and composting practices.Rubbish Collection Franchise, Basic DocumentsFolder 1675443June 2003-June 200916Scope and ContentsDocuments related to the establishing of rubbish collection franchises in the City of Berkeley.Transfer Station RevnueFolder 1775444June 2008-October 200917Scope and ContentsFinancial documents detailing the revenue from transfer stations.2009 Jurisdiction ReportsFolder 1875445August 200918Scope and ContentsStatistical documents related to recycling in the City of Berkeley.January-March 2009, OACAFolder 1975447January-August 200919Scope and ContentsA collection of financial and statistical documents related to recycling companies and transfer stations near the City of Berkeley.Information Systems, Inc., April-June 2009Folder 2075448August 200920Scope and ContentsFinancial documents detailing the transactions of Information Systems, Inc.Zero Waste Commission Packet 10-09Folder 2175449January-September 200921Scope and ContentsForms and documents related to a meeting of the Zero Wast Commission and the intended agenda.Franchise TakeoverFolder 2275450October 2009-April 201022Scope and ContentsFinancial documents and correspondences focused on the recycling-related franchises in the City of Berkeley.Second Quarter Fiscal Year 2010Folder 2375451July 2009-March 201023Scope and ContentsFinancial documents related to the recycling in the City of Berkeley during the second fiscal quarter of 2010.ACWMA Mitigation 2002Folder 2475452January-March 201024Scope and ContentsA collection of documents related to the refuse fund in the City of Berkeley. It includes financial spreadsheets, mission statements, policy guidelines, and correspondences.Disaster Debris ManagementFolder 2575453January-March 201025Scope and ContentsA collection of materials from the California Emergency Management Agency Recovery Division detailing the proper means of managing debris in the event of a disaster.Zero Waste Commision Current MinutesFolder 2675454May 2009-March 201026Scope and ContentsDocuments, printouts meeting minutes for a meeting of the Zero Waste Commission.First Quarter Fiscal Year 2010, Transfer Station StatisticsFolder 2775455January-March 201027Scope and ContentsStatistical documents related to transfer station performance during the first quarter of 2010.Anaerobic Digestion Workshop April 12, 2010, San Diego, CAFolder 2875456April 12, 201028Scope and ContentsMaterials related to a presentation on anaerobic composting.Evergreen Environmental ServicesFolder 2975457December 2008-June 201029Scope and ContentsDocuments related to the contracting company Evergreen Environmental Services and there work for the City of Berkeley.Stop Waste, Other Landfill Reports and FormsFolder 3075458June-August 201030Scope and ContentsReports and forms related to transfer stations and landfills.ORBS Request for Proposals and Quarter 3Folder 3175459August 2009-August 201031Scope and ContentsA collection of documents related to the third quarter for transfers stations in the City of Berkeley and requests for proposals.Box 3Box 375460Zero Waste ItalyFolder 175461April-July 20101Scope and ContentsMaterials for a presentation on Zero Waste initiatives. Contains materials in Italian.Transfer Station RevenueFolder 275462December 20102Scope and ContentsFinancial documents related to transfer station revenue.Rate StructureFolder 375463December 20103Scope and ContentsFinancial documents and a proposal for the integration of waste management fees in the City of Berkeley.Waste Management Data, October-December 2009Folder 475464December 20104Scope and ContentsStatistical data related to the waste management system in the City of Berkeley.Alameda County Waste Managment Administration Progres ReportFolder 575465March 20115Sloan Vasques ReportFolder 675466March 20116Scope and ContentsA report by Sloan Vasques, Inc. assessing the solid waste management division for the city of Berkeley.Tim, StatisticsFolder 7754672009-April 20117Scope and ContentsStatistical information derived from a meeting with Tim Burroughs.Mitigation Fund Balance 646Folder 8754682010-December 20118Scope and ContentsFinancial and statistical documents related to the Mitigation fund.Landfill Reports 2009, City of BerkeleyFolder 975469December 20119Climate Action ReserveFolder 107547010Scope and ContentsDocuments and materials related to a presentation on Climate Action Reserve's Carbon Offsets Program. Filed at the end of this section due to lack of defining dates.City Building Regulatory StandardsFolder 117547111Scope and ContentsA copy of the recycling and composting guidelines for buildings in the City of Berkeley.Recycling in SchoolsFolder 127547212Scope and ContentsA collection of documents related to the proper procedures and guidelines for recycling in public schools.Unfiled Papers Folder 1Folder 13754731998-199013Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession. Notable inclusions: procedural guidelines for the City of Berkeley and charter amendments for the Alameda County Waste Reduction and Recycling Initiative.Unfiled Papers Folder 2Folder 14754741996-200014Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession, organized chronologically by year. The primary focus of these documents lies in the curbside recycling and plant debris pick-up programs for the City of Berkeley, solid waste managements statistics, and budget sheets for the Solid Waste Management Administration.Unfiled Papers Folder 3Folder 1575475200115Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession, organized chronologically by year. Contains correspondences concerning the Earth's 911 program.Unfiled Papers Folder 4Folder 16754762002-200316Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession, organized chronologically by year. Mainly composed of statistical and financial documents related to the City of Berkeley's recycling program. Invoices from contractors have also been included.Unfiled Papers Folder 5Folder 1775477200417Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession, organized chronologically by year. Includes a report on the disposal and use of polystyrene in California, documents related to the management of the Public Works Department, and handwritten notes by Tania Levy.Unfiled Papers Folder 6Folder 1875478200418Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession, organized chronologically by year. Primarily composed of handwritten notes by Tania Levy, but also contains personnel forms.Unfiled Papers Folder 7Folder 1975479200519Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession, organized chronologically by year. Primarily composed of financial documents related to the operations of recycling industries and contractors in the City of Berkeley.Unfiled Papers Folder 8Folder 2075480200520Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession, organized chronologically by year. Primarily composed of financial and statistical documents related to recycling programs in the City of Berkeley.Unfiled Papers Folder 9Folder 2175481200621Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession, organized chronologically by year. Composed of human resources documents, materials related to the Ecology Center, and financial records of the Public Works department.Unfiled Papers Folder 10Folder 2275482200622Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession, organized chronologically by year. Primarily composed of handwritten notes on scrap paper, financial documents, and administrative materials related to the operation of the Solid Waste Management Department.Box 4Box 475486Unfiled Papers Folder 11Folder 17548320071Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession, organized chronologically by year. Primarily composed of financial and statistical documents, materials concerning composting initiatives, and contact lists.Unfiled Papers Folder 12Folder 27548420072Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession, organized chronologically by year. Primarily composed of documents related to personnel management for the Solid Waste Management Administration.Unfiled Papers Folder 13Folder 37548520073Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession, organized chronologically by year. Primarily composed of financial and administrative documents, but also includes a newspaper article on a tailor.Unfiled Papers Folder 14Folder 47548720084Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession, organized chronologically by year. Primarily composed of financial and administrative documents, also includes handwritten notes by Tania Levy.Unfiled Papers Folder 15Folder 57548820085Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession, organized chronologically by year. Primarily composed of financial documents and emails related to the operations of the Solid Waste Management Administration.Unfiled Papers Folder 16Folder 67548920096Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession, organized chronologically by year. Primarily composed of administrative documents. Also contains graphical rendering of statistical information, a PR handout, and email correspondence.Unfiled Papers Folder 17Folder 77549020107Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession, organized chronologically by year. Contains handwritten notes, printouts of online information, financial documents, and a questionnaire and document request.Unfiled Papers Folder 18Folder 87549120108Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession, organized chronologically by year. Contains financial and administrative documents, 2011 city council meeting schedule, and guidelines for the payment of recycling deposits.Unfiled Papers Folder 19Folder 97549220119Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession, organized chronologically by year. Composed of financial documents, printed handouts, emails, and a sign listing Tania Levy as a member of the 2011-2012 US Composting Council.Unfiled Papers Folder 20Folder 1075493201110Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession, organized chronologically by year. Composed of financial documents, faxed copies of old recycling program forms, and an assessment of the Solid Waste Management Division for the City of Berkeley.Unfiled Papers Folder 21Folder 1175494201111Scope and ContentsThe City of Berkeley Solid Waste Rate Model Master Data Table-Expenses. 144 pages.Unfiled Papers Folder 22Folder 1275495201112Scope and ContentsA series of handwritten notes by Tania Levy.Unfiled Papers, NondatedFolder 137549613Scope and ContentsA collection of documents found loose at the time of accession, organized chronologically by year. These have been added to the end due to lack of defining dates. Composed of administrative documents, adverts, and contact lists.Fliers, Brochures, and Handouts, NondatedFolder 147549714Scope and ContentsA collection of materials related to recycling programs. Primarily contains materials intended for use in raising public awareness of certain programs.Report on the Use of Waste PaperFolder 157549815Scope and ContentsA report detailing the variety of uses for waste paper, as well as recommending some of them.Notes and Contact InformationFolder 167549916Scope and ContentsHandwritten notes and contact information found loose in Tania Levy's papers.Box 5Box 575500Misc Unfiled Materials Folder 1Folder 1755011Scope and ContentsA collection of manuals, magazines, and adverts found loose in Tania Levy's files.Misc Unfiled Materials Folder 2Folder 2755022Scope and ContentsA collection of manuals, magazines, and adverts found loose in Tania Levy's files.Misc Unfiled Materials Folder 3Folder 3755033Scope and ContentsA collection of manuals, magazines, and adverts found loose in Tania Levy's files.The AIKAN SystemItem 1755041Scope and ContentsPresentation materials for a seminar on the Aikan system of composting.Multifamily Green Building GuidlinesItem 2755052Scope and ContentsA manual dedicated to laying out the proper procedures for running a environmentally friendly multifamily home.Other Homes and GardensItem 3755063Scope and ContentsA book detailing methods of establishing a self-sufficient home.Legal Sized Papers &amp; Audio/visual materialBox 675507PhotosFolder 175513April-August 19941Scope and ContentsA collection of photographs of Tania Levy, children doing gardening, and a variety of recycling program related topics.Sample PR, San FranciscoFolder 275514September 20002Scope and ContentsA variety of documents meant to function as public relations for recycling programs in San Francisco.Yard Debris: Other CitiesFolder 375515September 2002-January 20033Scope and ContentsA collection of materials related to the programs handling yard debris in other cities near Berkeley.XX7 N06Folder 4755162002-20034Scope and ContentsFinancial and statistical documents related to the project labeled XX7N06.Recycling Grant FundsFolder 57551720065Scope and ContentsFinancial documents related to recycling grant funds in the City of Berkeley.Climate Action PlanFolder 67551820076Scope and ContentsA collection of documents related to the City of Berkeley's action plan for reducing their impact on the environment.Bighorn CurrentFolder 77551920077Scope and ContentsA collection of documents related to the operations of the Bighorn transfer station.Misc Loose PapersFolder 8755208Scope and ContentsDocuments of legal length that have been found loose in Tania Levy's papers.California Integrated Waste Management Board, "Redefining Re-Refining"Item 1755091Scope and ContentsA VHS tape containing a video aiming to dispel myths surrounding re-refined oil.Recycling Requirements for a Building PermitItem 2755102Scope and ContentsCity of Oakland, Construction and Demolition Recycling. Completing your Recycling Plan. Completing your Summary Report. Two copies are available of this VHS tape.Self-Reliant Cities: Energy and the Transformation of Urban AmericaItem 3755113Scope and ContentsA book concerning methods of establishing environmentally friendly practices for urban environments.Debris ManagementCD 175508June 1999Scope and ContentsA CD copy of the teaching materials for a course on debris management from FEMA.

