<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.01.02/02Archon Finding Aid Title J.01.02/02Sean BruceUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:21:51 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J1/2/2 Rebecca Veach, Assistant to the Vice President for Academic Affairs
    
      Veach, Rebecca
    
    J.01.02/02
    1771
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1977-1979
    Date acquired: 03/05/2012
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This is a collection of files donated by Rebecca Veach, former Assistant to the Vice President of Academic Affairs for Sangamon State University. It is split into two major sections, a file of administrative documents from 1978 and early 1979, and a copy of the Operations and Procedures manual for Sangamon State University from 1977.The first section contains a large number of different types of documents relating to the administration of the Academic Affairs department. It includes budget reports, correspondences, procedure guidelines, program descriptions, major requirements, faculty lists, a draft of a dedication speech, proposals, and university news releases.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Rebecca Veach  
  
    Correspondence
    Records
    Statistics
  
  Box 1Box 175103Chron File 78-79: December 1978-January 1979Folder 1751041978-19791Scope and ContentsA series of personal papers from Rebecca Veach. Contains correspondences, faculty lists, task force lists, and more.Chron File 78-79: October 18-November 31Folder 27510519782Scope and ContentsA collection of personal papers from Rebecca Veach. It includes correspondences, faculty lists, and proposals.Chron File 78-79: September 15-October 17Folder 37510619783Scope and ContentsA collection of personal papers from Rebecca Veach. It includes correspondences, a copy of academic procedural guidelines, budget reports, and statistical reports.Chron File 78-79: September 2-14Folder 47510719784Scope and ContentsA collection of personal papers from Rebecca Veach. It includes correspondences, course lists, program guides, budget reports, and grading policies.Chron File 78-79: August 10-September 1Folder 57510819785Scope and ContentsA collection of personal papers from Rebecca Veach. It includes catalog changes, assistantship lists, policy guidelines, university news releases, program requirements, and correspondences.Chron File 78-79: February 8-April 27Folder 67510919786Scope and ContentsA collection of personal papers from Rebecca Veach. It includes correspondences, budget reports, a draft of the dedication speech for the SSU observatory, faculty lists, and more.Sangamon State University Operations and Procedures Manual: Title Page and Table of ContentsFolder 775110November 19777Sangamon State University Operations and Procedures Manual: OutlineFolder 875111November 19778Sangamon State University Operations and Procedures Manual: I Academic ProgramFolder 975112November 19779Sangamon State University Operations and Procedures Manual: II Financial AffairsFolder 1075113November 197710Sangamon State University Operations and Procedures Manual: III Grants and ContractsFolder 1175114November 197711Sangamon State University Operations and Procedures Manual: IV LibraryFolder 127511512Sangamon State University Operations and Procedures Manual: V MicellaneousFolder 1375116November 197713Sangamon State University Operations and Procedures Manual: VI PersonnelFolder 1475117November 197714Sangamon State University Operations and Procedures Manual: VII Status of StudentsFolder 1575118November 197715Sangamon State University Operations and Procedures Manual: VIII Administrative ServicesFolder 1675119November 197716Sangamon State University Operations and Procedures Manual: IX Administrative Policies BulletinsFolder 1775120November 197717

