<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.51.01/02Archon Finding Aid Title J.51.01/02UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:07:24 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J51/1/2. Interracial Education Records, 1969-1975
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    
      Interracial Education Program
    
    J.51.01/02
    624
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1969-1975
    Date acquired: 11/07/1989
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Interracial Education Program records include grant proposal summaries, reports, memos and correspondence on the two major projects directed by Gus Stevens with assistance from Chris Breiseth &amp; Phil Kendall. One project was a series of summer institutes for school administrators and teachers designed to develop educationally effective attitudes and behavior in interracial schools.  The other was a program of weekend workshops and public lectures to help citizens of the community  adjust  to school desegregation.  
  
    Arrangement Note
By subject  
  
    Accruals and Additions
Added pamphlet: "Summer Institute on Interracial Education," SSU, 1972 to box 1, folder 1. Source unknown. Chris Schnell, June 1, 2017.  
  
    Correspondence
    Reports
    Records
  
  Box 1Box 154675SUMMER INSTITUTESFolder 1546761Scope and ContentsLetters, memos, syllabi and reports on Summer Institutes funded under Title IV of the 	Higher Education Act
Letters, memos, syllabi and reports on Summer Institutes funded  under Title IV of the 	Higher Education ActWORKSHOPS AND PUBLIC LECTURESFolder 2546772Scope and ContentsGrant proposal summary; letters, memos and reports on Workshops and Public Lectures funded under Title I of the Higher Education  Act
Announcements, letters, memos and reports on Workshops and Public Lectures funded under Title I of the Higher Education Act
Clippings, minutes, letters and memos on Workshops and Public Lectures funded under Title I of the Higher Education Act
Grant proposal; clippings, letters, memos and reports on Workshops and Public Lectures funded under Title I of the Higher Education Act  
Court order on school desegregation plan for Springfield, IL; letters, memos and reports on Workshops and Public Lectures funded under Title I of the Higher Education Act

