<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.51.05Archon Finding Aid Title J.51.05UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:07:30 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J51/5. Public Affairs Program Course Materials "Home Rule in Illinois" (PAC 408), 1973-1974
    
      Miller, Lynn
    
    J.51.05
    628
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1973-1974
    Date acquired: 06/23/1981
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Papers and materials relevant to the course PAC 408 "Cities of the State: Responsibility vs., Control,  taught in the fall of 1973 by Lynn Miller.  File includes student papers for cases,  source guides case digest, "Home Rule" newsletter from November 1972-Novemebr 1973, mid term paper, summaries of case studies involving Illinois Home Rule.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetically  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Lynn Miller  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Revised 3/6/1997  
  
    Course Materials
    Papers
    Newsletters
  
  Box 1Box 154407Cohn, Rubin G., "Judicial Decisions Interpreting Illinois Constitutional Home Rule Provisions"Folder 1544081Cole, Stephanie, "Home Rule Used by Local Governments in Illinois: Some Early Trends"Folder 2544092Cole, Stephanie, "Illinois Home Rule in Historical Perspective"Folder 3544103Forrest, Clyde W., "Improved Land Use Control Procedures for the Home Rule Municipality"Folder 4544114Green, Eugene, "Home Rule, Preemption, and the General Assembly"Folder 5544125Guide to Sources: In Municipal Home RuleFolder 6544136Hartman, Allen, "The Chicago Home Rule Commission: Reports and Recommendations"Folder 7544147Home Rule: A Case Digest by the University of Illinois Law StudentsFolder 854415July 19728Home Rule NewsletterFolder 9544169Home Rule Units in IllinoisFolder 105441710Kitsos, Thomas R., "Constitutional Constraints on Illinois Local Government: The Response of the Sixth Illinois Constitutional Conventions"Folder 115441811Levin, Edward M. Jr., "City power and the Federal System: Home Rule in Context"Folder 125441912Mack, Susan, "Home Rule Referenda in Illinois"Folder 135442013Midsemester ExaminationFolder 145442114MiscellaneousFolder 155442215Parkhurst, John C., "Article VII--Local Government"Folder 165442316Preliminary Report--Assembly on Home Rule in IllinoisFolder 175442417Schoeplein, Robert N., "Home Rule and Local Government Finance: An Economist's Perspective"Folder 185442518Summaries of Cases involving Illinois Home RuleFolder 195442619Young, J. Nelson, "Home Rule and Local Government Finance: A Legal Perspective"Folder 205442720

