<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.06.07/245Archon Finding Aid Title J.06.07/245UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:27:19 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J6/7/245. Environmental Science Program Student Records, 1971-1972
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    
      Johnson, Walter
    
    J.06.07/245
    517
    
      0.50 Cubic Feet
    
    1971-1972
    Date acquired: 12/01/1989
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Student papers cover environmental problems and proposed solutions at local,  state and national levels.  Topics included are waste disposal, recycling, and environmental legislation.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Environmental Science  
  Box 1Box 169522Farrimond, David, The Solid Waste ProblemFolder 1695241Hansen, R. H., Recycled Paper: The Product and its Consumption by the Government of the State of IllinoisFolder 2695252Lipsett, K. and Risberg, B., Environmental Awareness PollFolder 3695263Schemerhorn, David R., Springfield's Rat SituationFolder 4695274Stock, Jonelle, A Study of the Raw Water in Lake SpringfieldFolder 5695285Wright, John B., A Study and Comparison of the Federal, New Jersey and Illinois Environmental Protection ProgramsFolder 6695296Box 2Box 269523Betts, James F., A Comparison of the Pollution Control Mechanisms of Illinois, Missouri and the Federal GovernmentFolder 1695301Duffey, Terrence M. A Comparison in Pollution ControlFolder 2695312Hansen, R. H., Comparative Review of the Environmental Plans of the States of Connecticut and IllinoisFolder 3695323Klickna, Marjorie, Environmental Protection: A Summary of the Federal Laws and the Reaction of Illinois and Utah to those LawsFolder 4695334Oehmke, David W., A Comparison of the Colorado Pollution Control Agencies to the United States and Illinois Environmental Protection AgenciesFolder 5695345Brenne, M. J., Recycling in SpringfieldFolder 6695356Cowen, Dan, Beardstown's Sewage Systems and the Illinois RiverFolder 7695367

