<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.06.20/02Archon Finding Aid Title J.06.20/02UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:27:38 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J6/20/2. Center for the Study of Middle Size Cities Criminal Justice Awareness Project, 1976-1978
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    
      Center for the Study of Middle Size Cities
    
    J.06.20/02
    522
    
      4.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1976-1978
    Date acquired: 08/30/1979
    1
    2
    3
    4
    5
    6
    7
    8
    9
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Records and papers of the Criminal Justice Awareness Project of the Center for the Study of Middle-Size Cities including correspondence, working appears, questionnaires, grant materials, publications and computer printouts concerning criminal justice in Illinois, urban geography, needs of local government officials in Illinois, the Illinois Criminal Justice System and related topics.
This project was funded by the Illinois Law Enforcement Commission for 1976-1977 with the objectives of identifying officials involved with law enforcement and criminal justice decision-making, the ascertainment of the training of these individuals, the determination of their role in criminal justice planning, the funding of a series of regional workshops in criminal justice and the development of and field-test of a curriculum and information delivery system.  The project ran January 1976 to June 1977.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Received disorganized; rearranged as to CJAP files, working papers, publications, and printouts  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Sue Ann Schleder, Secretary  
  Box 1Box 170245Criminal Justice Awareness Project (CJAP), CorrespondenceFolder 170247January-March 19761CJAP CorrespondenceFolder 270248April-June 19762CJAP CorrespondenceFolder 370249July-December 19763CJAP CorrespondenceFolder 470250January-March 19774CJAP CorrespondenceFolder 570251April-August 19775CJAP CorrespondenceFolder 670252September 1977-19786MiscellaneousFolder 7702537CJAP PersonnelFolder 8702548CJAP Pilot TestingFolder 970255February 19779Box 2Box 270256Progress ReportsFolder 1702581976-781CJAP Workshop PlanningFolder 2702592CJAP Staff PositionsFolder 3702603City and County Officials, listsFolder 4702614Curriculum Advisory CommitteeFolder 5702625First Instrument and MailingsFolder 6702636CJAP Training ComponentFolder 7702647Individualized Instruction: Pre-Test Questionnaire and Post-Test QuestionnaireFolder 8702658Instrument/Questionnaire #2Folder 9702669Pre- and Post-Course QuestionnairesFolder 107026710ProposalFolder 1170268November 197611Box 3Box 370257Releases to ReprintFolder 17026919781Slide Presentation: The Challenge of Crime in a Changing SocietyFolder 2702702Work Activity CodesFolder 3702713Workshop: County Board MembersFolder 470272January 19774Workshop: Nominal Group ProcessFolder 570273March 5, 19765Workshop: Petersburg, Mt. Vernon, and ChampaignFolder 6702746Unidentified MaterialsFolder 7702757Box 4Box 470276Bibliography: Urban Geography AnnotationsFolder 1702781Criminal Justice and Local Government: Selected Illinois Statutes and Attorney General OpinionsFolder 270279August 19772Criminal Justice Awareness: A Program Guide, typescriptFolder 3702803Criminal Justice Awareness: A Program Guide, published guideFolder 470281August 19774Criminal Justice Awareness: A Trainer's Guide, originalFolder 5702825Criminal Justice in Illinois, original typescriptFolder 6702836Box 5Box 570277Criminal Justice in Illinois, original typesettingFolder 1702841Criminal Justice in Illinois, printer's dummyFolder 2702852Criminal Justice in Illinois Report DistributionFolder 3702863Criminal Justice Information Needs of Illinois Local Government OfficialsFolder 4702874Scope and Contents(Center for the Study of Middle-Sized Cities)Criminal Justice Information Needs of Local Government Officials in Small Towns, typescriptFolder 5702885Criminal Justice Training for Local Government Officials: An EvaluationFolder 670289June 19786Scope and ContentsCJAP Center for the Study of Middle-Sized CitiesDworak, Robert, Local Government Responsibilities for Criminal JusticeFolder 770290August 19777Milner, S. Burkett, Introduction to the Illinois Criminal Justice SystemFolder 870291August 19778Smith, Regan G., The Juvenile Justice System in Illinois, typescriptFolder 970292July 19779Box 6Box 670293VouchersFolder 170295January-May 19761VouchersFolder 270296June 19762Vouchers, Salaries, Postal, DuplicatingFolder 370297January 1976-January 19773VouchersFolder 470298January 1976-June 19774VouchersFolder 5702991977-785Vouchers, Central StoresFolder 6703006Vouchers, Fringe BenefitsFolder 7703017Vouchers, TravelFolder 870302February 1976-July 19778Vouchers, Account 21-115  Human Resource CenterFolder 9703039Box 7Box 770294Scope and ContentsComputer Printouts: Analysis of the questions used in the CJAP.  Labels as on Covers 	or on Printouts: Accuracy not guaranteed.CJAP Set 1.  Profile, City/County Cross Tab, Population Cross Tab, Title Cross Tab, Type of LGO Cross TabFolder 170304June 14, 19761CJAP Project Set 1.  Q1-Q5 Cross Tab, State Residence, City/County Residence, Age, Education, CJ CoursesFolder 2703052City/County vs. All Ques. and PopulationFolder 3703063CJAP Project Set 2 Partial.Folder 4703074Scope and ContentsCity/County Residence, Age-Complete, Education-Complete, CJ Course-Complete, Q6 Tile-Complete, CJAP Process Set 2 (Partial), Cross Tabs-Population, Type of LG, Title, State ResidenceCross Tabulations PrintoutsFolder 570308May 22, 19785CJAP Project Set 1. Cross Tab, Q6-Title, Q6A-Member of CJ Committee, Q7-Full Time EmployeeFolder 670309June 14, 19766Box 8Box 870310Q6A, Q6B, Q7, OccupationFolder 170312June 15, 19761Q6A OccupationFolder 2703132Box 9Box 970311Budget and voucher Records, CJAP (21-118)Folder 17031419781Criminal Justice in Illinois: An Information Resource for Local Government OfficialsFolder 2703152

