<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.06.20/06Archon Finding Aid Title J.06.20/06UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:27:48 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J6/20/6. Center for the Study of Middle Size Cities Citizen's Attitudes of Public School Dst 186
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    
      Center for the Study of Middle Size Cities
    
    J.06.20/06
    526
    
      1.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1978-1978
    Date acquired: 10/29/1979
    1&amp;2
    Printout
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The Center for the Study of Middle Size Cities designed and implemented this study under the sponsorship of the American Association of University Women to identify attitudes of citizens of District #186 toward the public school system.  The survey records include interview and screening materials.  
Working papers are boxed. Findings (computer printouts) are shelved unboxed with working papers.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Rough  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Bob Wesley  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Note: The individual interview forms were discarded 8/15/1988, and the computer printouts of these statistics retained.  
  Unbox ItemsItem 1699841Computer Printouts: American Association of University Women (AAUW) Study FrequencyItem 16998211Scope and Contents(unboxed item)Computer Printouts: AAUW Citizen's Perceptions of Public Education In Springfield, IllinoisItem 26998312Scope and Contents(unboxed item)Box 1Box 169975American Association of University Women, Code BookFolder 1699771Scope and Contents(for coding responses to Survey of Attitudes of Citizens of District #186 toward the Public School System)Screening and Interview FormsFolder 2699782Box 2Box 269976Completed Surveys (loose, no folder)Heading 169979Completed Interview Forms, replaced numbersHeading 269980Completed Interview Forms, numbers have been replacedHeading 369981

