<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.06.25/500Archon Finding Aid Title J.06.25/500UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:28:05 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J6/25/500. Center for the Study of Middle Size Cities Publications, 1982-1985
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    
      Center for the Study of Middle Size Cities
    
    J.06.25/500
    533
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1982-1985
    Date acquired: 09/27/1988
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The Publications of the Center for Community &amp; Regional Studies 1982-84 deal with citizen attitudes or problems in rural Illinois counties.  These include water supply, hospital service, foreign investments, air transportation, needed services and hospital marketing.  
  Box 1Box 169431Alternatives for Administering CSBG Funds in Jefferson, Franklin, Williamson, and Jackson Counties. Dr. Race D. DaviesFolder 1694321An Analysis of Residents' Attitudes Toward Hospital Services in The Knox County AreaFolder 2694332Attitudes of Springfield Area Businesspeople Toward Foreign Direct Investments. Dr. David E. O'GormanFolder 3694343Changing Air Transportation Services for Smaller Metropolitan Regions. Dr. William D. WarrenFolder 4694351980-824The City of Springfield Project: Study # 1 Citizen Perceptions Regarding Public Services in Springfield, Ill.Folder 5694365Scope and ContentsDr. Race D. Davies, Dr. Doh C. Shinn, Dr. Phillip M. Gregg, Mr. David C.  ThomasExecutive Summary: Citizens Perceptions and Preferences Regarding Public Services in SpringfieldFolder 6694376Scope and ContentsRace D. Davies, Doh C. Shinn, Phillip M. Gregg, David C. ThomasThe Economic Impact of Sangamon State University on Springfield and Sangamon County. Dr. Mark Erenburg, Ms. Sharon BaumFolder 7694387Identification of Small Ill. Municipalities That Need Assistance With Water Supply Problems.  William D. Warren, Race D. DavisFolder 8694398The Impact of Natural Gas Price Increases on Revenue of City, Water, Light, and Power Company. Sumol Padungchai, PhdFolder 9694409The 1984 Analysis of Citizen Opinions Regarding Taxes and Services in Springfield, Ill. Dr. Race D. Davies, Dr. Doh C. Shinn, Dr. Phillip M. GreggFolder 106944110Sangamon County Needs Assessment Study.  David Thomas, Director Survey Research Unit CCRSFolder 116944211Sangamon County Needs Assessment: Executive Summary.  Dolo Brooking, Project DirectorFolder 126944312Setting Priorities: Community Perceptions of Needed Services. Harry J. Berman, PhD, John Poertner, D.S.W.Folder 136944413Subjective Measures of Service Cutbacks.  Doh C. Shinn, Phillip M. Gregg, Race D. DaviesFolder 146944514Survey InstrumentFolder 156944615Tactical Hospital Marketing: A Survey of the State of the Art. Paul K. McDevitt, Lisa A. ShieldsFolder 166944716Evaluations and Results of the 1985 Civil Service Staff Evaluation Process – A Report on the Staff and Supervisor Survey Study ResultsFolder 176944817The Economic Impact of Ten Cultural Institutions on the Economy of the Springfield, Illinois SMSA, by David CwiFolder 186944918Scope and ContentsSpringboard Arts Study, Report No. 4, 1/21/1980.  Study was a combined effort of the Center for the Study of Middle-size Cities (SSU), Community Arts Council of Springfield, and The Johns Hopkins University

