<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.10.01/06Archon Finding Aid Title J.10.01/06UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:28:35 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J10/1/6. Library, Miscellaneous Papers, 1971-1998
    
      Library
    
    J.10.01/06
    542
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1971-1998
    Date acquired: 07/23/2002
    1
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This collection consists of miscellaneous library documents including budget information, holdings and growth charts, as well as reports from Dr. David Kaser and Carlton C. Rochelle and the North Central Association of Colleges and Schools.  Also included are agendas with notes from meetings between the Dean of the Library and the Vice President for Academic Affairs from 1991-1998.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Subject  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Jane Treadwell  
  Box 1Box 147621History (Budget allocations)Folder 1476221971-811Budget package banking summary FY83Folder 24762319832Budget information FY82Folder 34762419823Staff - Library employees, job descriptionsFolder 44762519824Holdings-Monthly holdings and growth charts and projected circulation statisticsFolder 5476261977-865Pricing tables of periodicals and indexesFolder 64762719816Long Range PlanFolder 7476281980-817Responses to Questions regarding use of library materials from the BORFolder 847629September 19818Scope and ContentsResponses to Carol Floyd's QuestionsBOR Non-academic Evaluation ReportFolder 94763019829Excerpts of reports from the North Central Association of Colleges and Schools (NCA)Folder 10476311981-8210Kaser ReportFolder 1147632197511Scope and ContentsReport of Dr. David Kaser of Indiana University on library prospects and problemsRochelle ReportFolder 1247633197912Scope and ContentsReport of Carlton C. Rochelle of New York University evaluating the effects of the Kaser Report suggestionsProgram-Administrative InformationFolder 1347634198213Brookens Building-Report on the building and floor plansFolder 1447635197714Annual Report of ArchivesFolder 15476361973-74, 1982-83, 1983-8415General Information about Library and Organizational ChartFolder 16476371986-8716Library Faculty Evaluation GuidelinesFolder 17476381972-7417Library Faculty InformationFolder 18476391971 and 198718Library BudgetFolder 19476401971-9719Reserve Readings PolicyFolder 20528567/15/199720Scope and ContentsAlyce Scott, Head of CirculationVice President for Academic Affairs (VPAA) LogsFolder 21476416/1/1983 – 6/1/199021Scope and Contents1.	SSU State University Library Meeting with VPAA  Jun. 1, 1983
2.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Re: Meeting with Mike Ayers on Jun. 8, 1983
3.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Re: Meeting with Mike Ayers on Jun. 10, 1983
4.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Re: Meeting Agenda Jun. 16, 1983
5.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Re: Meeting with Mike Ayers on Jun. 20, 1983
6.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Re: Meeting with Mike Ayers on Jun. 22, 1983
7.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Re: Meeting with Mike Ayers on Jul. 8, 1983
8.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Re: Meeting with Mike Ayers on Jul. 18, 1983
9.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Re: Meeting with Mike Ayers on Jul. 26, 1983
10.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Re: Meeting with Mike Ayers on Aug. 23, 1983
11.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Re: Meeting with Mike Ayers on Aug. 29, 1983
12.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Re: Meeting with Mike Ayers on Sep. 7, 1983
13.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Re: Meeting with Mike Ayers, Dick Durbin, and Mike Daley on Sep. 9, 1983
14.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Re: Meeting with Mike Ayers on Sep. 12, 1983
15.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Re: Meeting with Mike Ayers on Sep. 15, 1983
16.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Re: Agenda for Library Program Committee Meeting on Sep. 19, 1983
17.	VPAA Meeting Agenda on Oct. 17, 1983
18.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Re: Meeting with Mike Ayers on Nov. 1, 1983
19.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Re: Meeting with Mike Ayers on Jan 23, 1984
20.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Re: Meeting with Mike Ayers on Feb. 6 1984
21.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Feb. 14, 1984 Re: Meeting with Mike Ayers on Feb. 13, 1984
22.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Apr. 5, 1984 Re: Meeting with Mike Ayers on Apr. 4, 1984
23.	VPAA Log from Brian Alley Apr. 10, 1984 Re: Meeting with Mike Ayers on Apr. 9, 1984
24.	VPAA Minutes from Jul. 13, 1984 Meeting
25.	VPAA  Agenda from Jul. 16, 1984 Meeting
26.	VPAA Agenda from Jul. 30, 1984 Meeting
27.	VPAA Agenda from Aug. 6, 1984 Meeting
28.	VPAA Agenda from Aug. 10, 1984 Meeting
29.	VPAA Agenda from Aug. 22, 1984 Meeting
30.	VPAA Agenda from Aug. 27, 1984 Meeting
31.	VPAA Agenda from Sep. 3, 1984 Meeting
32.	VPAA Agenda from Oct. 15, 1984 Meeting
33.	VPAA Agenda from Oct. 22, 1984 Meeting
34.	VPAA Agenda from Jan. 14, 1984 Meeting
35.	VPAA Agenda from Feb. 2, 1985 Meeting
36.	VPAA Agenda from Mar. 21, 1985
37.	VPAA Agenda from May 9, 1985 Meeting
38.	VPAA Agenda from Aug. 22, 1985 Meeting
39.	VPAA Agenda from Oct. 2, 1985 Meeting
40.	VPAA Agenda from Jul. 25, 1986 Meeting
41.	VPAA Agenda from Jan. 30, 1987 Meeting
42.	VPAA Agenda from Jun. 23, 1987 Meeting
43.	VPAA Agenda from Aug. 14, 1987 Meeting
44.	VPAA Agenda from Oct. 2, 1987 Meeting
45.	VPAA Agenda from Nov. 5, 1987 Meeting
46.	VPAA Agenda from Jan. 26, 1988 Meeting
47.	 VPAA Agenda from Apr. 5, 1988 Meeting
48.	VPAA Minutes from Sep. 28, 1988 Meeting
49.	VPAA Minutes from Oct. 12, 1988 Meeting
50.	VPAA Minutes from Nov. 9, 1988 Meeting
51.	VPAA Agenda from Feb. 28, 1989 Meeting
52.	Memorandum from Library Program Committee to Brian Alley, Re: Nine-month Contract Option for Library Faculty
53.	VPAA Agenda from Sep. 11, 1989 Meeting
54.	VPAA Minutes from Sep. 29, 1989 Meeting
55.	Memorandum Nov. 29, 1989 - from Brian Alley to Wayne Penn Re: Request for Additional Student Wage Funds
56.	VPAA Agenda from Feb. 6, 1990 Meeting
57.	VPAA Agenda from Jun. 5, 1990 MeetingVPAA Weekly MeetingFolder 2247642FY9122Scope and Contents1.	Memorandum From: Brian Alley – May 1, 1990 – To The University Community – Re: Termination of Periodical Loans
2.	Letter from Sangamon State University Chapter of Local 4100, IFT/AFT AFL-CIO – Jul. 10, 1990 – Re: Collective Bargaining Agreement
3.	Library Hours Draft – Jan. 14, 1991- May 12, 1991
4.	Memorandum From: Brian Alley – Jan. 14, 1991 – To Wayne Penn – Re: Administrative Status for Program Administrative Assistants
5.	Memorandum From: Brian Alley – Jan. 24, 1991 – To Wayne Penn – Re: Working Papers
6.	Memorandum From: Nina S. Adams, Michael Ayers – Apr. 1, 1991 – To Edward Wass – Re: Extra Merit CompensationVPAA – Biweekly MeetingFolder 2347643FY9223Scope and Contents1.	Memorandum From: Anne Draznin – Mar. 9, 1987 – To Michael Ayers – VPAA, and Wayne Penn – Re: Student Retention
2.	Library Non-Personal Services FY92 – Jul. 31, 1991
3.	Memorandum From Brian Alley – Aug. 1, 1991 – To Wayne Penn – Re: Replacement for Instructional Services Librarian Position Number 1005
4.	Memorandum From Brian Alley – Aug. 1, 1991 – To Wayne Penn, VPAA – Re: List of Faculty Books
5.	Memorandum From: Brian Alley – Aug. 2, 1991 – To Wayne Penn, VPAA – Re: Academic Affairs Computer Advisory Committee
6.	VPAA Agenda from Aug. 19, 1991 Meeting
7.	VPAA Agenda from Sep. 3, 1991 Meeting
8.	VPAA Agenda from Sep. 16, 1991 Meeting
9.	SSU Library Periodical Budget Projections, Revised Oct. 1991
10.	VPAA Agenda from Oct. 1, 1991 Meeting
11.	VPAA Agenda from Oct. 14, 1991 Meeting
12.	Letter from Naomi B. Lynn, SSU President - To Anne Draznin – Legal Studies Faculty – Re: 1987 Memo with suggestions for improving campus climate
13.	SSU News Article: SSU Library Closes Too Soon – Oct. 23, 1991
14.	VPAA Agenda from Oct. 29, 1991 Meeting
15.	VPAA Agenda from Dec. 6, 1991 Meeting
16.	Memorandum From: Brian Alley – Dec. 12, 1991 – To Wayne Penn, VPAA – Re: Replacement for Instructional Services Librarian Position Number 1004
17.	Memorandum From: Brian Alley – Dec. 19, 1991 – To Wayne Penn, VPAA – Re: Request for Student Wage Funding
18.	Memorandum From: Brian Alley – Jan. 22, 1992 – To Wayne Penn, VPAA – Re: Suggestions for Additional Budget Cuts
19.	VPAA Agenda for Feb. 10, 1992 Meeting
20.	VPAA Agenda for Mar. 3, 1992 Meeting
21.	Brookens Library Closing Flyer dated Mar. 7, 1992
22.	VPAA Agenda for Mar. 23, 1992 Meeting
23.	Memorandum From: Larry Dale – Mar. 24, 1992 – To Brian Alley – Re: Announcement Draft: Media Services Announces Temporary Service Cutbacks
24.	Memorandum From Brian Alley – Apr. 16, 1992 – To Wayne Penn, VPAA – Re: 1992 Support Function Reviews
25.	VPAA Minutes from Aug. 5, 1992 Meeting from Academic CabinetCommittee on Educational Quality and ProductivityFolder 2447644FY9024Scope and Contents1.	State of Illinois Board of Higher Education: Committee on Scope, Structure, and Productivity of Illinois Higher Education – An Action Agenda for Illinois Higher Education: Improving Quality, Cost Effectiveness, and Accountability in the 1990's Mar. 6, 1990 - Guidelines
2.	Sangamon State University Accreditation Self-Study Report Volume I 1986-1987
3.	Sangamon State University Accreditation Self-Study Report Volume II "Basic Institutional Data" 1986-1987
4.	Memorandum From: Wayne Penn, VPAA – Feb. 28, 1990 – To Committee on Educational Quality and Productivity – Re: Meeting Time
5.	Regency Report – Regency Universities System
6.	State of Illinois Board of Higher Education – Committee on Scope, Structure, and Productivity of Illinois Higher Education: Improving the Quality, Accountability, and Productivity of Illinois Higher Education – Jan. 18, 1990
7.	Papers: Raising Productivity in Higher Education
8.	Sample "Snapshot" Data on Each Academic Program - 1983-1989
9.	Committee on Productivity and Quality – Minutes for Mar. 9, 1990 Meeting
10.	Memorandum From Wayne Penn, VPAA – Feb. 20, 1990 – To Brian Alley –Re: Committee on Educational Quality and Productivity
11.	VPAA –  State of Illinois Board of Higher Education Report – Mar. 6, 1990Agendas with notes of meetings between the Dean of the Library and VPAAFolder 2547645January – December 199125Agendas with notes of meetings between the Dean of the Library and VPAAFolder 2647646January – December 199226Agendas with notes of meetings between the Dean of the Library and VPAAFolder 2747647January – December 199327Agendas with notes of meetings between the Dean of the Library and VPAAFolder 2847648January – December 199428Agendas with notes of meetings between the Dean of the Library and VPAAFolder 2947649January – December 199529Agendas with notes of meetings between the Dean of the Library and VPAAFolder 3047650January – December 199630Agendas with notes of meetings between the Dean of the Library and VPAAFolder 3147651January – December 199731Agendas with notes of meetings between the Dean of the Library and VPAAFolder 3247652January – December 199832Upper Division Colleges – ERIC Search ResultsFolder 334765333ED318386, HE023484Item 147654Nov. 1989331Scope and ContentsEffective Marketing Strategies Flow from Sound Segmentation Data.  Chen, Henry C. K.; And OthersED312950, HE023007Item 247655Jan. 1989, 1983332Scope and ContentsThe Twentieth Campus. An Analysis of the California State University's Proposal to Establish a Full-Service Campus in the City of San Marcos in Northern San Diego County.  Commission Report 89-2.  California State Postsecondary Education Commission, Sacramento,ED287335, HE020671Item 3476561987333Scope and ContentsAssociate/Bachelor Degree Articulation. Hochberg, L. Jim, Sr.  24 Apr. 1987. 10 p.; Paper presented at the convention of the American Association of Community and Junior Colleges, April 22-25, 1987 (Dallas, TX)ED285463, HE020599Item 4476571986 &amp; 1987334Scope and ContentsAge Group and Sex of Students, Fall 1986. State University of New York. Office of Institutional Research Report No. 8-87. State Univ. of New York, Albany.  Office of Institutional Research and Analytical Studies. Jul. 1987, 719 p.EJ310221, HE518841Item 547658Summer 1984335Scope and ContentsUpper-Level Colleges Yesterday, Today, and Tomorrow;  Cardozier, V. R. ; Educational Record, v65 n3 p30-35EJ308, HE518787Item 647659November-December 1984336Scope and ContentsDifferential Pricing of Undergraduate Education, Yanikoski, Richard A. ; Wilson, Richard F.  Journal of Higher Education, v55 n6 p.735-50ED277331, HE019953Item 747660Apr. 1986337Scope and ContentsA Longitudinal Cross Validation of a Basic Skills Testing Remediation Paradigm for Older, Reentry College Juniors.  Suddick, David E.; Collins, Burton A.  8p.ED274243, HE 019677Item 847661June 1986338Scope and ContentsAnalysis for the State University's Criteria for Approving Permanent Upper-Division and Graduate Off-Campus Centers; A Report to the Governor and Legislature in Response to Senate Bills 785, 1060, and 1103 (1985). Commission Report 86-19. California State Postsecondary Education Commission, Sacramento,  29 p.ED270063, HE019378Item 947662November 1985339Scope and ContentsInstructional Costs per Student Credit Hour: Differences by Level of Instruction. Brinkman, Paul T. , National Center for Higher Education Management Systems, Boulder, Colo. 30, 33p.ED268934, HE019302Item 1047663April 19863310Scope and ContentsLong-Term Educational Attainment in an Open-Access University System: Effects of Ethnicity, Economic Status, and College Type.  Lavin, David E.; And Others.  36p.ED267697, HE019165Item 1147664May 19853311Scope and ContentsStrategic Planning and Management:  A survey of Practices and Benefits in Higher Education.  Meredith, Mark  63p.ED261570, HE018309Item 1247665March 19, 19853312Scope and ContentsBridging the Gap:  A Case Study of Cooperative Strategies to Improve the Transfer Experience, Bowles, Dympna J.; and Others 15p.ED252122, HE017951Item 134766619843313Scope and ContentsThe Upper Level College Revisited, Higher Education Series, Topical Paper 8401, Cardozier, V.R. Texas Univ., Austin, Dept. of Educational Administration 35p.EJ261819, HE515592Item 144766719813314Scope and ContentsExplaining the Academic Performance of Community College Students Who Transfer to a Senior Institution; Phlegar, Archie G.; And Others.  Research in Higher Education, v15 n2 p99-108EJ224151, JC502074Item 1547668Summer 19793315Scope and ContentsThe Role of the Upper-Level University in American Higher Education; Kintzer, Frederick C. ; Community College Frontiers, v7 n4 p35-40ED211019, HE014680Item 16476691981 &amp; 19823316Scope and ContentsA National Study of Upper-Level Institutions; AASCU Studies, 1981/2; Bell, David P. American Association of State Colleges and Universities, Washington, D.C. Sep. 1981, 34p. Report No: ISBN-0-88044-058-9ED205085, HE014111Item 1747670May 19813317Scope and ContentsAn enrollment Impact Study to Determine Whether to Implement Lower Divisions at Four Upper Division State Universities; AIR Forum 1981 Paper; Hector, Henry J. ; Christal, Melodie E.  20p.ED202279, HE013786Item 1847671July 19803318Scope and ContentsQuality in Higher Education: A Community College Perspective; Priest, Bill J.  Education Commission of the States, Denver, Colo. Inservice Education Program; State Higher Education Executive Officers Association,  10p.ED180329, HE012059Item 1947672October 19793319Scope and ContentsA National Study of Upper-Level Institutions: Some Initial Observations; Bell, David P. , Oct. 1979; 11p.  Paper presented at the Southern Association of Institutional Research Conference (Orlando, FL. October 25, 1979)

