<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.52.00Archon Finding Aid Title J.52.00UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:07:48 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J52. Student Papers, Various Subjects, 1970-1983
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    J.52.00
    637
    
      1.66 Cubic Feet
    
    1970-1983
    Date acquired: 05/25/1976
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Student papers acquired by University Archives on a variety of subjects.  Many deal with Springfield and other local topics.  
Separate folder J52 contains a copy of the Boxlist/Inventory of authors and titles for the individual J52/(name) files.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical order by student name within program  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Papers are grouped according to class, some may represent odds and ends acquired piecemeal.  
  
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 141093Ahmed, Syed R. DropoutFolder 141094Spring 19761Alexander, Brian.  Eugene Debs and the American Socialist Movement, 1900-1926Folder 2410952Alexander, Brian. Lincoln's Humor and Lincoln Relics in the Illinois State Historical LibraryFolder 3410963Analysis of the Security Function at Sangamon State University (SJP 455)Folder 441097Fall 19744Arth, Jim J. Survey of Cemetery Costs in IllinoisFolder 5410981976-12-185Bahlow, Pat. Accessibility and the Handicapped (PAC 435)Folder 6410996Barker, R-Lou P. Guide for Genealogical Research (Library Lab)Folder 74110019757Barringer, Judy. The Status of Female Librarians (WCS 453)Folder 8411018Bartolomucci, Pat. Program Evaluation Review TechniqueFolder 9411029Benoit, Martin W. Business Analysis – Ford and Iroquois CountyFolder 1041103197610Berry, Richard W. An Analysis of the Illinois Senate Race: Allan Dixon v. Dave O'NealFolder 114110411Best, Kathleen L. The Illinois Open Meetings act, June 15, 1980: Will It Remain  a Boondoggle?Folder 1241105198012Bockstruck, Cynthia. Group Counseling with Mild and Moderately Retarded AdultsFolder 1341106198013Boren, Michael B. When did an Aeroplane First Land in Pick County, Illinois?Folder 144110714Brager, Jon. Sangamon County (Economics Population, Growth, Government)Folder 154110815Brandt, Chet. Sources Pertaining to Central Illinois, 1800-1860Folder 164110916Brockschmidt, William. The Springfield Race Riot of 1908Folder 174111017Burton, Larry K. Position Report on Library MaterialFolder 184111118Campbell, Anne. The New Woman of the TwentiesFolder 194111219Campo, Terry T. Influencing Illinois: The Business of Lobbying, July 1979Folder 204111320Cannon, Scott H. The War Against Social Interests in Illinois: The Public Interest Lobbies FightFolder 214111421Cantrall, Dan. Poverty and Policy in Illinois HistoryFolder 224111522Carpenter, Alice E. Library CurriculumFolder 234111623Carriker, Grace E. An Early History of Montgomery County, Illinois and Some of Its Settlers, the CarrikersFolder 244111724Carroll, Timothy. America's Treatment of the Poor: An Assessment Using Local Government RecordFolder 254111825Casper, Robert I. and Phillip Grause. An Opinion Research Survey of Divernon High SchoolFolder 264111926Coberly, Margaret. Self Image and Listening Skills in a Client Worker RelationshipFolder 274112027Collins, Margaret &amp; Pharra Phipp. Report on Springfield Nursing HomeFolder 284112128Croenne, Marsha and Patty Dye. Which is a Better Place to Live?:  Taylorville or Springfield?Folder 294112229Cross, Grace G. Controversial Viewpoints Concerning Abraham LincolnFolder 304112330Croteau, Catherine. A Study of the Senior Learner Program at SSUFolder 3141124February, 198331Box 2Box 241125Damrau, Ellen M. Therapy for the Deaf."  PSY ProgramFolder 141126March, 19791Day, Jo. How Does the Springfield Community View SSU?Folder 2411272Day, William L. An Episodic Review of Prison Industry History in IllinoisFolder 3411283Debolt, Dean. The Contribution of Miss Margaret Cross Norton to American Archival DevelopmentFolder 4411294Debolt, Dean.  History of the Metallurgical LaboratoryFolder 5411305Dickison, Jeffery I. Hypnotic AnalgesiaFolder 6411316Downey, Ted. Congressional HelpersFolder 7411327Downey, Ted.  An Experience in GovernmentFolder 8411338Eitenmiller, George A.  Inventory SystemsFolder 9411349Finchum, Jim. Satellite CommunicationsFolder 1041135Fall 197810Foss, Joyce and John Record. St. Johns Hospital Community Perception StudyFolder 114113611Prevelletti, Chris. The International Year of the Disabled Person in IllinoisFolder 124113712Friedland, Milton D. Freedom to Read in 20th Century AmericaFolder 134113813Gallois, Howard.  Decreasing the Disrobing Behavior of a Profoundly Retarded WomanFolder 144113914Gardiner, Gerry.  The Black Community: Circa 1920Folder 154114015Gardiner, Gerry.  What was … Tear Gassing of Students at SIU?Folder 164114116Green, Kimberly.  Subculture Barriers to Good CommunicationFolder 174114217Harris, Shirley A.  The Teacher Center in Illinois: A Different Way to GrowFolder 184114318Hendrickson, Kristin.  Sexuality of the Spinal Cord Injured FemaleFolder 194114419Hicks, David.  Penal Procedures in 2001,  DavisFolder 2041145Spring 197120Hopkins, Dottie.  A Look at the Indians and the Battles of the Little BighornFolder 214114621Horney, Deborah A.  Blind Multi-handicapped individuals and Self Injurious BehaviorFolder 224114722Swang, Shan-Wen.  Communication Counseling and CultureFolder 234114823Box 3Box 341149Irwin, Lewis. Anti-Mormon Violence in IllinoisFolder 1411501Jackson, Garry M.  The Placebo EffectFolder 2411511973-03-092Jenning, Richards L.  An Analysis of Services Provided by the City of SpringfieldFolder 3411523Jet, Marsha White.  Day Care CentersFolder 4411534Kinion, Jack E.  An Argument for the Controversial Materials in Sangamon State University LibraryFolder 5411545Kablesky, Jane.  Social Service in SpringfieldFolder 6411556Koefoed, Elizebeth.  Communication with the HA/LD ChildFolder 7411567Krohe, Jim.  Politics of SchoolsFolder 8411578Krohe, Jim. The Springfield Race Riot Trial of 1908Folder 9411589Krohe, Jim and Stephen Morse. The Effect of Race Riot on Black Housing Patterns Since 1908Folder 104115910Krohe, Jim.  School Board Elections in SpringfieldFolder 114116011Levandouski, Marry L.  Welfare FraudFolder 124116112Lusch, Mark A.  The Photo Voltaics MarketsFolder 13411621980-10-1513Macdonald, Greg. A Look at the 1928 ElectionFolder 144116314Mackay, Jamey L.  The Prescriptive Application of Meditation as Indicated by Primary Representational SystemFolder 154116415McMahan, Ann.  Project Bike PathFolder 1641165197116Mcquown, Celia.  Two NeighborhoodsFolder 174116617Mahoney, Mary Beth.  The Sangamon County Juvenile Court System, its History and DevelopmentFolder 184116718Majewski, Judy.  Poverty and Organized Religion in SpringfieldFolder 194116819Manningg, Barbara.  AmnestyFolder 204116920Mansfield, Greg.  Aging in America: An Annotated BibliographyFolder 214117021Markwood, Evelyn.  Equal Rights AmendmentFolder 224117122Melton, Lawrence C., Jr.  Factors Influencing the Decision of Dependent Employment vs. Self EmploymentFolder 234117223Miller, Lori.  The Progressive Case ReviewedFolder 244117324Monson, D.B.  Environmental Psychology: The Drinking EnvironmentFolder 254117425Moore, Peggy.  1980 Political Race for Representative to U.S. Illinois 20th District Paul Findley v. Dave RobinsonFolder 264117526Netznik, Susan.  Self-awareness: Self-Disclosure Implications in CommunicationFolder 274117627Myers, Tony.  The Neon StreetFolder 284117728Box 4Box 441178O'Dell, Elizabeth.  Alan J. Dixon vs. David C. O'NealFolder 1411791980-12-031Olien, David W.  Construction and Execution of a Public Opinion Poll in Sangamon County, IllinoisFolder 2411801973-12-042Olien, David W.  Federal Revenue Sharing: A Report from Macon County, IllinoisFolder 3411811973-05-203Olien, David W.  Perspectives on the 1966 Freedom of Information Act and a Test of Freedom in the Walker AdministrationFolder 4411821973-09-204Patton, Annabelle.  Big Brother/Big Sister of Sangamon County: An OverviewFolder 5411831974-11-015Patton, Larry.  Dissent in Illinois, 1861-1865Folder 6411841972-11-016Patton, Larry.  Illinois Attitudes toward Slavery and Relating Issues Prior to the Election of 1860Folder 7411851972-12-077Patton, Larry.  The Rebirth of the Ku Klux Klan and its Development in the MidwestFolder 8411861972-05-308Patterchak, Janice.  How the Lincoln Home Area Became a National History SiteFolder 9411871972-03-149Petzing, Chas E.  Papers 1980Folder 104118810Scope and ContentsWetlands: Their Impact on Life; Employment Practices of the United Nations; The People's Republic of China and Richard Nixon; and Attaining Environmental Quality: The Role of the Technical Decision Maker.Pluta, Bill.  State Energy Conservation Policy in Illinois -- An Overview, Plus an Analysis of Programs for Local GovernmentsFolder 11411891979-05-0811Powell, J.  Servomechanism Feedback Sites Involved in the Hypothalamic-Pituitary-Adrenal Stress ResponseFolder 12411901974-12-1912Powers, S.B.  Thru the Walls: A Manual for Organizing and Empowerment with the Prisoner Support Movement, undatedFolder 134119113Unknown Author.  Real Estate, undatedFolder 144119214Reavy, Brenda.  The Well of Loneliness by Radclyff Hall, undatedFolder 154119315Reid, Marcel D.  The Case of the Springfield, Sangamon County Regional Planning CommissionFolder 1641194Fall 197616Rieken, Homer G.  The Van Winkle AppointmentFolder 17411951972-03-0717Russo, Ed.  Springfield's Illinois Central Railroad Depot, 1890, undatedFolder 184119618Rose, Janet.  Education of the Deaf: The Methods Controversy, undatedFolder 194119719Box 5Box 541198Sarff, Megg.  War Was Never Meant to be Turned into Reckless SlaughterFolder 1411991972-03-171Schnepp, Susan.  The Emergency Employment Act and Its Implementation in SpringfieldFolder 2412001972-06-052Schullian, Ted.  A Cultural Comparison of the Sauk and Fox Indians and the Contemporary AmericansFolder 3412011977-10-213Schulte, Kurt L.  An Evaluation of the Real Property Acquisition Procedures Used by the State of IllinoisFolder 4412021983-05-194Schwarberg, John M.  Case Study of the Illinois State FairFolder 5412031976-12-165Sedlak, Sally L.  Opinions of the City Council on State and Federal GovernmentsFolder 6412041972-03-206Shuey, Linda.  Metropolitan Intergovernmental RelationsFolder 741205Spring 19747Sloan, Carol.  Criminal Commitments to Mental InstitutionsFolder 8412061974-05-098Smith, Larry.  Portuguese in Springfield, undatedFolder 9412079Stock, Jonelle B.  Witness to HistoryFolder 10412081973-12-0910Suttles, Dennis E.  The F. W. Jansen Furniture Company of Quincy, IllinoisFolder 1141209May 197711Suttles, Dennis E.  James Rutledge of New Salem: Fact or FictionFolder 12412101978-05-1212Suttles, Dennis E.  Scott County Sources: An Annotated Research Guide to Local History, 1818-1978Folder 134121113Suttles, Dennis E.  A Selected BibliographyFolder 1441212197714Suttles, Dennis E.  The Stephan A. Douglas Klan No. 72 of Winchester, Illinois: A Problem in HistoriographyFolder 15412131978-05-0815Sweatman, Dennis L.  The Net Fiscal and Political Effects of Revenue Sharing in the City of Springfield, IllinoisFolder 16412141975-05-0516Thomson, John C.  History 497 Final Exam: Politics of Foreign AidFolder 17412151974-05-0917Unknown Author.  Treaty of Versailles, undatedFolder 184121618Vanzant, Don M.  The Effects of the Third Awakening on Rural IllinoisFolder 19412171984-10-0919Van Houten, Jim.  The Integral Phalanx: The Sangamon Association, 1844-1850, undatedFolder 204121820Wagonner, Horace Q.  The Illinois Prairie Purchasing Pattern:  An Analysis of the Relation Between Cultural Backgrounds and Land Selection in Montgomery and Macoupin Counties, Illinois, 1819-1850Folder 2141219May 197721Weyhenmeyer, Charles H.  The Springfield Emergency Employment Act Project: Mediating Technology in the City Coordinator's OfficeFolder 22412201972-11-1322Worley, Sue E.  A Profile of the Sangamon County Poor FarmFolder 23412211983-12-0523

