<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.10.06/00Archon Finding Aid Title J.10.06/00UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:28:58 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J10/6. Library Bibliographic Instruction Workshop Records, 1974
    
      Library
    
    J.10.06/00
    552
    
      0.50 Cubic Feet
    
    1974
    Date acquired: 11/01/1979
    1
    2
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This series includes planning papers and printed programs for the Bibliographic Instruction Workshop offered by the SSU library in May 1974.  It also includes a collection of instructional materials from other academic libraries; library guides, handbooks, articles, and books.  These materials are indexed separately.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Workshop materials and separate Index to separate Instruction Materials Collection  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Florence Lewis  
  Box 1Box 165304Library Skills: A Program in Self-InstructionFolder 16530519701Scope and Contents140 pp.  Library Technology Inc., McGraw-Hill Book Co.Specimen Set for Study Skills Test  McGraw-Hill Book Co.Folder 26530619702Job description, Instructional Services LibrarianFolder 36530719723Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois: Sangamon State UniversityWorkload plan, Instructional Services LibrarianFolder 46530819724Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois: Sangamon State UniversityLibrary Use Instructional Programs Being Developed at the Brigham Young University Clark LibraryFolder 5653095Scope and ContentsList of programs available, under development, and costLarson, Russ. Teaching Research Methods in Freshman CompositionFolder 6653106Scope and ContentsEastern Michigan University.  7 pp.  Prepared for the 4th Annual Conference on Library Orientation for Academic Libraries.Adams, Judd N. The Place of Library Competency in a Competency-Based History ProgramFolder 7653117Scope and Contents15 pp.  Springfield, Illinois: Sangamon State UniversityERIC Clearinghouses.  List, reprinted by Milner Library, Illinois State University, NormalFolder 8653128Model for Selecting Media in Vocational/Technical Education. 2 ppFolder 9653139Television Production 74; Script on art of television production. 10 pp.Folder 106531410Library Research Workshops, Spring Semester 1974Folder 1165315197411Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois: Sangamon State UniversityStevens, Charles H., Marie P. Canfield, and Jeffrey J. Gardner. Library Pathfinders: A New Possibility for Cooperative Reference ServiceFolder 1265316January 197312Scope and ContentsCollege and Research Libraries, pp. 40-46Kuo, Frank F. A Comparison of Six Versions of Science Library InstructionFolder 1365317July 197313Scope and ContentsCollege and Research Libraries, pp. 287-290The Library as a Lab. From Sourdough, Newsletter of the Alaska Library Association, Vol. 3, #4Folder 1465318July 197214Scope and ContentsDescribes orientation and library instruction at the University of Alaska, FairbanksBibliography of Commercially Prepared Library Instruction Materials on the High School and/or College LevelFolder 156531915Scope and Contents26 pp.  Prepared by Illinois Central College, Peoria, ILScript, procedures to produce a slide-tape presentation. 11 pp.Folder 166532016LOEX News, Volume 1, #2.Folder 1765321May 1, 197417QuickClue. Bookmarks from the Goodstein Foundation Library, Caspar College, New York.Folder 186532218The Chicano and Native American Ethnic Library College at Lansing Community College  (brochure)Folder 1965323197419Bookmark, LC classification.  Rochester, New York: Monroe Community College LibraryFolder 206532420Library Instruction Goals and Objectives. 8 pp. Kenosha, Wisconsin: University of Wisconsin-ParksideFolder 216532521Competency-Base B.A. in History Proposal. Springfield, Illinois: Sangamon State University. 10 pp.Folder 226532622Filing. Carlinville, Illinois: Blackburn CollegeFolder 236532723Library Instruction Programs: A Wisconsin DirectoryFolder 246532824Scope and Contents36 pp. Kenosha, Wisconsin: University of Wisconsin-ParksideRochester, New York: Monroe Community College LibraryFolder 256532925Scope and ContentsBibliographic Searching Guides on the following topics:Audiovisual TechnologyBusinessData ProcessingDental HygieneHuman ServicesNursingPolice ScienceRecreationSpringfield, Illinois: Sangamon State University LibraryFolder 266533026Scope and ContentsBibliographic Searching Guides on the following topics:Community Arts ManagementCriminal JusticeDemography	DrugsEnvironment	Film and Media SelectionGroup CounselingHuman Development CounselingHuman Sexuality and ReproductionIllinois Legislative ProcessLegal ResearchLiterary ResearchMinority Children's BooksMunicipal Home RulePsychologyReadingSimulation GamesStudent Rights and Student GovernanceTelevision BroadcastingUnited NationsVocational and Occupational GuidanceWatergateWomen StudiesDekalb, Illinois: Swen Parson Library, Northern Illinois UniversityFolder 276533127Scope and ContentsBibliographic Searching Guides:Education HumanitiesMusic and ArtPeriodicals and NewspapersSociologyNormal, Illinois: Milner Library, Illinois State UniversityFolder 286533228Scope and ContentsBibliographic Searching Guides:AnthropologyBook ReviewsBusinessCareersCollege SelectionEducationEncyclopedias and YearbooksEnglish LiteratureMedical LiteraturePeriodicalsPhilosophyGuide to Purdue University Library.  10 pp.Folder 2965333August 197329Monroe Community College Library, New York.  Bibliographic Searching Guide: WitchcraftFolder 306533430Library Guide.  University of Wisconsin-ParksideFolder 316533531Scope and ContentsIncludes student information, how to find a book, interlibrary loans, citing materials, citing non-profit materialsTen Basic Facts About EMU Library. 7 pp.  Library Guide. Michigan: Eastern Michigan UniversityFolder 326533632Library Guide.  Elmer Holmes Bobst Library, New York UniversityFolder 336533733Fort Collins, Colorado: Colorado State UniversityFolder 346533834Scope and ContentsLibrary Guide.  Includes information, book location, periodicals, government documents, borrowing, reference, directoryBradshawm, Charles I.  Using the Card Catalog 104 pp. Brigham Young University PressFolder 3565339197135Library Handbook.  Lansing Community College, MichiganFolder 366534036Box 2Box 265341Champaign, Illinois: Parkland Community CollegeFolder 1653421Scope and ContentsBibliographic GuidesAccountingAgricultureConstruction TechnologyDental AssistingDental HygieneDraftingElectronics TechnologyFarm EquipmentFood DistributionInhalation TherapyLegal SecretarialMechanical TechnologyMicro-Precision TechnologyNursingOperating Room TechnologyRadiology TechnologyRecreation Area and FacilitiesRecreation LeadershipSecretarial ScienceCarbondale, Illinois: Southern Illinois University, Morris LibraryFolder 2653432Scope and ContentsBibliographic Guides:Afro-Americans, Blacks, Colored, NegroesBiographical SourcesBirth ControlDissertations and ThesesEnergy 		Harlem RenaissanceHomosexuality and LesbianismPeriodicalsRefuse Disposal 	Strip MiningUndergraduate Library InformationUrbana, Illinois:  University of Illinois LibraryFolder 3653443Scope and ContentsBibliographic GuidesAmerican LiteratureBlack HistoryBiographyCard CatalogEducationFilm ReviewsInformationPolitical SciencePollutionResearch in Current TopicsMacomb, Illinois:  Western Illinois University LibraryFolder 4653454Scope and ContentsBibliographic Guides.How to Find a BookInformation SourcesMLA BibliographyPlaysReaders' Guide to Periodical LiteratureLibrary Guide.  University of Illinois Library, Urbana, IllinoisFolder 5653465Library guide, tour of the Fogler Library (self-guided), University of Maine at OronoFolder 6653476A Selected List of Library Sources in the Field of Special EducationFolder 76534819717Scope and ContentsHenry Pfeiffer Library, MacMurray College, Jacksonville, IllinoisLibrary Guide.  Morris Library Handbook, Southern Illinois University, Carbondale, IllinoisFolder 8653498Bibliographic Guides.  Harlan Hatcher Graduate Library, University of MichiganFolder 9653509Scope and ContentsAmerican Literature.  22 pp.  October 1973.
French Language and Literature.  51 pp.  December 1973.
Documents Handbook.  20 pp.  1973Other material and miscellaneousFolder 106535110

