<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.10.09/05Archon Finding Aid Title J.10.09/05UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:29:15 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J10/9/5. Library, Academic Projects Subject Files, 1971-1974
    
      Library
    
    J.10.09/05
    556
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1971-1974
    Date acquired: 10/03/1990
    1&amp;2
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The Academic Programs Subject File includes memos and reports pertaining to proposed programs, the development of those programs already in existence, and the committee preferences of the faculty for the period from 1971-1974.  The materials, compiled by Dean DeBolt, concentrate upon the development of the Teacher Education Program and the Applied Study Term.  Secondary files focus upon Legal Services Committee, Social Science research and Natural Science program objectives, and the proposed programs of Midwest Studies &amp; Environmental Design.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Subject  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Dean DeBolt  
  Box 1Box 151607AST information and memosFolder 1516091971-741TEP program developmentFolder 2516101972-742TEP program developmentFolder 3516111972-743Committee information, Faculty preference and committee reference formsFolder 4516124Box 2Box 251608Legal Services Committee memos and member listFolder 1516131972-731Midwest Studies proposed program fileFolder 2516142Scope and ContentsContains memos, position papers, consultant reports, and task force findingsEnvironmental Design proposed program fileFolder 3516153Scope and ContentsMemos and task force informationSocial and Natural Science FileFolder 4516164Scope and ContentsContains notes on social science research, and memos by Richard Sames, also the goals statement of the Natural Sciences Department.

