<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.10.01/07Archon Finding Aid Title J.10.01/07UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:29:20 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J10/1/7. Library Dean's Records
    
      Library
    
    J.10.01/07
    558
    
      1.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1973-
    Date acquired: 07/21/2003
    1
    2
    3
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This collection contains records from the Brookens Library Dean's office.  
Records include memorandums of Library Cabinet meetings, SSU Foundation records, Senate Library Committee records 1995-1997, Gifts to Library, Academic Affairs Speaker's Committee Correspondence, general library correspondence, Speaker's Fund proposals (completed), Surveys, Questionnaires, and Reports: 1991-1994, University Library Council Records, and the Dennis C. Foss award nominees for teaching excellence.
Included are the records from Brian Alley (first Dean of Brookens Library), Pat Breivik, Edward Wass, and Jane Treadwell.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Subject  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Jane Treadwell  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Additional material acquired July, 2005  
  Box 1Box 147673Brian Alley - Dean of Library Services – Scholarship: Dennis Foss AwardFolder 14767419911Scope and Contents1. 1990 Foss Award Committee: Leroy A. Jordan, Assistant Vice President for Academic Affairs for Educational Services and Outreach, Chairperson
A.	Mike Kern, Vice President SSU Alumni Association
B.	Beverly Peterson, SSU Student Senate
C.	Mike Holmes, SSU Student Senate
D.	Evelyn Maisonet, SSU Student Senate
2. Memorandum - From: Leroy Jordan - Mar. 23, 1990 – To: Brian Kasher, President Student Senate – Re: Dennis Foss Award
3. Memorandum - From: Leroy Jordan – Apr. 3, 1990 – To: Beverly Peterson, Mike Homes, Evelyn Maisonet – Re: Dennis Foss Awards Committee
4. Memorandum - From: Leroy Jordan, Assistant Vice President for Academic Affairs – May 8, 1990 – To: Wayne Penn, Vice President for Academic Affairs – Re: Dennis C. Foss Award Fro Creative Excellence in Teaching – 1989-1990 Recipient, Judith A. Shereikis
5. Memorandum - From: Leroy Jordan – Feb. 6, 1991 – To: Nellie Sims, President, Student Senate – Re: Dennis Foss Award for Outstanding Teaching
6. Correspondence - From: Leroy Jordan to Sandy Sampias, President Alumni Association – Re: Dennis Foss Award Brochure – Feb. 6, 1991
7. Mention of "Blurb" in SSU Newspaper about Dennis Foss Award – Feb. 14, 1991
8. SSU Weekly Newspaper Mentioning Dennis Foss Award in Vol. 4, Number 19, Feb. 4, 1988 Issue
9. Sample of Dennis Foss Award Nomination Form – Apr. 8, 1991
10. Memorandum - From: Leroy Jordan, Assistant VPAA – Apr. 29, 1991 – To Nancy Ford, Acting VPAA – Re: 1991-92 Dennis Foss Award Recipient, George GruendelBrian Alley – Dean of Library Services – Scholarship – Dennis Foss AwardsFolder 24767519922Scope and Contents1. 1992 Foss Award Committee: 
A. Brian Alley – Dean of Library Services
B. Helen Dunn – SSU Alumni Association
C. Jules Gambill – SSU Student 
D. Amber Kimmel – SSU Student
E. Brian Zsuda – SSU Student
2. Letter Sent Out for Dennis C. Foss Award
3. Memorandum - From: Brian Alley, Dean of Library Services – Mar. 24, 1992 – To: Sharon Helding, Student Senate President – Re: Foss Award
4. Correspondence – From: Brian Alley, Dean of Library Services – Apr. 24, 1992 – To: Helen Dunn – Re: Serving on Dennis Foss Awards Committee
5. Memorandum - From: Brian Alley – Apr. 24, 1992 – To: Jules Gambill, Amber Kimmel, Brian Zsuda – Re: Serving on Dennis Foss Award Committee
6. Memorandum - From: Brian Alley – Apr. 27, 1992 – To: Camille McCabe – Re: Nomination
7. Memorandum - From: Brian Alley, Dean of Library Services – May 4, 1992 – To: Wayne Penn, VPAA – Re: Dennis C. foss Award for Creative Excellence in Teaching, 1991-92
8. Nominees for Dennis C. Foss Award – 1992 
A. Joel Adkins
B. Alfred Arkley
C. Craig Brown
D. Michael Duvall
E. Gareth Gardiner
F. George Gruendel
G. Ron Havens
H. Thomas Hughes
I. John Knoepfle
J. Pat Langley
K. Robert McGregor
L. Tim Miller
M. Adil Muhammed
N. Kenneth Oldfield
O. Robert Sipe
P. Larry Smith
Q. Larry Stonecipher
R. Gary Storm
S. Theresa Sullivan-Stewart
9. Foss Award Nominations Count – Rachell Anderson received the most votes (9)Brian Alley – Dean of Library Services – Dennis C. Foss AwardFolder 34767619933Scope and Contents1. Correspondence – From: Naomi B. Lynn, President, SSU – Feb. 9, 1993 - To: Ray Bruzan – Re: Nomination of Charles Schweighauser for Dennis C. Foss Award
2. Correspondence – From: Brian Alley, Dean of Library Services – Apr. 28, 1993 – To: Helen Dunn – Re: Serving on Dennis Foss Award Committee
3. Correspondence – From: Brian Alley, Dean of Library Services – Apr. 28, 1993 – To: Liz Blair – Re: Serving on Dennis Foss Award Committee
4. Correspondence – From: Brian Alley, Dean of Library Services – Apr. 28, 1993 – To: Denise Ray – Re: Serving on Dennis Foss Award Committee
5. Correspondence – From: Brian Alley, Dean of Library Services – Apr. 28, 1993 – To: Brian Szuda – Re: Serving on Dennis Foss Award Committee
6. List of 1993 Dennis C. Foss Award Committee: 
A. Brian Szuda – Student
B. Denise Ray – Student
C. Liz Blair – Student
D. Helen Dunn – Alumni Association
7. Memorandum – From: Brian Alley, Chair, Dennis Foss Award Committee – May 5, 1993 – To: Wayne Penn, VPAA – Re: Dennis C. Foss Award Recipient for 1993 – Daniel J. Gallagher
8. Dennis C. Foss Award Nomination FormsPat Breivik and Brian Alley – Deans, Library Services – SSU FoundationFolder 447677FY73-FY864Scope and Contents1. January 1973 – Foundation Report
2. September 1974 SSU Foundation Report
3. Bylaws of Sangamon State University Foundation (As Amended Sep. 17, 1973)
4. Memorandum – From: Dean Debolt – Apr. 27, 1977 – To: Pat Breivik – Re: Materials About the SSU Foundation
5. Sangamon State University Foundation 1976-77 Members List
6. Memorandum – From: Patricia Senn Breivik – Sep. 11, 1978 – To: Tom Goins – Re: SSU Library Special Borrower's Card
7. Memorandum – From: Alex B. Lacy, Jr. President – Dec. 15, 1980 – To: Faculty and Staff – Re: Sangamon State University Foundation
8. Memorandum – From: Brian Alley, Dean Library Services – Mar. 31, 1983 – To: George Stone – Re: Barlu and Barker Foundation
9. Memorandum – From: Brian Alley, Dean, Library Services – Apr. 5, 1983 – To: Ina Robertson – Re: Duplicate Materials for SSU Foundation
10. Newsletter, Lincoln Library – Nov. 11, 1983 – Gifts and Memorials Section
11. Memorandum – From: Brian Alley, Dean, Library Services – Nov. 17, 1983 – To: George Stone – Re: Library Borrowing Privileges
12. Memorandum – From: Ina Robertson – Mar. 2, 1984 – To: Brian Alley, Dean of Library Instructional Services – Re: Grant Proposal Writing Workshop: Request for Funds
13. Correspondence – From: Brian Alley, Dean, Library Instructional Services – Mar. 14, 1984 – To: Mrs. Bridget Lamont, Director, Illinois State Library – Re: Letter of Intent for Approval to Apply for a State Library Mini-Grant 
14. Memorandum – From: Brian Alley, University Librarian and Dean of Library Instructional Services – Mar. 19, 1984 – To: George L. R. Stone, Executive Director, SSU Foundation – Re: Request for Ina Robertson to Attend Grant Proposal Writing Workshop
15.  Memorandum – From: Brian Alley – Jul. 10, 1984 - To: George L.R. Stone, SSU Foundation – Re: Request for Check
16. Memorandum – From: Brian Alley – Nov. 12, 1984 – To: Joyce Bennett – Re: Alumni Borrowing Card
17. SSU Alumni Association Invitation to Graduation Reception – May 10, 1985
18. Memorandum – From: Dick Kipp – May 21, 1985 – To: George Stone, SSU Foundation – Re: Angels for the Library
19. Memorandum – From: Brian Alley, Dean Library Services – Oct. 18, 1985 – To: Library Program Faculty – Re: Alumni Phonathon 
20. Memorandum – From: Michael Ayers, VPAA – Oct. 28, 1985 – To: University Community – Re: SSU Foundation Phonathon
21. Memorandum – From: Michael Ayers, VPAA – Oct. 28, 1985 – To: Deans – Re: SSU Foundation Phonathon
22. Memorandum – From: Brian Alley, Dean Library Services – Oct. 29, 1985 – To: Library Program Faculty – Re: SSU Foundation Phonathon 
23. Memorandum – From: Brian Alley, Dean, Library Services – Dec. 4, 1985 – To: George Stone, SSU Foundation – Re: Library Borrowing Privileges for Alumni Association Members
24. Memorandum – From: Brian Alley, Dean, Library Services – Dec. 16, 1985 – To: Michael Ayers, VPAA – Re: Foundation Money for Faculty Development
25. Memorandum – From: Durward Long, President, SSU – Jan. 15, 1986 – To: George Stone, President, SSU Foundation – Re: Issuance of Library Cards 
26. Memorandum From: Brian Alley, Dean, Library Services – Feb. 3, 1986 – To: Ina Robertson – Re: Our Recent Conversation with George Stone Regarding Library CardsBrian Alley – Dean of Library Services – SSU FoundationFolder 547678FY915Scope and Contents1. Library Revenues and Expenses as of Oct. 29, 1990Edward Wass – Interim Dean of Library Servces – Dennis C. Foss AwardFolder 64767919946Scope and Contents1. Memorandum - From: Wayne Penn, VPAA – Feb. 24, 1994 – To: Ned Wass, Interim University Librarian &amp; Dean of Library Instructional Services - Re: Dennis C. Foss Award
2. Memorandum - From: Edward Wass, Interim Dean of Library Services – Feb. 28, 1994 – To: Donovan Pepper, President, Student Senate – Re: Dennis Foss Award for Creative Excellence in Teaching
3. Correspondence – From: Edward Wass, Interim Dean of Library Services – Feb. 28, 1994 – To: Mike Griesheim – Re: Choosing a Representative from SSU Alumni Association to Serve on Award Committee
4. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Interim Dean of Library Services – Mar. 2, 1994 – To: Staff – Re: Foss Award Nomination Forms 
5. Memorandum – From: Ned Wass, Interim Dean of Library Services – Mar. 8, 1994 – To: Brian/SSU News – Re: Correction to Notice of 3/3/94 on Foss Award
6. Memorandum – From: Ned Wass, Interim Dean of Library Services – Apr. 11, 1994 – To: Donovan Pepper, President, Student Senate – Re: Foss Award Committee
7. Memorandum – From: Ned Wass, Chair, Dennis Foss Award Committee – May 5, 1994 – To: Wayne Penn, VPAA – Re: Dennis C. Foss Award, 1994
8. Correspondence – From: Edward Wass, Interim Dean of Library Services – May 6, 1994 – To: Kevin Engels – Re: Serving on the 1994 Dennis C. Foss Award Committee
9. Correspondence – From: Edward Wass, Interim Dean of Library Services – May 6, 1994 – To: Denise Ray – Re: Serving on the 1994 Dennis C. Foss Award Committee
10. Correspondence – From: Edward Wass, Interim Dean of Library Services – May 6, 1994 – To: Toby Kellogg – Re:  Serving on the 1994 Dennis C. Foss Award Committee
11. Correspondence – From: Edward Wass, Interim Dean of Library Services – May 6, 1994 – To: Steven Henriksen – Re: Serving on the 1994 Dennis C. Foss Award Committee
12. List of 1994 Dennis C. Foss Award Committee Members:
A. Kevin Engels – Student
B. Denise Ray – Student
C. Toby Kellogg – Student
D. Steven Henriksen – Alumni
13. List of 1994 Foss Award Nominations:
A. David O' Gorman – 1 vote
B. Dan Whitley – 1 vote
C. Barbara J. Hayler – 2 votes
D. Donald Vanover – 2 votes
E. James Pancrazio – 4 votes
F. Judith Everson – 8 votesEdward Wass – Interim Dean of Library Services – Dennis C. Foss AwardFolder 74768019957Scope and Contents1. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Interim Dean of Library Services – Feb. 28, 1995 - To: Herb Jones, President, Student Senate – Re: Dennis Foss Award for Creative Excellence in Teaching 
2. Correspondence – From: Edward Wass, Interim Dean of Library Services – Feb. 28, 1995 – To: Mike Griesheim – Re: Choosing Representative from SSU Alumni Association to Serve on Award Committee
3. Memorandum – From: Ned Wass, Interim Dean of Library Services – Mar. 1, 1995 – To: Ann Augspurger, Editor SSU Weekly – Re: Dennis Foss Award 
4. Memorandum – From: Ned Wass, Interim Dean of Library Services – Mar. 1, 1995 – To: The Sangamon Star – Re: Dennis Foss Award
5. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Interim Dean of Library Services – Mar. 3, 1995 – Re: Foss Award Nomination Forms
6. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Interim Dean of Library Services – Mar. 16, 1995 – To: Herb Jones, President, Student Senate – Re: Dennis Foss Award for Creative Excellence in Teaching
7. Memorandum – From: Herb Jones, President, Student Senate – Mar. 27, 1995 – To: Dean Wass – Re: Dennis Foss Award
8. Memorandum – From: Ned Wass, Interim Dean of Library Services – Apr. 7, 1995 – To: Members of the 1995 Dennis Foss Award Committee: Helen Dunn; Jenni Grigsby; Cissy Hylak; Neil Malone – Re: Our Meeting on Apr. 18, 1995
9. Memorandum – From: Marcia – Apr. 11, 1995 – To: Instructional Services Librarians – Re: Dennis C. Foss Award Nomination Forms
10. Memorandum – From: Ned Wass, Chair of Dennis Foss Award Committee – Apr. 19, 1995 – To: Dennis Foss Award Committee Members: Helen Dunn; Jenni Grigsby, Cissy Hylak, Neil Malone – Re: Next Foss Committee Meeting
11. Memorandum – From: Ned Wass, Chair, 1995 Foss Award Committee – Apr. 26, 1995 – To: Wayne Penn, Vice President for Academic Affairs – Re: 1995 Dennis C. Foss Award for Creative Excellence in Teaching – Award Announcement – Donald F. Stanhope
12. Correspondence – From: Edward Wass, Interim Dean of Library Services, Chair, Dennis Foss Award Committee – May 3, 1995 – To: Cissy Hylak – Re: Serving on 1995 Dennis Foss Award Committee
13. Correspondence – From: Edward Wass, Interim Dean of Library Services, Chair, Dennis Foss Award Committee – May 3, 1995 – To: Neil Malone – Re: Serving on 1995 Dennis Foss Award Committee 
14. Correspondence – From: Edward Wass, Interim Dean of Library Services, Chair, 1995 Dennis Foss Award Committee – May 3, 1995 – To: Helen Dunn – Re: Serving on 1995 Dennis Foss Award Committee
15. 1995 Dennis Foss Award Nomination Forms
16. List of Dennis Foss Award Nominations:
A. Cecelia Cornell – History Program – 1 vote
B. Bob Dixon – Visual Arts Program – 6 votes
C. Anne Draznin – Legal Studies Program – 1 vote
D. Elizabeth Goins – Business Administration Program – 3 votes
E. Randy Kucera – Public Administration Program – 1 vote
F. Ethan Lewis – English Program – 2 votes
G. Deborah McGregor – History Program – 1 vote
H. James Pancrazio – Human Development Counseling Program – 1 vote
I. Larry Smith – Communication Program – 2 votes
J. Donald Stanhope – Accountancy Program – 1 vote plus 2 supporting letters and 4 reference letters
K. Dan Whitley – Clinical Psychology Program – 1 voteEdward Wass, Interim Dean of Library Services – Dennis Foss Award Nomination ProceduresFolder 8476818Scope and Contents1. Memorandum – From: Wayne Penn, VPAA – Feb. 3, 1995 – To: Ned Wass, Interim Dean Library Services – Re: Dennis C. Foss Award
2. Memorandum – From: Ned Wass, Interim Dean Library Services – Feb. 13, 1995 – To: Wayne Penn, VPAA – Re: Dennis Foss Award Criteria
3. Memorandum – From: Porter McNeil – To: Leroy Jordan – Feb. 14, 1992 – Re: Foss Award Publicity
4. List of Who Received Foss Award Nomination Forms:
A. Bill Bloemer – Dean, School of Liberal Arts and Sciences
B. Alex Casella - Dean, School of Public Affairs and Administration
C. Mary Mulcahy – Dean, School of Health and Human Services
D. John Munkirs – Dean, School of Business and Management
E. Homer Butler – Vice President of Student Services
F. Wayne Penn – Vice President of Academic Affairs
G. Cheryl Peck – University Relations
H. Shirley Crayton – SSU Upper Division Center – Peoria
I. Herb Jones – President, Student Senate
5. Dr. Dennis C. Foss Award for Creative Excellence in Teaching Pamphlets
6. Copies of SSU Weekly dating from March 6, 1995 through April 4, 1995 with articles about Foss Award
7. Dennis C. Foss Award Nomination FormsEdward Wass – Dean of Library Services – Senate Library CommitteeFolder 947682FY95/96/979Scope and Contents1. Memorandum - From: Ned Wass, University Librarian – Nov. 15, 1995 – To: Wayne Penn, Provost and Vice-Chancellor for Academic Affairs – Re: Circulation Policy Changes
2. Memorandum - From: Ned Wass – Dec. 1, 1995 – To: Department Heads and Library Faculty – Re: Senate Library Committee Meeting for Dec. 8, 1995
3. Interim Campus Senate Library Committee Agenda for Dec. 8, 1995 Meeting
4. Status Report – Brookens Library – Dec. 8, 1995
5. Memorandum - From: Dr. H.T. Loevy, Chair – Jan. 17, 1996 – To: Members of the University Library Council – Re: Next University Library Council Meeting Scheduled for Mar. 29, 1996
6. Correspondence - From: Craig S. Bazzani – Jan. 23, 1996 – To: Senator Paul Simon
7. Library Committee Meeting – Jan. 26, 1996 – Agenda
8. Memorandum - From: Ned Wass – Feb. 5, 1996 – To: Interim Campus Senate Library Council Committee Re: Committee Meeting Agenda
9. Memorandum - From: Ned Wass – Feb. 7, 1996 – To: Interim Campus Senate     Library Committee Members – Re: Library Circulation Policy Proposal
10.  Memorandum - From: Ned Wass – Feb. 12, 1996 – To: Interim Campus Senate Library Committee Members – Re: Upcoming Meeting for Feb. 23, 1996
11. Memorandum - From: Ned Wass – Mar. 14, 1996 – To: Interim Campus Senate     
12. Library Committee – Re: University Library Council Meeting for Mar. 29, 1996 Cancelled
13. Memorandum - From: Ned Wass – Mar. 19, 1996 – To: Members of the Interim Campus Senate Library Committee – Re: University Library Council Meeting Rescheduled for Apr. 22, 1996
14. Memorandum - From: Ned Wass – Mar. 25, 1996 – To: Bill Jordan, Chair, Interim Campus Senate Library Committee – Re: Revised Circulation Policy Proposal 
15. Memorandum - From: Theresa Sullivan Stewart – Nov. 22, 1996 – To: Luther Skelton, Chair, Faculty Senate – Re: Charges to the Library Committee
16. Memorandum - From: Marcia Rossi – Feb. 13, 1997 – Senate Library Committee Members – Re: Senate Library Committee Meeting for Mar. 4, 1997
17. Memorandum - From: Linda Kopecky, Chair, Library Instructional Services Program – To: Ned Wass, University Librarian – Mar. 25, 1997 – Re: Proposal to Extend Library Hours
18. Memorandum - From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Mar. 18, 1997 – To: Faculty Senate Library Committee – Re: Next Faculty Senate Library Committee Meeting for Mar. 25, 1997
19. Memorandum - From: Theresa Sullivan Stewart – Mar. 20, 1997 – To: Campus Library Committee – Re: Agenda for Mar. 25, 1997 Meeting
20. Minutes for Mar. 4, 1997 Library Committee Members Meeting – Mar. 25, 1997
21. Memorandum - From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Apr. 2, 1997 – To: Senate Library Committee Members – Re: Meeting on Apr. 10, 1997
22. Memorandum - From: Theresa S. Stewart – Apr. 7, 1997 – To: Senate Library Committee Members – Re: Agenda for Meeting on Apr. 10, 1997
23. Minutes for Apr. 10, 1997 Campus Library Committee Meeting – Apr. 30, 1997
24. Memorandum - From: Edward Wass, University Librarian – Apr. 10, 1997 – To: Theresa Sullivan-Stewart, Chair, Faculty Senate Library Committee – Re: Library Hours
25. Interim Campus Senate Library Committee Progress Report – 1997 
26. Interim Campus Senate Library Committee Progress Report – Submitted to the Faculty Senate, UIS – Apr. 18, 1997 – Prepared by Theresa Sullivan Stewart, Chairperson, Senate Library Committee
27. UIS Campus Senate BYLAWS – Adopted June 21, 1996 – Last Amended: Sept. 5, 1997
28. Library Hours Survey Results
29. Memorandum - From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Instructional Services – Sep. 20, 1996 – To: Michelle Burch, President, Student Senate – Re: Student Representation on Senate Library Committee	  
30. Senate Library Committee – Minutes of Sep. 24, 1996 Meeting
31. Senate Library Committee – Agenda of Sep. 24, 1996 Meeting
32. Memorandum - From: Edward Wass – Oct. 28, 1996 – To: Michelle Burch, President, Student Senate – Re: Senate Library Committee
33. Senate Library Committee – Agenda of Oct. 29, 1996 Meeting
34. Memorandum - From: Theresa S. Stewart – Nov. 12, 1996 – To: Library Committee – Re: Steering Committee Meeting – Thursday, Nov. 7, 1996
35.  Charges – Library Committee AY96/97 – To Be Approved at Campus Senate Meeting – Dec. 6, 1996
36. Memorandum - From: Theresa S. Stewart – Dec. 16, 1996 – To: Ned Wass – Re: Library CommitteeEdward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Academic Affairs Speakers Committee - General CorrespondenceFolder 10476831994-9810Scope and Contents1. Memorandum – From: Wayne Penn, VPAA – Nov. 7, 1994 – To: The University Community – Re: Support for Speakers
2. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services, Chair of Academic Speakers Committee – Apr. 2, 1997 – To: Wayne Penn, VPAA and Provost – Re: Academic Affairs Speakers Committee
3. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair of Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Apr. 23, 1997 – To: CFC/Social Work Club – Re: Request to Speakers Committee 
4. CFC/Social Work Club – Speakers Fund Proposal
5. Resume – Helena Goscilo – July 1997 – Speaker Candidate
6. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services, Chair of Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Sep. 15, 1997 – To: Faculty Members of the Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Razak Dahmane and Marya Leatherwood – Re: AY 1997-98 Activity
7. Memorandum – From: Women's Studies, International Studies, The Women's Center, Communications Program et al. Per Pat Langley – Sep. 24, 1997 – To: Speakers Series Committee – Re: UIS Speaker Series: Changing Lives of Russian Women
8. Memorandum – From: Maria Mootry, English and African-American Studies – Sep. 25, 1997 – To: Ned Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Re: Proposal for a Major "Speaker Series" Event 
9. Memorandum – Speaker Fund Proposal: Speaker Series Major Event – Gwendolyn Brooks Poetry
10. Resume – Cranston Sedrick Knight – Sep. 25, 1997 – Speaker Candidate
11. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Sep. 26, 1997 – To: Robert Doyle, President, Student Senate – Re: Academic Affairs Speakers Committee
12. Letter – From: Len Cain, Graduate Assistant, UIS English Department – Sep. 30, 1997 – To: Academic Affairs Speakers Committee, C/O Marcia Rossi – Re: Requesting Support for Verbal Arts Festival
13. Memorandum – From: Michael Theall, Dir., CTL – Sep. 30, 1997 – To: Marcia Rossi – Speakers Fund – Re: Speakers Fund – Speakers Series Proposal
14. Format for Speaker Fund Proposal
15. Speakers Fund Proposal for a Speakers Series Event – Gender and the University
16. Resume – Charol Shakeshaft – Speakers Series Candidate
17. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Sep. 30, 1997 – To: Club Advisors – Re: Speakers Application Form and Information
18. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair – Oct. 8, 1997 – To: Academic Affairs Speakers Committee Members: R. Dahmane, M. Leatherwood, T. Miller, and J. Sistrunk – Re: Proposals and Meeting Date
19. Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Agenda – Oct. 13, 1997
20. Memorandum – From: The Newman Club, Michael Theall, Advisor – Oct. 14, 1997 – To: Speaker's Fund – Re: Attached Proposal
21. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair – Oct. 14, 1997 – To: Academic Affairs Speakers Committee Members – R. Dahmane, M. Leatherwood, T. Miller, and J. Sistrunk – Re: Additional Proposals
22. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Oct. 28, 1997 – To: Michael Theall – Re: Request for Funding
23. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Oct. 28, 1997 – To: Professor Annettee Van Dyke – Re: Request for Funding
24. Memorandum – From: Women's Issues Caucus – To: Academic Affairs Speakers Bureau Committee – Re: Funds for Residency by Dr. Christina Brinkley
25. Resume of Christina F. Brinkley, PH.D – Aug. 1996 – Speaker Candidate
26. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Oct. 28, 1997 – To: Michael Theall – Re: Request for Funding
27. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Oct. 28, 1997 – To: Pat Langley – Re: Request for Funding
28. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Oct. 28, 1997 – To: Sherri McLaughlin – Re: Request for Funding
29. Sherri McLaughlin, President – Counseling Academic and Professional Honor Society International – HDC, UIS Newsletter
30. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Oct. 28, 1997 – To: Professor Maria Mootry – Re: Request for Funding
31. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Oct. 28, 1997 – To: Bobbi Harris – Re: Request for Funding
32. Memorandum – From: Maria Mootry, Convener, African-American Studies Program – Oct. 28, 1997 – To: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Re: Funding for AAS Fall, 1997 Speaker Series
33. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Oct. 30, 1997 – To: Harry Berman – Re: Academic Affairs Speakers Committee
34. Letter – From: Marcia Rossi, Secretary for Dean of Library Services – Nov. 24, 1997 – To: Johanna Sistrunk – Re: Scheduling Meeting of Academic Affairs Speakers Meeting
35. Letter – From: Marcia Rossi, Secretary for Dean of Library Services – Nov. 24, 1997 – To: Tina Miller – Re: Scheduling Meeting of Academic Affairs Speakers Meeting
36. Academic Affairs Speakers Committee Disbursement Report – Nov. 1997
37. Academic Affairs Speakers Committee Disbursement Report – Dec. 1997
38. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Dec. 4, 1997 – To: Len Cain, English Graduate Assistant – Re: Request for Funding
39. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Dec. 9, 1997 – To: Club Advisors – Re: Speakers Proposals for Spring Semester
40. Notice of Limited Funds for Academic Affairs Speakers for Following Year
41.	List of Approved Clubs for Speakers Committee Fund
42. Memorandum – From: Marcellus Leonard, Professor, English – Dec. 15, 1997 – To: Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Re: Playwriting/Production Workshop Series
43. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Feb. 2, 1998 – To: Marilyn Cook (c/o Community Arts Management Program) – Re: Request for Funding Proposal on Alzheimer's Disease
44. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Feb. 2, 1998 – To: Anthony Sisneros – Re: Request for Funding OLAS
45. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Feb. 2, 1998 – To: Bobbi Harris – Re: Request for Funding SWK/CFC Proposal
46. Correspondence – Letter From Marilyn Cook – Feb. 3, 1998 – To: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Re: Appreciation for Funding Received for Alzheimer's Project
47. Memorandum – From: Leonard Marcellus – Feb. 3, 1998 – To: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Re: Funding for Theatre Productions
48. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Feb. 4, 1998 – To: Marcellus Leonard – Re: Request for Drama Workshops
49. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Feb. 19, 1998 – To: Academic Affairs Speakers Committee Members: R. Dahmane, M. Leatherwood, T. Miller, and J. Sistrunk – Re: Proposal and Future Meeting
50. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Feb. 27, 1998 – To: Maria Mootry – Re: Request for Funding Shirlene Holmes
51. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Feb. 27, 1998 – To: Vibert White – Re: Request for Funding Arthur Magida 
52. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Feb. 27, 1998 – To: Pat Austin, VCAA Office – Re: Final Disbursement Report
53. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Feb. 27, 1998 – To: Wayne Penn, Provost and VCAA – Re: Disbursement Report
54. Academic Affairs Speakers Committee Disbursement Report – Feb. 27, 1998
55. Memorandum – From: Maria Mootry – Mar. 3, 1998 – To: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Re: Request for Funding Shirlene Holmes
56. Memorandum – From: Wayne Penn, Provost &amp; Vice Chancellor for Academic Affairs – Mar. 5, 1998 – To: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Re: Academic Affairs Speakers Committee Disbursement Report
57. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Apr. 2, 1998 – To: John Palmer, Director, Graduate Assistant Program, Lawrence Johnson, Associate Chancellor for Affirmative Action – Re: Graduate Assistant Interviewees for the Library
58. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Apr. 2, 1998 – To: Annette VanDyke, Women's Issues Caucus – Re: Processing Funds
59. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Apr. 2, 1998 – To: Bobbi Harris, CFC/Social Work – Re: Processing Funds
60. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Apr. 2, 1998 – To: Jennifer Cummins, Biology Club – Re: Processing Funds
61. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Apr. 9, 1998 – To: Pat Austin, VCAA Office – Re: Biology Club Award
62. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Apr. 10, 1998 – To: University Club/Organization Advisers – Re: Fall 1998 Academic Affairs Speakers Series Proposals
63. Flyer: Request for Proposals – Fall, 1998 UIS Speakers Series Event
64. Format for Speakers Series Proposals – Forms
65. Correspondence – From: Len Cain, English Program – Apr. 10, 1998 – To: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Re: Thanks for Support of Verbal Arts Festival
66. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Apr. 20, 1998 – To: Academic Affairs Speakers Committee Members: R. Dahmane, M. Leatherwood, T. Miller, and J. Sistrunk – Re: Proposal and Future Meeting
67. FY98 – Fiscal Accounting Statement – 4/30/1998 – Academic Enrichment Student Life
68. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – May 20, 1998 – To: Mike Townsend, Child, Family, and Community Services – Re: Speakers Committee Request
69. Academic Affairs Speakers Committee Disbursement Report – May 21, 1998Edward Wass – Dean of Library Services – Gifts to LibraryFolder 1147684FY9611Scope and Contents1. Memorandum – From: George A. Lindsley – Aug. 7, 1995 – To: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Re: 1) Presentation of Books 2) Renewal of Borrower's Card
2. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Aug. 9, 1995 – To: Dr. Charles and Janice Perino – Re: Receipt of 51 Periodical Issues
3. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Aug. 9, 1995 – To: Charles Kelly – Re: Receipt of Book donated to UIS Brookens Library
4. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Aug. 16, 1995 – To: Jane Knipmeyer – Re: Receipt of Three Books Donated to Brookens Library
5. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Aug. 18, 1995 – To: Nancy Ford – Re: Receipt of Two Books Donated to Brookens Library
6. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Aug. 22, 1995 – To: Joseph J. Hovish – Re: Receipt of a Book Donated to Brookens Library
7. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Aug. 22, 1995 – To: Larry Shiner – Re: Receipt of Twenty Books Donated to Brookens Library
8. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Aug. 24, 1995 – To: Charles S. Dick, President, Westminster College, Salt Lake City, Utah – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
9. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Aug. 24, 1995 – To: Joan Ortman, President, Nu Pi Chapter – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
10. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Aug. 24, 1995 – To: Sally Clarke, Assistant Professor of History, The University of Texas at Austin – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
11. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Aug. 24, 1995 – To: Judy Everson, Associate Professor of Speech, English – Re: Receipt of Three Books Donated to Brookens Library
12.   Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Aug. 29, 1995 – To: Dr. James H. Stebbings – Re: Receipt of 143 Issues of American Journal of Epidemiology, v. 99-122, Donated to Brookens Library
13. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Sep. 13, 1995 – To: Judy Everson, Asso. Prof. Speech, English 
– Re: Receipt of 3 Books Donated to Brookens Library
14. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Sep. 19, 1995 – To: John Miller, Prof. Psychology/Director, Counseling Center – Re: Receipt of Donation of 6 Books and 87 Periodical Issues to Brookens Library
15. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Sep.25, 1995 – To: Institute of Public Affairs – Re: Receipt of Donation of 3 Books to Brookens Library
16. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Sep. 26, 1995 – To: Elizabeth Goins – Re: Receipt of Monetary Donation to Brookens Library
17. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Sep. 26, 1995 – To: Scott Beam – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
18. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Oct. 5, 1995 – To: Dick Kipp – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to    Brookens Library
19.  Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Oct. 11, 1995 – To: Mr. G. William Horsley – Re: Receipt of         256 Volumes or Binders of CCH Legal Material to Brookens Library
20.  Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Oct. 17, 1995 – To: John Miller, Professor, Psychology – Re: Receipt of Donation of 6 Books and 85 Periodical Issues to Brookens Library
21. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Oct. 26, 1995 – To: Mary Foster – Re: Receipt of 39 Books Donated to Brookens Library
22. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Oct. 30, 1995 – To: Clyde A. Bridger – Re: Receipt of 292 Books Donated to Brookens Library
23. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Nov. 16, 1995 – To: Razak Dahmane, Assistant Professor, English – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
24. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Nov. 30, 1995 – To: The Psychohistory Review – Re: Receipt of 9 Books Donated to Brookens Library
25. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Dec. 13, 1995 – To: Patricia A. Langley, Prof. Women's Studies and Legal Studies – Re: Receipt of 49 Volume Book Set: The New Anchor Bible, Donated to Brookens Library
26. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Dec. 13, 1995 – To: Stephen Poole – Re: Receipt of 36 Books and 82 Audio Tapes Donated to Brookens Library
27. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Dec. 13, 1995 – To: John Holtz, Assoc. Prof. Library Instructional Services – Re: Receipt of 2 Books Donated to Brookens Library
28. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Dec. 18, 1995 – To: Kathy Stepniewski, Dept. of Veterans Affairs – Re: Receipt of Various Miscellaneous Materials Donated to Brookens Library
29. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Jan. 3, 1996 – To: Donald Yohe, Assoc. Prof., Child, Family, and Community Services – Re: Receipt of 35 Books Donated to Brookens Library
30. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Jan. 4, 1996 – To: Charles Schweighauser, Prof. Astronomy/Physics, English, Environmental Studies – Re: Receipt of 96 Periodical Issues Donated to Brookens Library
31. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Jan. 10, 1996 – To: Janis Swanton, American Contract Bridge League Unit 208 – Re: Receipt of 10 Books Donated to Brookens Library
32. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Jan. 29, 1996 – To: John C. Redfern – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
33. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Feb. 7, 1996 – To: Kevin Maffett, Superintendent – Financial Statements, State Farm Insurance – Re: Receipt of CPCU Text Books Donated to Brookens Library
34. Memorandum – From: James H. Stebbing – Mar. 9, 1996 – To: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services, Brookens Library, UIS – Re: Receipt of Donated Materials for IRS Purposes
35. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass – Mar. 18, 1996 – To: Patricia A. Langley – Re: Receipt of 49 Volumes of the new Anchor Bible for IRS purposes
36. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass – Mar. 26, 1996 – To: John Holtz, Prof. Library Instructional Services – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
37. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass – Apr. 9, 1996 – To: Kenneth A. Andersen, Prof. Emeritus of Speech Communication, UIUC – Re: Receipt of 213 Periodical Issues Donated to Brookens Library
38. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Apr. 11, 1996 – To: Barbara J. Hayler, Prof. Criminal Justice – Re: Receipt of 7 Books Donated to Brookens Library
39. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Apr. 26, 1996 – To: Barbara Blankenship, Administrative Assistant – Re: Receipt of VHS tape Donated to Brookens Library
40. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – May 8, 1996 – To: Dick Kipp, Assistant Professor, Library Instructional Services – Re: Receipt of 2 Books Donated to Brookens Library
41. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – May 8, 1996 – To: David Grebner – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
42. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – May 22, 1996 – To: Ken Andersen, Prof. Emeritus of Speech Communication, UIUC – Re: Continued Support of Quarterly Journal of Speech
43. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – May 28, 1996 – To: John Redfern – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
44. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – May28, 1996 – To: William D. Warren – Re: Receipt of 22 Books Donated to Brookens Library
45. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Jun. 5, 1996 – To: Mary Jane MacDonald – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
46. Memorandum -  From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Jun. 6, 1996 – To: Barbara J. Hayler, Prof. Criminal Justice – Re: Receipt of 10 Books Donated to Brookens Library
47. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Jun. 7, 1996 – To: Stephen Becker, Assoc. Professor, Environmental Studies, UIS – Re: Receipt of  Donation of 38 Periodical Issues and 28 Documents to Brookens Library
48. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Jun. 14, 1996 – To: Ray Shroeder, TV Office/Access 4 Springfield – Re: Receipt of CD Donated to Brookens Library
49. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Jun. 24, 1996 – To: Sojid Ansari – Re: Receipt of 11 Books Donated to Brookens Library
50. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Jun. 26, 1996 – To: Peggy Boyer Long, Managing Editor, Illinois Issues – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
51. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Jun. 26, 1996 – To: Christa Hockensmith, Assistant Professor of Chemistry – Re: Receipt of 3 Books Donated to Brookens Library
52. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Jun. 26, 1996 – To: Harold S. Kipp, Assistant Prof., Library Instructional Services – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
53. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Jun. 26, 1996 – To: Peggy Boyer Long, Managing Editor, Illinois Issues – Re: Receipt of 6 Books Donated to Brookens Library
54. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Jun. 26, 1996 – To: Tim Olstead – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
55. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Jun. 27, 1996 – To: Jack Genskow – Re: Receipt of 46 Books Donated to Brookens LibraryNed Wass, Dean of Library Services – Gifts to LibraryFolder 1247685FY9712Scope and Contents1. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jul. 10, 1996 – To: Jack Van Der Slik – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
2. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jul. 17, 1996 – To: James J. Pancrazio – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
3. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jul. 17, 1996 – To: Annette Van Dyke – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
4. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jul. 17, 1996 – To: Linda Kopecky – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
5. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jul. 17, 1996 – To: Harold S. Kipp – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
6. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jul. 24, 1996 – To: Jack Genskow – Re: Receipt of 9 Books Donated to Brookens Library
7. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Aug. 13, 1996 – To: John Holtz – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
8. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Aug. 14, 1996 – To: Diana Kleidon – Re: Receipt of Two Books Donated to Brookens Library
9. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Aug. 20, 1996 – To: Dick Kipp – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
10. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Aug. 23, 1996 – To: Dick Kipp – Re: Receipt of 2 Books Donated to Brookens Library
11. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Aug. 28, 1996 – To: Nada Chang, Associate Professor, Biology – Re: Receipt of 15 Books Donated to Brookens Library
12. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Aug. 28, 1996 – To: Dick Kipp Assistant Professor, Library Instructional Services – Re: Receipt of 3 Books Donated to Brookens Library
13. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Sep. 3, 1996 – To: Anne Morgan – Re: Receipt of 20 Periodical Issues Donated to Brookens Library
14. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Sep. 3, 1996 – To: Dick Kipp – Re: Receipt of 6 Books Donated to Brookens Library
15. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Sep. 3, 1996 – To: John C. Redfern – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
16. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Sep. 3, 1996 – To: Institute of Public Affairs – Re: Receipt of 2 Books Donated to Brookens Library
17. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Sep. 3, 1996 – To: Karen Moranski, Assistant Prof. English – Re: Receipt of 2 Books Donated to Brookens Library
18. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Sep. 4, 1996 – To: Dick Kipp, Assistant Professor, Library Instructional Services – Re: Receipt of 3 Books Donated to Brookens Library
19. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Sep. 6, 1996 – To: Norm Hinton – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
20. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Sep. 6, 1996 – To: Illinois Issues – Re: Receipt of 2 Books Donated to Brookens Library
21. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Sep. 13, 1996 – To: Dr. Bill Becker – Re: Receipt of 24 Periodical Issues Donated to Brookens Library
22. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Sep. 18, 1996 – To: Chancellor Naomi Lynn – Re: Receipt of 8 Books Donated to Brookens Library
23. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Sep. 30, 1996 – To: Dick Kipp, Assistant Professor, Library Instructional Services – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
24. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Oct. 4, 1996 – To: John "Top Hat" Redfern – Re: Receipt of 7 Books Donated to Brookens Library
25. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Oct. 9, 1996 – To: Ray Schroeder – Re: Receipt of Video Tape Donated to Brookens Library
26. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Oct. 9, 1996 – To: Nancy Scannell – Re: Receipt of Video Tape Donated to Brookens Library
27. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Oct. 14, 1996 – To: Robert Ishizaki – Re: Receipt of 110 Books Donated to Brookens Library
28. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Oct. 23, 1996 – To: Rozanne Flatt – Re: Receipt of 25 Books Donated to Brookens Library
29. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Nov. 11, 1996 – To: Dick Kipp, Assistant Professor, Library Instructional Services – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
30. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Nov. 11, 1996 – To: Karen Moranski – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
31. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Nov. 20, 1996 – To: Judy Everson, Professor of Speech &amp; English – Re: Receipt of 2 Books Donated to Brookens Library
32. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Nov. 20, 1996 – To: George M. Irwin, President, Quincy Foundation – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
33. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jan. 6, 1997 – To: John "Top Hat" Redfern – Re: Receipt of 5 Books Donated to Brookens Library
34. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jan. 6, 1997 – To: Judy Everson, Associate Professor, Speech, English – Re: Receipt of 2 Books Donated to Brookens Library
35. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jan. 6, 1997 – To: Peggy Boyer Long, Editor, Illinois Issues – Re: Receipt of 3 Books Donated to Brookens Library
36. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jan. 13, 1997 – To: Marcia Salner, Professor, Educational Administration – Re: Receipt of Donation of 24 Periodical Issues to Brookens Library
37. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jan. 15, 1997 – To: Derek Richards – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
38. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jan. 22, 1997 – To: Karen Moranski, Assistant Professor, English – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
39. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Feb. 19, 1997 – To: Nancy Scannell, Assistant Professor, Economics – Re: Receipt of Book and VHS Tape Donated to Brookens Library
40. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Feb. 25, 1997 – To: John Redfern – Re: Receipt of 6 Books Donated to Brookens Library
41. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Feb. 25, 1997 – To: Nancy Scannell, Assistant Professor, Economics – Re: Receipt of 2 Books Donated to Brookens Library
42. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Feb. 25, 1997 – To: Betty Bennett, Programming Secretary – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
43. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Feb. 25, 1997 – To: Judy Everson, Professor, Speech and English – Re: Receipt of 2 Books Donated to Brookens Library
44. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Mar. 25, 1997 – To: Larry Shiner, Professor, Philosophy – Re: Receipt of 25 Books Donated to Brookens Library
45. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Apr. 21, 1997 – To: Dr. Bill Becker, Agrosystems Management, Inc., Soil Fertility Consultant – Re: Receipt of 25 Periodical Issues Donated to Brookens Library
46. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Apr. 23, 1997 – To: Timothy D. Koschmann, Ph.D. SIU, Dept. of Medical Ed. Cognitive Science Div. – Re: Receipt of 112 Periodical Issues Donated to Brookens Library
47. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Apr. 23, 1997 – To: Larry Shiner, Professor, Philosophy – Re: Receipt of 13 Books Donated to Brookens Library
48. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Apr. 24, 1997 – To: Ruth A. Slottag – Re: Receipt of 3 Books Donated to Brookens Library
49. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – May 12, 1997 – To: Marguerite Summers – Re: Receipt of 103 Books and 599 Periodical Issues Donated to Brookens Library
50. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – May 19, 1997 – To: Mary Martin – Re: Receipt of 184 Books Donated to Brookens Library
51. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – May 28, 1997 – To: John Holtz, Associate Professor, Library Instructional Services – Re: Receipt of 2 Books Donate to  Brookens Library
52. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – May 29, 1997 – To: Peggy Boyer Long, Editor, Illinois Issues – Re: Receipt of 3 Books Donated to Brookens Library
53. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – May 29, 1997 – To: Nancy Scannell, Professor, Economics Program – Re: Receipt of Video Tape Donated to Brookens Library
54. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jun. 4, 1997 – To: Dick Kipp, Assistant Professor, Library Instructional Services – Re: Receipt of 2 Books Donated to Brookens Library
55. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jun. 17, 1997 – To: Nancy Scannell, Assistant Professor, Economics  – Re: Receipt of 3 Books Donated to Brookens Library
56. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jun. 17, 1997 – To: Peggy Boyer Long, Editor, Illinois Issues – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
57. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jun. 19, 1997 – To: Karen R. Moranski, Assistant Professor, English – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
58. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jun. 20, 1997 – To: Becky Garretson, Director of Public Relations, Memorial Medical Center – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
59. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jun. 25, 1997 – To: Barbara Pickering – Re: Receipt of 28 Volumes of Time-Life Literary Art Books Donated to Brookens Library
60. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jun. 27, 1997 – To: Susan D. Bond, Recycling Coordinator/Health Educator, Sangamon County Department of Public Health – Re: Receipt of 3 Videos Donated to Brookens LibraryBox 2Box 247686Dean of Library Services – Gifts to LibraryFolder 147687FY981Scope and ContentsEdward Wass.
1. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jul. 10, 1997 – To: Ching-Shu Lin – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
2. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jul. 14, 1997 – To: Alyce Scott – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
3. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jul. 16 1997 – To: Illinois State Bar Association – Re: Receipt of 5 Books Donated to Brookens Library
4. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jul. 18, 1997 – To: Laurence A. Weinstein – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
5. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jul. 22, 1997 – To: Barbara Hayler – Re: Receipt of 10 Books Donated to Brookens Library
6. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jul. 28, 1997 – To: Institute of Public Affairs – Re: Receipt of 2 Books Donated to Brookens Library
7. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jul. 30, 1997 – To: Sheri McLaughlin – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
8. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jul. 30, 1997 – To: Nancy R. Enright – Re: Receipt of 10 Books Donated to Brookens Library
9. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Aug. 1, 1997 – To: Denise Green, Assistant Prof., Library Instructional Services – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
10. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Aug. 4, 1997 – To: Yvonne Herbet – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
11. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Aug. 5, 1997 – To: Barbara Hayler, Professor Criminal Justice – Re: Reciept of 9 Books Donated to Brookens Library
12. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Aug. 11, 1997 – To: Anne Draznin, Professor, Legal Studies – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
13. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Aug. 13, 1997 – To: Dick Kipp, Assistant Professor, Library Instructional Services – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
14. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Aug. 20, 1997 – To: Nancy Scannell, Assistant Professor, Economics – Re: Receipt of Book and Video Donated to Brookens Library
15. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Sep. 8, 1997 – To: Dick Kipp, Assistant Professor Library Instructional Services – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
16. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Sep. 8, 1997 – To: Steve Egger, Dean, School of Health and Human Services – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
17. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Sep. 11, 1997 – To: Dan A. Whitley, Associate Professor, Educational Psychology – Re: Receipt of 146 Books Donated to Brookens Library
18. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Sep. 18, 1997 – To: Mary Jane McDonald – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
19. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Sep. 19, 1997 – To: Charles Wheeler, Assoc. Prof/Director, Public Affairs Reporting – Re: Receipt of 1,192 Illinois Issues Press Summaries Donated to Brookens Library
20. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Sep. 25, 1997 – To: Ruth Friedman – Re: Receipt of 377 Books, 95 Records, and 26 Periodicals Donated to Brookens Library
21. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Oct. 1, 1997 – To: Wang Shouyi – Re: Receipt of 3 Books Donated to Brookens Library 
22. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Oct. 15, 1997 – To: Don Yohe – Re: Receipt of 8 Books Donated to Brookens Library
23. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Oct. 17, 1997 – To: Nancy Enright – Re: Receipt of 3 Books Donated to Brookens Library
24. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Oct. 22, 1997 – To: PsychoHistory Review, Larry Shiner, ed. – Re: Receipt of 3 Books Donated to Brookens Library
25. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Nov. 3, 1997 – To: Carol G. Covey, Collection Development Librarian – Re: Receipt of 35 Books Donated to Brookens Library
26. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Nov. 4, 1997 – To: Charles Wheeler, Director, Public Affairs Reporting – Re: Receipt of 1,912 Documents Donated to Brookens Library
27. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Dec. 2, 1997 – To: Dick Kipp, Assistant Professor, Library Instructional Services Re: Receipt of 3 Books Donated to Brookens Library
28. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Dec. 9, 1997 – To: Charles Speta – Re: Receipt of 31 Books Donated to Brookens Library
29. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Dec. 9, 1997 – To: Gigi Moore – Re: Receipt of 2 Periodical Issues Donated to Brookens Library
30. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Dec. 9, 1997 – To: Dick Kipp, Assistant Professor, Library Instructional Services – Re: Receipt of 4 Books Donated to Brookens Library
31. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Dec. 19,. 1997 – To: J. Q. Adams and Janice R. Welsch – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
32. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Dec. 19, 1997 – To: ICASA – Re: Receipt of 4 Books Donated to Brookens Library
33. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Dec. 19, 1997 – To: Nancy Scannell – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
34. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Dec. 19, 1997 – To: Bill Warren – Re: Receipt of 8 Books Donated to Brookens Library
35. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jan. 6, 1998 – To: J.Q. Adams &amp; Janice R. Welsch – Re: Receipt of 2 Books Donated to Brookens Library
36. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jan. 9, 1998 – To: J.V. Perino – Re: Receipt of 16 Periodical Issues Donated to Brookens Library
37. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jan. 9, 1998 – To: Dick Kipp, Assistant Professor, Library Instructional Services – Re: Receipt of 2 Books Donated to Brookens Library
38. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jan. 9, 1998 – To: Phil Gregg – Re: Receipt of 15 Books and 18 Documents Donated to Brookens Library
39. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jan. 22, 1998 – To: John Redfern – Re: Receipt of 11 Books Donated to Brookens Library
40. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Feb. 2, 1998 – To: Nancy Scannell – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
41. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Feb. 11, 1998 – To: Karen Moranski, Assistant Prof. English Program – Re: Receipt of 6 Books Donated to Brookens Library
42. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Feb. 12, 1998 – To: Dr. Dorothea H. El Mallakh, Director Intl. Research Center for Energy &amp; Economic Development – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
43. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Feb. 13, 1998 – To: Dick Kipp, Assistant Professor, Library Instructional Services – Re: Receipt of 5 Periodical Issues Donated to Brookens Library
44. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Feb. 13, 1998 – To: Nancy Enright – Re: Receipt of 13 Books Donated to Brookens Library
45. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Mar. 4, 1998 – To: Barbara Hayler – Re: Receipt of 3 Books Donated to Brookens Library
46. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Mar. 4, 1998 – To: Dick Kipp, Assistant Professor, Library Instructional Services – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
47. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Mar. 19, 1998 – To: Steve Becker – Re: Receipt of 3 Books Donated to Brookens Library
48. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Mar. 19, 1998 – To: John C. Brandt, Malcolm B. Niedner Jr. &amp; Jurgen Rahe – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
49. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Mar. 19, 1998 – To: Spiritual Assembly of the Baha'is of Springfield – Re: Receipt of 2 Books Donated to Brookens Library
50. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Mar. 19, 1998 – To: Razak Dahmane – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
51. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Apr. 9, 1998 – To: Steve Becker – Re: Receipt of 2 Books Donated to Brookens Library
52. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Apr. 9, 1998 – To: Dick Kipp, Assistant Professor, Library Instructional Services – Re: Receipt of 4 Books Donated to Brookens Library
53. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Apr. 9, 1998 – To: Sarel Herman – Re: Receipt of 435 Books and 21 Periodical Issues Donated to Brookens Library
54. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Apr. 28, 1998 – To: Nancy Enright – Re: Receipt of 5 Books Donated to Brookens Library
55. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – May 5, 1998 – To: Dick Kipp, Assistant Professor, Library Instructional Services – Re: Receipt of 2 Books Donated to Brookens Library
56. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – May 5, 1998 – To: Mary Jane MacDonald – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
57. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – May 14, 1998 – To: Walter H. Casey – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
58. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – May 28, 1998 – To: George B. Rose – Re: Receipt of 2 Books and 4 Periodical Issues Donated to Brookens Library
59. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – May 28, 1998 – To: Dr. Burton C. Witthuhn, Provost and Academic Vice President – Re: Receipt of 3 Books Donated to Brookens Library
60. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jun. 5, 1998 – To: David Braddock, Ph. D., Department of Disability and Human Development, University of IL. At Chicago – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens Library
61. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Jun. 11, 1998 – To: Dick Kipp, Assistant Professor, Library Instructional Services – Re: Receipt of Book Donated to Brookens LibraryDean of Library Services – Speakers Fund Proposals, CompletedFolder 247688AY97-982Scope and ContentsEdward Wass.
1. Speakers Fund Proposal – Apr. 3, 1997 – Group Proposing Event – Ron Sakolsky, Associate Professor and faculty advisor to the Students for Cultural and Intellectual Democracy (SCID). Proposed Speaker – Stephen Dunifer
2. Speakers Fund Proposal – Oct. 23, 1997 – Group Proposing Event – World Affairs Council of Central Illinois Co-Sponsored by UIS – Description of Event – Conference on: "The Global Economy, Promises and Perils" – Speakers: Professors Tobin, Aliber and Wehrle and Dr. Truman 
3. Memorandum – From: Judith Everson, Professor and Chair, Academic Speakers Committee – Apr. 18, 1997 – To: Edward Wass, Dean Library Services – Re: Invitation for Speaker's Presentations Proposals 
4. Speakers Fund Proposal – Apr. 18, 1997 – Group Proposing Event – UIS English Program and the James Jones Literary Society, Seventh James Jones Symposium - Flyer for Sixth James Jones Symposium, Nov. 2, 1996
5. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Apr. 23, 1997 – To: Ron Sakolsky, Advisor, Students for Cultural and Intellectual Democracy – Re: Request to Speakers Committee
6. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair of Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Apr. 23, 1997 – To: Judith Everson, Professor of Speech and English – Re: Speakers Series Proposal
7. Flyer - Symposium on Women's International Human Rights Meeting – Sep. 10, 1997 – The Women's Center and International Student Services, UIS – Funding provided by others
8. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Oct. 25, 1997 – To: Jennifer Cummins – Re: Speakers Fund Award of $90.00 Given to Biology Club for Prairie Restoration Speech Given by Becky Meyers
9. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Chair, Academic Affairs Speakers Committee – Oct. 25, 1997 – To: Jennifer Cummins – Re: Decline of Funding for Spring Welcome Back LuncheonDean of Library Services: Surveys, Questionnaires, ReportsFolder 3476891991-953Scope and ContentsBrian Alley 1991- 94; Edward Wass 1994-95.
1. Correspondence – From: James L. Mullins, Ph.D., Director of Library Services – Jul. 25, 1991 – To: Brian Alley, Dean of Library Services, SSU – Re: Permission to Publish Results of Survey of Librarian Salaries at Public II-A Institutions
2. Survey – ILCSO Access to Periodical Databases Survey – 11/1991 – Person Responding – Brian Alley, Dean of Library Services, SSU
3. Survey – Library Cost Containment and Downsizing, FY92 – A Quick Questionnaire for the College and University Library Association (CULA) – 12/19/1991 – Person Responding – Brian Alley, Dean of Library Services, SSU
4. SSU-Peoria Student Survey – Summary of Results From May, 1991 Survey
5. Spring 1992 Survey of One-Year-Out SSU Graduates  - Results for Sections I, II, and III (Attitude-Related Questions) – Survey Conducted and Tables Prepared by: Survey Research Office – Institute for Public Affairs – Sangamon State University
6. Graduate Attitudes by Kind of SSU Degree Survey, Sections I, II, III – Oct. 29, 1992 – Results – Pages 1-105
7. Correspondence – From: Dr. Ronald N. Bukoff, School of Library and Information Science, Indiana University – Feb. 4, 1994 – To: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Feb. 4, 1994 – Re: Survey of Censorship and the American College Library, 1988-1993
8. Survey – Market Data Retrieval- 1995 College/University Library Survey – Sep. 1995 – Person Responding: Edward Wass, Dean of Library ServicesDean of Library Services – Senate Library CommitteeFolder 447690FY984Scope and ContentsEdward Wass.
1. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, University Librarian – Sep. 10, 1997 – To: Luther Skelton, Chair, Campus Senate – Re: Senate Library Committee
2. Brookens Library – Results to Connecting to UIS Library Databases – Oct. 1997
3. University and Library Budget Data for FY1971-1998
4. Library Materials Budget as of Nov. 15, 1997
5. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Sep. 23, 1997 – To: Members of the Faculty Senate Library Committee ( C. Cornell, B. Jordan, J. Peach, D. Stanhope) – Re: Committee Operations/University Library Council
6. Memorandum – From: Campus Senate Committee on Committees – Sep. 24, 1997 – To: All Faculty – Re: Appointments to Campus Senate Committees for AY97/98
7. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Oct. 2, 1997 – To: Members of the Faculty Senate Library Committee, C. Cornell, B. Jordan, J. Peach, D. Stanhope – Re: Committee Membership
8. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Oct. 31, 1997 – To: Pat Langley – Re: Senate Library Committee Appointments
9. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Nov. 13, 1997 – To: Dan Matthews and Laurel Newman – Re: Senate Library Committee
10. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Nov. 21, 1997 – To: Senate Library Committee: Razak Dahmane, Bill Jordan, Adil Mouhammed, Jan Peach, and Mike Townsend – Re: Senate Library Committee Meeting
11. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Nov. 24, 1997 – To: Senate Library Committee: Razak Dahmane, Bill Jordan, Adil Mouhammed, Jan Peach, and Mike Townsend – Re: Senate Library Committee Meeting
12. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Dec. 3, 1997 – To: Senate Library Committee: R. Dahmane, B. Jordan, A. Mouhammed, J. Peach, and M. Townsend – Re: Senate Library Committee Meeting
13. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass, Dean of Library Services – Dec. 4, 1997 – To: Senate Library Committee Members – Re: Background InformationDean of Library Services – University Library CouncilFolder 547691FY985Scope and ContentsEdward Wass.
1. University Library Council Minutes – Feb. 7, 1997
2. University Library Council Agenda – Sep. 17, 1997
3. Memorandum – From: Cindy Clennon, Contract Coordinator, CIC Center for Library Initiatives – Aug. 26, 1997 – To: CIC Library Director – Re: Consortial Proposal from Lexis-Nexis 
4. University Library Council – Oct. 3, 1997 Meeting – Status Report
5. Memorandum – (e-mail) From: Cheryl Brown – Dec. 23, 1997 – To: Edward Wass, Dean, Library Services – Re: Next Meeting of the University Library Council – Friday, Apr. 10, 1998
6. Memorandum (e-mail) – From: Ray Schroeder – Mar. 30, 1998 – To: Edward Wass – Re: LPC Meeting to Take Up Virtual Library Issues
7. University Library Council – Apr. 10, 1998 Meeting – Status Report, Agenda Item #1
8. Memorandum (e-mail) – From: Anne Sharon – Apr. 10, 1998 – To: Robert Wedgeworth – Re: University Library Council Meeting
9. Handwritten Notes From Meeting
10. Memorandum – From: Edward Wass – Apr. 17, 1998 – To: Marcia Rossi – Re: Next Meeting of the University Library Council
11. Memorandum – From:  J. David Stewart, Assistant Vice President for Planning and Budgeting – Apr. 17, 1998 – To: Members of the University Library Council – Re: Illinois HB 2696, Advisory Commission: Internet Privacy ActDean of Library Services – Gifts to LibraryFolder 651589FY996Dean of Library Services – Gifts to Library by Norris L. Brookens estateFolder 76843219997Dean of Library Services – Gifts to LibraryFolder 868429FY20018Scope and ContentsDean Edward WassDean of Library Services – Gifts to LibraryFolder 968430FY20029Dean of Library Services – Gifts to LibraryFolder 1068431FY200310Scope and ContentsDean: Jane TreadwellDean of Library Services – Gifts to LibraryFolder 1151590FY04 &amp; FY0511Scope and ContentsDean: Jane TreadwellDean of Library Services – Gifts to LibraryFolder 1251591FY06 &amp; FY0712Scope and ContentsDean: Jane TreadwellBrookens Library Usage StudyFolder 13520637/31/198713Scope and ContentsSurvey Research Office of the Public Affairs Institute, SSUBrookens Library User Survey and MemosFolder 1452064198714Brookens Library Usage SurveyFolder 1552065198915Brookens Library Usage SurveyFolder 1652066199216Brookens Library Program StatisticsFolder 1752067199617Box 3Box 352161Technical Services StatisticsFolder 1521621993-981Interlibrary Loan StatisticsFolder 2521631980-982Media Lab Work MemoFolder 3521649/27/19953Academic Affairs Speaker's CommitteeFolder 4521651998-994Academic Affairs Speaker's Awards &amp; ProposalsFolder 5521661998-995University Library CouncilFolder 6521671998-996

