<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>P.Ayers M.Archon Finding Aid Title P.Ayers M.UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:30:28 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    P/Ayers. Michael Ayers, Personal Papers, 1968-1973
    
      Ayers, Michael
    
    P.Ayers M.
    100
    
      1.40 Cubic Feet
    
    1968-1973
    Date acquired: 07/00/1979
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This collection includes working papers for reports and articles on air pollution, water pollution, the Illinois Environmental Protection Agency, and the Illinois Pollution Control Board.
Also included are notes and working papers for Ayers's dissertation, "An evaluation of Water Pollution Control In and By the State of  Illinois."  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical by title and topic  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Michael Ayers  
  
    Papers
    Journal Articles
  
  Box 1Box 115856Dissertation.  Ayers, Michael.  "An Evaluation of Water Pollution Control In and By the State of Illinois."  255 p.Folder 1158581Dissertation drafts and chartsFolder 2158592Other Working PapersFolder 3158603Bibliography, Environmental PollutionFolder 4158614Clean Air Act, 1971Folder 5158625Early Water Pollution Control (in Illinois), by Clarence KlassenFolder 6158636Economics of Clean WaterFolder 7158647Scope and ContentsU.S. Department of the Interior, Federal Water Pollution Control Administration.  The Economics of Clean Water.  Volume 1:  Detailed Analysis. March 1970.  168 p.; U.S. Department of the Interior, Federal Water Pollution Control Administration.  The Economics of Clean Water: Summary Report.  March 1970. 41 p.EPA Act of 1970, Illinois House Bills and Amendments, Correspondence, StatementsFolder 8158658Environment: IllinoisFolder 9158669Scope and ContentsJanuary 1971; Spring 1971; February/March 1973 (volume 2, number 2); April-May 1973 (volume 2, number 3)Fish Kills Caused by Pollution, 1960-73Folder 101586710Scope and ContentsIllinois Department of Conservation, Division of Fisheries.  Procedures Used by the Illinois Department of Conservation in the Investigation of Pollution Caused Fish Kills.  January 1971.  17 p.; "Illinois Pollution Caused Fish Kills, 1960-70."; "Pollution Caused Fish Kill Log", 1972, 1971FishingFolder 111586811Scope and ContentsU.S. Department of the interior, Fish and Wildlife Service. Bureau of Sport Fisheries and Wildlife.  15 Years of Better Fishing (the Dingell-Johnson Act).  1967  32 p.Illinois Air Pollution Control Board. Rules, Regulations and Laws, 1970Folder 121586912Scope and Contents"Summary of Illinois Air Pollution Laws." Illinois Legislative Council File 7-607. April 21, 1970; State of Illinois Pollution Control Board.  "Rules and Regulations Governing the Control of Air Pollution." As Amended August 19, 1969; Amendments and Addition to the Rules and Regulations Governing the Control of Air Pollution," Adopted by the Illinois Air Pollution Control Board, March 	25, 1970; Chapter V, Air Quality Standards, Adopted September 25, 1969."Illinois Attorney General, Report of Pollution Activities, 1970Folder 131587013Illinois Bureau of Water Pollution Control, Report (? ca. 1970-71)Folder 141587114Illinois Department of Public Health, Annual Reports, 1959 to 1970Folder 151587215Illinois Division of Sanitary Engineering, Bureau of Stream PollutionFolder 161587316Control, Annual Reports, 1967-69Folder 171587417Illinois.  Environmental Protection Act. 1970 and 1971 revisionFolder 181587518Illinois.  Environmental Protection Agency. Annual Report, 1971Folder 191587619Box 2Box 215857IEPA Budget and AppropriationsFolder 1158771Scope and ContentsAudit Report for Fiscal Year, 1973; 			Appropriations Staff, Agency Report. April 3, 1972; Appropriation Bills, 1973EIPA Evaluation MaterialsFolder 2158782Scope and ContentsNumeric Tabulation of Enforced Actions, 1970-71; Summary of Cases Filed Before the Pollution Control Board Since 2/4/71; The New Environmental Protection Act vs. the Old Environmental Quality Act.IEPA FormsFolder 3158793IEPA Legislation, 1971Folder 4158804IEPA Organization Charts and Statements of Purpose, 1970-73Folder 5158815IEPA Progress Report, 1972Folder 6158826Scope and ContentsOur Shared Environment: A Report of Progress by the Illinois; EPA Fiscal Year 1972.IEPA Water Pollution Monitoring, 1972Folder 7158837Scope and Contents"Water Pollution Monitoring by the EPA." August 11, 1972. 11p.Illinois Federal Grant Review, July 1, 1972 through Dec. 31, 1972. 133 p.Folder 8158848Illinois Ground Water Pollution. By William H. Walker, Journal AWWA, Jan. 1969Folder 9158859Illinois Pollution Control Board Newsletter, #35-60, 1971-73 (nos. 35, 48, 50-51, 53-54, 57-60)Folder 101588610Illinois Pollution Control Board Newsletter, #61-78, 1973 (nos. 61-68, 76-78)Folder 111588711Illinois Pollution Control Newsletter, #79-90, 1974 (nos. 79-80, 83-90)Folder 121588812Illinois Pollution Control Opinions, 70-7 to 70-56Folder 131588913Box 3Box 315890Illinois Pollution Control Board Opinions, 71-8 to 71-100Folder 1158911Illinois Pollution Control Board Opinions, 71-103 to 71-272Folder 2158922Illinois Pollution Control Board Opinions, 71-276 to 71-343Folder 3158933Illinois Pollution Control Board Opinions, 71-350 to 72-263Folder 4158944Illinois Pollution Control Board R70-1 to R70-17Folder 5158955Illinois Pollution Control Board R71-1 to R71-15Folder 6158966Illinois Pollution Control Board Rules and Regulations, 1970Folder 7158977Box 4Box 415898Illinois Sanitary Water Board Act of 1917 and revision 1966Folder 1158991Illinois Sanitary Water Board Annual Report, 1969-70Folder 2159002Illinois Sanitary Water Board Rules and Regulations.  Publications SWB-(7-15,18), SWB-7Folder 3159013Scope and ContentsWater Quality StandardsIllinois Sewerage Survey, 1970. (Covers 1880-1970)Folder 4159024Illinois Soil and Water Conservation Districts Law.  1971. 49 p.Folder 5159035Mine-related Pollution. 15 pp.Folder 6159046Oklahoma Water Pollution Control BoardFolder 7159057Scope and ContentsGuide for an Investigation of a Fish Kill; Indications of Water Pollution; Collection of Quality of Water SamplesOregon.  Water Quality ControlFolder 8159068Scope and Contents"Standards of Quality for Public Waters of Oregon and Disposal Therein of Sewage and Industrial Wastes." 40 p.; State of Oregon. Department of Environmental Quality. Water Quality; Control in Oregon. Dec. 1970. 28 p.Public Water Supplies in Illinois. 1972. 12 p.Folder 9159079Pollution Control, 1971Folder 101590810Scope and ContentsTheoretical Efficiency in Pollution Control: Comment" by Donald C. Shoup. Western Economic Journal, 9, Number 3 (September 1971), 310-316.Project RegisterFolder 111590911Scope and ContentsU.S. Department of the Interior. Federal Water Pollution Control Administration. Project Register, Dec. 31, 1969. 150 p.Sewage and Water Works ConstructionFolder 121591012Scope and ContentsU.S. Department of the Interior. Federal Water Pollution Control Administration. Sewage and Water Works Construction. 1966, 1967, 1968.Sewage Treatment, Illinois, 1966, 1968Folder 131591113Scope and ContentsSanitary Water Board.  rules and Regulations for Certification of Operators of Sewage Treatment Works.Solid Waste Disposal Districts Act, IllinoisFolder 141591214Scope and ContentsDepartment of Public Health. Solid Waste Disposal Districts Act. 11 p. n.d. (Circular No. 4.801)Texas. Program Review Guidelines, 1971. Circular No. A-95 (revised)Folder 151591315Waste Water Treatment, Oct. 1969.Folder 161591416Scope and ContentsU.S. Department of the Interior. Federal Water Pollution Control Administration. "A Primer on Waste Water Treatment." 25 p.Water. Cost of Clean Water, 1971Folder 171591517Scope and ContentsU.S. Environmental Protection Agency. Cost of Clean Water: volume 1, Municipal Investment Needs. March 1971. 21 p.; U.S. Environmental Protection Agency. Cost of Clean Water: Volume 2, Cost Effectiveness and Clean Water. March 1971, 128 p.Water and Sewage FacilitiesFolder 181591618Scope and ContentsU.S. Department of Agriculture. Economic Research Service. Status of Water and Sewage Facilities in communities Without Public Systems. Agricultural Economic Report No. 143, Oct. 1968, 20p.Water is LifeFolder 191591719Scope and ContentsU.S. Department of Agriculture, Soil Conservation Service, Champaign, Illinois. Water is Life for these Illinois Towns. 1971. 12 p.Water Pollution Control ActFolder 201591820Scope and ContentsU.S. Department of the Interior. Federal Water Pollution Control Administration. Federal Water Pollution Control Act: Oil Pollution Act. 1966/67.Water Pollution Control Act, 1971Folder 211591921Scope and ContentsU.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Federal Water Pollution Control Act. Sept. 1971, 62 p.Water Pollution from Oil/Gas, 1960-71Folder 221592022Scope and Contents"Man-hours spent in investigating cases of water pollution resulting from oil field operations in the state of Illinois, 1960-72."Water Pollution Regulations of Illinois, 1972Folder 231592123Scope and ContentsIllinois. Environmental Protection Agency. Water Pollution; Regulations of Illinois. Through March 7, 1972. 36 p.Water Quality Act of 1965Folder 241592224Scope and ContentsPublic Law 89-234. laws of the 89th U.S. Congress.Water. "Showdown."Folder 251592325Scope and ContentsU.S. Department of the Interior. Federal Water Pollution Control. Showdown for	Water. 1968.

