<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.12.06/103Archon Finding Aid Title J.12.06/103UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:30:37 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J12/6/103. Stuart A. Anderson Papers, 1972-1977
    
      Anderson, Stuart A.
    
    J.12.06/103
    585
    
      0.50 Cubic Feet
    
    1972-1977
    Date acquired: 10/11/1988
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Stuart Anderson's Educational Administration Papers: Includes correspondence, newspaper clippings and information concerning Springfield's Public School Board, the Educational Administration Degree, and the Illinois Board of Higher Education.  Information on the case of Prof. Redge Ranyard vs. Prof. Stuart A. Anderson is included. (1972-77)  "Running for Public Office"  Workshop information is included with written copies of speeches and 5 tapes with the same information.  The workshop was sponsored in 1976 jointly by Lincoln Land Community College and SSU.  The Illinois Legislative Studies Center of SSU  transcribed the speeches.  Those involved were Dick Anderson, Don Adams, Mary Jo Arndt, Rep. Doug Kane, Sen. John Davidson, Bill Cellini, Wally Gairk, Bob Estill, Ben Kinngham, Bill Hey (Dir. Legislative Council),  and Josephine Oblinger.  
  Box 1Box 164095Springfield School Board informationFolder 1640971973-771Stuart Anderson's correspondence relating to the ADE DegreeFolder 2640981976-772Springfield Public Schools informationFolder 3640991972-763Springfield Education AssociationFolder 46410019734Illinois Board of Higher EducationFolder 5641011978-805Case of Ranyard vs. AndersonFolder 6641021976-776Box 2Box 264096Copy of Dick Anderson's SpeechFolder 1641031Speech of Mary Jo Arndt, Rep. Doug Kane, and Sen. John DavidsonFolder 2641042Speech of Bill CelliniFolder 3641053Speech of Wally Gair, Bob Estill, and Ben KinninghamFolder 4641064Speech of Bill HeyFolder 5641075Speech of Josephine OblingerFolder 6641086Five cassette tapes of the above speechesFolder 7641097

