<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>P.Golden IArchon Finding Aid Title P.Golden IUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:35:09 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    P/Golden. Larry Golden, Personal  Papers, Series I
    
      Golden, Larry
    
    P.Golden I
    109
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1977-1981
    Date acquired: 00/00/1991
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Personal  papers consist of articles on assorted topics, as well as information and correspondence from many projects Professor Golden has been involved in, including the American Civil Liberties Union, the Brown vs. The Board Project Committee, Energy Conservation, Faculty Union Council, Springfield City Government, and Springfield East Association. Also includes information on an NEH funded project, 1977 Summer Seminar for College teachers.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Larry Golden  
  
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 116417American Civil Liberties Union, 1977Folder 1164181Articles, 1 of 2Folder 2164192Scope and Contents"Are Lawyers, Agents Spoiling Pro Sports?" 1971; "Technology and Utopian Thought", 1971; "Graduate Education in Psychology-A Passionate Statement"; "The Transformation of Higher Education and the Emerging White-Collar Proletariat" from "Schooling in Capitalist America"; "The Use of Social Science and the Death Penalty Cases: Reflections on Change and the Empirical Justification of Constitutional Policy", 1978; "Education for Justice:  A Modern Statement of the Platonic View"; "Books and the Arts": "Eichmann; the System; the Victims" 1963Articles, 2 of 2Folder 3164203Scope and Contents"Watergate:  Some Basic Issues" 1974; "The Power Game:  who rules Springfield" ca 1976;  "A Consumer Guide to Doctors for Sangamon County", 1974; "Maximum Feasible Participation:  A General Overview"; "Equality Before The Law" Bibliography; "Thinking Small"; "Radical Decentralization:  A Response to American Planning Dilemmas"; "1776 from a Utilitarian Perspective:  Hume and Bentham on Revolution"Brown vs. Board Project Committee, 1979Folder 4164214CorrespondenceFolder 5164225Course InformationFolder 6164236Energy Conservation InformationFolder 7164247Faculty Union Council/EttingerFolder 8164258Freedom of Speech Tape, 1978Folder 9164269MiscellaneousFolder 101642710National Endowment for the Humanities-1977 Summer Seminars for College TeachersFolder 111642811Research NotesFolder 121642912Springfield City Government:  Is it time for a change? 1978Folder 131643013Springfield East Association Project ChoiceFolder 141643114Faculty Development at Sangamon State University, 1984Folder 151643215

