<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.12.09/120Archon Finding Aid Title J.12.09/120UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:36:45 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J12/9/120. Leon S. Cohen Papers, 1961-1976
    
      Cohen, Leon
    
    J.12.09/120
    598
    
      1.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1961-1976
    Date acquired: 11/29/1989
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Series 1 contains information about the Legislative Applied Study Term and the Legislative Staff Internship Program, the main activities of the Legislative Studies Center.  Of special interest are papers on both programs:  "Legislative Internships and Research training,"  presented at the 1974 Annual Meeting of the Midwest Political Science Association, and "Teaching Practical Politics in a Academic Setting,"  presented at the 1976 annual meeting of the Midwest Political Science Association.
Series II contains correspondence, course syllabi,  research project records and drafts of scholarly articles, with emphasis on Detroit and New York politics.  
  
    Arrangement Note
By subject  
  Box 1Box 164396Sangamon State UniversitySeries 1643971972-1976Legislative Applied Studies Term and Legislative Staff Internship Program, Records and CorrespondenceFolder 1643991973-19751A Set of Questions to Guide Analysis for PAC on Political ReformFolder 264400n.d.2Correspondence and MemosFolder 3644011975-773Information about Legislative Internship Programs in 14 StatesFolder 46440219764Student Evaluation ReportsFolder 56440319745Student's Legislative Applied Study Term JournalFolder 664404Fall 19756Illinois Office of Education Visiting Team, Correspondence and RecordsFolder 76440519757Illinois Office of Education Visiting Team, ReportFolder 864406April 19758State University of New York at Albany and Wayne State UniversitySeries 264398Course materials (folder 1 of 3)Folder 1644071965-19721Course materials (folder 2 of 3)Folder 2644081965-19722Course materials (folder 3 of 3)Folder 3644091965-19723Research Project: New York State ConventionFolder 46441019674Independent Research - drafts &amp; outlines (folder 1 of 2)Folder 56441119655Independent Research - drafts &amp; outlines (folder 2 of 2)Folder 66441219656Predominant Group Loyalties in Voting Behavior: The 1961 Municipal Election in Detroit, MichiganFolder 7644157Scope and ContentsProposal and outline for Master's Thesis (Wayne State University, 1962)Research Projects (folder 1 of 2)Folder 8644131965-718Research Projects (folder 1 of 2)Folder 9644141965-719

