<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>P.LewisArchon Finding Aid Title P.LewisUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:37:17 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    P/Lewis. Florence Lewis, Personal Papers, 1969-1988
    
      Lewis, Florence
    
    P.Lewis
    117
    
      4.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1969-1988
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Box 1-5 Are the personal papers of Florence Lewis, Assistant Professor of Library Instructional Services, one of the first Librarians at SSU. Her files contain correspondence, reports, memoranda, and other materials related to the library, library collections, higher education, library resources in Springfield, the Illinois State Library, early library development at SSU (1969-1970), and other materials on library history at SSU.
Box 6 contains course materials for LES 401- Legal Research and Writing 1977-78 and SJP 340-Introduction to Research in Social Justice 1979.
Box 7 contains notes on Florence Lewis's Book "Instructional Services Librarians: The Sangamon State Experience."
Box 8 contains information on the library regarding courses and library instruction.
 Boxes 9-10 include a collection of her book Prospectus and correspondence with M.E. Sharpe (book publisher) for her book which was never published; along with other papers related to her years of service to Brookens Library.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Florence Lewis  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Acquisition Dates:  7/74, 12/76 &amp; 5/95, 2005  
  
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 116795SVALC-listing and holdings of other LibrariesFolder 1167961AV Reference ReportsFolder 2167971970-712Annual ReportFolder 3167981974-753Breivik, Patricia Senn. ResumeFolder 41679919734Budget-LibraryFolder 51680019735Cabinet, Library CabinetFolder 61680119746Cabinet, Library Cabinet MinutesFolder 71680219747Card Catalog-Arrangement Memorandum from Erma J. MorganFolder 81680319708Circulation PolicyFolder 91680419709Collection-Items Not Clarified by Library of CongressFolder 101680510Collection DevelopmentFolder 1116806197211Coordinator of Library ServicesFolder 121680712Coordinator of Library Services, Job DescriptionFolder 1316808197213Criminology-BibliographyFolder 141680914Documents-U.N.Folder 1516810197215Film Rental PolicyFolder 1616811197316Faculty EvaluationFolder 1716812197217Faculty Evaluation/Hoinacki, LeeFolder 18168131972-7418First Year of Operation-(Includes Analysis of Library Resources in Springfield)Folder 191681419Government Publications, Lists of JournalsFolder 2016815197120Human Resources FileFolder 21168161971-7321Instructional Services Librarian's Backup and Duties ListFolder 2216817197422Instructional Services Librarian's Brochure Suggestion-Ted KneeboneFolder 2316818June 197423Instructional Services Librarian's Position Description, etc.Folder 2416819197324Journals, Lists of Higher Education PublicationsFolder 251682025Kaser Report, Review of SSU LibraryFolder 2616821197526Library Philosophy-DraftFolder 27168221971-02-1427Loan Policy on Library MaterialsFolder 281682328New and Expanded Programs (NEPR Documents) ConcerningFolder 291682429Paralegal and Other related ProgramsFolder 3016825197530Non-Print Materials- Sources of, by subject, Liz FrazerFolder 311682631Organization ChartFolder 321682732Periodical ListFolder 3316828197133Planning For Library Use, Memos and Related DocumentsFolder 34168291970-7234Position Papers, Terry WhiteFolder 351683035Box 2Box 216831Premises, Promises, Programs (Memos, Hours, Guides, etc.)Folder 1168321970-721PrioritiesFolder 216833Nov. 19712Program-Class Schedule Copy SubmittedFolder 3168343Program CommitteeFolder 4168351973-744Program LiaisonFolder 51683619735Program StatementFolder 6168376Questionnaire: On Use of the Library, SummaryFolder 716838Spring, 19717Questionnaire, MemosFolder 81683919728Reserves, Procedure for Handling Reserve ListsFolder 91684019729Teaching Library- A StatementFolder 101684110Workshop-Biographic Workshop (See Green Folder)Folder 1116842May 197411Photocopies of Articles, Newspapers and ReportsFolder 121684312Collective BargainingFolder 1316844197513Higher Education --BiographiesFolder 141684514Higher Education --Bibliographic Teaching-FootnotesFolder 151684615Higher Education --Readings (Copies Articles and Notes)Folder 161684716Higher Education --Journals in SSU Collection (Missing)Folder 1716848197317Higher Education --Readings: Cross, Patricia. New Students of the SeventiesFolder 181684918Illinois --Board of Higher Education Master Plan, Phase IIFolder 1916850196619Illinois --BHE Master Plan Phase III-LibraryFolder 2016851196920Illinois --BHE Report on New Senior InstitutionsFolder 2116852196821Illinois --BOR Governing Policy for the Regency SystemFolder 2216853197222Illinois --Library Association Convention MemoFolder 2316854197423Illinois --Public Library Systems BrochureFolder 241685524Illinois Legislative Process/Legislative Department copied From Basic Illinois GovernmentFolder 2516856197025Box 3Box 316857Illinois State Library, Memos, Notes, Correspondence and DraftsFolder 1168581969-1Illinois State University BookletsFolder 21685919712Illinois Valley Library Council-MembersFolder 316860Fall 19753Junior Colleges in Illinois, Report of Selected Data and Characteristics of Illinois Public Junior CollegesFolder 4168611969-704Legal Studies-Collection/Development/MicroficheFolder 51686219745Libraries-Illinois, Illinois Libraries, Vol. 53, No. 8Folder 61686319716Library --College Associates ConferenceFolder 71686419717Library --Community Use-Reading/Photocopied ArticlesFolder 81686519678Library --Developmental and Program Reading, Booklets onFolder 91686619709Library --Faculty Status-Selected BibliographyFolder 101686710Library --Interlibrary Loan CodesFolder 1116868197011Library --Pathfinders M.I.T.Folder 1216869197212Library Resources in the Springfield AreaFolder 131687013Lincoln Land Community College Library, Booklet and MemoFolder 141687114Public Information Act, Copies of BillFolder 1516872196615Sangamon Valley Academic Library Consortium-Union, List of ResourcesFolder 161687316Report of Sabbatical Research Project by Florence LewisFolder 1716874Spring 198617Box 4Box 416875Articles, Newspaper Clippings, Copies of Magazine Articles, etc. on Alternative EducationFolder 1168821Beecham, Kelly. Letter Offering Support and AssistanceFolder 21688319732Bunnell, Bob. Hand Written NotesFolder 3168843Conferences --1st Quincy Conference on Alternatives in EducationFolder 41688510/724Conferences --2nd Quincy Conference on Alternatives in EducationFolder 51688610/735Conferences --National Conference on Alternative EducationFolder 6168876Conferences --Alternative Learning Festival, Webster Groves, MissouriFolder 7168887Conferences -Wingspread Report, Johnson Foundation. Current Trends in EducationFolder 8168898Consultants, List of Possibles, District #186- Project Capital, RecommendationsFolder 9168909Indiana Univ. Educational Alternatives Project, Includes Handouts, publications, etc.Folder 1016891197310Mahan, David Interview Notes, St. Louis Public SchoolsFolder 111689211Memo to all Faculty - Alternative Public High School and Responses from FacultyFolder 12168931973-07-0612Memos/Alternative Public High SchoolFolder 131689413Quincy, Il. Education by Choice ProjectFolder 1416895197314Programs-Materials on the Webster Groves Project and Other Pilot ProgramsFolder 151689615Stage Two Proposals. Originals and Distribution Lists for Alternative Public High SchoolsFolder 161689716Box 5Box 516876Tutorials-Students Interested in HSWWFolder 1168981ReportsFolder 2168992Wisconsin--Open Schools. Final Report of the Governor's Commission on EducationFolder 31690011/703Scope and ContentsIncluding the Open School, a Supplement to the First ReportMetro, St. Louis, Visit, Interview Notes, Handouts and BookletFolder 41690119734BibliographyFolder 5169028/19735Bibliography-3 Riordan, Robert C. Alternative Schools in Action. Bloomington, In.Folder 61690319726Bibliography-5 Wurman, Richard S., Ed. Yellow Pages Of Learning ResourcesFolder 7169047Bibliography-6 Changing Schools, Number 6, Evaluation for Alternative SchoolsFolder 8169058Bibliography-7 Curriculum Report. NASSP. More Options...Folder 916906March 19739Bibliography-10 Nation's Schools, All about AlternativesFolder 1016907Nov. 197210Bibliography-12 Tucson, Arizona: Project MOREFolder 1116908197311Bibliography-13 Berkeley, California: Experimental School Program of the Berkeley School District, n.d.Folder 121690912Bibliography-15 Quincy, Illinois: Education by ChoiceFolder 131691013Bibliography-16 Louisville, Kentucky: Working Papers. The Louisville Brown School Task ForceFolder 1416911Jan. 197214Bibliography-17 Massachusetts: Kaleidoscope 7, E.S.E.A. Title III Projects in MassachusettsFolder 1516912Winter 197315Bibliography-18 Minneapolis, Minnesota: Southeast Alternatives. Minneapolis Public SchoolsFolder 16169131972-7316Bibliography-19 St. Louis, Missouri: Highlights of First Year at Metro High SchoolFolder 1716914197317Bibliography-20 Hanover, New Hampshire: Critical Factors in Planning An Alternative School Program, Planning and Implementing Alternative Public Schools: Two Case StudiesFolder 181691518Scope and ContentsPosition Paper Prepared by the National Consortium on Educational Alternatives. n.d.Bibliography-21 New Rochelle, New York: New Rochelle's School for Inquiry, Involvement, and Independent StudyFolder 1916916April 197019Bibliography-22 Philadelphia, Pennsylvania: The School Without Walls: Philadelphia's Parkway Program, Bremer, John and Von Moschzisker, Michael. New York: Holt, Rinehart and WinstonFolder 2016917197120Bibliography-23 Seattle, Washington: Alternative Education in Seattle Public Schools, Seattle School BoardFolder 2116918June 197221Experimental Schools Program of the Berkeley Unified School DistrictFolder 2216919Oct 197222Scope and ContentsPublications Concerning Alternative Public High SchoolsRacine Alternative School ProposalFolder 23169201971-11-1623Scope and ContentsPublications Concerning Alternative Public High SchoolsSoutheast Alternatives Experimental Schools Program, MinneapolisFolder 2416921197224Scope and ContentsPublications Concerning Alternative Public High SchoolsOff-Campus School Program, Bellevue Public Schools, Bellevue, Wash.Folder 2516922197125Scope and ContentsPublications Concerning Alternative Public High SchoolsEducation by Choice, Application for Planning Grant, Quincy, Il.Folder 2616923197226Scope and ContentsPublications Concerning Alternative Public High SchoolsHappiness is Metro High School. Information BookletFolder 271692427Scope and ContentsPublications Concerning Alternative Public High SchoolsMemos-Alternative high school ProposalsFolder 281692528Scope and ContentsPublications Concerning Alternative Public High SchoolsClass MaterialsBox 616877LES 401-Legal Research and Writing-1977Folder 116926 Fall 1978 and Spring 19781SJP 340-Introduction to Research in Social JusticeFolder 21692719792Box 7Box 716878Academic Planning Project SSUFolder 1169281972-731Annual Report and Related InformationFolder 2169291982-832ArchivesFolder 3169301970-3Armitage, Katherine VisitFolder 41693119844Assembly Library Advisory CommitteeFolder 51693219755Bibliography of Charles A. and Anne Morrow LindberghFolder 6169336Calendar 1990/Date Book 1988Folder 7169347Conference on the Evaluation of Library Instruction, University of DenverFolder 81693519738Scope and ContentsIncludes Tickets, correspondence, Evaluation and Conference MaterialsFourth Annual Conference on Library Orientation for Academic Libraries. Eastern Michigan UniversityFolder 91693619749Dana-Thomas House Foundation and Related Newspaper ClippingsFolder 101693710Dillon, Howard. Organizing the Academic Library for InstructionFolder 1116938197511Florence Lewis, Work LoadFolder 12169391980-8612Guide Cover Revisions, Memos, Notes and SurveysFolder 13169401972-8713Instructional Services Librarians: The Sangamon State ExperienceFolder 141694114Instructional Services Librarians: The Sangamon State Experience. Book ProspectusFolder 15169421986-8715Scope and ContentsIncludes Contract and correspondenceInstructional Services Librarian: The Sangamon State Experience. Chapter 1 NotesFolder 161694316Instructional Services Librarian: The Sangamon State Experience. Part II Chapter 4 NotesFolder 171694417Instructional Services Librarian: The Sangamon State Experience. Part II Chapter 4 NotesFolder 181694518Instructional Services Librarian: The Sangamon State Experience. Chapter 5 NotesFolder 191694619Instructional Services Librarian: The Sangamon State Experience. Chapter 5 NotesFolder 201694720Instructional Services Librarian: The Sangamon State Experience. Chapter 6 and 7 NotesFolder 211694821Klintworth, Barbara. Exploring Professionalism: Professionals and Paraprofessionals in Academic LibrariesFolder 221694922Kneebone, Ted. Overview of Cataloging DepartmentFolder 2316950197423Lewis, Florence  Libraries and Independent Learners: A Limited Study. Illinois Libraries. Spfld, Il: Vol 58, No 6, Pg. 504Folder 2416951197624Library Cabinet Meeting: Agenda, Minutes and Working PapersFolder 25169521972-8025Library Cabinet Meeting: Agenda, Minutes and Working PapersFolder 26169531985-8826Library FacultyFolder 27169541971-7427Library Faculty Personnel PapersFolder 281695528Library Faculty RetreatFolder 29169561982 1983, 199029Library Faculty SearchFolder 301695730Library Instruction-Bibliographic Instruction Subcommittee, Working papers, Memos and ActivitiesFolder 311695831Library Instruction-Conferences. E. Michigan UniversityFolder 32169591971-05-0732Scope and ContentsNotes, Handouts and General InformationLibrary Instruction-Courses. Correspondence with the University of California, IrvineFolder 3316960197533Library Instruction-Courses: UNI 301, Library Lab. Course Description and ProceduresFolder 3416961197534Library Instruction-Courses: LES 401, Legal Research and WritingFolder 35169621977-8335Library Instruction-Courses: UNI 405, Library ResearchFolder 3616963198136Library Instruction-Courses: PAC 414, Class SurveyFolder 371696437Library Instruction-Early Planning, General InformationFolder 381696538Library Instruction-Early Planning, OrientationFolder 3916966197139Library Instruction-General Library Skills TestFolder 401696740Library Instruction-General Library Skills Test. Pretest for Library Lab StudentsFolder 4116968Fall 197541Library Instruction-Liaison ProgramFolder 42169691971-7442Library Instruction-Program Guides to Resources and Services (Master Copies)Folder 4316970198843Library Instruction-QuestionnaireFolder 4416971197244Library Instruction-Quotations and PhilosophyFolder 451697245Library Instruction-Study Guides and TestsFolder 461697346Library Instruction-Teaching AidsFolder 471697447Library Instruction-Taxonomy of Library Skills and Resources at SSUFolder 4816975197448Library Instruction-WorkshopsFolder 49169761971-7949Library NotesFolder 50169771969-7050Library NotesFolder 51169781970-7251Library Notes: Implementation and EvaluationFolder 52169791972-7552Library Program Meetings: Agenda, Minutes and Working PapersFolder 53169801981-8253Library Program Meetings: Agenda, Minutes and Working PapersFolder 54169811982-8454Box 8Box 816879Library Program Meetings: Agenda, Minutes and Working Papers, 1985-87Folder 1169821Library Program Meetings: Agenda, Minutes and Working PapersFolder 21698319872Library Program Planning StatementFolder 31698419793Library Skills Test, Instructions for Taking the Library Skills Test on the Plato computer SystemFolder 4169854Midwest Academic Library Conference (MALC)Folder 51698619875Miscellaneous Reports and Memos involving Florence LewisFolder 6169871973-746Miscellaneous Memos, Reports and PapersFolder 7169887NCA ReportFolder 8169891973-878Newspapers ArticlesFolder 9169901975-919Outline for Instructional PlanningFolder 10169911978-7910Scope and ContentsIncludes Memos, Minutes and Agendas from the Library Cabinet Meetings (Bound)Pictures and PostcardsFolder 111699211Program Evaluation CommitteeFolder 12169931973-7412RetirementFolder 131699413Spencer, RobertFolder 141699514Box 9Box 916880Guides to LibrariesFolder 1169961970-19851Library Instruction – Patricia Knapp ArticleFolder 21699719702Library Instruction – Patricia Knapp Montieth College Library ProjectFolder 3169983Library Faculty EvaluationsFolder 4169991971-19724Evaluation Conference Papers and FormsFolder 5170001971-19735SSU Faculty Job Descriptions and Workload PlansFolder 6170016SSU Instructional Services Librarian Job Description and FunctionsFolder 7170027SSU Library Instruction – Early Planning Bibliographic WorkshopFolder 8170038SSU Library Information HandoutsFolder 9170049Library Instruction – SSU Courses – Legal Research and Writing – Course Planning Materials (Original)Folder 10170051972-197610SSU Library Instruction – Library Courses – Library Lab:  Basic Sources of InformationFolder 1117006197511Credit Hours Generated by the Library Program from 1975/76 – Spring 1980 (est.), Cost per Credit Hour by ProgramFolder 1217007Fall 1977-Spring 197812Library Instruction – University of Illinois at ChampaignFolder 131700813Library Instructional Programs:  Earlham CollegeFolder 141700914Library Instruction – Northern Illinois UniversityFolder 151701015General Library Skills Test – Answer KeyFolder 161701116Library Instruction – SSU Workshops – Instructional Aids – Checklist (MJM)Folder 171701217Oral History ProceduresFolder 181701318Library/Archives – MinutesFolder 19170141973-197419Library Orientation and InstructionFolder 20170151973-197820Map Collection SSU Library – MJM ProposalFolder 2117016197421Library Philosophy for RetreatFolder 2217017197422Session 4 Law/Literature Summaries – LES 401Folder 2317018Oct. 197423Library Instruction – SSUFolder 241701924Workshop HandoutFolder 2517020Fall 197525Box 10Box 1016881Library Instruction – SSU Guide to SourcesFolder 1170211974-19891Scope and ContentsIncludes: Illinois state, U.S. government publications, history, basic literary research, grants, writing papers, business and financial information, Constitution of the U.S., gerontology, community arts management, and legal researchIllinois Libraries Miscellaneous Issue – Florence Lewis Article, Springfield IL, Vol. 58 No.6Folder 217022June 19762John Knoepfle Poetry Article in Illinois TimesFolder 317023March 3-9, 19783Report on Bibliographic Instruction Sub-CommitteeFolder 4170241979-11-024Rochell ReportFolder 51702519795Senior Learner Program and Library GuidesFolder 6170261979-11-206Library Instruction – SSU Courses – Library ResearchFolder 717027Fall, 1980-817Charles A. Lindbergh Fund NewslettersFolder 81702819818Library Instruction – LOEXFolder 91702919819College and Research Libraries Journal – Vol. 44 No. 3Folder 1017030May, 198310Scope and ContentsLibrarian Status Article Used for ResearchLibrary ProgramFolder 11170311983-8411Guide to Sources – SSU Library Instruction ArticlesFolder 12170321973-198512Scope and ContentsIncludes: legal research, psychology, U.S. government publications, Illinois state publications, criminal justice, manuscript collections, Gale literary series, writing, locating/evaluating resources, and missing proceduresPublications, INFOTRAC Information, ISL Graduate InternshipsFolder 13170331983-198613Articles about SSU Library – Brian AlleyFolder 1417034198414Interlibrary Borrowing Code – ILCSO Circulation LibrariansFolder 15170351986-05-0215Articles about SSU Library – Pat BreivikFolder 1617036198716SSU Library Program RE:  Faculty Rank, Salaries, etc.Folder 1717037198717Professional Activities Report:  SSU Library Resources and Services, Availability Study, ABC Files, ISL Functions – ActivitiesFolder 1817038198718Selected BibliographyFolder 191703919Book Prospectus Prepared by Florence Lewis, "Instructional Services Librarians: The Sangamon State Experience"Folder 2017040June 198720Contract from M.E. Sharpe Inc. (Book Publisher)Folder 2117041198721Workshops, Guides – MastersFolder 2217042Spring 198822Telephone DirectoryFolder 2317043Jan. 198823

