<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>P.SakolskyArchon Finding Aid Title P.SakolskyUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:37:23 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    P/Sakolsky. Ron Sakolsky, Personal Papers, 1972-1978
    
      Sakolsky, Ron
    
    P.Sakolsky
    119
    
      3.16 Cubic Feet
    
    1972-1978
    Date acquired: 02/00/1982
    1
    2
    3
    4
    5
    6
    7
    8
    9
    oversize items
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Papers of Ron Sakolsky, Assistant Professor of Public Administration (1972-), and the People's Institute, a non-profit corporation that did research, consulting and related activities for powerless individuals and groups in Springfield (1974-78).  Includes minutes, correspondence, reports, papmhlets, manuscripts, planning material and memoranda as well as newsclippings, press releases and a CBS News interview tape.  Correspondence includes letters received from or sent to Sakolsky, University Administrators and faculty, Samgamon County doctors, pharmacists and the general public.  Of particular note are the materials concerning the controversy over the publication of the "Consumers Guide to Doctors for Sangamon County".  Other People's  Institute research and publications are include: "The Power  Game: Who Rules Springfield" and the never published  "Doing you own Divorce in Springfield."  Also includes DES Action Group materials, an activist organization that supported the children of mothers who took  the carcinogenic drug DES to prevent miscarriages in the 1950's. DES materials include correspondence between Sakolky and the medical community concerning DES, newsclippings, planning materials and press packets.  Also includes Sakolsky essays: SSU student papers; and Sakolsky's Utica College class materials, syllabus and new student orientation materials.  
  
    Arrangement Note
By organization and then by activity  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Ron Sakolsky  
  
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 116273People's Institute Records: Springfield Power StructureSeries 1162741976-1978General PapersFolder 1162751976-19781Scope and ContentsMinutes, membership, list, letters and banks statementsPeople's Institute Publication: The Power Game: Who Rules SpringfieldFolder 216276ca. 19762Scope and Contents1st and 3rd editionsSakolsky essay: "The Springfield Housing Market: Some Considerations"Folder 3162773Proposed Environmental Policy for Lake Springfield, by CWLP Environmental coordinator James M. HenneberryFolder 41627819744People's Institute Records: A Consumer Guide to DoctorsSeries 2162791974-1979Manuscript, A Consumer Guide to Doctors for Sangamon County, 2nd editionFolder 5162801974-105Planning Materials, doctors lists and questionnairesFolder 6162816General correspondenceFolder 7162821974-19777Scope and ContentsIncludes Sangamon County Medical Society Alert memorandum and chronology of eventsUniversity administration-related memorandaFolder 8162831974-19758Requests for guideFolder 9162841974-19759News-clippings and articlesFolder 10162851976-197910Interview with Ron Sakolsky, CBS News, Newsbreak with Charles OsgoodFolder 11162861974-10-1411Scope and Contents60 minutes cassetteSakolsky essay: "How to Choose a Physician"Folder 121628712OversizeItem 1162881Scope and ContentsRecord album spoof, "Sly and the Family Practice Clinic, featuring Ron Sakolsky on sound affects"Box 2Box 216289People's Institute Records: A Consumer Guide to PharmaciesSeries 1162991974-1975People's Institute publication: A Consumer's Guide to Springfield PharmaciesFolder 10163001975-0810Planning materialFolder 111630111Scope and ContentsIncludes pharmacy list, questionnaires, reports on the Illinois Pharmacy Practice ActCorrespondence, memoranda, news releases, requests for GuideFolder 12163021974-197512News-clippingsFolder 13163031974-197513Osco Drugs, Prescription Price BookFolder 1416304197414Counter guide published by Health Services Management ProgramFolder 1162901975-091Scope and ContentsSSU Consumer Guide to Physicians in Sangamon CountyCollected doctors guides and health brochuresFolder 2162912Collected doctors guides and health brochuresFolder 3162923Collected doctors guides and health brochuresFolder 4162934Collected doctors guides and health brochuresFolder 5162945Collected doctors guides and health brochuresFolder 6162956Collected doctors guides and health brochuresFolder 7162967Collected doctors guides and health brochuresFolder 8162978Collected doctors guides and health brochuresFolder 9162989Box 3Box 316305People's Institute Records: Doing Your Own DivorceSeries 1163091977Student project, school game?Folder 8163108Kathy Leo, An Inquiry Into Direct Action for Social ChangeFolder 9163119Donna Murdock, Listing Journal Jazz and Blues: Cultural ImpactFolder 101631210Mark D. Kaye, Tutorial Uncooperative CommunitiesFolder 111631311Seniorities Bracy, A Guide for Women in Administrative PositionsFolder 12163141981-0612Evaluation formsFolder 131631513Utica College papersSeries 2163161971-1972New Student Orientation, Planning papersFolder 1416317197114Urban Government Course: Syllabus, Research MaterialsFolder 1516318ca. 197215Springfield's Permanent Government: A People's GuideFolder 1616319197416Prescription Drug Price Posting Project, The RX Rip-off, Public Citizen, Washington D.C.Folder 11630619741Ralph Nader's California Citizen Action Group, A Shopper's Guide to Sacramento Area PharmaciesFolder 2163071974-092Federal Trade Commission, Seattle Regional Office, Prescription Drug Prices, Consumer Survey HandbookFolder 3163081974-103Box 4Box 416320Correspondence Art Club EntriesFolder 11632119841Box 5Box 516322Correspondence Art Club EntriesFolder 11632319841Box 6Box 616324Correspondence Art Club EntriesFolder 11632519841Scope and ContentsIncludes over sized Haymarket Mail ArtBox 7Box 716326Haymarket Mail Art ExhibitFolder 11632719861Box 8Box 816328Scope and ContentsPrint-outs of e-mail concerning arrest of Drs. Sakolsky and Dennis Fox for leaf-letting at a
Springfield mayoral candidates debate at SSU on March 15, 1995. Arranged by date received.UndatedFolder 11632919951Folder 2163301995-04-112Folder 3163311995-04-1231995-04-13Folder 41633241995-04-14Folder 5163335Folder 6163341995-04-156Folder 7163351995-04-167Folder 8163361995-04-178Folder 9163371995-04-189Folder 10163381995-04-1910Folder 11163391995-04-2011Folder 12163401995-04-21 - 1995-04-2612Folder 13163411995-05-04 - 1995-05-0813Box 9Box 916342Scope and ContentsAlternative Roots, Cultural Democracy, and other activist newspapers, arranged alphabetically and by date of publication.Adventures in Pioneer Crafts and Folk Life (Clayville publication), E.F. Pearson, Illus. by R.M. PhillipsFolder 1163431The Alliance for Cultural Democracy – (Imagination)Folder 2163442Scope and ContentsMidwest Bulletin, Jan. 1990
Newsletter- Southwest Region, Winter, 1991 
Pamphlets: Membership (Blue)
Pamphlets: Counter Quincentennial Columbus Campaign – 1992
Columbus "Quincentennial Funny Money" Anti-Columbus Protest of 500 year anniversary of landing – 1992.Alternate Roots – Regional Organizations of Theaters South – publicationFolder 3163453Scope and ContentsWinter1988; Summer 1989, Spring 1990; Winter 1990, Spring 1991, Summer 1992; Annual Meeting 1992; Summer 1993; Fall/Winter 1993-94; Spring/Summer 1994; Annual Meeting 1995; Annual Meeting 1996; Summer 1997.Alternate Roots publication: Unity Partnership (UP) From the ROOTS (Regional Organization Of Theaters/Arts South)Folder 4163464Scope and ContentsFall 1999/Winter 2000; Summer/Fall 2000;
Spring/Summer 2001 # 2; January 2002; Spring 2002; Summer 2002.A Draft for a Declaration of Cultural Human Rights – Original and CopyFolder 5163475Scope and ContentsCultural Democracy – Course Syllabus – PAC 414 Fall Semester 1989 – Ron Sakolsky.Cultural Democracy: "A Journal Devoted to Cultural Activism"Folder 6163486Scope and ContentsIssue # 35 Winter 1988; Issue # 36 Summer 1988; Issue # 37 Spring 1989; Issue # 39 Spring 1990; Issue # 41 Fall 1993; Issue # 42 Winter 1994; Issue # 43 Fall/Winter 1994; Issue # 44 Spring 1996A Feeling for Life – Cultural Identity, Community and the ArtsFolder 7163497Scope and ContentsFestivals andthe Politics of Culture: National Center for Urban Ethnic Affairs, Washington, D.C.Milwaukee Hispanic Arts Council, Milwaukee, WI.1980; "How to '92" – A Project
of the Alliance for Cultural Democracy's campaign for a Post-Columbian World – Intended as an "Ongoing Manual for Cultural Activism for 1992" – printed as an anti- Quincentennial protest against the celebration of "Columbus Day."Huraca'nFolder 8163508Scope and ContentsThe Alliance for Cultural Democracy Special Project National Program –"500 Years of Resistance" – Fall/Winter 1990 Vol. 1 #1; Summer 1991 Vol. 2 #'s 1 and 2; Summer 1992 Issue # 3; Imaginaction III – Cultural Vision and Struggle in the 1980's – Event Poster – La Pena Cultural Center.New Art Examiner publicationFolder 9163519Scope and ContentsJanuary 1996; April 1996; May 1996; Summer
1996; September 1996; October 1996; November 1996.Open Dialogue publicationFolder 101635210Scope and ContentsThe Newsletter of the Association of American Cultures– Winter 1990 Vol. 7 Issue #1; Fall 1990 Vol. 7 Issue #2; Jan./Feb. 1991 Vol. 8 Issue #1; Spring 1991 Vol. 8 Issue #2; Winter 1992 Vol. 9 Issue #1. Village Voice Newsletter – Identity Crisis: Can the Alternative Arts Survive Capitalism - December 15, 1992.

