<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>P.Stone Series IIArchon Finding Aid Title P.Stone Series IISandra LongenUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:37:49 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    P/Stone. Ralph Stone, Personal Papers, 1990-  Series II
    
      Stone, Ralph
    
    P.Stone Series II
    125
    
      2.30 Cubic Feet
    
    Date acquired: 06/00/1990
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The Ralph Stone papers, Series II contain research index cards, copies of primary &amp; secondary materials, dealing with the Pana-Virden mine riot and Illinois labor and national labor movements including radical and communist groups, cooperatives, and John H. Walker and Dunca McDonald, who were both linked to the labor movements in Illinois.  A minor portion of the file is devoted to subjects  of personal interest to Mr. Stone.  These subjects include various individuals, race relations in Springfield IL., the Macoupin County Courthouse, and the selection and use of audio-visual equipment.  
  
    Arrangement Note
By subject  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Charles B. Strozier  
  
    Papers
    Reports
    Newspaper Clippings
    Audio Tapes
    Correspondence
  
  Box 1Box 118175Pana - Virden mine crisis and riots 1898, various news articlesFolder 1181761Dissertation:  Eleanor Burhorn "Strike of Coal Miners at Pana, Illinois"Folder 2181772Thesis:  Olsen "Virden Riot"Folder 3181783Pana - Virden mine riots - commentaryFolder 4181794Black strike breakers (1865-1900) - commentaryFolder 5181805Il. State Board of Arbitration, fourth annual report (1899) - &amp; - United Mine Workers, 10th Annual MeetingFolder 6181816Il. State Board of Labor Statistics, annual reports (1893-1900)Folder 7181827STONE:  Pana - Virden correspondence and research notesFolder 8181838Gen. Alexander Bradley:  "The Great Coal Miner's Strike of 1897." - &amp; - Edward A. Weick:  "General Alexander Bradley"Folder 9181849Child Labor in Illinois - mine workFolder 101818510Dennis McMurray:  Illinois Coal Mining in the 1930's (various articles) - &amp; - State Journal Register:  "Springfield North RevisitedFolder 111818611Film list:  Illinois coal mining strikes and disasters - &amp; - Quincy History:  "Early Ventures that Failed", "The Great Coal Famine of 1919"Folder 121818712STONE:  Illinois Coal Miners correspondence and research notesFolder 131818813Labor Party of Illinois, Platform - &amp; - excerpt from thirty sixth annual proceedings, Illinois Federation of Labor (1918)Folder 141818914Illinois Federation of Labor proceedings 1913 - 1924 (not complete)Folder 151819015Nancy Hunt:  "Organizing Illinois' Coal Miners' wives:  Gender and Class Politics in the Illinois Miner Writings of Agnes Burns Weick"Folder 161819116Knights of Labor in Illinois (1886)Folder 171819217Mount Olive Miner's CemeteryFolder 181819318Labor HistoryFolder 191819419Stephone Booth:  "An Historiographic Look at Radicalism, Ethnic Groups, and the American Labor Movement, 1870-1940"Folder 201819520Progressive Mine Workers of America - &amp; - CommunismFolder 211819621Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers - Brief HistoryFolder 221819722STONE:  National Miners Union research notes - &amp; -  Fliege: "The National Miners Union and It's Illinois  Strike of 1929"Folder 231819823STONE:  National Mining correspondenceFolder 241819924Socialist Reconstruction of SocietyFolder 251820025Agnes Burns Weick:  official materials, National Women's Trade Union League - &amp; - Women's Auxillary of  Progressive Miners of AmericaFolder 261820126Agnes Burns Weick:  various writings and correspondenceFolder 271820227STONE:  Agnes Burns Weick correspondenceFolder 281820328Ohio Historical Society:  Inventory of Max S. Hayes papersFolder 291820429Ohio Historical Society:  Inventory of Charles Emil Ruthenberg papersFolder 301820530U of I, Chicago Circle:  Guide to Victor Orlander papersFolder 311820631Wayne State University: Collection inventories for: Edward A. WeickFolder 321820732Wayne State University: Collection inventories for: John and Phyllis Collier CollectionFolder 331820833Wayne State University: Collection inventories for: George and Grace Brewer CollectionFolder 341820934Wayne State University: Collection inventories for: Carl Person CollectionFolder 351821035Wayne State University: Collection inventories for: John Edelman CollectionFolder 361821136Wayne State University: Collection inventories for: Mary Van Kleek PapersFolder 371821237Wayne State University: Collection inventories for: newsletters and guide to Library of Labor and Urban AffairsFolder 381821338Harriet ReidFolder 391821439Illinois State Vice Commission - various news reports (1913)Folder 401821540Race Relations in Springfield Illinois - &amp; - Suggested Research Topics in Springfield HistoryFolder 411821641A. Gilbert Belles: "The Black Press in Illinois"Folder 421821742STONE:  Selected materials regarding A - V equipmentFolder 431821843Macoupin County Courthouse informationFolder 441821944STONE: selected readings of a personal natureFolder 451822045Florence E. Parker: a copy of her willFolder 461822146STONE: Rough draft of "A History of The American Worker"Folder 471822247Quincy Public Library &amp; Illinois State Historical Library:  genealogy informationFolder 481822348Audio tape:  Sounds of Days Past (WWII)Folder 491822449Box 2Box 218225SCOOP:  general Co-op informationFolder 1182261The Cooperative LeagueFolder 2182272Florence Parker:  "Labor and Cooperatives"Folder 3182283Recent events:  Co-op news and magazine articles (1980-)Folder 4182294Co-op's and Labor, various articlesFolder 5182305Academic articles, Co-op HistoryFolder 6182316Articles on cooperation: George Halonen, "Cooperation"Folder 7182327Articles on cooperation: Allan Benson, "The Growing Grocery Bill"Folder 8182338Articles on cooperation: Edward Bemis, "Cooperative Distribution"Folder 9182349Articles on cooperation: Albert Sonnicksen, "Consumers Cooperation"Folder 101823510Farm Labor research information - &amp; - Cooperation research informationFolder 111823611STONE: General Correspondence, Co-op'sFolder 121823712John Doyle:  Farmers Union, Il. State Cooperative Society, STONE:  correspondenceFolder 131823813John Walker:  various writings 1914-1929Folder 141823914John Walker:  various correspondence 1916-1948.  STONE:  John Walker correspondenceFolder 151824015Writings about John WalkerFolder 161824116Duncan McDonald:  Various writingsFolder 171824217Duncan McDonald:  IFL - UMW materials - &amp; - STONE:  "Duncan McDonald and John Walker"Folder 181824318Duncan McDonald:  correspondence (1915-1960)Folder 191824419STONE:  research correspondence - Walker, McDonald Co-opsFolder 201824520Box One of Research Index Cards; Topics covered: Co-op's, McDonald, and Labor movementFolder 211824621Box Two of Research Index Cards; Topics covered; Walker, Labor history, and United Mine WorkersFolder 221824722Audio tape:  Woody Guthrie, Music of the DepressionFolder 231824823Box 3Box 318249Box Three of Research Index Cards; Topic covered - Labor generally, references to primary sourcesFolder 1182511Box 4Box 418250Box Four of Research Index Cards; Topic covered - Pana - Virden, and coal mining generallyFolder 1182521

