<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>P.WorthyArchon Finding Aid Title P.WorthySandra LongenUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:37:53 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    P/Worthy. James C. Worthy, Personal Papers, 1961-1966 &amp; 1970-1971
    
      Worthy, James
    
    P.Worthy
    128
    
      1.50 Cubic Feet
    
    1961-1971
    Date acquired: 06/00/1973
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Personal papers of James Carson Worthy (1910-1998), Professor  of Public Affairs and Management at SSU (1972-1978) including his papers as a member of the U.S. President's Commission on Campaign costs (1961-1962) comprising of correspondence, agendas and minutes of meetings, drafts and final reports of the Commission, travel vouchers, press clippings, staff memoranda, research reports, and miscellaneous publications relating to campaign funds, the financing of federal elections, political contributions, and party finance, along with final reports on Financing Presidential Campaigns.  Correspondents include Walter P. Ruether, Alexander Heard, Lee C. White, Herber E. Alexander, Charles Percy, Irvin Lechliter, and Russell B. Long; also includes papers as Chairman of the Illinois Board of Higher of Education Master Plan Committee N, On Governing structure (1970-71), including publications, reports, staff memoranda, minutes, position papers, statements, correspondence, newspaper clippings, and written responses from the University of Illinois, Southern Illinois University, the Board of Regents and Regency  Universities, the Board of Governors and its universities, Illinois junior colleges, private colleges, the Board of Higher Education, governance of the universities by Boards, campus problems and the status of the Chicago Circle Campus.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological; (original Worthy arrangement kept intact)  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
James C. Worthy  
  
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 116367CorrespondenceFolder 11636819611CorrespondenceFolder 2163691962-012CorrespondenceFolder 3163701962-023CorrespondenceFolder 4163711962, 19664Agendas &amp; Minutes of Commission MeetingsFolder 5163721961-19625Scope and Contents1st meeting (organizational, meeting members, outlining goals) no minutes exist, however there are written notes in Worthy Correspondence, November 9, 1961
2nd meeting, November 28, 1961, Minutes
3rd meeting, December 21, 1961, Minutes
4th meeting, Jan. 22-23, 1962, Agenda, Minutes, &amp; Amendments
5th meeting, February 9-10, 1962, Agenda &amp; Minutes
6th meeting, March 16-16, 1962, Agenda &amp; MinutesDrafts and Final Report of the Commission: Financing Presidential Campaigns, Report of the President's Commission on Campaign CostsFolder 61637319626Scope and ContentsIncludes Final edition, Superintendent of Documents publication, April 18, 1962.President's Commission on Campaign CostsFolder 7163747Scope and ContentsPress clippings and photostats of finance editorialsStaff research memorandums, publications, articles, &amp; theses utilized by members of the CommitteeFolder 8163758Scope and Contents"Meaning &amp; Application of the Federal Statutes Regulating Political Campaign Activities" (Confidential Memorandum, June 23, 1956) prepared by firm of Arnold,Portas &amp; Porter. (Known as Porter Memorandum) "Minnesota Poll, Release of December 3, 1961, Minneapolis Sunday Tribune, '72% Oppose Federal Funds for Candidates Seeking Presidency'"
President's Commission on Campaign Costs, Staff Memorandum: "Congressional Recommendations Since 1941", December 14, 1961
President's Commission on Campaign Costs, "Spot Announcements", December 18, 1961
President's Commission on Campaign Costs, Staff Memorandum: Supplement to the Porter Memorandum of June 23, 1956, "Meaning &amp; Application of the Federal Statutes Regulating Political Campaign Activities," December 19, 1961 
President's Commission on Campaign Costs, Staff Memorandum: "Universal Voter Registration Act", December 19, 1961Staff research memorandums, publications, articles, &amp; thesesFolder 9163769Scope and ContentsPresident's Commission on Campaign Costs, Staff Memorandum:"Summary of a Proposal
by Dan Brink for Financing Political Campaigns", January 12, 1962
President's Commission on Campaign Costs, Staff Memorandum: "1. State Regulation of
Political Finance, 2. Library of Congress Study on Campaign Financing by Governmental Units at Any Level", January 17, 1962
President's Commission on Campaign Costs, Staff Memorandum: "Replies to December 13th letter from the Commission on: 1. Ceilings, 2. Rates for newspaper advertising, other media, 3. Reduce campaign time, 4. Disclosure, 5. Other miscellaneous suggestions, Feb. 5, 1962. "Count of Replies to the Commission Letter of Inquiry", Feb. 7, 1962. President's Commission on Campaign Costs, Staff Memorandum: "Corporations &amp; Labor Unions under Section 610 of the Federal Corrupt Practices Act", March 5, 1962
"Regulation of Political Finance: The Pressure For &amp; Against Change", by Herbert E. Alexander, Director, Citizens' Research Foundation, November 13-16, 1966
Bound materials relating to Presidential campaigns, advertising, &amp; finance, submitted to the Commission by the Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc., Frank Stanton, President, 1952-60: "Broadcasting &amp; Politics" by Herbert E. Alexander, 1966; "Should Political Broadcasting Be Fair or Equal?" by Anne W. Branscomb; "Plea for Pay for Politicking" by Warren Moscow, 1961Box 2Box 216377PublicationsFolder 1163781Scope and Contents"Tax Incentives for Political Contributions?" by Herbert E. Alexander, Citizens' Research Foundation, Study No. 3, March 1961
"Responsibility in Party Finance" by Herbert E. Alexander, Citizens' Research Foundation, Study No. 7, July 1963
"Financing State Senate Campaigns: Multnomah County, Oregon, 1964" by Donald
G. Balmer, Citizens' Research Foundation, Study No. 8, 1966
"Federal Regulation of Campaign Finance: Some Constitutional Questions" by
Albert J. Rosenthal, Citizens' Research Foundation, Study No. 18, 1972
"The Minnesota Republican Neighbor-To-Neighbor Drive: Successful Small Gift Solicitation" by Thomas L. Pahl, Citizens' Research Foundation, Study No. 19, 1971
"Campaign Funds As An Intraparty Political Resource; Connecticut, 1966-1968" by David Adamany, Citizens' Research Foundation, Study No. 20, 1972
"State Election Services in Oregon" by Donald G. Balmer, Citizens' Research Foundation, Study No. 21, 1972
"Money, Politics &amp; Public Reporting" by Herbert E. Alexander, Citizens' Research Foundation, February 1960
"Regulation of Political Finance" by Herbert E. Alexander, 1966 Master Plan Committee N, on Governing Structure, Illinois Board of Higher EducationMaster Plan Committee N, Publications ConsultedFolder 2163792Scope and Contents"Illinois State Higher Education: Diversity Within Order" by Robert Marsh. Reprinted from the Summer 1969 issue of the Education Record
"Challenge, Planning, Progress: Growth in Illinois Higher Education, 1962-1968". A report of the State of Illinois Board of Higher Education, December 1968
Copies of other articles and book chaptersBoard of Higher Education MaterialsFolder 3163803Scope and ContentsPublications, reports, studies, &amp; handouts: "Legal Bases of Coordinating Boards of Higher Education in Thirty-Nine States" by
Robert L. Williams, Chicago, Council of State Governments, September 1967, "Critical Issues Before Committee N," "Regional Advisory Councils," BHE Rules &amp; Regulations, April 28, 1965, other BHE reports and handoutsFolder 4Folder 4163814Scope and ContentsSystem vs.institutional governing boards/status of Chicago Circle (Worthy
heading) consists of notes &amp; draft documents on the structure of the Higher Education System in Illinois, as well as the status of the Chicago Circle Campus of the University of Illinois. Important reports include: "Issues &amp; Alternatives Regarding Governing Structure" by James C. Worthy. Includes draft documents of 11/11/970, 11/23/970 &amp; final 12/5/970 internal document.
"Definition of Powers Coordinating &amp; Governing Boards in Higher Education", Staff Memorandum "A Rationale for Change: Staff for Committee N", an Internal Document "Confidential"
"An Experimental Move Towards A System of Institutional Boards for Public Higher Education in IllinoisMinutes of Meetings of Committee NFolder 5163825Scope and ContentsMeeting Schedule for Committee N
Tentative Timetable for Principal Events
Agenda, August 29, 1970
First Meeting, Minutes, August 29, 1970
Informal remarks of James B. Holderman at first meeting, Comm. N
Second Meeting, Minutes, September 14, 1970
Third Meeting, Minutes, September 28, 1970
Agenda, October 5, 1970
Notes on Meeting 10/24/1970
Committee N Hearing, 10/30/1970
Meeting of December 11, 1970, Unofficial Minutes
Excerpt from Minutes of Meeting of Committee N, December 28, 1970
Agenda, January 9, 1971
Agenda, February 27, 1971
Minutes, February 27, 1971Box 3Box 316383Reports, position papers &amp; letters submitted to theFolder 1163841Scope and Contents"Rationale for the Statewide Higher Education Coordinating Board: by Lyman A. Glenny, January 14-15, 1971
"Committee N &amp; the University of Illinois:, prepared for the University of Illinois Citizens Committee by Charles E. Flynn, Director, February 5, 1971
"Chicago Circle Campus: A Special Case for Committee N"
"The Suburbs, The City, &amp; The State: New Trends in the 70's"
Various speeches of presentations to the Committee - most untitled &amp; speakers unnamed
Other position papers &amp; letters regarding hearingsCorrespondenceFolder 2163851968-19712Scope and ContentsConsists of letters received &amp; sent regarding the work of Committee N. Letters used in distribution of the final report also included. Includes letters from George L. Clements regarding factors bearing on Worthy's chairmanship of reconstituted committee &amp; from Otto Kerner regarding final report of the Committee.Newspaper Clippings of articles, editorials, &amp; commentary concerning Committee N, its goals &amp; actionsFolder 3163863Folder 4Folder 4163874Scope and ContentsUniversity of Illinois responses consisting of written letters, telegrams, position papers in response to a Committee N questionnaire distributed by Mr. Worthy regarding the structure of Illinois Higher Education &amp; the University of Illinois &amp; its campuses. Correspondents include Joseph Begando, Chancellor, U.of I. Medicalm Center; J.W. Peltason, Chancellor, U. of I.; the U. of I. Faculty Senate; Norman Parker, Chancellor, Chicago Circle Campus; &amp; David D. Henry, President, U. of I.Folder 5Folder 5163885Scope and ContentsSouthern Illinois University Responses consists of letters &amp; position papers with regard to the restructuring of the Higher Boards. Writers include George W. Linden, President, University Senate; Robert G. Layer, Chancellor, SIU; &amp; Clarence W. Stephens, Chairman, University Administrative Council.Folder 6Folder 6163896Scope and ContentsBoard of Regents Responses consists of position papers &amp; letters from members of the Board of Regents on alternatives to present organization pattern for higher education. Writers include Franklin G. Matsler, Executive Director; Gordon H. Millar; also includes position papers &amp; letters from the Regency Universities of Northern Illinois University &amp; Illinois State University, F.R. Griegle, President.Folder 7Folder 7163907Scope and ContentsBoard of Governors Responses consisting of letters &amp; position papers from members of the Board of Governors of State Colleges &amp; Universities regarding the restructuring of the Higher Boards. Writers include F.H. McKelvey, Consultant to Board of Governors; Ben L. Morton, Executive Officer; Robert A. Stipes, Jr., Chairman; Quincy Doudna, President, Eastern Illinois University; Jerome M. Sachs, President, Northeastern Illinois State College.Folder 8Folder 8163918Scope and ContentsIllinois Junior Colleges Responses consisting of letters &amp; position papers from members of the Illinois Junior College Board &amp; from Illinois Junior Colleges in regard to the restructuring of the Higher Boards. Correspondents include: Fred L. Wellman, Executive Secretary, Illinois Junior College Board; Frank F. Fowle, Chairman, IJCB; Mary Miller, President, Danville Junior College; Oscar E. Shabat, Chancellor, City Colleges of Chicago; Ashley Johnson, Acting President, Prairie State College.Folder 9Folder 9163929Scope and ContentsIllinois Private Colleges &amp; Universities consisting of letters &amp; position papers from
members of the Federation of Independent Illinois Colleges &amp; Universities &amp; other private colleges &amp; universities in Illinois. Writers include: Raymond Baumhart, S.J.,
President, Loyola University; A.L. Schilling, President, North Central College; Joseph J. Boyd, Executive Director, Illinois State Scholarship Commission; George Burditt,Chairman, Higher Education Committee, Illinois General Assembly; W.
Russell Arrington, Senator, Illinois State Senate; Hudson T. Armerding, President,
Wheaton College; Rolf A. Weil, President, Roosevelt University; Harold W. Reed,
President, Olivet Nazarene College; &amp; James E. Crimi, President, Aurora College.Folder 10Folder 101639310Scope and ContentsCommittee Members Lists &amp; Correspondence (Worthy heading) consisting of lists of Committee N members, copies of letters sent &amp; received regarding asking members to serve, acknowledging receipt of Committee reports, requests for information on Committee N, letters regarding travel, meetings, &amp; other details, Master Plan Committee N, on Governing structure, Illinois Board of Higher Education, &amp; Working Papers continued. Writers include: George Burditt, Lyman A. Glenny, &amp; Paul Simon.Folder 11Folder 111639411Scope and ContentsBHE &amp; Other Documents Relevant to the Work of Committee N consisting of reports &amp; internal memorandums of various boards, examining groups &amp; others on universities &amp; governing structures. Notable reports include: "The Illinois System of Public Higher Education" by Boyd R. Keenan. Staff Memorandum No. 31, Commission on State Government - Illinois, August 26, 1966. "Report: Goals &amp; Reorganization" by James B. Holderman, Illinois Board of Higher Education, June 1969. Executive Directors Reports No. 79, 80, 85, &amp; 90.part of a Visit to the University of Illinois at Chicago Circle, Chicago, Illinois, May 3-6, 1970 for the Commission on Higher Education of the North Central Association of Colleges &amp; Secondary Schools.Box 4Box 416395Master Plan Committee N on Governing Structures, Illinois Board of Higher Education  (folder 1 of 3)Folder 1163961Scope and ContentsConsists of statements, copies of letters, papers &amp; other documents given as opinions to Committee N or presented at hearings. Writers include: David D. Henry, President, University of Illinois; Robert Stuart, Chairman of the Board, National Can Corporation; Norman A. Parker, Chancellor, U. of I. Chicago Circle; Oscar E. Shabat, Chancellor, City Colleges of Chicago; Emory Williams, Chairman, Health Education Commission of the Illinois Board of Higher Education; Clyde Choate, Illinois State Senator. A majority of these papers are copies of previous statements received - the originals are divided by sector &amp; in the RESPONSES files. Two major reports are included with this set of study papers: Provisional Development Plan, University of Illinois, 1971-72 through 1980-81. Prepared for presentation to the Illinois Board of Higher Education, September 1970. The Lieutenant Governor's Committee on Southern Illinois University: A Practical Study of Campus Problems, September 1970. Offical name is: Lieutenant Governor Simon Commission on Campus Disorder. 3 folders.Master Plan Committee N on Governing Structures Illinois Board of Higher Education  (folder 2 of 3)Folder 2163972Master Plan Committee N on Governing Structures Illinois Board of Higher Education  (folder 3 of 3)Folder 3163983Report of Master Plan Committee N - Governing Structure, A Report to the Illinois Board of Higher EducationFolder 416399June 19714History of the Management Program, Sangamon State University: A Personal Memoir, by James C. WorthyFolder 534491August, 19765Box 5Box 516400Management 301: class notes and materialsFolder 11640119771Management 401: class notes and materialsFolder 21640219772Management 421: class materialsFolder 31640319753Misc. Class notesFolder 41640419754Center for teaching technologiesFolder 51640519725Gaming center (development of)Folder 61640619726Future of the Management programFolder 7164071972-19767Appointment and relative documentsFolder 8164081972-19768SSU Foundation-donationsFolder 9164091974-19769The Beginnings of the Management Program at Sangamon State University: A Personal Chronicle, written by James WorthyFolder 1016410197610Box 6Box 616411JCW EvaluationsFolder 1164121972-19751Letters of commendationFolder 2164131973-19752Management booklet distributionFolder 31641419763MiscFolder 4164151973-19774

