<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>A.02.01/01Archon Finding Aid Title A.02.01/01UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:38:06 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    A2/1/1. Sangamon State University Major Reports and Documents,1963-1995
    
      Sangamon State University
    
    A.02.01/01
    134
    
      1.66 Cubic Feet
    
    1963-1995
    Date acquired: 09/02/1976
    1
    2
    3
    4
    5
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Major reports and documents concerning the need for a senior university in Springfield and Sangamon State University (1963-  ) including Becker and Becker Master Plan (1970), the master plans of the Illinois Board of Higher Education, the Budinger  Report, the Crane Report, the Ferber Report, the Report on New Senior Institutions, the Robinson Report, and other prominent documents instrumental in SSU history.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Acquired Piecemeal  
  
    Reports
  
  Box 1Box 121452Agenda for Action ReportFolder 121457July 19741Scope and ContentsSubmitted by ad hoc committee to President Robert C. Spencer.  101 pages, two copies.Becker and Becker Master PlanFolder 221458June 19702Scope and ContentsLong-range facilities plan and construction timetableBlue MemoFolder 321459February 19703Scope and ContentsPresident Spencer (recruiting and hiring faculty)Blue MemoFolder 421460December 19704Scope and ContentsPresident Spencer (recruiting and hiring faculty)Board of Higher Education Master PlansFolder 5214611964-19715Scope and ContentsPhase I, July 1964; Phase II, December 1966; Phase III, May 1971Brookens, Norris; Journal and Register (obituary)Folder 62146219696Budinger Report, History of SSUFolder 721463May 19727Scope and ContentsApplied Study Term report by Francis J. Budinger.Committee for Higher Education in Central IllinoisFolder 8214641969-708Crane ReportFolder 921465January 19639Scope and ContentsStudy directed by Robert M. Crane at request of Springfield Committee for Higher EducationBox 2Box 221453DeBolt, Dean, Sangamon State University History,  n.d.Folder 1214661Economic Impact of SSU on Springfield and Sangamon CountyFolder 221467October 19842Scope and ContentsCenter for Community and Regional Studies. Enabling Act for SSU, Public Act 76 - 131.Enrollment in Institutions of Higher Education in Illinois, Board of Higher EducationFolder 3214681957 - 1978, December 1978,3Esser Report, study of feasibility of a research park at SSUFolder 421469March 19834Ferber Report, Need for a senior college in SpringfieldFolder 521470March 19675Fink Report to President Spencer, On-Campus Student Housing Feasibility StudyFolder 621471April 19776Friedland, Milton D., notes from meeting of Steering Committee of Association of Commerce &amp; IndustryFolder 721472February 19687Giesecke, Ernst, Some Thoughts on the First Ten Years of Sangamon StateFolder 821473November 19798Box 3Box 321454Guide to Alternative Colleges and Universities, Beacon PressFolder 12147419741What You Always Wanted To Know About Sangamon...Folder 2214752Scope and ContentsHeyman, Mark, What You Always Wanted To Know About Sangamon (and were unable to find out because you were out of town) by the Summer Faculty (as told to Mark Heyman), 1971Hoffman, George, paper on founding of SSUFolder 3214761982 (?)3Scope and ContentsCopy of Illinois Senate Bill No. 955 (first appropriation for SSU)Matsler, Franklin G., The Naming of Sangamon State UniversityFolder 42147719854Metzger, Walter P., Personnel Problems at SSUFolder 521478May 19775NCA Status StudyFolder 621479May 19726Scope and ContentsNCA Status Study, prepared by SSU faculty and administration for Commission on Institutions of Higher Education of North Central AssociationNCA Evaluation Team Report on SSUFolder 721480June 19787Newman Report on Higher Education, USOEFolder 821481March 19718OSPI (Office of Supt. of Public Instruction) ReportFolder 921482August 19719Program Review Task Force ReportFolder 1021483197310Progress Report on Academic Programs, SSUFolder 1121484September 197011Report on New Senior Institutions, IBHEFolder 1221485February 196812Box 4Box 421455Robinson, Sarah Anne, Proposed Model for SSUFolder 121486 January 19701Robinson, Sarah Anne, Proposed Model for A Utopian UniversityFolder 221487April 19702Robinson, Sarah Anne, Reform Within a University DepartmentFolder 32148819693Scope and ContentsReform Within a University Department, or What to do while Waiting for the RevolutionSangamon State University's MandateFolder 42148919714Southeast Sector Development Concept -- brochure/mapFolder 521490September 19705Springfield Southeast Sector Development StudyFolder 621491May 19756Scope and ContentsHarland Bartholomew &amp; AssociatesSSU Self-Study Report to NCA, Springfield Committee on Higher Education ReportsFolder 72149219657University in Process, SSU Self-Study Report to NCAFolder 8214938Box 5Box 521456Master Plan for Higher Education Phase IIIFolder 121494June 19691Scope and ContentsCommittee B-Admission and Retention of Students; Committee Q-Teacher Preparation; 	Committee R-Graduate Education; Committee S-Social Work Education; Committee T-Public Administration; Committee U-Legal EducationHouse Bill to Reorganize Higher EducationFolder 2214951995-02-022Governor's Task Force on Higher education, Report on GovernanceFolder 3214961992-06-153Governor's Task Force on Higher Education, Final ReportFolder 421497January 19934Scope and ContentsOffice of Lieutenant Governor (missing)Senate Bill No. 987, Merger of UofI and SSUFolder 5214981993-04-055Scope and ContentsSenate Bill No. 987, 88th General Assembly. Merger of the University of Illinois and Sangamon State University. (2 copies)Proposal for the Establishment by the University of Illinois of a New Institution of Higher Education in SpringfieldFolder 62149910/676Soil Test Report, Lake View FarmFolder 7215001955-11-127Basic Management Report, Lake View Form, A.H. LubinFolder 8215011945-10-198Soil Test Report, W.H. Franklin FarmFolder 9215021955-11-129

