<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>C.01.06/01Archon Finding Aid Title C.01.06/01UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:42:34 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    C1/6/1. University Week, "School &amp; Community Day" Fall 1970
    C.01.06/01
    153
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    Date acquired: 03/27/1973
    1
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Papers of the School and Community Day program held as the Fall 1970 University Week on December 17, 1970.  Includes schedule of events, press releases and tapes of speakers including Dr. Warren Stradberg, Dr. Robert Brissenden and Dr. Michael J. Bakalis.  Also included on tape are the panel discussions between SSU students and community participants.
HISTORICAL NOTE:
There was no University Week on the SSU Calendar in 1970.  The "School and Community" Program scheduled a full day of talks and discussions.  This "School and Community" Day became unofficially the first University Week at SSU.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
RESTRICTED:  Do not use master audio or video tapes.  Make dubs for patrons.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
acquired piecemeal  
  
    Audio Tapes
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 162507Press Release and ProgramFolder 1625141Introduction-Children and Freedom; Introduction-The Teacher Development CenterAudiotape 162508Discussion, Introduction-Panel--Learning and the Younger ChildAudiotape 262509Introduction, Talk by Exec. Dir. of Teacher Certification BoardAudiotape 362510Introduction, Talk by Asst. Dean, New School for Behavioral Studies, UNDAudiotape 462511Scope and ContentsIntroduction, Panel--Learning in AdolescenceIntroduction, Panel--What Teachers Can Learn from StudentsAudiotape 562512Introduction-Education and Social Problems, Closing RemarksAudiotape 662513

