<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>C.01.06/02Archon Finding Aid Title C.01.06/02UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:42:37 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    C1/6/2. University Week, "Education &amp; Government" Winter 1970-1971
    C.01.06/02
    154
    
      0.67 Cubic Feet
    
    1970-1971
    Date acquired: 04/02/1973
    1
    2
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Papers and tapes of University Week Winter 1970-71 which features the theme of Education and Government: SSU studies itself in a Changing Society.  Discussion panels and speakers included Alan A. Drazek, Robert Lehnhausen, Father John Cortelyou, Alban Weber, J. David Jones, W. Joseph Gibbs, William Horsley, Wilbur Moulton, Richard Damashek, Roger Sweet, Stan Sokolik, Dr. Michael J. Baklis, Dr. Jmaes B. Holderman, and Springfield mayor Nelson Howarth.  Topics of speakers and discussions included campus disorders, federal aid to private education, Illinois personnel needs, governance (at SSU),  teaching and learning ar Sangamon State, and the Illinois Board of Higher Education.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological according to events  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
RESTRICTED:  Do not use master audio or video tapes.  Make dubs for patrons.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
acquired piecemeal  
  
    Audio Tapes
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 162492Working Papers (schedule, memos, letters, press releases)Folder 1624941Post-University Week Memos &amp; Texts of Some TalksFolder 2624952Legislative Panel, Campus Disturbances: How to Avoid Them?Audiotape 162496Seminar on Institutional Self-Study: The Problems of Teaching and Learning at SSUAudiotape 262497Scope and Contents2 reelsTown Meeting: "The Governance Process at SSUAudiotape 362498Talk: Government Aid to Private EducationAudiotape 462499Meeting of BHE--Testimony on Master Plan, Phase IIIAudiotape 562500Box 2Box 262493Talk: Supt of Public Instruction and Exec Dir of BHEAudiotape 162501Seminar on Institutional Self-Study: The Problems of Teaching and Learning at SSUAudiotape 262502Talk: Mayor of SpringfieldAudiotape 362503Panel Discussion: Ten Candidates for Springfield City CouncilAudiotape 462504Talk: Personnel Needs of the State of IllinoisAudiotape 562505Talk: Personnel Needs of the Department of Local Govt ServicesAudiotape 662506

