<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>C.01.06/03Archon Finding Aid Title C.01.06/03UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:42:41 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    C1/6/3. University Week, "The Year 2001" Spring 1971
    C.01.06/03
    155
    
      2.33 Cubic Feet
    
    Date acquired: 04/06/1973
    1
    2
    3
    4
    5
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Papers, programs, memorandums, reports, announcements, tapes (audio &amp; video), booklets, press releases of University Week- Spring 1971 which had the theme "The Year 2001: Sangamon State Probes the Future."  Includes papers of Universiyt Week Coordinating Committee, chaired by Cullom Davis.  The University week was also called Universiyt Days since it only covered Sunday May 23 through Wednesday May 26 1971.  Speakers and participants included: Rob Fishcer, Arthur C. Clarke, Brent Ashabranner, Dennis Little, Thomas Turner, Anthony Doens, Dr. Daniel Bloomfield, Dr. Lewis Kurke, Dr. William MCCLure, Colonel Matthew Parrish, Steven J. Ruma, Jacqueline Jackson, Denny Kelley, Clyde L. Chaote, John R. Pettifrod, John P. Clarke, James Henneberry, Dr. Richard Moy, Dan Bannister, Earl W. Henderson Jr., Nelson Howarth, Owen Anderson, John Noak, Ausitn Carley, Gus Stevens, Robert Jackson, Judy Everson, Robert C. Spencer and Frederick Ordway III.
Subjects and topics of talks include fururism, forecasting, utopias, science fiction, third world, medical care, Springfield in the yar 2001, volunteerism, Stapol (game), Delphi Project: SSU in the year  2001, urban life in the year 2001, population problems and policies in 2001, public education in 2001, family,  2001: A Space Oydessy, picture/phone, Mem-Brain I, and electric car.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological according to schedule of events  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
RESTRICTED:  Do not use master audio or video tapes.  Make dubs for patrons.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
acquired piecemeal  
  
    Accruals and Additions
Added Audio cassette (?): "The Year 2001: SSU Probes the Future" to box 2. Source unknown, this appears to be a copy of the original audio created for "SSU Archives." Chris Schnell, June 1, 2017.  
  
    Papers
    Audio Tapes
  
  Box 1Box 162400Working Papers (memos, printed program, press release, questionnaire)Folder 1624011Working Papers (memos, agendas, reports)Folder 2624022SSU Faculty Panel discussing University Week on WICS (incomplete)Videotape 162403Sampling of University Week events (30 minutes)Videotape 262404Sampling of University Week events (30 minutes)Videotape 362405Sampling of University Week events (30 minutes)Videotape 462406Sampling of University Week events (30 minutes)Videotape 562407Box 2Box 262408Audio--Brent Ashabrenner, Volunteerism in the Year 2001Audiotape 262410Audio--Dennis Little, Forecasting the FutureAudiotape 362411Audio--Thomas Turner, Playing the World GameAudiotape 462412Audio--Panel on public education, Alternative FuturesAudiotape 662414Audio--Panel, The Future of the FamilyAudiotape 762415Audio--Anthony Downs, Urban Life in the Year 2001Audiotape 862416Audio--Symposium on Health in 2001Audiotape 962417Scope and Contents2 reelsAudio--Steven J. Ruma, The Manager of Change: A Look Ahead to 2001Audiotape 1062418Audio--Jacqueline Jackson, The Endless Pavement: A Futuristic Children's BookAudiotape 1162419Audio--Sounds of the City, recorded at Art Fair in Old Capitol MallAudiotape 1262420Audio--John Noak, SSU in the Year 2001Audiotape 1862426Audio--Austin Carley &amp; Gus Stevens, The Third World in the Year 2001Audiotape 1962427Audio--Robert Jackson &amp; Judy Everson, Utopias &amp; Science Fiction as FuturismAudiotape 2062428Audio--Frederick Ordway III, audio for above videoAudiotape 2362431Video--Arthur C. Clarke, Life in the Year 2001Videotape 162409Scope and Contents2 1-hour tapesVideo--Brent Ashabrenner, Population Problems and Policies in 2001Videotape 562413Scope and Contents2 1-hour tapesVideo--Interview w/Denny Kelley, Clyde Choate, John PettifordVideotape 1362421Video--Interview w/John Clarke, Rev. Farries MorrisonVideotape 1462422Video--Interview w/James Henneberry, Mrs. William Gingold, Dr. Richard Moy, Dan BannisterVideotape 1562423Video--Interview w/Earl Henderson Jr., Hon. Nelson Howarth, Owen AndersonVideotape 1662424Scope and ContentsAlso on this tape--five interviews with bystandersVideo--Excerpts from above interviews edited to coherent 30 minutesVideotape 1762425Video--SSU Pres. Spencer, Time Capsule CeremonyVideotape 2162429Video--Frederick Ordway III, The Background and Making of '2001: A Space Odyssey'Videotape 2262430Scope and ContentsNO AUDIOVideo--University Week sampling, including excerpt of Ordway on the making of 2001 &amp; interviewees' reactions to Ordway 's workVideotape 2462432SSU Reports: "The Year 2001: SSU Probes the Future"Audiotape ?81913May 23, 1971Box 3Box 362433FoldersFolder 1624341Planning--memos, minutes, draftsFolder 2624352Monitors' Reports on eventsFolder 3624363Program Information SheetsFolder 4624374ExhibitsFolder 5624385Physical PlanningFolder 6624396Publicity, UniversityFolder 7624407Publicity, UniversityFolder 8624418PrintingFolder 9624429Press ClippingsFolder 106244310SSU press releasesFolder 116244411Radio and newspaper coverageFolder 126244512Paid advertisementsFolder 136244613Letters of thanksFolder 146244714Releases for speakersFolder 156244815STAPOLFolder 166244916Mem-BrainFolder 176245017Education in the Year 2001Folder 186245118Food and refreshmentsFolder 196245219Box 4Box 462453Working Papers on Guest SpeakersFolder 1624541Anthony Downs, Urban Life in 2001Folder 2624552Exhibit, Springfield in 2001Folder 3624563Thomas Turner, World Resources InventoryFolder 4624574Frederick Ordway, The Making of 2001: A Space OdysseyFolder 56245852001: A Space OdysseyFolder 6624596Exhibit--PicturephoneFolder 7624607Kenneth Organski, Problems of Democracy in the FutureFolder 8624618Dennis Little, Forecasting the FutureFolder 9624629Time Capsule Ceremony (w/microfilm of Cullom Davis's students' essays on alternative futures)Folder 106246310Steven J. Ruma, Manager of ChangeFolder 116246411Jacqueline Jackson, The Endless PavementFolder 126246512The Third World in the Year 2001Folder 136246613Delphi Project--SSU in the Year 2001Folder 146246714Brent Ashabrenner--Population ProblemsFolder 156246815Symposium on Mental and Physical Health in 2001Folder 166246916Exhibit--Electric CarFolder 176247017Utopias and Science FictionFolder 186247118Expenditures (invoices, letters, contracts)Folder 196247219Arthur C. Clarke, writer of 2001 . . .Folder 206247320University Week ReportFolder 216247421Scope and ContentsPlanning Committee to SSU Pres. SpencerTime CapsuleBox 562475May 26, 1971Scope and ContentsDeposited at Marine Bank, Opened June 11, 2001Letter of DepositFolder 1624761Trust AgreementFolder 2624772Program from University Week, The Year 2001Folder 362478May 24-26, 19713Contents list of CapsuleFolder 4624794Photograph placing information into the Time CapsuleFolder 5624805Scope and ContentsBlack and white photograph of Robert C. Spencer, Donald R. Patton, Robert J. Saner and George C. Hoffman placing information into the Time CapsuleHandwritten note from Donald R. Patton regarding the photographFolder 6624816Copy of: Delphi Project: SSU in the Year 2001Folder 7624827The Sangamon Gazette, Vol. 1 No. 12Folder 862483May 19, 19718Focus, No. 8Folder 962484May 11, 19719Memo to the Academic Vice President from Robert C. SpencerFolder 1062485December 197010Scope and ContentsSubject: Considerations in appointing new facultyMemo to the President of Sangamon State University in 2001 from Robert C. Spencer, President 1971Folder 116248611Scope and ContentsSubject: What we did during the first year of Sangamon StateInformation packet sent to prospective faculty membersFolder 1262487197112Scope and Contentsa. 1970 - 1971 Guide to Sangamon State University
b. Brochure - Robert C. Spencer's speech to the Committee on Higher Education for Central Illinois, 1969
c. Brochure - The Applied Study Quarter at Sangamon State University
d. Brochure - Facts about Sangamon State UniversityTape recording of University Planning Symposium, Delphi Project : Sangamon State in the Year 2001Folder 136248813The Year 2000 - A collection of student essaysFolder 146248914Scope and ContentsOn Alternative Futures for the 21st Century, MicroficheManila folder containingFolder 156249015Scope and Contentsa. Photo copy of memo concerning the appointing of new faculty
b. Agenda for Board of Regents meeting, May 20, 1971
c. Memo to participants in SSU Governance Weekend, May 8-9, 1970
d. Memo to participants in SSU Governance Weekend, May 8-9, 1970 - Plan of Governance
e. Memo to participants in SSU Governance Weekend, May 8-9, 1970 - Draft of a constitution for SSU
f. President's report to board of regents, May 20, 1971
g. Memo to Steering Committee on Academic Planning (SCAP) from Robert Spencer
h. Remarks to the University Assembly, January 7, 1971
i. Remarks to the Board of Regents concerning the emphasis on Public Affairs at SSU from Dekalb, March 18, 1971
j. Memo to Members of Board of Regents, fellow Regency Presidents and Dr. Matsler, February 18, 1971
k. Newsletter from Robert Spencer to Members of the Board of Regents, the Regent's Staff, and Associates at Northern and Illinois State Universities - January 14, 1970
l. Memo to Board of Regents, fellow Presidents, and Dr. Matsler from Robert C. Spencer, March 15, 1971
m. Remarks of President Robert C. Spencer, SSU MP III Hearing, March 16, 1971
n. Brochure - Applied Study Quarter at SSU
o. Brochure - Robert Spencer's speech to the Committee on Higher Education for Central Illinois
p. 1970-71 Guide to Sangamon State UniversityPrograms from Time Capsule opening CeremonyFolder 1662491June 11, 200116

