<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>C.01.06/05Archon Finding Aid Title C.01.06/05UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:42:49 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    C1/6/5. University Week, "The Environmental Crisis" Spring 1972
    C.01.06/05
    157
    
      0.40 Cubic Feet
    
    1972
    Date acquired: 04/18/1973
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Papers, correspondence, letters, memoranda, pamphlets and audio tapes of University Week- Spring 1972 which was held May 8-12, 1972 and had the theme "The Environmental Crisis: What can be Done?"  Includes papers, planning documents, letters, timetables, and other records of  Edward Hawes, Coordinator of the University Week.  Speakers and participants included: Bob Fried, Hugh Iltis, Diane Korling, John Schwegman, Theodore Voneida, Griscom Morgan, John Nowlan, John Kleine, Van Rensselear Potter, Roberto Excolar, Robert L. Clayton, A.J. Rogers, Janet Malone, Dr. Yvonne Brackville, Lea Botts, Rutherford Pitt, Saul Alinsky, John Kramer, and Marilyn Domer among others.  Topics of talks and discussions centered on ecology, conservation of natural resources, environmental policy, strip mining, the environmental crisis in urban Aerica, politics land use and pollution, and other environmentally-related topics.  See Box list or schedule of events for more comprehensive listing.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological according to schedule of events  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
RESTRICTED:  Do not use master audio or video tapes.  Make dubs for patrons.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
acquired piecemeal  
  
    Audio CDs
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 162364Planning PapersFolder 1623851CorrespondenceFolder 2623862Coordinator's Report w/ Evaluation &amp; RecommendationsFolder 3623873Bob Fried w/spokesmen from industry &amp; government, Is the Energy Crisis Real?Audiotape 162365Hugh Iltis, Growth, Adaptation and Extension--Ecological Implications of Political 	StupidityAudiotape 262366Scope and Contents2 cassettesDiane Korling w/John Schwegman, Destruction and Rebirth:  Prairies and Woodlands in 	IllinoisAudiotape 362367Scope and Contents2 cassettesTheodore Voneida w/student organizers from Ohio, Southern Ohio: Strip MiningAudiotape 462369Griscom Morgan, The Human Scale of SchoolsAudiotape 562368Scope and Contents2 cassettesRep. John Nowlan w/John Kleine, The Politics of Pollution Control Legislation: Administrative and Legal AspectsAudiotape 662370Griscom Morgan, American Indians and a Natural EcologyAudiotape 762371Scope and Contents2 cassettesVan Rensselaer Potter, Bioethics and TechnologyAudiotape 862372Van Rensselaer Potter, Bioethics and Individual CompetenceAudiotape 962373Robarto Escolar, Environment and the University: The Chilean CaseAudiotape 1062374Griscom Morgan, Resistence [sic], Community and the Environmental CrisisAudiotape 1162375Robert L. Clayton, Black America and the Environmental CrisisAudiotape 1262376Robarto Escolar, Environment in Chile: A Marxist ExperimentAudiotape 1362377A. J. Rogers, Robert Clayton &amp; Janet Malone, Economic Development, Population and the CrisisAudiotape 1462378Yvonne Brackville w/Janet Malone, Women and the Environmental Crisis: A Radical ApproachAudiotape 1562379Scope and Contents2 cassettesA. J. Rogers, Is Urban Society and Endangered Environment?  A Liberal's Approach to Environmental EconomicsAudiotape 1662380Scope and Contents2 cassettesLea Botts, Rutherford Platt, Sol Alinsky et al, Politics, Land Use and PollutionAudiotape 1762381Scope and Contents2 cassettesSol Alinsky, Environmental Crisis in Urban America--What Can Be DoneAudiotape 1862382Scope and Contents2 cassettesJohn Kramer, Marilyn Domer et al, Grassroots Ecology Actions and Their Philosophical BasesAudiotape 1962383Scope and Contents2 cassettesDick Hill, Music for The Tree House EnvironmentAudiotape 2062384

