<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>C.01.06/06Archon Finding Aid Title C.01.06/06UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:42:51 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    C1/6/6. University Week, "Careers" Fall 1972
    C.01.06/06
    158
    
      1.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1972
    Date acquired: 04/23/1973
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Papers and tapes of University Week- Fall 1972 including proposals, draft plans, programs, posters, announcments memoranda to community and faculty, and tapes of speakers and discussions. Planned by the University Week committee chaired by G. Ernst Giesecke, the University week covered the theme "careers  in the 70's and 80's and spanned a period of six weeks; each week having a central theme or topic.
Speakers and particpants included Ivar Berg, Judy Everson, Daryl Hohweiler, Robert Reid, Harold L. Hodgkinson, Robert L. Appel Jr., Cullom Davis, James B. Holderman, Sister Mary Patrick O'Brien, Robert L. Poorman, James Rosser, Robert C. Spencer, John F. Grede, Sherwood Dees, Mark Erenburg, Joyce Griffin, John H. Keiser, Douglas Kindschi, John Swalec, Wayne Obannon, and Ruth Shinn.  Topics and subjects of speakers included work, higher education, careers, employment-Illinois, and discrimination in employment.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological according to schedule of events  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
RESTRICTED:  Do not use master audio or video tapes.  Make dubs for the patron.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
acquired piecemeal  
  
    Audio Tapes
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 162363Planning Documents &amp; Working PapersFolder 1623221Planning Documents, Working Papers &amp; CorrespondenceFolder 2623232BudgetFolder 3623243Career Resource MaterialsFolder 4623254Minutes and Notes of MeetingsFolder 5623265Media and Room Bookings for MeetingsFolder 6623276Planning and SchedulingFolder 7623287Dr. Ivar BergFolder 8623298Dr. Stuart TaylorFolder 9623309Higher Education and the World of WorkFolder 106233110Harold L. HodgkinsonFolder 116233211Robert L. Appel, Jr. and PanelFolder 126233312Dr. James M. RosserFolder 136233413Planning Documents &amp; Working Papers, Week IIIFolder 146233514Dr. John F. Grede &amp; PanelFolder 156233615William O'BannonFolder 166233716Career Opportunities for All, Week VFolder 176233817Planning and Developing Your Career, Week VIFolder 186233918Ruth Shinn, Speaker, Week VIFolder 196234019USOE, Marie Martin, Career Education Reports &amp; ProposalsFolder 206234120Agenda &amp; Schedule, First DraftFolder 216234221Agenda &amp; Schedule, Second DraftFolder 226234322Agenda &amp; Schedule, Third DraftFolder 236234423Agenda &amp; Schedule, Fourth DraftFolder 246234524Agenda &amp; Schedule, Fifth DraftFolder 256234625Concept &amp; Format Letter to FacultyFolder 2662347August 197226CalendarsFolder 276234827Courses Bearing on CareersFolder 2862349Fall 197228Cover Letter for Fall CoursesFolder 2962350July 197229Guide to CareersFolder 306235130Possible ContributorsFolder 316235231Materials Handed Out--Originals, Copies &amp; Distribution RecordsFolder 326235332BibliographyFolder 336235433Transcripts (folder 1 of 2)Folder 346235534Transcripts (folder 2 of 2)Folder 356235635var Berg w/Panel, Work and Values in a Changing SocietyAudiotape 162357Scope and Contentsmaster--2 cassettes; dub--2 cassettesHarold Hodgkinson, Higher Education and Horatio Alger: The End of an EraAudiotape 262358Scope and Contentsmaster--2 60-min videos; dub--2 audio cassettesPanel of SSU Faculty, Higher Education and the World of WorkAudiotape 362359Scope and Contentsmaster--1 cassette; dub--1 cassetteJohn F. Grede w/Panel, Career Education in Higher EducationAudiotape 462360Scope and Contentsmaster--1 reel; dub--1 	cassetteWm Tom O'Bannon, Employment Trends in Illinois in the National PerspectiveAudiotape 562361Scope and Contentsmaster--1 cassette; dub--1 cassetteRuth Shinn, Breaking Patterns of Discrimination in EmploymentAudiotape 662362Scope and Contentsmaster--2 cassettes; dub--2 cassettes

