<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>C.01.06/07Archon Finding Aid Title C.01.06/07UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:42:54 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    C1/6/7. University Week, "Quo Vadis?" Winter 1972-1973
    C.01.06/07
    159
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1972-1973
    Date acquired: 04/23/1973
    1
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Papers and tapes of the University Week- Winter 1972-73 including programs, schedules of events, biographies of speakers, announcements, flyers, posters, etc.  Coordinated by Hugh Barlow, the University  week carried the theme "Quo Vadis? The Search for Identity, Liberation and Justice"  spanned two weeks, January 28 through February 9, 1973.  Speakers and participants included Orrin Klapp, Norman Denzin, Rabbi Jon Konheim, Rev. Richard Ahlgrim, Rev. James Fry, Msgr, Irvin Will,  Conald Foust, Ralph Smith, Florenz Criley, Karl Flipper, Cheter Ruiz, Madeline Golde, Family of Women Band, Edward Green, John Miller, Richard Quinney, and apoetry reading entitled "Brainchild".  Topics and areas of discussion included identity, idnetity in religion, identity in children and jusitce.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological according to schedule of events  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
RESTRICTED: Do not use master audio or video tapes.  Make dubs for patrons.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
acquired piecemeal  
  
    Audio Tapes
    Papers
    Videotapes
  
  Box 1Box 162310Announcement, Printed Program, PosterFolder 1623111Orrin Klapp, Collective Search for Identity in Modern Society"Audiotape 162312Norman Denzin, Identity Crisis in ChildrenAudiotape 262313Panel of clergy, Changes in Identity of Organized ReligionAudiotape 362314Ralph Smith, Mystification of the Law and Suppression of MinoritiesAudiotape 462315Panel, Blacks, Women, Chicanos and the Labor MovementAudiotape 562316Family of Woman (All Female Rock Band), Music and DiscussionAudiotape 662317Women of SSU, Poetry ReadingsAudiotape 762318Edward Green, Justice for Ethnic Minorities: Confrontations with Law and OrderAudiotape 862319Richard Quinney, Theory and Practice in the American State--An Analysis of Current Public PolicyAudiotape 962320John Miller w/staff &amp; inmates from Marion, Workshop on Transactional Analysis and "The Game"Videotape 162321

