<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>C.02.02/12 Series IArchon Finding Aid Title C.02.02/12 Series IUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:44:23 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    C2/2/12. Faculty Senate, Personnel Policies Committee Records 1965-1980  Series I
    
      Faculty Senate
    
    C.02.02/12 Series I
    179
    
      0.66 Cubic Feet
    
    1965-1980
    Date acquired: 05/14/1990
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Faculty Senate Personnel Committee papers, memoranda, letters, various reports and articles pertaining to the following topics: personnel policies, tenure process,  policies appeals and due process; recruitment policies and nepotism policies.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Assembly Office  
  
    Records
  
  Box 1Box 161986Faculty Committee File InformationFolder 1619881956-19801Scope and ContentsFaculty Senate Personnel Policy Committee FilesFaculty Senate Personnel Policy CommitteeFolder 26198919802Faculty Senate Committee on Personnel Policies: Tenure ProcessFolder 3619903Faculty Personnel Policies - Sangamon State University Division of Academic AffairsFolder 461991Fall 19794Personnel Policy CommitteeFolder 5619921978-795Procedures, Policies and Practices for Personnel in Academic AffairsFolder 661993January 1, 19736Scope and ContentsOffice of the Vice President and Provost, EdwardsvilleFaculty Senate Personnel Policy CommitteeFolder 761994February-September 19797Faculty Senate Personnel Policy CommitteeFolder 861995October-December 19798Box 2Box 261987Faculty Senate Personnel Policy CommitteeFolder 16199619781Faculty Senate Personnel Policy CommitteeFolder 26199719782Scope and Contents"Eric Clearinghouse on Higher Education College and University Faculty Handbook Collection, Nov. 1977
"Consultation on Personnel Problems at SSU" by David Fellman, Apr. 21, 1977
"Due Process for Faculty at SSU – Report on a Consultation" by Ray A. Howe, Apr. 25-26, 1977
"Personnel Problems at SSU – Report on a Consultation," by Walter P. Metzger, May 4-6, 1977Faculty Senate Personnel Policy CommitteeFolder 36199819783Scope and Contents"The Meaning of Academic Due Process"
"Hard Times, Values, and Academic Unions"
"Academic Freedom and Tenure in the Quest for National Security"
"Report on Retirement and Academic Freedom"
"Statement on Professors and Political Activity"
"Report of the Special Committee on Academic Personnel Ineligible for Tenure"
"Statement on Procedural Standards in the Renewal or Non-renewal of Faculty Appointments"
"Faculty Appointments and Family Relationships"
"The Two Decisions of the U.S. Supreme Court, June 29, 1972"

