<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.52.08/00Archon Finding Aid Title J.52.08/00Sandra LongenUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:44:25 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J52/8. Oral History Student Projects
    J.52.08/00
    1830
    
      0.83 Cubic Feet
    
    1993-2006
    1
    2
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Collection of oral history student projects, many of which were made during History professor Dr. Deb McGregor's Oral History Methods course.  Others were donated by UIS students, most with local history connections.  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Acquired from students taking the Oral History Methods course  
  Memoirs &amp; Permission slipsBox 177336Davis, Bobby L.Folder 1773384/11/20091Scope and ContentsJennifer Humphrey, interviewer, 27 pp., includes permission slipHarris, Kathryn M.Folder 27733920062Scope and ContentsJainean M. Smith, interviewer, 27 pp., includes permission slipHasara, KarenFolder 3773403/7/20113Scope and ContentsBrian Hendricks, interviewer, 30 pp., includes permission slipHearne, BetsyFolder 477341March 20124Scope and ContentsKathleen Brinkmann, interviewer, 57 pp., includes permission slipHelms, Elaine ThirlwallFolder 5773424/27/19935Scope and ContentsRochelle Morgan, interviewer, 31 pp., includes permission slipJohnson, David L.Folder 6773434/17/20126Scope and ContentsLisa R. Sweet, interviewer, not transcribed, permission slipKammin, WadeFolder 7773443/10/20127Scope and ContentsGail Rein, interviewer, 60 pp., includes permission slipLeeper, CorwinFolder 8773453/25/20098Scope and ContentsScott Johnson, interviewer, 24 pp., includes permission slipPodeschi Family - Richard, Rick and RJFolder 97734612/8/20049Scope and ContentsAmanda Landacre Podeschi, interviewer, 64 pp., appendices, includes permission slipSnodgrass, Gloria - South's GreenhouseFolder 10784583/21/201210Scope and ContentsMonica Kroft, interviewer, no transcription, includes permission slipVarious Law Enforcement PersonnelFolder 1177347June 200111Scope and ContentsDennis W. Bowman, interviewerInterviewed:Bratcher, Jerry, 9 pp.Cotter, James V., 11 pp.Daughtry, Sylvester, 5 pp.Diegelman, Robert F., 8 pp.Elrod, Richard J., 7 pp.Kitterman, Richard, 17 pp.Koby, Tom, 8 pp.Lesanky, Henry, 24 pp.Lunney, Robert F., 11 pp.Matthews, William, 13 pp.Murphy, Patrick, 13 pp.Rosenblatt, Dan, 18 pp.Sorrentino, Charles, 8 pp.Stephens, Darrel W., 10 pp.Steward, Robert, 8 pp.Wexler, Chuck, 7 pp.Williams, Gerald L., 7 pp.Williams, Hubert, 7 pp.no permissions slipsGarrett, RobertFolder 128206510/17/200412Scope and ContentsGarrett was an Air Force veteran in both the Korean and Vietnam wars. Interviewer: Sherry Benneman. Tape in box 2.Williams, WilliamFolder 138206910/16/200413Scope and ContentsWilliams was a U.S. Army veteran in the Korean War. Interviewer: Sherry Brenneman.Babitzke, Theresa A.Folder 14820779/9/201014Scope and ContentsBabitzke was a SSU gerontology student in 1982CDs and TapesBox 277337Harmony, Ben and CharlieItem 17734820061Scope and ContentsChris Reynolds, Interviewer5 CDs, includes Interview documentsHasara, KarenItem 27848020042Scope and ContentsBrian Hendricks, Interviewer
1 tapeHearne, Elizabeth "Betsy"Item 3784813/12/20123Scope and ContentsKathleen A. Brinkmann, interviewer
1 CDHorner, "Hap" HenryItem 47734920064Scope and ContentsJohn L. Garner, interviewer
2 CDs &amp; 1 tapeHouston, MikeItem 57735020065Scope and ContentsPam Springer, interviewer
1 CDJohnson, David L.Item 6773514/17/20126Scope and ContentsLisa R. Sweet, interviewer
2 tapesKammin, WadeItem 77848203/10/20127Scope and ContentsGail Rein, interviewer
2 CDsKitterman, G.Item 8773528Scope and ContentsGreg Smith, interviewer2 CDsPodeschi Family: Richard, "Rick" and "RJ"Item 9784839Scope and ContentsAmanda Landacre Podeschi, interviewer
4 CDsSchimm, BillItem 1077353200610Scope and ContentsLori Giordano, interviewer
1 CDSnodgrass, Gloria - South's GreenhouseItem 1178459201211Scope and ContentsMonica Kroft, interviewer
1 CDWade, James M.Item 1277354200612Scope and ContentsJamie Annell, interviewer
1 CD &amp; 1 tapeGarrett, RobertItem 138207310/17/200413Scope and ContentsInterviewer: Sherry Brenneman1 tape

