<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.52.04/00Archon Finding Aid Title J.52.04/00UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:08:23 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J52/4. Student Papers, Illinois House Contracts Compliance Committee, 1971-1972
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    J.52.04/00
    644
    
      0.49 Cubic Feet
    
    1971-1972
    Date acquired: 12/19/1978
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Records of the Illinois House Contracts Compliance Committee (1971-72) containing minutes, transcripts of hearings, copies of written testimony and research files.  
Witnesses include representatives of labor organizations and unions manufacturers, state government officials and fair employment practice agencies.  
Research files cover laws and guidelines for equal employment opportunity, minority employment, minority statistics, sex discrimination and labor employment at Lincoln Land Community College &amp; Sangamon State University.
The  House Contracts Compliance committee was created by the Illinois House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 373 of June 30, 1971.  
The  Committee was charged to "study compliance with and  enforcement of existing laws requiring non- discrimination in employment based on race, color, creed, national origin, sex or physically and mentally handicapped."  
The Committee held 11 public hearings and published it's final report in June 1972.  (Illinois Documents IL Y4.c76: 1/972).  
  
    Arrangement Note
Committee files, hearings (chronological), research files  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Horace Martin, SSU Graduate student  
  
    Reports
  
  Box 1Box 141320Committee Papers:Folder 1413221Scope and Contentsannouncements and schedules; minutes and agendas; press releases; summations of testimonyChicago HearingFolder 2413231972-02-152Scope and Contentswitness schedule; transcripts; statementsSpringfield HearingFolder 3413241972-02-233Scope and Contentswitness schedule; transcripts; statementsChicago HearingFolder 4413251972-04-064Scope and Contentsstatements; schedule of witnessesSpringfield HearingFolder 5413261972-04-045Scope and Contentstranscripts; statementsStaff Agencies HearingFolder 6413271972-04-286Scope and Contentsschedule of witnesses; testimony; statementsBox 2Box 241321LLCC/SSU EEO/AA complianceFolder 1413281Scope and Contentsminority employment in construction; minority statistics, HCC Committee questionnaire; sex discrimination guidelines

