<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.102/7Archon Finding Aid Title MC.102/7Johnson, ScottUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:44:34 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC102/7. Recycling Archives: Myra Nissen Collection
    MC.102/7
    1837
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1989-1997
    1991
    Date acquired: 06/04/2014
    MC102/7
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This collection contains a variety of resources and publications relating to recycling and waste management.  Documents primarily concern policy, technology, program implementation and management.  Most documents found in the collection pertain to California recycling programs.  The publications consists of guides, newsletters, booklets, books, policy papers, and programs.Myra Nissen worked at the North California Recycling Association from 1990 to 2004.  She received her Bachelor of Arts degree in Cultural Anthropology from the University of California and a Masters degree in Environmental Studies from Prescott College, Arizona.  She is currently a board member for the North American Society of Homeopaths (NASH).Dan Knapp and the Institute for Local Self Reliance are responsible for coordinating the collections of material related to recycling for donation to the UIS Archives.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Collection is filed by the company, organization, or program responsible for/or related to the material.  The files are arranged by year.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Nissen, Myra  
  Myra Nissen ThesisItem 27853219982Scope and ContentsThesis written by Myra Nissen for a Masters in Environmental Studies from Prescott College, Arizona in August of 1998.
The thesis is titled "Recycling: Selected History and Current Trends, with a Focus on California."Myra Nissen CollectionBox 1785081989-1998Garbage Solution: A Public Official's Guide to Recycling and Solid Waste Management TechnologiesFolder 17850919891Scope and ContentsGuide written by Marian R. Chertow of the National Resource Recovery Association/ The U.S. Conference of Mayors74 pages, paperback.Solid Waste: Issues and AnswersFolder 2785101989-19902Scope and ContentsNewsletter printed by Engineering and Environmental Consulting firm R.W. Beck and Associates.  Two copies: Special Issue No. 2 (1989), and newsletter from 1990James River Corporation bookletFolder 37851119903Scope and ContentsBooklet titled "Working To Protect The Environment We Share" printed by the James River Corporation, a manufacturer and converter of paper related products based in Richmond, VA.The Earthworks Group PublicationsFolder 4785121990-19914Scope and ContentsThree books published by The Earthworks Group: "15 Simple Things Californians Can Do To Recycle,""The Recycler's Handbook," and "Kid Heroes of the Environment."Gildea Resource Center: The Future of RecyclingFolder 57851319915Scope and ContentsPolicy Paper authored by Paul Relis and assisted by Karen Hurst and Judy Lehrer. Published by the Community Environmental Council, Inc.  44 Pages, paperback.Sun Microsystems Environmental Program DocumentsFolder 67851419916Scope and ContentsFiles includes press release for Sun Microsystems environmental program launch,"Illuminations" Vol. 6 no. 1, and "Conserve@Sun" advertising.Worldwatch Paper 101Folder 77851519917Scope and ContentsFile includes the January 1991 booklet titled "Discarding the Throwaway Society", and the October, 1991 booklet "Shaping Cities: The Environmental and Human Dimensions"  Booklets printed by the Worldwatch InstituteCalifornian's Against Waste Foundation publicationsFolder 87851619918Scope and ContentsFile consist of two copies of "Guide to Recylced Printing and Office Paper," and "Shopper's Guide to Recycled Products."Xerox Corp. Business Guide to Waste Reduction and RecyclingFolder 97851719929Scope and ContentsBook written by Abhay K. Bushan for the Xerox Corporation Environmental Leadership Program. 112 pages, paperback.  Printed by Xerox.Directory of Bay Hazardous Waste Management FirmsFolder 1078518199210Scope and ContentsDirectory printed by the Solid Waste Management Program of San Francisco.  Directory categorizes firms by material recycled.Los Angeles Integrated Solid Waste Management OfficeFolder 11785191992-199311Scope and ContentsFile contains three guides printed by the ISWMO. "A Resource Guide to Recycled Construction Products and Energy Efficiency," "Construction and Demolition Waste Recycling Guide," and "Wood You Recycle?"Hewlitt Packard and the Environment: Reduce, Reuse, Recycle, Buy RecycleFolder 1278520199312Scope and ContentsGuide printed by Hewlitt Packard for their Cupertino/ Santa Clara Site Operations.California Integrated Waste Management BoardFolder 13785211993-199713Scope and ContentsVarious reports, studies, draft material, meeting agendas, and loose papers relating to the California Integrated Waste Management Board.Northeast Recycling CouncilFolder 1478522199414Scope and ContentsReport "Value Added to Recyclable Materials in the NorthEast" prepared by Roy F. Weston for the Northeast Recycling Council, Council of State Governments. Brattleboro, VT.Department of Conservation, "Curbside Recycling, Cost, and Funding Study"Folder 1578523199415Scope and ContentsStudy created by the Department of Conservation of California regarding the costs and funding of curbside collection programs in California.National Recycling Coalition DocumentsFolder 16785241994-199716Scope and ContentsDocuments include: 2 NRC newsletters "The NRC Connection" from Sept. 1994 and Fall 1997, the NRC's 16th Annual Congress and Exposition Program Review (1997), and a NRC State of Recycling release (1994)40 CFR- Chapter 5: Council on Environmental QualityFolder 1778525199517Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of chapter 5 of the Public Information Regulations CFR Title 40- Protection of EnvironmentISLR Publication GuideFolder 1878526199618Scope and ContentsListing guide for publications from the Institute for Local Self- RelianceAlameda County Waste Management AuthorityFolder 19785271996-199719Scope and ContentsFile includes Alameda County Source Reduction and Recycling Plan Draft (1997), "Resourceful Purchasing" Manual (1996), and the Alameda County Waste Management Authority 1996-97 Annual Report10 Easy Ways to Buy RecycledFolder 2078528199720Scope and ContentsBook written by Joel Makower and published by the Department of Conservation. 104 pages, paperbackEcology Action, "Waste Assessment and Recommendations for Surgery Center"Folder 2178529199721Scope and ContentsReport of recommendations for Surgery Center by Ecology Action.NRDC: "Too Good to Throw Away"Folder 2278530199722Scope and ContentsReport by Allen Hershkowitz published by the Natural Resources Defense Council. 86 pages, paperback.U.S. Department of Commerce Advanced Technology Program Guide for Program IdeasFolder 2378531199823Scope and ContentsGuide printed by the United States Department of Commerce pertaining to the Advanced Technology PRogram. 13 pages, paperback.

