<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>E.01.01/00Archon Finding Aid Title E.01.01/00UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:45:20 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    E1/1/0. President's Office, General Records, 1969-1986
    
      President/Chancellor
    
    E.01.01/00
    185
    
      0.66 Cubic Feet
    
    1969-1986
    Date acquired: 05/31/1979
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Artificial file issued by the President's Office is arranged chronologically.  Typical forms and subjects include: correspondence, memoranda, reports (I.e. President's Report SSU, Long Range Development Plan) and various workshop materials.  
Newspaper clippings include: President Lacy's resignation (1984) and Hunt for Tenants for SSU cooperative complex (1984). The Bulk of the materials are from the early 1970's.  Official files or personal papers are kept in other collections in the Archives.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  
    Source of Acquisition
President/Chancellor  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Acquired Piecemeal; artifical record series for chronologal materials from the President
Received: 5/31/1979, 10/28/1974  
  Box 1Box 157221Folder 1572221969-19701Chronology of Academic Planning SSU ManuscriptItem 157223May 196911Scope and ContentsNotes &amp; questions that Spencer "was asking myself in May prior to my formal interview at O'Hare Airport" &amp; interview notes concerning position of President for SSU"Notes on the Initial Organization of SSU"Item 257224August 15, 196912Governance of the University; a draft statement &amp; proposal by Robert C. SpencerItem 357225October 24, 196913Scope and ContentsIncludes copy of draft "Organization of the 	University by Sarah Robinson, Oct. 3, 1969Measuring Progress: Rewards, Punishments, Freedoms, &amp; Standards in the Academic Community by Robert MarshItem 45722614Folder 2572271969-19702WorkshopItem 157228October 196921Scope and ContentsIncludes transcripts of tapes, Spencer's opening talk, sessions, questions &amp; answers; Spencer's notes; &amp; Sarah Robinson's notes on university as presented.  Oct. 24 &amp; 25, 1969Folder 357229November-December 19693Kick-off Luncheon for Million-dollar fund raising, Remarks of President Robert C. SpencerItem 157237November 12, 196931SSU Staff DirectoryItem 257238December 12, 196932SSU Staff DirectoryItem 357239December 24, 196933Newsletter to the Board of Regents from President SpencerItem 457240December 16, 196934Scope and ContentsComments on: 1) university land use &amp; area planning, 2) public advisory committee on program &amp; curriculum planning, 3) Personnel Office, 4) SSU Admissions Office on Washington Street, 5) comparative salary schedules, &amp; 6) recruitment of facultyMemo to all staff regarding Springfield Sun item that President Spencer is establishing a rowing club at SSUItem 557241January 9, 196935Folder 457230January - June 4, 19794Administrative Procedures, Memo #1-70 regarding PersonnelItem 157242January 12, 197041Scope and ContentsConcerning new positions, recruitment, appointment , &amp; planning for 	future positionsNewsletter to Board of Regents, #2Item 257243January 14, 197042Scope and ContentsRegarding: 1) reaction to Jan. 4, Regents meeting, 2) appointment information published in local 	newspaper, 3) SSU appointments in comparison with other Regency institutions, 4) The Commuting Student 5) space for library processing, 6) first SSU publication – general announcement &amp; flyerStaff Newsletter, #1Item 357244January 15, 197043Administrative Memo #2-70Item 457245January 28, 197044Scope and ContentsRemarking on use of "Dr." in 	titles, recommends use of "Mr."Staff Newsletter, #2Item 557246January 29, 197045Letter from Springfield Mayor, Nelson HowarthItem 657249January 30, 197046Scope and ContentsInviting recipients to attend a briefing on SSU plans by Robert Spencer, Feb. 5, 1970Copy of memo to President Spencer from Bob MacAlisterItem 757250February 3, 197047Scope and ContentsRegarding maintaining contact with parents of studentsAnnouncement by President Spencer authorizing Lincoln's Birthday as a holidayItem 857251February 11, 197048Staff Newsletter, #3Item 957252February 23, 197049Memorandum to George Cohen, entitled, Considerations in hiring new facultyItem 1057253February 24, 1970410Scope and ContentsPopularly known as the BLUE MEMOMemorandum to Academic Vice President, Considerations in Appointing New FacultyItem 1157254December 1970411Memo to all professional staff members regarding Coordination of Reports, Grant Applications, &amp; Requests for Data from External SourcesItem 1257255412Staff Newsletter, #4Item 1357256March 13, 1970413Memo to all Senior Staff regarding Control of Entertainment Expenses at SSUItem 1457257414Memo to George Cohen, The Academic Program Statement, and draft portions for catalogItem 1557258March 16, 1970415Memo to George Cohen regarding The Academic Program Statement, about retaining G. Ernest Giesecke on consulting basisItem 1657259March 30, 1970416Staff Newsletter, #5Item 1757260undated (probably 4-22-70)417Memo to All Staff regarding personnel policies relating to University Civil Service employeesItem 1857261April 2, 1970418Scope and Contentsand Sangamon State University Personnel Policies for University Civil Service EmployeesMemo to Cohen, Scheuerman, &amp; MacAlister, regarding purchasingItem 1957262April 2, 1970419Memo to Cohen, Scheuerman, &amp; MacAlister, regarding travelItem 2057263April 2, 1970420Memo to Cohen, Scheuerman, &amp; MacAlister, regarding consultant servicesItem 2157264April 3, 1970421Memo to planning task forceItem 2257265April 13, 1970422Scope and ContentsRegarding guidelines for the completion of the writing program statements which includes: Time table, the Announcements, development Programs &amp; Courses, &amp; commentary notesMemo to All Administrative OfficersItem 2357266April 15, 1970423Scope and ContentsRegarding Committees &amp; Task Forces of the Board of Higher Education &amp; the SSU 		representatives on the committeesMemo to Staff concerning: Rate changes - Blue Cross-Blue Shield Health InsuranceItem 2457267April 23, 1970424Staff Newsletter, #6Item 2557268May 7, 1970425Memorandum #1 to participants in SSU Governance WeekendItem 2657269May 8-9, 1970426Scope and ContentsRegarding, Some Thought Questions Concerning the Nature of University GovernanceMemorandum #2 to participants in SSU Governance WeekendItem 2757270May 8-9, 1970427Scope and ContentsRegarding, Assumptions Concerning the Proposed Plan of Governance for 			Sangamon State UniversityMemorandum #3 to participants in SSU Governance WeekendItem 2857271May 8-9, 1970428Scope and ContentsRegarding, A Draft Document of a Constitution for SSUNewsletter to the Board of RegentsItem 2957272May 12, 1970429Scope and ContentsConcerning: 1) progress on interim campus facilities, 2) the Governance Weekend, 3) the state of admissions, 4) a faculty conclave in June, &amp; 5) the status of faculty recruitmentMemo to the Administrative CouncilItem 3057273May 19, 1970430Scope and ContentsConcerning, Travel Expenses: Candidates, Consultants, New Staff, &amp; Invited ConfereesRobert C. Spencer's Travel PlansItem 3157274May 22-June 4, 1970431Manuscript &amp; memorandum with notes in Spencer's handwriting to be sent to all members of the "Draft Committee on University Governance"Item 3257275May 27, 1970432Scope and ContentsRegarding the drafting of the Interim Governance DocumentSpeech given to the Springfield High School Graduating Class of 1970Item 3357276June 4, 1970433Scope and ContentsThe Committee For Higher Education In Central IllinoisFolder 557231June-December, 19705Memo to All Staff Members, regarding Groundbreaking CeremoniesItem 157277June 8, 197051Memo &amp; Attached Pay Plan to All Staff MembersItem 257278June 15, 197052Scope and ContentsRegarding University Pay Plan Relating to Civil Service EmployeesStaff Newsletter #7Item 357279June 18, 197053SSU Prospective Student SurveyItem 457280July 1, 197054Scope and ContentsMemo to All Staff, July 8, 1970, stating that George Cohen is no longer with the administration, &amp; announcing appointment of Cullom Davis as interim Vice President for Academic Affairs.SSU Guide To Academic ProgramsItem 557281July 22, 197055Memo to All Staff, regarding Motor PoolItem 657282July 27, 197056Memo announcing the appointment of the Interim Student Financial Aid Advisory CommitteeItem 757283August 4, 197057Memorandum announcing the appointment of:Item 857284 August 14, 197058Scope and Contents1) the Committee on Curriculum, 2) the Faculty Recruitment Committee, 3) the Faculty-Student Advisory Committee to the Board of Regents, 4) the President's Advisory Committee, 5) the Administrative Council, 6) the Professional Standards Committee, 7) the Applied Study Committee, 8) the Planning Committee for the Opening of the UniversityMemo to All Faculty &amp; Professional Staff regarding "Case Studies in A AdministrationItem 957285September 9, 197059Newsletter to the Board of RegentsItem 1057286September 14, 1970510Scope and ContentsOn the "Eve of the Opening of Sangamon State University" announcing the timetable, the progress on the physical facilities &amp; announced plan of functions to celebrate the occasion.  Remarks of James B. Holderman, Executive Director of the Illinois Board of Higher Education to the faculty of SSULetter from Mrs. Spencer, Mother of Robert C. Spencer, congratulations on opening the universityItem 1157287511Letter from Mayor Nelson Howarth of appreciationItem 1257288512Copy of letter from Dean Bill Ferrante proffering good wishes for SSUItem 1357289September 17, 1970513Letter to Students explaining the changes &amp; delays caused by wet weather in planned activitiesItem 1457290514Remarks of Robert Spencer to First Convocation of Faculty, Students &amp; FamiliesItem 1557291September 20, 1970515Staff Newsletter #8Item 1657292September 22, 1970516Memo to all Faculty &amp; Staff, regarding Committee NItem 1757293September 22, 1970517Memo to all Faculty, Staff, &amp; StudentsItem 1857294September 24, 1970518Scope and ContentsRegarding "Regents' Action on the Interim Governance Document, Changes in Committees, &amp; Other MattersMemo to all Faculty &amp; StaffItem 1957295October 14, 1970519Scope and ContentsRegarding The Meeting of the Board of Regents in Springfield, Oct. 15Faculty/Staff Campus Newsletter, Vol. 1, No. 1Item 2057296October 14, 1970520Scope and ContentsFrom the Office of the President, concerning the Nepotism Committee, the Bookstore Committee, Faculty Meeting on Academic &amp; Physical Planning, &amp; Official Enrollment for Fall Quarter 1970An Outline of Planning Tasks Ahead for SSUItem 2157297October 16, 1970521Faculty/Staff Campus Newsletter, Vol. 1, No. 2Item 2257298October 16, 1970522Scope and ContentsConcerning the Organization of SSU, the Interim Committee on Public Safety, the Interim Council on Student Services, &amp; University CalendarFaculty/Staff Campus Newsletter, Vol. 1, No. 3Item 2357299October 29, 1970523Scope and ContentsConcerning: 1) statement on nepotism, 2) outline of planning tasks ahead for SSU, 3) the Professional Standards Committee, 4) the Interim Student Handbook, 5) the University Bookstore, &amp; Public SafetyMemo concerning the Thanksgiving WeekendItem 2457300November 5, 1970524Memo to the University Assembly concerning Public Appointments to the AssemblyItem 2557301November 9, 1970525Scope and ContentsThe process, &amp; brief biographies of the recommended personsFaculty/Staff Campus Newsletter, Vol. 1, No. 4Item 2657302November 10, 1970526Scope and ContentsConcerning the results of the University Assembly election, the public membership of the Assembly, the Interim Committee on Public Safety, &amp; summarized minutes of the Oct. 28th meeting of the Professional Standards CommitteeLetter to members of the University Assembly inviting them to an informal gathering to meet on Nov. 18, 1970Item 2757303November 11, 1970527Memo to Chairmen of Interim CommitteesItem 2857304November 30, 1970528Scope and ContentsConcerning progress reports, deadlines, &amp; the transition to the University Assembly CommitteesMemo to All Senior Staff: Announcement of the Open House for the General PublicItem 2957305November 30, 1970529Memo from Robert Spencer to the Board of RegentsItem 3057306December 14, 1970530Scope and ContentsConcerning the Hoffman response regarding salary payment for George Cohen, the 	Academic Calendar, 1972-1973, Administrative Memo #3 regarding purchasing policy &amp; procedures, &amp; information on the success of the SSU Open HouseMemo to faculty &amp; members of the AssemblyItem 3157307December 22, 1970531Scope and ContentsRegarding the 	President's charge to the Steering Committee on Academic planning; includes charge on goldenrod memo dated Dec. 15, 1970Memo regarding HolidaysItem 3257308December 16, 1970532Memo to the Faculty &amp; Members of the University Assembly, on The Planning Tasks Ahead for SSUItem 3357309December 22, 1970533Memo to the Academic Vice President from President Spencer entitled, Considerations in Appointing New FacultyItem 3457310December 1970534Scope and ContentsRevision of the 2-24-70 document, commonly called the BLUE MEMO1970: Interim Governance Document - DraftFolder 65723261970: Guide to Academic Programs - DraftFolder 7572337Folder 85723419708Letter to Board of Regent Members with enclosed three sections of the long-range development plan for SSU:Item 157311June 197081Scope and Contents1) Long Range Development Plan - I.  Academic Plan for SSU - Original Draft in Process of Revision; II. Projected Enrollment at SSU - Original Draft in Process of Revision; III.  Long Range Building Program at SSU- Original Draft in Process1971:  Academic Graduation StandardsFolder 9572359Folder 10572361971 - 197210Remarks to the University Assembly (First State of the University Address)Item 157312January 7, 1971101Faculty/Staff Newsletter, Vol. 1, #5Item 257313January 18, 1971102Scope and ContentsRegarding administrative changes, the President's Cabinet, &amp; leave of absence for Chris VlahoplusLetter to the Board of RegentsItem 357314January 21, 1971103Scope and ContentsDetailing the uproar on campus &amp; in the press over the appointment of SCAP &amp; Doug Kindschi as its head; includes Statement releases by SSU President Spencer to the press, Jan. 13, 1971; letter of response of the Assembly through Speaker Keiser to the Illinois Association for Higher Education, Jan. 21, 1971; Kindschi report from the Steering Committee for Academic Planning progress report, Jan. 12, 1970 (NOTE: should be 1971)Memo to All Staff regarding Travel RegulationsItem 457315January 28, 1971104Faculty/Staff Newsletter, Vol. 1, #6Item 557316February 12, 1971105Scope and ContentsConcerning the budgetary process for higher education in Illinois, especially Sangamon State University's request for FY 1971-1972; selected actions of the Board of Higher Education at its 2/2/71 meeting, the Vice Presidential Search for Academic Affairs.February Letter to the Board of RegentsItem 657317February 18, 1971106Scope and ContentsConcerning planning progress, the Vice Presidential search, community reaction to the SSU program, &amp; evaluation &amp; appointment of incumbent faculty including a report of "Interim Faculty Evaluation Procedures for Contract Renewal, 	Academic Year 1971-1972" as approved by the AssemblyMemo to All Faculty concerning the recommendations of the Faculty Evaluation &amp; Reappointment Committee for 1971-1972Item 757318March 1, 1971107Memo to Members of the Faculty concerning University WeekItem 857319March 11-19, 1971108Invitation for University WeekItem 957320March 5, 1971109Letter to the Board of RegentsItem 1057321March 15, 19711010Scope and ContentsConcerning campus news &amp; items for the March BOR meetingLetter to Robert Howard of the Sangamon County Historical SocietyItem 1157322March 16, 19711011Scope and ContentsConcerning possible renovation of the Shepherd or McClelland 	farmhouses into restored headquarters for the Historical SocietyRemarks to the Board of Regents concerning the emphasis on Public Affairs at SSU at DeKalbItem 1257323March 18, 19711012Memo to the University Community, concerning clarification of the Spring quarter calendarItem 1357324April 6, 19711013Memo to All Faculty &amp; Staff concerning the Academic Calendar adopted by the BOR for 1971-1972Item 1457325April 16, 19711014Announcement of Memorial Day as a holidayItem 1557326May 25, 19711015Memorandum to "The President of SSU in 2001" from SSU President Robert SpencerItem 1657327May 19711016Scope and ContentsConcerning "What we did during the first year of Sangamon State University", listing the contents of the time capsule deposited during University Week May 1971Letter to the Board of RegentsItem 1757328June 8, 19711017Scope and ContentsConcerning University relations with Senator G. William Horsley, fall enrollment projections, &amp; Keiser as new Vice President for Academic AffairsLetter to the Board of RegentsItem 1857329June 11, 19711018Scope and ContentsConcerning editorials in the local 			newspapers regarding Horsley/SSU relationsMemo to Roger Sweet, Speaker of the University Assembly, concerning President's response to Bills #46 &amp; 47Item 19573301019Newsletter to the Board of RegentsItem 2057331July 19, 19711020Scope and ContentsConcerning the Phase B 	Interim facility, the Special Committee to Select Architects for Phase II, &amp; Dean &amp; faculty recruitmentLetter to the Board of RegentsItem 2157332September 1, 19711021Scope and ContentsConcerning progress on Phase B Interim facilities, the perimeter road &amp; northeast parking lot, the facilities for the September meeting, &amp; the proposed amendments to the Interim Governance DocumentManuscript notes concerning the "Remarks of Robert C. Spencer at Regency staff 	hearings on SSU's FY73 operating budget requestItem 2257333September 19711022Scope and ContentsIncludes the pessimistic premise on SSU budgeting before the breakthrough in negotiations on Sept. 27, 1971; the draft of Budget Presentation Strategy Meeting Sept. 16, 1971, summaries of SSU operating budget requests &amp; rationale, revised request (Sept. 21, 1971) &amp; Board staff recommendations, Sept. 27, 1971Memo to All Faculty &amp; StaffItem 2357334October 1, 19711023Scope and ContentsConcerning the President's absence from campus Oct. 4-20, 1971Memo to Phil Bradley, Speaker of University Assembly concerning the President's comments on Assembly Bill #5Item 24573351024Scope and ContentsAnd a charge to the Faculty Retention CommitteeSangamon State University's MandateItem 2557336November 19711025Scope and ContentsExcerpts from: Board of Higher Education Documents, Statements by BHE Executive Director, Statements by Governor Richard Ogilvie, Statements by President Robert C. Spencer - Prepared by the Office of Academic PlanningState of the University AddressItem 2657337December 2, 19711026Letter to Mark Siebert, concerning academic recruitment &amp; 				requests of the Steering Committee of the United Faculty of SSUItem 2757338December 28, 19711027Letter to Vladimir T. BorovanskiItem 2857339January 18, 19721028Scope and ContentsConcerning the founding date for SSU; Spencer states that the public law for SSU was enacted in June 1969; its effective date was July 1, 1969; the first President was appointed on July 13, 1969, &amp; reported for work on Sept. 1, 1969, &amp; that SSU opened for students on Sept. 23, 1970Memo of Holiday Calendar for SSUItem 2957340January 21, 19721029Memo to Robert MacAlister, announcing changes in student employment wage &amp; salary administrationItem 3057341January 21, 19721030Announcement of Visit of Board of Regents Chairman, Dr. Barr to SSUItem 3157342February	17-18, 19721031Memo to the University AssemblyItem 3257343February 21, 19721032Scope and ContentsConcerning the appointment of 			the North Central Association Self-Study Committee for an accreditation 			report for May 1, 1972Memo to the Speaker of the University Assembly concerning the expansion of the President's CabinetItem 3357344April 25, 19721033Administrative Organization at Sangamon State UniversityItem 3457345May 19721034Scope and ContentsA retrospective essay prepared for the Status Report submitted to the North Central Association of Colleges &amp; Secondary SchoolsAnnouncement of the 4 1/2 % Salary Adjustment for Civil Service EmployeesItem 3557346August 14, 19721035Announcement of a Series of Dinners for New Faculty, Division Heads, Deans, Veteran Faculty, Senior Staff &amp; Respective SpousesItem 3657347August 24, 19721036Copy of never-issued memo, but distributed to President's CabinetItem 3757348Nov. 16, 19721037Scope and ContentsConcerning Office Duty Time &amp; release time for governanceMemo to Stan Sokolik, Speaker of the University Assembly, regarding University Assembly Bill #54Item 3857349December 7, 19721038October WorkshopFolder 22752419692Scope and ContentsIncludes transcripts of tapes, Spencer's opening talk, sessions, questions &amp; answers; Spencer's notes; &amp; Sarah Robinson's notes on university as presented. Oct. 24 &amp; 25, 1969.Chronology of Academic Planning SSU ManuscriptItem 1275261969-19791Scope and ContentsNotes &amp; questions that Spencer "was asking myself in May prior to my formal interview at O'Hare Airport" &amp; interview notes concerning position of President for S.S.U., May 1969.Box 2Box 2276501973Folder 1276511"Doing the Truth" by Robert SpencerItem 12765211Scope and ContentsTaken from Let The Entire Community Become Our University by Philip C. Ritterbush, editor;  explains the applied study program at SSULetter to students requesting their participation in the Student-to-Student grant programItem 2276531973-01-1612Letter to Faculty &amp; Staff concerning the budget cuts of the Governor made upon the education budget of the BOR &amp; BHEItem 3276541973-03-0813Letter of congratulations to Dr. Mudinger on being selected President of Illinois CollegeItem 4276551973-03-1314Letter to Thomas A. Roose concerning the student apartment project of the Roosevelt National DevelopmentItem 5276561973-03-2015Letter to Richard Hayes, Chairperson of the Illinois Association of Affirmative Action Officers concerning Edyth ColeItem 6276571974-04-0116Letter to Debie Murphy, Managing Editor of Vidette, Illinois State UniversityItem 7276581973-04-1517Memo concerning SSU acquisition of Vachel Lindsay HomeItem 8276591973-05-0418Letter to the Board of RegentsItem 9276601973-05-0819Scope and ContentsConcerning tenure decisions, a progress report on the President's house, &amp; a revised schedule for SSU's Academic Master PlanLetters concerning Tenure Decision CommitteeItem 10276611973-05-17110Scope and ContentsLetters to Geoffrey Cornog, Mary Yntema, Redge Ranyard, Norman Hinton, Chris Breiseth, David Everson, Mark Erenburg, informing them that the Tenure Decision Committee had recommended them for tenure, however, the Board of Regents at its May meeting had deferred action on the processMemo to the University Community, Status of University WomenItem 11276621973-05-25111Memo to Mary Jane MacDonald, concerning the availability of salary information in the University ArchivesItem 12276631973-05-29112Copy of a letter to Fred Crossland of the Ford FoundationItem 13276641973-06-02113Scope and ContentsConcerning SSU's request for a Ford Foundation Venture Fund &amp; the uses to which such grant would be put; includes copy reply from the Ford Foundation to the President advising him of the approval of the request, July 20, 1973Memo to All University Staff, concerning Civil Service Employee Participation in University Governance &amp; Service ActivitiesItem 14276651973-06-19114Memo to All Faculty &amp; Staff, concerning Staff Educational BenefitsItem 15276661973-06-19115Letter to Peter Sawers, Robert H. Hayes &amp; Associates, Inc.Item 16276671973-06-22116Memo and attached document concerning the annual report of Dr. Charles Brim regarding comparative Regency university salary schedules &amp; recommendationsItem 17276681973-06-17117Letter to William Moskoff concerning the use of University funds at the Sangamo Club for entertainment purposes because of its alleged sexist practicesItem 18276691973-07-18118Letter to John H. Brand, Vice President of Birkman &amp; Associates, Inc. concerning the Birkman Seminar held at SSUItem 19276701973-08-27119Memo to all civil service employees, concerning a 3% salary increase for civil serviceItem 20276711973-09-10120Letter to the BOR concerning the Housing Situation at SSUItem 21276721973-09-13121Letter to the Board of Regents &amp; Dr. Franklin Matsler, concerning University Governance Documents &amp; the upcoming referendum procedureItem 22276731973-09-17122Administrative Bulletin, Vol. 4, #1 concerning the Ford Venture FundItem 23276741973-09-17123Memo to Division Heads concerning Policy Implementation Relative to the Administration of Computer Resources at SSUItem 24276751973-09-21124Letter to Robert Barr of Sidley &amp; Austin, ChicagoItem 25276761973-09-27125Memo to Board of Regents concerning Governance at SSUItem 26276771973-10-17126Report to the President from the Advisory Committee on Audio/Visual EquipmentItem 27276781973-10-29127Memo to Faculty &amp; Staff on Energy ConservationItem 28276791973-11-09128Memo to Administrative &amp; Civil Service Staff ordering shut-down of the University for December 26-28, 1973Item 29276801973-12-131291974Folder 2276812Memo, concerning the University Assembly Research Study (governance study conducted by the Center for Research &amp; Development of Higher Education at UCLA-Berkeley)Item 1276821974-01-0321Letter to Ralph StoneItem 2276831974-02-1222Letter &amp; attached essay to the Subcommittee on Goals of the APT Committee concerning "Ends, Means, &amp; Administrators"Item 3276841974-02-1823Letter from the Springfield Area Neighborhood OrganizationItem 4276851974-02-1924Administrative Bulletin, Vol. 4, #9Item 5276861974-03-2825Scope and ContentsConcerning University Assembly Bill #4-1 relating to TenureSchedule, Starved Rock Seminar, "Liberal Arts &amp; Public Affairs"Item 627687April 4-6, 197426Scope and ContentsSchedule, Starved Rock Seminar, "Liberal Arts &amp; Public Affairs"Memo to the Executive Committee of the University Assembly regarding U.A. Bill #18 (1972) on affirmative actionItem 7276881974-04-1127Memo to Division Heads &amp; President's StaffItem 8276891974-04-2428Scope and ContentsConcerning Advice in re: Organizational, Management, &amp; Developmental Needs of SSUMemo to Robert Crowley, Speaker, Fourth University AssemblyItem 9276901974-04-2629Scope and ContentsConcerning Council on Academic Affairs' Discussion of a Bill Relating to Faculty TenureMemo concerning Organizational, Management &amp; Developmental Needs of SSUItem 10276911974-05-08210Memo to Robert Crowley, Speaker of the Assembly, concerning the President's veto of Assembly Bill #4-2Item 1127692211Scope and Contents"A Bill to Regulate the Structure &amp; Responsibilities of Personnel Committees: Program, Cluster, &amp; University"Memo to All Faculty concerning Spring 1974 Tenure RecommendationsItem 12276931974-05-08212Memo on "Chapter II" on Organizational Management &amp; Development Needs of SSUItem 13276941974-06-13213Scope and ContentsMemo to Division Heads, Deans, Program Chairmen, NCA Action Team, Speaker of the University Assembly, &amp; Others, concerning "Chapter II" on Organizational Management &amp; Development Needs of SSU  (See April 24, 1974 Memo on the same subject for Chapter I)."President's Report Sangamon State University Five Years of Growth and Accomplishment - 1970 - 1975"Item 14276951974-06-30214Notes on Implementation: #1 Proposed TimetableItem 15276961974-07-16215Scope and ContentsAdministrative Reorganization &amp; Governance Revision from the President's OfficeReorganization Paper: #1 The President's Office from the President's OfficeItem 16276971974-07-16216Scope and Contentsrevised July 18, 1974Notes on Implementation: #2: Positions in the President's Office from the President's OfficeItem 17276981974-07-17217Notes on Implementation: #3 Grants &amp; Contracts from the President's OfficeItem 18276991974-07-18218Title: Assistant to the President of SSUItem 19277001974-07-22219Scope and ContentsThis supersedes job description dated July 17, 1974Memo concerning "University in Process"Item 2027701220Scope and Contentsto Members of the Board of Regents, Presidents Nelson &amp; Budig, &amp; Franklin G. Matsler concerning "University in Process", the Self-Study Report of  Sangamon State University for the North Central Association of Colleges &amp; Secondary Schools, and the report, "University in Process"Memo to All Civil Service Employees concerning Across-the-Board IncreaseItem 21277021974-07-24221Reorganization Paper: #2 University Relations from the President's OfficeItem 22277031974-07-24222Notes on Implementation: #4 Proposed TimetableItem 23277041974-07-29223Scope and ContentsReorganization of the Divisions of Business Affairs &amp; Planning &amp; Development from the President's OfficeReorganization Paper: #3 (revised)Item 24277051974-07-29224Scope and ContentsDivisions of Business Affairs &amp; Planning &amp; Development from the President's OfficeReorganization Paper: #4Item 25277061974-07-29225Scope and ContentsMerger of the Division of Student Services with the Division of Academic Affairs from the President's OfficeReorganization Paper: #5 Academic Affairs from the President's OfficeItem 26277071974-08-01226Memo to All SSU Civil Service Secretarial Personnel concerning Administrative ReorganizationItem 27277081974-08-30227Memo to the University Faculty concerning Nomination for the ACE 1975-76 Fellow in Academic AdministrationItem 28277091974-09-17228President's Report to the Board of RegentsItem 29277101974-09-26229Scope and Contents"Sangamon State University-Springfield, Illinois" for the Meeting at Springfield"Where is the Library Today?" &amp; "General Library Skills Test"Item 3027711230Administrative Bulletin, Vol. 4, #11 regarding University Legal ServicesItem 31277121974-09-27231Memo to All Members of the Faculty concerning Selection Committee for Dean of FacultyItem 32277131974-010-07232Memo to Members of the Faculty concerning Transition Committee on Reorganization in Academic AffairsItem 33277141974-10-09233Memo to Speaker, University Assembly, Members, University Council concerning Broadcast CommitteesItem 34277151974-11-082341975Folder 3277163Memo to Harvey Koplo, Spokesperson for the Council of Concerned StudentsItem 1277171975-04-0431Scope and ContentsConcerning Concerned Students Response to NCA Evaluating Team Report Your Memo of April 1, 1975Memo to Members of the Board of Regents to bring them up-to-date on events at SSUItem 2277181975-05-0232Memo to Board of Regents concerning New &amp; Expanded Program RequestsItem 3277191975-05-2733Memo to Faculty &amp; Administrative Employees on twelve-month Appointments regarding Vacation Accumulation PolicyItem 42772034Memo to All Administrative Employees regarding Administrative &amp; Exempt Civil Service Salary StudyItem 5277211975-07-1535Memo regarding Buffet SupperItem 6277221975-07-1736Scope and ContentsMemo to Allen, Breiseth, Giesecke, Johnston, Keiser, Kendall, Kindschi, &amp; Shiner, regarding Buffet Supper Friday Evening, July 25, with the Illinois Community College BoardMemo regarding Buffet SupperMemo to Larry Shiner regarding the documentation of evaluations &amp; program directions in the Communications ProgramItem 7277231975-07-1137Administrative Bulletin, Vol. 4, # 19Item 8277241975-08-1338Scope and ContentsRegarding Released Time for Staff Participation in Governance Activities &amp; University ServiceMemo to the Vice Presidents &amp; Deans &amp; Chris Brieseth regarding Cocktails Prior to LLCC-SSU Faculty DinnerItem 9277251975-08-1539Memo regarding University Community Life CenterItem 10277261975-08-19310Scope and ContentsMemo to the Board of Regents, Fellow Presidents, &amp; Dr. Matsler, regarding University Community Life Center, and "University 			Community Life Center Preliminary Program Statement - Revised", August 1975Memo to the University Faculty Clayville Advisory Committee regarding Faculty Advisory Committee for ClayvilleItem 11277271975-10-17311Memo to File, "Memorandum to File Concerning Honorary Degrees at SSUItem 12277281975-10-27312Administrative Bulletin, Vol. 5, #3Item 13277291975-10-31313Scope and ContentsRegarding Achieving Parity for Nonexempt Civil Service PersonnelLetter to Dr. William Engbretson, President Governors State University regarding 			the possibility of offering joint honorary doctoral degreesItem 1427730314Administrative Bulletin, Vol. 5, #5Item 15277311975-11-06315Scope and ContentsRegarding Appointment of an Arts Task Force; its Charge, Procedure, &amp; CalendarMemo to Division Heads &amp; Academic CabinetItem 16277321975-11-14316Scope and ContentsProceedings of the Meeting of the Health Education Commission of the BHE, Nov. 6, 1975,at the Bismarck Hotel in ChicagoMemo to Frank Matsler &amp; the Board of Regents Staff, Season's GreetingsItem 17277331975-12-233171976Folder 4277344Memo to Keiser, Brieseth, &amp; Vlahoplus regarding Commencement SpeakerItem 1277351976-01-0541Memo to Division Heads regarding Discussion of Patterns of Growth, Recruitment Strategies, &amp; Institutional Planning for Jan. 22, 1976Item 2277361976-01-2242Memo to The Venture Fund Advisory Committee regarding The Venture FundItem 3277371976-02-0243Memo to Division Heads, Deans, Senior Staff &amp; Program Coordinators regarding University Data Book: A Subscription to an Information SystemItem 4277381976-02-0644Memo to Division Heads regarding Decisions on Enrollment Projections &amp; Recruitment PolicyItem 5277391976-02-1045Memo to Division Headsregarding attached memo from Frank Matsler concerning Presidential goals statementsItem 6277401976-02-2046Memo to Division Heads &amp; Robert Spencer from Wilbur Moulton regarding Staffing Plan Budget EstimatesItem 72774119776-03-0447Letter from C.F. Marley, President, Legislative Research AssociatesItem 8277421976-04-0848Administrative Bulletin, Vol. 5, #7Item 92774349Scope and Contentspage 12Memo to All Fiscal Officers, regarding Year-end Budget &amp; Purchasing ProceduresItem 10278131976-04-14410Memo to Mr. C.F. Marley, President, Legislative Research AssociatesItem 11278141976-05-13411Scope and ContentsResponse to previous letter &amp; chargesConfidential memo to Chris Breiseth concerning dealing with Mr. C.F. MarleyItem 12278151976-05-17412Remarks on the Occasion of the Dedication of Brookens Library by Robert SpencerItem 13278161976-05-19413Letter to James Elsass, Board of Higher Education &amp; copy of the Monthly Staff Level Report for the month of March for SSUItem 14278171976-05-20414Memo to John Keiser, Vice President for Academic Affairs &amp; Chris Breiseth, Chairperson, Faculty SenateItem 15278181976-06-01415Scope and ContentsRegarding Inquiry of the Jewish Community Relations council into the Professional &amp; Social Climate for Jewish Faculty at SSUMemo to the Board of Regents regarding Goals, Progress, &amp; AccountabilityItem 16278191976-06-08416Letter to Mr. C.F. Marley, President, Legislative Research AssociatesItem 17278201976-06-11417Scope and ContentsRegarding their concerns that the University is contributing to fornication &amp; adultery in response to his attached letter, &amp; note from Spencer to Chris BreisethLetter from Mr. C.F. Marley and attached Resolution for Restoration of Common Sense &amp; Decency in Public EducationItem 18278211976-06-15418Memo to Division Heads, regarding Extra Compensation for Faculty &amp; Administrative EmployeesItem 19278221976-06-16419Memo to Division Heads regarding Waiver RequestsItem 20278231976-06-18420Memo to John H. Keiser &amp; Academic Deans regarding FY-77 Title I ApplicationsItem 21278241976-07-26421Memo to All Fiscal Officers regarding Property Control &amp; the Use of Change of Location or Status FormsItem 22278251976-08-06422Memo to Division Heads &amp; Steering Committee on University HousingItem 23278261976-08-06423Scope and ContentsRegarding Developmental Strategies for Intergenerational Housing for SSU: A University           Village with Elders in ResidenceMemo to All Continuing Faculty, Aug. 9, 1976; Reception &amp; Sherry on Aug. 27, 1976Item 2427827Aug. 1976424Memo to Franklin Matsler, Executive Director, Illinois Board of RegentsItem 25278281976-08-10425Scope and ContentsRegarding Concerns About the Completion of SSURemarks of Robert C. Spencer at Meeting of Council for the Advancement &amp; Support of Education (Case) on Higher Education &amp; State RelationsItem 2627829Sept. 7-9, 1976426Scope and ContentsRegency Hyatt Hotel, Nashville, TennesseeMemo to the BOR regarding Developing Agenda for Completion of SSUItem 27278301976-09-07427Administrative Policies Bulletin from the Office of the President regarding Benefits Policy &amp; Records for Administrative EmployeesItem 28278311969-09-17428Memo to Mary Kate Yntema regarding Aug. 30 report of the 				Faculty Senate Standing Committee on Personnel PoliciesItem 29278321976-09-28429Letter to the Paul Findley, U.S. RepresentativeItem 30278331976-10-12430Memo to Chris Vlahoplus to suggest some recruitment strategiesItem 31278341976-10-12431Memo from M. Kent Jennings regarding Michelle HoymanItem 32278351976-11-05432Administrative Policies Bulletin from the Office of the President regarding Extra Compensation for University EmployeesItem 33278361976-12-01433Memo to Division Heads, Deans, &amp; Program Coordinators regarding Use of the President's Conference RoomItem 34278371976-12-02434Administrative Bulletin, Vol. 4, #3Item 35278381976-12-17435Scope and ContentsRegarding Salary IncreasesMemo to Hoinacki, Cohen, Penn, &amp; Breiseth  asking them to review the attached memo concerning Possible Appointment of Governor Christopher Bond of Missouri as Visiting Professor of Public Affairs at SSUItem 36278391976-12-17436Scope and ContentsDuring the Spring 1977 Semester1977Folder 5278405Memo to Division Heads, Academic Deans, Chris Breiseth regarding Discussion of Draft Long Range Academic Plan &amp; CompletionItem 1278411977-01-0451Letter to Christopher Bond expressing disappointment that he would be unable to accept the visiting Professor of Public Affairs PositionItem 2278421977-01-0452Memo to Hoinacki, Choen, Penn, &amp; Breiseth with Bond letter &amp; Spencer's responseItem 3278431977-01-0553Memo to Goins, Keiser, Vlahoplus regarding Statement of Economic Interest (pursuant to Illinois Governmental Ethics Act or to BOR Regulations)Item 4278441977-01-0654Memo to Division Heads, regarding Compilation of Opinions &amp; Correspondence of University AttorneysItem 5278451977-01-2455Letter to Dr. Leon Perley, President, Illinois Central CollegeItem 6278461977-02-0256Scope and ContentsIn response to his letter asking for SSU's endorsement of the statement of goals of the newly-established Central IL. Higher Education CouncilLetter of congratulations to Dr. Donald Price, Vice President of Rand McNally Co. on his reappointment to the Chairmanship of the Illinois Board of Higher EducationItem 7278471977-02-0257Administrative Bulletin, Vol. 6, #4Item 8278481977-02-0758Scope and ContentsRegarding A Policy Decision Relating to Peer Review &amp; Personal LiabilityAdministrative Policies Bulletin regarding Contract Dates &amp; Pay PeriodsItem 9278491977-02-1559Memo to Mike Townsend regarding Boys' Club of SpringfieldItem 10278501977-02-16510Administrative Bulletin, Vol. 6, #6Item 11278511977-02-22511Scope and ContentsRegarding Emergency Closing of the UniversityMemo to Louise Allen Concerning the Visit of Dr. Francis H. Heller, Consultant on Academic QualityItem 12278521977-02-24512Memo to Robert Spencer &amp; Division Heads from Wilbur Moulton regarding Draft of Financial Exigency Policy &amp; Procedures StatementItem 13278531977-02-24513Memo to Phil Kendall regarding Private Fund-RaisingItem 14278541977-02-28514Letter to Don Olson regarding student housing mattersItem 15278551977-03-08515Administrative Policies Bulletin, #4Item 16278561977-03-15516Scope and ContentsAdministrative Policies BulletinsConsultation on University Life Experiences at Sangamon State University by Richard Hulet, Tallahassee, FloridaItem 1727857517Letter to President Spencer &amp; SSU from John D. Millett regarding Review of Governance &amp; ManagementItem 18278581977-03-18518Consultation on Academic Quality at Sangamon State University by Francis H. Heller, Lawrence, KansasItem 1927859519Memo to Vice President Keiser &amp; Academic CabinetItem 20278601977-04-01520Scope and ContentsRegarding attached letter from the Chief of the Consumer Fraud &amp; Protection Division of the Office of the Attorney GeneralMemo to Academic Cabinet &amp; Program Coordinators regarding 	Self-Help Efforts Toward University Completion &amp; the Reports of Thess ConsultantsItem 21278611977-04-01521State of the University by Robert C. Spencer, President Sangamon State UniversityItem 22278621977-04-01522Memo regarding A New National Science Foundation "Rotator" Program for Women, Minorities, &amp; Handicapped IndividualsItem 23278631977-04-14523Administrative Policies Bulletin, #5Item 24278641977-04-15524Scope and ContentsContracting for ServicesMemo to Keiser &amp; KendallItem 25278651977-04-15525Memo to Regan Smith, Speaker, University, &amp; Chris Breiseth, Chairperson, FacultySenate, &amp;/or their successorsItem 26278661977-04-18526Scope and ContentsRegarding Action on U.A. Bill 6-12 Relating to Appeals Board Procedures for 1977-78Memo to John Keiser &amp; Division Heads, Your Memorandum of April 12 Concerning the Lab Classroom BuildingItem 27278671977-04-19527Letter to Dr. Robert Poorman, President of Lincoln Land Community CollegeItem 28278681977-04-19528Scope and ContentsConfidential concerning rumors that there was a plan for SSU to takeover or merge with LLCCConsultation on Personnel Problems at SSU by David Fellman, Vilas Professor of Political Science, University of Wisconsin-MadisonItem 29278691977-04-22529Due Process for Faculty at SSU Report on a Consultation, by Ray A. Howe, Deputy Superintendent, Dearborn Public Schools, Deerborn, MichiganItem 3027870April 25-26, 1977530Memo to John Keiser, Academic Deans, &amp; Charles Pinkus regarding SSU's Grading System &amp; the NCA StudyItem 31278711977-05-27531Letter to Dr. Gordon Millar, Vice President for Engineering, Deere &amp; Company concerning the Clayville Rural Life CenterItem 32278721977-06-01532Memo to Division Heads, Academic Deans, &amp; Program Coordinators, with attached report of Walter Metzger,"Personnel Problems at SSU"- a Report on a Consultation, May 4-6, 1977Item 33278731977-06-02533The Rationale for Integrating Libraries into the Educational Mainstream, a Paper given by Robert SpencerItem 3427874June 13-15, 1977534Scope and ContentsAt the Leadership Conference for Integrating Libraries into the Educational Mainstream at SSUMemo to Division Heads regarding The Regents' Study of University PublicationsItem 35278751977-07-11535Letter to George Bonham, Editor of Change MagazineItem 3627876536Memo to John Keiser with attached announcement of a meeting in Columbus, OhioItem 37278771977-08-29537Memos to Larry Shiner &amp; Louise Allen, regarding Participation in the United WayItem 38278781977-09-07538Memo to All Fiscal Officers regarding Inventory &amp; Property ControlItem 39278791977-10-10539Memo to Coleman, Goins, &amp; Keiser regarding Administration Approval for Committing University ResourcesItem 40278801977-11-01540Memo to BOR regarding Goals Statement for 1977-78Item 41278811977-11-22541Statement of Robert C. Spencer Upon the Occasion of the Announcement of His Resignation as President of Sangamon State UniversityItem 42278821977-12-19542Spencer's Christmas Card to Faculty &amp; StaffItem 43278831977-12-065431978Folder 6278846Memo to Jack Coleman, Thomas Goins, John Keiser regarding Statement of Economic Interests (pursuant to Illinois Governmental Ethics Act or to BOR's Regulations)Item 1278901978-01-0561Memo to the SSU Community from Regan Smith, Speaker, University Assembly &amp; Mary Kate Ynema, Chairperson, Faculty SenateItem 2278861978-01-1662Scope and ContentsRegarding Address by President Spencer entitled State of the University &amp; Concerns for the Immediate FutureMemo to All Faculty from Keiser regarding Matters Related to My Acting Presidency, Feb. 1 - Aug. 1, 1978Item 3278871978-01-2663Memo to President's Cabinet from John Keiser  regarding Presidential Authority in My AbsenceItem 4278881978-02-0164Administrative Policies Bulletin, No. 1, Supplement 1Item 5278911978-02-0165Scope and Contents"Benefits Policy &amp; Records for Administrative Employees"Memo to All Faculty regarding Address to the FacultyItem 6278921978-03-0166Report to President's Cabinet, Directors, Coordinators, from John H. Keiser regarding NCA Report on SSU &amp; the University responseItem 7278931978-06-2167Memo from Larry Shiner to Alex Lacy, Jr. &amp; Richard Sames regarding future Directions of Educational AdministrationItem 8278941978-11-27681979Folder 7278957Administrative Policies Bulletin, #6Item 1278961979-01-2971Scope and ContentsRegarding Gifts, Grants, &amp; ContractsAdministrative Policies Bulletin #7Item 2278971979-03-0972Scope and ContentsRegarding Space Assignment ResponsibilitiesMemo to The University Community regarding Holiday ObservancesItem 3278981979-09-1973Memo to All Faculty regarding Faculty MeetingItem 4278991979-10-0174Memo to All Faculty regarding Cluster MeetingsItem 5279001979-10-1775The Sangamon River Basin Project, Remarks by Alex B. Lacy, President SSU, The Greater Springfield Chamber of CommerceItem 6279011979-11-1376Memo of regarding Executive Officer in Charge of University Matters During Winter Break, 12/22/79 through 1/1/80Item 7279021979-12-17771980Folder 8279038Memo to All Faculty regarding Intersession 1980 and 1981Item 1279041980-01-2281Memo to University Community regarding Additional session on the new Office of Personnel ServiceItem 2279051980-03-3182Letter to Friends of Sangamon River Basin inviting them to a conference launching the Sangamon River Basin Project &amp; attached copy of the ProjectItem 327906198004-0783Letter to Returning Faculty Members &amp; attached orientation scheduleItem 4279071980-08-1184Memo to All Faculty &amp; Staff regarding Dedication Ceremony of On-campus Student HousingItem 5279081980-08-2185Memo to University Community, 1980 United Way CampaignItem 6279091980-09-1686Memo to The University Community regarding Holiday ObservancesItem 7279101980-09-1187Memo to The University Community regarding the move to the PAC Building &amp; announcing a get-togetherItem 8279111980-10-1588Memo to The University Community regarding the Otis Morgan Scholarship Fund DriveItem 9279121980-10-2889Memo to Faculty &amp; Staff regarding the Sangamon State University Foundation &amp; announcing their appointment of a full time Executive Director, Judith StephensItem 10279131980-12-158101981Folder 9279149Memo to The University Community regarding University observance honoring the released hostagesSeries 1279151981-01-28Memo to The University Community regarding 1981 United Way CampaignSeries 2279161981-09-16Memo to The University Community regarding International MonthSeries 3279171981-10-14Address By President Alex B. Lacy, Jr. Delivered At A University Convocation at the Public Affairs Center Auditorium, Sangamon State UniversityFolder 10279181982-09-20101983Folder 112791911Memo announcing University Convocation regarding the impact of the state's budget cuts on the UniversityItem 1279201983-01-18111Memo to The University Community regarding Budget DecisionsItem 2279211983-01-18112Memo to The University Community regarding the Vice President for Academic Affairs AppointmentItem 3279221983-05-261131983Folder 122792312Vice President for Academic Affairs Search Committee: Memo to VPAA Search Committee from George Gruendel, Speaker, University Assembly regarding Organizational MeetingItem 1279241983-10-26121List of the Contents of Recruitment Package to be approved by Affirmative Action OfficerItem 227926122Memo from Velma L. Carey, no date, Subject - Affirmative Action - Good Faith Search ProceduresItem 327927123Calendar of the Vice Presidential Search CommitteeItem 427928124Members of the VPAA Search CommitteeItem 527929125Position Description for the VPAA &amp; Dean of Faculty SSU &amp; AdvertisementsItem 627930126Memo to The University Community regarding the Gymnasium AdditionFolder 13279311984-03-1413To The University Community from the Presidential Search Committee, L. Milton McClure, Chair, regarding Campus Visits for Presidential CandidatesFolder 14279321984-05-0314Memo to The University Community, from Alex B. Lacy, Jr. regarding Revised Policy &amp; Procedures for all University PublicationsFolder 15279331984-05-2315Reception Invitation from Dr. &amp; Mrs. Alex LacyFolder 16279341984-06-2216News Clippings, regarding President Alex B. Lacy's ResignationFolder 1727935198417Notice to All Students, Faculty, &amp; Staff  regarding Notice of Briefing Sessions for BOR MeetingsFolder 18279361984-01-2718Brochure announcing the Training Seminar on The Freedom of Information ActFolder 19279371984-09-2819President's Convocation AddressFolder 20279381984-11-0120Open House Celebration of the University's 15th AnniversaryFolder 21279391984-11-0421Memo to SSU Faculty &amp; Staff from President Durward  Long regarding U.S. Savings Bond CampaignFolder 22279401985-03-1322Convocation Address by President Durward LongFolder 23279411985-05-1023Administrative Policies Bulletin #13Folder 24279421985-10-2424Scope and ContentsTo The University Community regarding Fees for Use of the GymPresident Spencer news articles &amp; Staff DirectoryFolder 327525Nov-Dec 19693"Remarks of President Robert C. Spencer at Kick-off Luncheon for Million-dollar fund raising"Item 1275301969-11-1231SSU Staff DirectoryItem 2275311969-12-1232SSU Staff DirectoryItem 3275321969-12-2433Newsletter to the Board of Regents from President SpencerItem 4275331969-12-1634Scope and ContentsComments on: 1) university land use &amp; area planning, 2) public advisory committee on program &amp; curriculum planning, 3) Personnel Office, 4)SSU Admissions Office on Washington Street, 5) comparative salary schedules, &amp; 6) recruitment of faculty.Memo to all staff regarding Springfield Sun item that President Spencer is establishing a rowing club at SSUItem 5275341969-1-935"Notes on the Initial Organization of SSU"Item 2275271963-08-152Governance &amp; Organization of SSUItem 327528October, 19693Scope and Contents"Governance of the University; a draft statement &amp; proposal" by Robert C. Spencer, Oct. 24, 1969; includes copy of draft "Organization of the University by Sarah Robinson, Oct. 3, 1969.Folder 427535Jan- June 4, 19704Administrative Procedures regarding Personnel, Memo #1-70Item 1275361970-01-1241Scope and Contentsconcerning new positions, recruitment, appointment &amp; planning for future positionsNewsletter to Board of Regents, #2Item 2275371970-01-1442Scope and Contentsregarding: 1) reaction to Jan. 4, Regents meeting, 2) appointment information published in local newspaper, 3) SSU appointments in comparison with other Regency institutions, 4) The Commuting Student 5) space for library processing, 6) first SSU publication – general announcement &amp; flyerStaff Newsletter, #2Item 5275401970-01-2945Letter from Springfield Mayor, Nelson HowarthItem 6275411970-02-0546Scope and ContentsInvites recipients to attend a briefing on SSU plans by Robert Spencer (January 30, 1970).Copy of memo to President Spencer from Bob MacAlisterItem 7275421970-02-0447Scope and ContentsRegarding maintaining contact with parents of studentsAnnouncement by President Spencer authorizing Lincoln's Birthday as a holidayItem 8275431970-02-1148Staff Newsletter, #3Item 9275441970-02-2349Memorandum to George CohenItem 10275451970-02-24410Scope and ContentsEntitled, "Considerations in hiring new faculty."  Popularly known as the BLUE MEMOMemorandum to Academic Vice PresidentItem 1127546Dec. 1970411Scope and Contents"Considerations in Appointing New Faculty"Memo to all professional staff membersItem 1227547412Scope and ContentsRegarding Coordination of Reports, Grant Applications, &amp; Requests for Data from External SourcesStaff Newsletter, #4Item 13275481970-03-14413Memo to all Senior Staff regarding Control of Entertainment Expenses at SSUItem 1427549414Memo to George CohenItem 15275501970-03-16415Scope and Contents"The Academic Program Statement" &amp; draft portions for catalogMemo to George CohenItem 16275511970-03-30416Scope and ContentsRegarding "The Academic Program Statement", about retaining G. Ernest Giesecke on consulting basisStaff Newsletter #5Item 1727552417Scope and Contentsundated (probably 4-22-70)Memo to All StaffItem 18275531970-04-02418Scope and ContentsRegarding personnel policies relating to University Civil Service employees &amp; "Sangamon State University Personnel Policies for University Civil Service Employees"Memo to Cohen, Scheuerman, &amp; MacAlister, regarding purchasingItem 19275541970-04-02419Memo to Cohen, Scheuerman, &amp; MacAlister, regarding travelItem 20275551970-04-02420Memo to Cohen, Scheuerman, &amp; MacAlister, regarding consultant servicesItem 21275561970-04-03421Memo to planning task forceItem 22275571970-04-13422Scope and ContentsRegarding guidelines for the completion of the writing program statements which includes: Time table, the Announcements, development Programs &amp; Courses, &amp; commentary notes.Memo to All Administrative OfficersItem 23275581970-04-15423Scope and ContentsRegarding Committees &amp; Task Forces of the Board of Higher Education &amp; the SSU representatives on the committeesMemo to Staff concerning: Rate changes - Blue Cross Blue Shield Health InsuranceItem 24275591970-04-23424Staff Newsletter, #6Item 25275601970-05-07425Memorandum #1 to participants in SSU Governance WeekendItem 2627561May 8-9, 1970426Scope and ContentsRegarding "Some Thought Questions Concerning the Nature of University Governance"Memorandum #2 to participants in SSU Governance WeekendItem 2727562May 8-9, 1970427Scope and ContentsRegarding "Assumptions Concerning the Proposed Plan of Governance for	Sangamon State University"Memorandum #3 to participants in SSU Governance WeekendItem 2827563May 8-9, 1970428Scope and ContentsRegarding "A Draft Document of a Constitution for SSU"Newsletter to the Board of RegentsItem 29275641970-05-12429Scope and ContentsConcerning: 1) progress on interim campus facilities, 2) the Governance Weekend, 3) the state of admissions, 4) a faculty conclave in June, &amp; 5) the status of faculty recruitmentMemo to the Administrative CouncilItem 30275651970-05-19430Scope and ContentsConcerning "Travel Expenses: Candidates, Consultants, New Staff, &amp; Invited Conferees"Robert C. Spencer's Travel PlansItem 3127566May 22-June 4, 1970431Manuscript &amp; memorandum of Robert SpencerItem 32275671970-05-27432Scope and ContentsWith notes in Spencer's handwriting to be sent to all members of the "Draft Committee on University  Governance" regarding the drafting of the Interim Governance DocumentSpeech given to the Springfield High School Graduating ClassItem 33275681970-06-04433Scope and Contents"The Committee For Higher Education In Central Illinois""Measuring Progress: Rewards, Punishments, Freedoms, &amp; Standards in the Academic Community by Robert MarshItem 4275291969-19704Folder 527569June-Dec, 19705Memo to All Staff MembersItem 1275701970-06-0851Scope and ContentsRegarding Groundbreaking CeremoniesMemo &amp; Attached Pay Plan to All Staff MembersItem 2275711970-06-1552Scope and ContentsRegarding University Pay Plan Relating to Civil Service EmployeesStaff Newsletter #7Item 3275721970-06-1853SSU Prospective Student SurveyItem 4275731970-07-0154Memo to All StaffItem 5275741970-07-0855Scope and ContentsStating that George Cohen is no longer with the administration, &amp; announcing appointment of Cullom Davis as interim Vice President for Academic AffairsSSU Guide To Academic ProgramsItem 6275751970-07-2256Memo to All Staff regarding Motor PoolItem 7275761970-07-2757Memo announcing the appointment of the Interim Student Financial Aid Advisory CommitteeItem 8275771970-08-0458Memorandum announcing the appointment ofItem 92757859Scope and Contents1) the Committee on Curriculum, 2) the Faculty Recruitment Committee, 3) the Faculty-Student Advisory Committee to the Board of Regents, 4) the President's Advisory Committee, 5) the Administrative Council, 6) the Professional Standards Committee, 7) the Applied Study CommitteePlanning Committee for the Opening of the UniversityItem 10275791970-08-14510Memo to All Faculty &amp; Professional Staff regarding "Case Studies in Administration"Item 11275801970-09-09511Scope and ContentsMemo to All Faculty &amp; Professional Staff regarding "Case Studies in Administration"Newsletter to the Board of Regents on the "Eve of the Opening of Sangamon State University"Item 12275811970-09-14512Scope and ContentsAnnouncing the timetable, the progress on the physical facilities &amp; announced plan of functions to celebrate the occasion.  Remarks of James B. Holderman, Executive Director of the 		Illinois Board of Higher Education to the faculty of SSU, Sept. 14, 1970.Letter from Mrs. Spencer, Mother of Robert C. Spencer, congratulations on opening the universityItem 1327582513Letter from Mayor Nelson Howarth of appreciationItem 1427583514Copy of letter from Dean Bill Ferrante proffering good wishes for SSUItem 15275841970-09-17515Letter to Students explaining the changes &amp; delays caused by wet weather in planned activitiesItem 1627585516Remarks of Robert Spencer to First Convocation of Faculty, Students, &amp; FamiliesItem 17275861970-09-20517Staff Newsletter, #8Item 18275871970-09-22518Memo to all Faculty &amp; Staff, regarding "Committee N"Item 19275881970-09-22519Memo to all Faculty, Staff, &amp; StudentsItem 20275891970-09-24520Scope and ContentsRegarding "Regents' Action on the Interim Governance Document, Changes in Committees, &amp; Other Matters"Memo to all Faculty &amp; StaffItem 21275901970-10-14521Scope and ContentsRegarding "The Meeting of the Board of Regents in Springfield, Oct. 15."Faculty/Staff Campus Newsletter, Vol. 1, No. 1Item 22275911970-10-14522Scope and ContentsFrom the Office of the President, concerning the Nepotism Committee, the Bookstore Committee, Faculty Meeting on Academic &amp; Physical Planning, &amp; Official Enrollment for Fall Quarter 1970"An Outline of Planning Tasks Ahead for SSU"Item 23275921970-10-16523Faculty/Staff Campus Newsletter, Vol. 1, No. 2Item 24275931970-10-16524Scope and ContentsConcerning the Organization of SSU, the Interim Committee on Public Safety, the Interim Council on Student Services, &amp; University CalendarFaculty/Staff Campus Newsletter, Vol. 1, No. 3Item 25275941970-10-29525Scope and ContentsConcerning: 1) statement on nepotism, 2) outline of planning tasks ahead for SSU, 3) the Professional Standards Committee, 4) the Interim Student Handbook, 5) the University Bookstore, &amp; Public SafetyMemo concerning the Thanksgiving WeekendItem 26275951970-11-05526Memo to the University AssemblyItem 27275961970-11-09527Scope and ContentsConcerning Public Appointments to the Assembly, the process, &amp; brief biographies of the recommended personsFaculty/Staff Newsletter, Vol. 1, No. 4Item 28275971970-11-10528Scope and ContentsConcerning the results of the University Assembly election, the public membership of the Assembly, the Interim Committee on Public Safety, &amp; summarized minutes of the Oct. 28th meeting of the Professional Standards CommitteeLetter to members of the University Assembly inviting them to an informal gathering to meet on Nov. 18, 1970Item 29275981970-11-11529Memo to Chairmen of Interim CommitteesItem 30275991970-11-30530Scope and ContentsConcerning progress reports, deadlines, &amp; the transition to the University Assembly CommitteesMemo to All Senior StaffItem 31276001970-11-30531Scope and ContentsAnnouncement of the Open House for the General PublicMemo from Robert Spencer to the Board of RegentsItem 32276011970-12-14532Scope and ContentsConcerning the Hoffman response regarding salary payment for George Cohen, the Academic Calendar, 1972-1973, Administrative Memo #3 regarding purchasing policy &amp; procedures, &amp; information on the success of the SSU Open HouseMemo to faculty &amp; members of the AssemblyItem 33276021970-12-22533Scope and ContentsRegarding the President's charge to the Steering Committee on Academic planning; includes charge on goldenrod memo dated Dec. 15, 1970Memo regarding HolidaysItem 34276031970-12-16534Memo to the Faculty &amp; Members of the University Assembly, on "The Planning Tasks Ahead for SSU"Item 35276041970-12-22535Memo to the Academic Vice President from President SpencerItem 3627605Dec. 1970536Scope and ContentsEntitled, "Considerations in Appointing New Faculty" (a revision of the 2-24-70 document, commonly called the BLUE MEMO)Interim Governance Document - DraftFolder 62760619706Guide to Academic Programs - DraftFolder 72760719707Letter to Board of Regent MembersFolder 82760819708Scope and ContentsThree sections of the long-range development plan for SSU, June 1970: 1) "Long Range Development Plan - I.  Academic Plan for SSU - Original Draft in Process of Revision; II.  Projected Enrollment at SSU - Original Draft in Process of Revision; III.  Long Range Building Program at SSU- Original Draft in ProcessAcademic Graduation StandardsFolder 92760919719Folder 10276101971 - 197210Remarks to the University AssemblyItem 1276111971-01-07101Scope and ContentsFirst State of the University AddressFaculty/Staff Newsletter, Vol. 1, #5Item 2276121971-01-18102Scope and ContentsRegarding administrative changes, the President's Cabinet, &amp; leave of absence for Chris VlahoplusLetter to the Board of RegentsItem 3276131971-01-21103Scope and ContentsDetailing the uproar on campus &amp; in the press over the appointment of SCAP &amp; Doug Kindschi as its head; includes Statement releases by SSU President Spencer to the press, Jan. 13, 1971; letter of response of the Assembly through Speaker Keiser to the Illinois Association for Higher Education, Jan. 21, 1971; Kindschi report from the Steering Committee for Academic Planning progress report, Jan. 12, 1970 (NOTE: should be 1971).Memo to All Staff, regarding Travel RegulationsItem 4276141971-01-28104Faculty/Staff Newsletter, Vol. 1, #6Item 5276151971-02-12105Scope and ContentsConcerning the budgetary process for higher education in Illinois, especially Sangamon State University's request for FY 1971-1972; selected actions of the Board of Higher Education at its 2/2/71 meeting, the Vice Presidential Search for Academic AffairsFebruary Letter to the Board of RegentsItem 6276161971-02-18106Scope and Contentsconcerning planning progress, the Vice Presidential search, community reaction to the SSU program, &amp; evaluation &amp; appointment of incumbent faculty including a report of "Interim Faculty Evaluation Procedures for Contract Renewal, Academic Year 1971-1972" as approved by the AssemblyMemo to All FacultyItem 7276171971-03-01107Scope and ContentsConcerning the recommendations of the Faculty  Evaluation &amp; Reappointment Committee for 1971-1972Memo to Members of the Faculty concerning University WeekItem 827618March 15-19, 1971108Invitation for University WeekItem 9276191971-03-05109Letter to the Board of RegentsItem 10276201971-03-151010Scope and ContentsConcerning campus news &amp; items for the March BOR meetingLetter to Robert Howard of the Sangamon County Historical SocietyItem 11276211971-03-161011Scope and ContentsConcerning possible renovation of the Shepherd or McClelland farmhouses into restored headquarters for the Historical SocietyRemarks to the Board of Regents concerning the emphasis on Public Affairs at SSU at DeKalbItem 12276221971-03-181012Memo to the University CommunityItem 13276231971-04-061013Scope and ContentsConcerning clarification of the Spring quarter calendarMemo to All Faculty &amp; StaffItem 14276241971-04-161014Scope and ContentsConcerning the Academic Calendar adopted by the BOR for 1971-1972Announcement of Memorial Day as a holidayItem 15276251971-05-211015Memorandum to "The President of SSU in 2001" from SSU President Robert SpencerItem 16276261016Scope and ContentsConcerning "What we did during the first year of Sangamon State University", listing the contents of the time capsule deposited during University Week May 1971Letter to the Board of RegentsItem 17276271971-06-081017Scope and ContentsConcerning University relations with Senator G. William Horsley, fall enrollment projections, &amp; Keiser as new Vice President for Academic AffairsLetter to Board of RegentsItem 18276281971-06-111018Scope and ContentsConcerning editorials in the local newspapers regarding Horsley/SSU relationsMemo to Roger Sweet, Speaker of the University AssemblyItem 19276291019Scope and ContentsConcerning President's response to Bills #46 &amp; 47July Newsletter to the Board of RegentsItem 20276301971-07-191020Scope and ContentsConcerning the Phase B Interim facility, the Special Committee to Select Architects for Phase II, &amp; Dean &amp; faculty recruitmentLetter to the Board of RegentsItem 21276311971-09-011021Scope and ContentsConcerning progress on Phase B Interim facilities, the perimeter road &amp; northeast parking lot, the facilities for the September meeting, &amp; the proposed amendments to the Interim Governance DocumentRobert C. Spencer RemarksItem 22276321971-09-271022Scope and ContentsManuscript notes concerning the "Remarks of Robert C. Spencer at Regency staff hearings on SSU's FY73 operating budget request; includes the pessimistic premise on SSU budgeting before the breakthrough in negotiations on Sept. 27, 1971"; the draft of Budget Presentation Strategy Meeting Sept.16, 1971, summaries of SSU operating budget requests &amp; rationale, revised request (Sept. 21, 1971) &amp; Board staff recommendationsMemo to All Faculty &amp; StaffItem 23276331971-10-011023Scope and ContentsConcerning the President's absence from campus Oct. 4-20, 1971Memo to Phil Bradley, Speaker of UniversityItem 24276341024Scope and ContentsConcerning the President's comments  on Assembly Bill #5, &amp; a charge to the Faculty Retention Committee.Excerpts from Board of Higher EducationItem 25276351025Scope and Contents"Sangamon State University's Mandate" – excerpts  from: Board of Higher Education Documents, Statements by BHE Executive Director, Statements by Governor Richard Ogilvie, Statements by President Robert C. Spencer - Prepared by the Office of Academic Planning, November 1971.State of the University AddressItem 26276361971-12-021026Letter to Mark SiebertItem 27276371971-12-281027Scope and ContentsConcerning academic recruitment &amp; requests of the Steering Committee of the United Faculty of SSULetter to Vladimir T. BorovanskiItem 28276381972-01-181028Scope and ContentsConcerning the founding date for SSU; Spencer states that the public law for SSU was enacted in June 1969; its effective date was July 1, 1969; the first President was appointed on July 13, 1969, &amp; reported for work on Sept. 1, 1969, &amp; that SSU opened for students on Sept. 23, 1970Memo of Holiday Calendar for SSUItem 29276391972-01-211029Memo to Robert MacAlisterItem 30276401972-01-211030Scope and ContentsAnnouncing changes in student employment wage &amp; salary administrationAnnouncement of Visit of Board of Regents Chairman, Dr. Barr to SSUItem 3127641Feb. 17-18, 19721031Memo to the University AssemblyItem 32276421972-02-211032Scope and ContentsConcerning the appointment of the North Central Association Self-Study Committee for an accreditation report for May 1, 1972Memo to the Speaker of the University Assembly concerning the expansion of the President's CabinetItem 33276431972-04-251033Statement on Governance at SSUItem 3427644May 19721034Scope and Contents"Statement on Governance at Sangamon State University" - An Essay Prepared for 			the Status Report Submitted to the North Central Association of Colleges 				&amp; Secondary Schools"Administrative Organization at SSUItem 3527645May 19721035Scope and Contents"Administrative Organization at Sangamon State University - A retrospective essay prepared for the Status Report submitted to the North Central Association of Colleges &amp; Secondary Schools"Announcement of the 4 1/2 % Salary Adjustment for Civil Service EmployeesItem 36276461972-08-141036Announcement of a Series of Dinners for New Faculty, Division Heads, Deans, Veteran Faculty, Senior Staff &amp; Respective SpousesItem 37276471972-08-241037Copy of never-issued memo, but distributed to President's CabinetItem 38276481972-11-161038Scope and ContentsConcerning Office Duty Time &amp; release time for governance.Memo to Stan Sokolik, Speaker of the University Assembly, regarding University Assembly Bill #54Item 39276491972-12-071039

