<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.102/9Archon Finding Aid Title MC.102/9Brian FranklinUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:52:34 -0400.engDescribing Archives: A Content Standard
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC102/9. Recycling Archives: Institute for Local Self Reliance (ILSR) Publications
    
      Seldman, Neil
    
    MC.102/9
    1857
    
      1.00 boxes
    
    1979-2007
    Date acquired: 03/17/2015
    1
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This collection contains a variety of publications relating to waste and recycling management.  Publications primarily concern policy, technology, program implementation and management.  The publications consists of newsletters, articles, guides, studies, journals, and books.Neil Seldman, founder of the Institute for Local Self Reliance, was responsible for coordinating this collection of materials related to recycling for donation to the UIS Archives.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
Open  
  
    Biographical or Historical Information
Dr. Neil Seldman was a manufacturer in New York City and a university lecturer in political science before co-founding the Institute for Local Self-Reliance in the Adams Morgan neighborhood of Washington, DC. Neil Seldman provides technical assistance to cities, community groups and businesses in the field of sustainable resource management. He has pioneered developments in processing, building deconstruction and small scale manufacturing from recycled materials. Dr. Seldman has also chronicled the US recycling movement in the last 50 years in "History of the US Recycling Movement, Encyclopedia of Technology Energy and Environment" and "Wasting in the US 2000." He has also documented worldwide recycling developments for the World Bank in "Recycling from municipal refuse: a state-of-the-art review and annotated bibliography." He is a founding member of the National Recycling Coalition at the First National Recycling Congress and the Grass Roots Recycling Network. According to Robin Cannon, Concerned Citizens of South Los Angeles, Dr. Seldman is known as grassroots organizer who, "shows communities how to fight against and how to fight for the sustainable solution to solid waste and economic problems." In recent years he has worked in Atlanta, Cleveland, Alachua County (Gainesville), FL, Reading, PA, Washington, DC, Bridgeport, CT, Austin, TX and Los Angeles. Dr. Seldman writes regularly for trade journals providing insight and criticism of poorly designed technologies and programs. From the  Institute for Local Self-Reliance website.Note written by   
  Box 1Box 179200ILSR Publications - 5 itemsFolder 1792011979-19861Scope and ContentsItem 1. Seldman, Neil; Ospina, Francisco. Report to the world bank: Solid waste collection and disposal project for the metropolitan area of Medellin, Columbia. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1979. 30 p.  illus. (table/charts)Item 2. Morris, David. Humanly scaled energy. Reprinted from Fire of Life: the Smithsonian book of the sun. Washington, DC: The Smithsonian Institution, 1981. 7 p.  illus.Item 3. Morris, David. The homegrown economy: a prescription for Saint Paul's future.  Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1983. 28 p.  illus. (table/charts/photos)Item 4. AMA Management Briefing. Toward pollution-free manufacturing.  Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1986. 122 p.  illus. (table/charts/photos)Item 5. Huisingh, Donald; MArtin, Lawrence; Aberth, John. AMA Management Briefing: Toward pollution-free manufacturing.  Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1986. 122 p.  illus. (table/charts/photos)Item 6. Morris, David; Abeles, Tom. Substituting agricultural materials for petroleum-based industrial products. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1986. 34 p.  illus. (table/charts)ILSR Publications - 4 itemsFolder 2792021987-19882Scope and ContentsItem 1. Morris, David; Platt, Brenda. Garbage disposal economics: a statistical snapshot. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1987. 101 p.  illus. (table/charts)Item 2. Seldman, Neil. Recycling goals and strategies: A working paper. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1988. 21 p.Item 3. Martin, Larry; Seldman, Neil. Legal and regulatory climate for municipal solid waste incineration: A technical working paper. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1988. 43 p.Item 4. Seldman, Neil. Solid waste technology and the society of the future: A working paper. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1988. 15 p.Garbage in Europe: Technologies, Economics and TrendsItem 17920319881Scope and ContentsPlatt, Brenda; Seldman, Neil; Franke, Bernd; Mayer, Bernd. Garbage in Europe: technologies, economics, and trends. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1988. 255 p.  illus. (table/charts)Proven profits from pollution prevention: Case studies in resource conservation and waste reduction - Volume IIItem 27920419892Scope and ContentsMartin, Larry. Proven profits from pollution prevention: Case studies in resource conservation and waste reduction - Volume II. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1989. 144 p.Directory of waste utilization technologies in Europe and the United StatesItem 37920519893Scope and ContentsThe Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR). Directory of waste utilization technologies in Europe and the United States. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1989. 163 p. illus. (table/charts)Salvaging the future: waste-based productionItem 47920619894Scope and ContentsRennie, Caroline; MacLean, Alair. Salvaging the future: waste-based production. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1989. 162 p. illus. (table/charts)Pitfalls and promise of resource recovery in Union County, New JerseyItem 57920719895Scope and ContentsPlatt, Brenda; Seldman, Neil; Woodruff, Ken; Iannarelli, Anthony. Pitfalls and promise of resource recovery in Union County, New Jersey. Second Edition. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1989. 180 p. illus. (table/charts)Waste reduction, recycling, and composting for Camden County, New JerseyItem 67920819906Scope and ContentsThe Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR). Waste reduction, recycling, and composting for Camden County, New Jersey. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1990. 252 p. illus. (table/charts/drawings)ILSR Publications - 2 itemsFolder 37920919903Scope and ContentsItem 1. Morris, David. A molecular basis for development: An environmental policy for the 1990s. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1990. 9 p.Item 2. The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR). Indiana's alternatives to solid waste disposal. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1990. 143 p. illus. (table/charts/drawings)ILSR Publications - 4 itemsFolder 47921019914Scope and ContentsItem 1. Morris, David. Urban resource management in the greenhouse age. From Proceedings of European workshop on cities and the global environment. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1991. 13 p.Item 2. The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR). Recycling and economic development in Washington D.C.. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1991. 80 p. illus. (table/charts/drawings)Item 3. Morris, David. Free trade: The great destroyer &amp; Trading our future: Talking back to GATT. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1991. 21 p.Item 4. Morris, David; Platt, Brenda; Sapon-Borson, Daniel; Gallaway, Matt; Ahmed, Irshad. Gwtting the most from our materials: Making New Jersey the state of the art. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1991. 85 p. (table/charts)ILSR Publications - 6 itemsFolder 57922219925Scope and ContentsItem 1. The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR). Getting the most from our materials: Strategies from the New Jersey conference. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1992. 78 p. illus. (table/charts)Item 2. Morris, David. The Mondragon System: cooperation at work. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1992. 57 p.Item 3. Morris, David. Getting from here to there: building a rational transportation system. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1992. 7 p.Item 4. Platt, Brenda; Zachary, Jill. Co-collection of recycables and mixed waste: problems and opportunities. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1992. 64 p. illus. (table/charts/drawings)Item 5. The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR). Toward common ground: the international workshop on biodegradability - meeting summary. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1992. 11 p. illus.Item 6. Bailey, John. Making the car pay its way: the case of Minneapolis roads. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1992. 11 p. illus. (table/charts)In-depth studies of recycling and composting programs: designs, costs, results: Volume I - Rural communitiesItem 77921119927Scope and ContentsPlatt, Brenda; Friedman, Naomi; Grodinsky, Carolyn; Suozzo, Margaret. In-depth studies of recycling and composting programs: designs, costs, results: Volume I - Rural communities. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1992. 113 p. illus. (table/charts)In-depth studies of recycling and composting programs: designs, costs, results: Volume III - Urban areasItem 87921219928Scope and ContentsPlatt, Brenda; Friedman, Naomi; Grodinsky, Carolyn; Suozzo, Margaret. In-depth studies of recycling and composting programs: designs, costs, results: Volume III - Urban areas.  Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1992. 190 p. illus. (table/charts)ILSR Publications - 5 itemsFolder 67921319936Scope and ContentsItem 1. Platt, Brenda; Morris, David. The economic benefits of recycling. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1993. 15 p. illus. (table/charts).Item 2. Morris, David. Ethanol: a fuel in transition, an industry emerging. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1993. 9 p. illus. (table/charts).Item 3. Morris, David; Ahmed, Irshad. Rural development, biorefineries and the carbohydrate economy. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1993. 13 p. illus. (table/charts).Item 4. Aunan, Lauri. States close the loop. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1993. 56 p. illus. (table/charts).Item 5. Ethanol: A 150 year struggle toward renewable future. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1993. 8 p.ILSR Publications - 9 itemsFolder 77921419947Scope and ContentsItem 1. Lewis, Michael. Recycling economic development through scrap-based manufacturing. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1994. 42 p. illus.(table/charts).Item 2. Ahmed, Irshad; Morris, David. Replacing petrochemicals with biochemicals: a pollution prevention strategy for the great lakes region. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1994. 55 p. illus. (table/charts).Item 3. Morris, David. Renewables, ethanol and renewable oxygenate standard. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1994. 8 p.Item 4. Ahmed, Irshad; Morris, David. Greenhouse gas emissions from ethanol and MTBE: a comparison. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1994. 9 p. illus. (table/charts).Item 5. Morris, David. Green taxes. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1994. 10 p. illus. (table/charts).Item 6. Seldman, Neil; Martin, Tom. Expanding scrap-based manufacturing through the community joint-venture process. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1994. 27 p. illus. (table/charts).Item 7. Martin, Tom. Creating local recycling markets. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1994. 31 p.Item 8. Lewis, Michael. Preparing a business plan for a small-scale recycling-related venture. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1994. 8 p.Item 9. Platt, Brenda. Minimizing waste, maximizing recycling. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1994. 34 p.Waste prevention, recycling, and composting options: lessons from 30 communitiesItem 97921519949Scope and ContentsUnited States Environmental Protection Agency. Waste prevention, recycling, and composting options: lessons from 30 communities. Washington, DC: United States Environmental Protection Agency, 1994. 168 p. illus.(table/charts).ILSR Publications - 6 itemsFolder 87921619958Scope and ContentsItem 1. Platt, Brenda; Jeanes, Henry; Kaufmann, Anne. Recycling means business in Baltimore, D.C., and Richmond. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1995. 78 p. illus. (table/charts).Item 2. Bailey, John; Morris, David. Taxing wind energy in Minnesota. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1995. 21 p. illus. (table/charts).Item 3. Morris, David. Restructuring Minnesota's tax system: taxing pollution rather than work and investment. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1995. 10 p. illus. (table/charts).Item 4. Seldman, Neil. Recycling - History in the United States. Taken from Encyclopedia of Energy Technology and the Environment.  Editors Attilo Bisio and sharon Boots. New York, NY: John wiley &amp; Sons, 1995. 17 p. illus. (table/charts).Item 5. Lewis, Michael; Clark, Russell; Vandall, Jeffrey; Seldman, Neil. Reuse Operations. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1995. 64 p. illus. (table/charts).Item 6. Lorenz, David; Morris, David. How much energy does it take to make a gallon of ethanol. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1995. 8 p. illus. (table/charts).ILSR Publications - 7 itemsFolder 9792171996-19979Scope and ContentsItem 1. Lewis, Michael; Vandall, Jeffrey; Clark, Russell; Seldman, Neil. Community development corporations and reuse operations. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1996. 34 p.Item 2. Wahl, Jenny B. Oil slickers: how petroleum benefits at the taxpayer's expense. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1996. 18 p. illus. (table/charts).Item 3. Biochemicals for the automotive industry. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1997. 17 p. illus. (table/charts/photos).Item 4. Platt, Brenda; Hyde, Jennifer. Sustaining businesses &amp; jobs through pallet repair and reuse. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1997. 27 p. illus. (table/charts/photos).Item 5. Platt, Brenda. Creating wealth from everyday items. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1997. 41 p. illus. (table/charts/photos).Item 6. Platt, Brenda; Hyde, Jennifer. Plug into electronic reuse. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1997. 47 p. illus. (table/charts/photos).Item 7. United States Environmental Protection Agency. Electronics reuse and recycling directory. Washington, DC: The United States Environmental Protection Agency, 1997. 11 p.ILSR Publications - 6 itemsFolder 10792181998-199910Scope and ContentsItem 1. Seldman, Neil. Thinking about solid waste management in the District of Columbia. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1998. 55 p. illus. (table/charts)Item 2. Morris, David; Kraker, Daniel. Roots, roots, roots for the home team: community-owned professional sports. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1998. 20 p. illus. (table/charts/drawings)Item 3. Morris, David; Kraker, Daniel. Roots, roots, roots for the home team: community-owned professional sports. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1998. 3 p. illus. (table/charts)Item 4. Place Matters Conference. Closer to home: a conversation about local owenership &amp; community.  Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1998. 43 p.Item 5. The Institute for Local Self-Reliance. Deconstruction of Building #28 at Stowe Village, Hartford, Connecticut.  Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1998. 37 p. illus. (table/charts/photos)Item 6. Leroux, Kivi; Seldman, Neil. Deconstruction: Salvaging yesterday's buildings for tomorrow's sustainable communities.  Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1999. 28 p. illus. (table/charts/photos)ILSR Publications - 7 itemsFolder 11792192000-200711Scope and ContentsItem 1. Platt, Brenda; Seldman, Neil. Wasting and recycling in the United States 2000. Athens, GA: GrassRoots Recycling Network, 2000. 64 p. illus. (table/charts).Item 2. The Alameda County Waste Management Authority &amp; The Alameda County Source Reduction and Recycling Board. Innovation, leadership, stewardship. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 2002. 20 p. illus. (table/charts/photos)Item 3. Institute for Local Self-Reliance. Facts to Act On: Release #42. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 2002. 11 p. illus. (table/charts/photos)Item 4. Metro. Metro construction industry recycling toolkit: recycling and salvage planning guide. Portland, OR: Metro, 2002. 48 p. illus. (table/charts).Item 5. Morris, David. Putting the public back into public investment. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 2005. 5 p.Item 6. Mutliple authors. The American Prospect: Special Report. Washington, DC: The American Prospect, 2006. 31 p. illus. (photos/drawings)Item 7. Daggett, Becca Vargo. Localizing the Internet: five ways public ownership solves the U.S. broadband problem. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 2007. 29 p. illus. (table/charts)The Carbohydrate EconomyFolder 12792201997-200212Scope and ContentsThe Carbohydrate Economy. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 1997-2002.Building a deconstruction companyFolder 1379221200113Scope and ContentsLivingston, Dennis; Jackson, Mark. Building a deconstruction company. Washington, DC: The Institute for Local Self-Reliance (ILSR), 2001. 86 p.  illus. (table/charts)

