<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.102/8Archon Finding Aid Title MC.102/8Brian FranklinUIS Archives/Special Collections05/12/2015Archives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:52:37 -0400.engDescribing Archives: A Content Standard
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC102/8. Recycling Archives: Nancy VandenBerg Collection
    MC.102/8
    1856
    
      1.66 Cubic Feet
    
    1977-2000
    Date acquired: 04/12/2015
    1
    2
    3
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This collection contains a variety of resources and publications relating to recycling management.  Documents primarily concern market analysis, policy, technology, program implementation and management.  The publications consists of correspondence, guides, newsletters, booklets, books, policy papers, and programs.Between 1985 and 1995, Nancy VandenBerg ran Markets for Recycled Products which focused on purchasing recycled products for waste reduction. This tiny consultancy had influence on federal, state and local government policy. Intentionally, projects were built on predecessors until there was a national movement. VandenBerg wanted to build markets for recovered materials as the collection process matured. She used speeches and handouts to energize those active in other aspects of recycling and to give them working tools. VandenBerg currently resides in Portugal.Dan Knapp and the Institute for Local Self Reliance are responsible for coordinating the collections of material related to recycling for donation to the UIS Archives.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Collection is filed by the company, organization, or program responsible for/or related to the material.  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
Open  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Nancy VanderBerg  
  Box 1Box 179137Government/Industry roundtables on buying recycled plastic products, Phase II: New England/Middle Atlantic States - section 1Folder 1791381991Section 11Government/Industry roundtables on buying recycled plastic products, Phase II: New England/Middle Atlantic States - Section 2Folder 27913919912Government/Industry roundtables on buying recycled plastic products, Phase II: New England/Middle Atlantic States - Section 3Folder 37914019913Government/Industry roundtables on buying recycled plastic products, Phase II: New England/Middle Atlantic States - Section 4Folder 47914119914Government/Industry roundtables on buying recycled plastic products, Phase II: New England/Middle Atlantic States - Section 5Folder 57914219915Government/Industry roundtables on buying recycled plastic products, Phase II: New England/Middle Atlantic States - Section 6Folder 67914319916Government/Industry roundtables on buying recycled plastic products, Phase II: New England/Middle Atlantic States - Section 7Folder 77914419917Government/Industry roundtables on buying recycled plastic products, Phase II: New England/Middle Atlantic States - AppendixFolder 87914519918Government/Industry roundtables on buying recycled plastic products, Phase II: New England/Middle Atlantic States - Corporate Roundtables on Buying Recycled Plastic Products 1990-1991Folder 97914619919Office Paper RecyclingFolder 10791471977-198010Historical RR Comments Early 1980'sFolder 11791481980-198211Bidnet, NHRRA, ANJR, Philly, Illinois SeminarFolder 1279149198612Seattle NRC, RR Articles, ICPS, Online, PA, Long Island NYS DecFolder 1379150198613New England Waste Management Official's Association (NEWMOA)Folder 1479151198714Buying recycled productsFolder 15791521988-198915Markets for recycled productsFolder 16791531990-199116PIMA MagazineFolder 17791541991-199217Markets for recycled productsFolder 18791551992-199318NVB Correspondence; 99% Recycling Related. Correspondence for Names/Timing issues as they progressed.  Part 1Folder 19791561985-200019NVB Correspondence; 99% Recycling Related. Correspondence for Names/Timing issues as they progressed.  Part 2Folder 20791571985-200020Procurement - Price preference history - NYCFolder 21791581990-199521NYC local law 19 - Recycling and procurement. Also executive orders.Folder 22791591987-199322U.S. Exec order - Impact of goals dataFolder 2379160199323PDWG acceptable recycled paper definitionsFolder 24791611991-199324Impact of in-plant scrapFolder 2579162199325Clinton's Exec order-final and Bush's Exec orderFolder 26791631991-199826FTC ENV labeling and consumerFolder 27791641992-199727NYS Dec regs changesFolder 28791651994-199528EPA guideline - fly ash in cementFolder 2979166198329Jorling - Santour and EPA guideline historyFolder 30791671979-199430State tables APIFolder 31791681987-199331Paper weigth conversion formulasFolder 3279169198832Government purchase of recycled productsItem 17917019851Principles of recycling and recommendations for state actionItem 27917119862High performance building guidelinesItem 37917219993Phase 1: Buy recycled programs in Alameda CountyItem 47917319954Resourceful purchasing: A hands-on buyers manualItem 57917419965Box 2Box 279175County of San Diego recycled product procurement studyItem 17917619901Government and industry roundtables on buying recycled plastic productsItem 27917719902Florida minimum recycled content tech study - Part 1Folder 17917819941Florida minimum recycled content tech study - Part 2Folder 27917919942Final report: A model for a comprehensive waste reduction procurement program. Sections 1-7Folder 37918019943Final report: A model for a comprehensive waste reduction procurement program. Sections 8-15, A and BFolder 47918119944Final Report: A model for a comprehensive waste reduction procurement program (Appendix C)Item 37918219943Buy-Recycled plan: with strategic timing and implementation recommendations to expand markets through government purchasingItem 47918319884Feasibility of federal procurement guidelines for construction products containing recovered materialsItem 57918419905Purchasing opportunities for recycled products for three principal materialsItem 67918519896Box 3Box 379186Box 2Box 279187County of San Diego recycled product procurement studyItem 17918919901Government and industry roundtables on buying recycled plastic productsItem 27919019902Florida minimum recycled content tech study - Part 1Folder 17919119941Florida minimum recycled content tech study - Part 2Folder 27919219942Final report: A model for comprehensive waste reduction procurement  program - Sections 1-7Folder 37919319943Final report: A model for comprehensive waste reduction procurement  program - Sections 8-15, A and BFolder 47919419944Box 3Box 379188Final report: A model for comprehensive waste reduction procurement program - Appendix CItem 17919519941Buy recycled plan: With strategic timing and implementation recommendations to expand markets through government purchasingItem 27919619882Feasibility of federal procurement guidelines for construction products containing recovered materialsItem 37919719903Purchasing opportunities for recycled products for three principal materials: metal, paper, plasticsItem 47919819894Letter from VandenBerg including summary of collection and curriculum vitaeFolder 17919920151

