<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>K.01.03/01Archon Finding Aid Title K.01.03/01Allison BatesUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:52:45 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    K1/3/1. Women's Center Event Flyers
    K.01.03/01
    1864
    
      0.66 Cubic Feet
    
    2002-2017
    Date acquired: 08/28/2015
    3
    Item4
    1
    2
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Women's Center event flyers for AY '03- AY '17: Includes flyers for Take Back the Night, RAD Women's Self Defense, student clubs and club activities, TGIF events, art shows, and Women's Center sponsored ECCE speakers. Also included are event invitations, event programs, event photographs, some office correspondence, orientation program materials, copies of awards given by the Women's Center, and blank thank you cards designed within the office. Included in separate folders are Women's Center meditation event flyers and TARA Meditation Club flyers.Of special note are several life-sized, hand-drawn posters of UIS students and participants in the 2013 event One Billion Rising. Also, a scrapbook devoted to the events surrounding the 1982 effort to pass the Equal Rights Amendment in Illinois includes several color photos of a pro-ERA march on the Illinois State Capitol.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Lynn Otterson  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Occasional deposits.  
  
    Accruals and Additions
New material received, May 2, 2017 from Lynn Otterson, added Sept. 12, 2017. Chris Schnell  
  Box 1Box 180091AY 2002-03Folder 1800921Scope and ContentsDecide to End Sexual Violence; Fall 2002 RAD Women's Self Defense; Chick Flick Sisterhood First Meeting 17 October 2002; Women's Center Annual Fall Reception 22 October 2002; Naomi B Lynn Award to Veronica Luz Espina 22 October 2002; Chick Flick Sisterhood Pajama Jam 15 November 2002; Rhythm Journeys Workshop 5 December 2002; Women's Studies and Women's Center Annual Holiday Party 12 December 2002; Roe v. Wade at 30 Brown Bag Lunch 22 January 2003; Spring 2003 RAD Women's Self Defense; Women's Issues Caucs Planning Meeting 19 February 2003; Vagina Monologues Brown Bag Lunch 28 February 2003; Discreet Rage 3 March 2003; Jane Smith 4 March 2003; Clothesline Project 8 March 200;3 UIS Journal Concerns Student Forum 15 April 2003; Springfest Dance 25 April 2003AY 2003-04Folder 2800932Scope and ContentsWhistleSTOP Safety Program; Fall 2003 RAD Women's Self Defense; Young Women's Day of Activism 23 October 2003; Women's Studies and Women's Center Annual Holiday Party 5 December 2003; Spring 2004 RAD Women's Self Defense; "Fighting For Freedom" Midwestern Women Abolitionists, Stacey Robertson 8 March 2004; Sexual Assault Awareness Month card; Women's Issues Caucus Bowling Fundraiser 4 April 2004; Azita Ziaei "Images of Women in Iran" art show 4 April 2004; Springfest CARE Workshop 19 April 2004; Women's Center Annual Spring Reception 28 April 2004AY 2004-05Folder 3800943Scope and ContentsFall 2004 RAD Women's Self Defense; "A Day to Remember" Candelight Vigil 11 September 2005; National Get Carded Day 23 September 2004; Domestic Violence Brown Bag Lunch Seminar 21 October 2004; Iron Jawed Angels showing 1 November 2004; Women's Issues Caucus Voting Poster; World AIDS Day 1 December 2004; Women's Center and Women's Studies Program Annual Holiday Party 3 December 2004; Women's Issues Caucus Planning Meeting 19 January 2005, Spring 2005 RAD Women's Self Defense; "Merge" art show 14 February 2005; Vagina Monologues 5 March 2005; Sheila Simon "A Life in Illinois Politics and Law" 28 March 2005; UIS Health Fair Quiz 13 April 2005; Springfest "1 in 4 No More" 13 April 2005; Women's Center Annual Spring Reception 20 April 2005; Awards to Women's Issues Caucus 2005; Thank You CardAY 2005-06Folder 4800954Scope and ContentsFirst Year Orientation Materials; Women's Issues Caucus Open House 31 August 2005; Fall 2005 RAD Women's Self-Defense Training; Caron Cadle "Goddess: A New (Old) Vision" 21 September 2005; Women's Issues Caucus Luncheon with Vicki Crompton 17 October 2005; Women's Issues Caucus Girls' Nite Out 18 October 2005; Pay-Equity Bake Sale 19 October 2005; Once Were Warriors showing 19 October 2005; Sherry Wolf "Whatever Happened to Feminism?" 25 October 2005; Women's Studies and Women's Center Annual Holiday Party 16 December 2005; Jane: An Abortion Service showing 23 January 2006; The Female Orgasm Event 31 January 2006; Spring 2006 RAD Women's Self Defense Training; UIS Counseling Center B.E.A.D. Project; Go Red for Women Brown Bag Lunch 6 February 2006; Valentine Cookie Baking 12 February 2006; Vagina Monologues 18 February 2006; Zakia Salime "Feminization of Islamist Women and the Power of Women's Rights" 8 March 2006; UIS Health Fair Quiz 5 April 2006; Women's Center Annual Spring Reception and Naomi B. Lynn Award 25 April 2006AY 2006-07Folder 5800965Scope and ContentsWhistleSTOP Safety Program; A Year of Ecofeminism; First Year Orientation Materials; Deborah Kuhn McGregor "The Ecology of Childbirth: Vitamin D Deficiency Rickets and Cesarean Section" 19 October 2006; The Clothesline Project 20 October 2006; Toxic Bust showing 26 October 2006; Commute the Art of Katerie Gladdys 6 November 2006; Women's Center and Women's Studies Annual Holiday Party 14 December 2006; Spring 2007 RAD Women's Self Defense; Robert Kuhn McGregor "Mary Austin's The Land of Little Rain" 21 February 2007; Rising Up of the Springdale Ladies Aid Society 31 March 2007; Gloria Lopez "Women at the Front of the Global Economy" 16 April 2007; Women's Center Annual Spring Reception 2007 May 1AY 2007-08Folder 6800976Scope and ContentsWomen's Issues Caucus We Believe Campaign Statement; 2007 Annual Oxfam Hunger Banquet 14 November 2007; Women and Gender Studies and the Women's Center Annual Holiday Party 2007 December 14; Spring 2008 RAD Women's Self Defense; Dr. Jean Kilbourne "Deadly Persuasion: Advertising and the Corruption of Relationships" 4 March 2008; Jan Goff-LaFontaine art show 4 April 2008; Naomi B. Lynn Awards 1 May 2008AY 2008-09Folder 7800987Scope and ContentsUIS Women's Center Open House 24 August 2008; Fall 2008 RAD Women's Self-Defense Training; Love Your Body Day Fair 18 October 2008; Healing Waters "I Will Carry My Sister's Pain" 30 October 2008; Women's Center and Women and Gender Studies Annual Holiday Party 12 December 2008; Spring 2009 RAD Women's Self-Defense Training; "Oh, The People You'll Meet" Workshop 8 February 2009; Michelle Garcia "Stalking Victimization in the United States" 15 April 2009; Clothesline Project 20 April 2009; Women's Center Annual Spring Reception 29 April 2009; UIS/LLCC 2nd Annual Take Back the Night 2 May 2009AY 2009-10Folder 8800998Scope and ContentsWomen's Center Friday Girl Talk; Wii Wednesday in the Women's Center; "Oh, the People You'll Meet!" workshop materials; Girls Under the Hood 8 October 2009; Love Your Body Day 21 October 2009; Friday Girl Talk- Music 6 November 2009; $tart $mart 29 January 2010; Spring 2010 RAD Women's Self Defense; Women's Issues Caucus Hot Chocolate Meet N' Greet 4 February 2010; Sara Evans "Women Candidates for the American Presidency" ECCE 24 March 2010; Take Back the Night 30 April 2010AY 2010-11Folder 9801009Scope and ContentsTGIF General Flyer; Women's Center General Flyer; Friday Girl Talk Flyer; UIS Women's Center Open House 24 August 2010; Lorena Johnson "Dark Night of the Soul" art show 30 September 2010; Campaign Against Gender Violence Planning Meeting 18 November 2010; Spring 2011 RAD Women's Self Defense Training; February TGIF Flyer; Henna Hands and Friends TGIF 11 February 2011; Chicks with Sticks Knitting TGIF 25 February 2011; Consent is Sexy Luau 7 April 2011; Selena ​movie and discussion TGIF 8 April 2011; Clothesline Project 18 April 2011; Take Back the Night 29 April 2011AY 2011-12Folder 108010110Scope and ContentsFirst Year Orientation Materials; Women's Center Open House 25 August 2011; Fall 2011 RAD Women's Self Defense; Dorm Decor TGIF 2 September 2011; Braid 'n Relax TGIF 30 September 2011; Dating Shouldn't Hurt 12 October 2011; "Female Mutilation: A Global Health Issue" 27 October 2011; Miss Representation showing 6 November 2011; Love Your Body Day 7 November 2011; What to Do if Someone Discloses a Sexual Assault to You training 27 January 2012; Chicks with Sticks Knitting TGIF 3 February 2012; Spring 2012 RAD Women's Self Defense; Persepolis movie and discussion TGIF 2 March 2012; Consent is Sexy Luau 29 March 2012; Tech for Just Us Girls 31 March 2012; Dr. David Lisak "Confronting the Realities of Sexual Violence in the University Community" ECCE 11 April 2012; International Women Talk 16 April 2012; Take Back the Night 20 April 2012AY 2012-13Folder 118010211Scope and ContentsWomen's Center open Sundays Flyer; Register to Vote in Sangamon County 30 August 2012; Women's Center Open House 30 August 2012; "This is What a Feminist Looks Like" t-shirt sale 30 August 2012; Dorm Decor TGIF 31 August 2012; Fall 2012 RAD Women's Self Defense; Half the Sky showing 1 October 2012; The Yellow Wallpaper showing and discussion ECCE event 7 October 2012; Barbie For President TGIF 12 October 2012; Make A Mask and Be a Goddess TGIF 26 October 2012; Women's Center Finals Study Hours 2012; ERA Event 7 December 2012; Knitting and Crochet TGIF 14 December 2012; Glitter Yourself TGIF 25 January 2013; Mehndi Hands and Friends TGIF 1 February 2013; Spring 2013 RAD Women's Self Defense; Make a Valentine Sunday- Undated; One Billion Rising 14 February 2013; Susan B Anthony TGIF 15 February 2013; Knitting and Crochet TGIF 24 February 2013; Feminist TGIF 30 March 2013; Clothesline Project 5 April 2013; 10 Paper Cranes to Heal the Violence April 2013; Into the Fire ECCE film and discussion 15 April 2013; Take Back the Night 19 April 2013; Secret Journal cardAY 2013-14Folder 128010312Scope and ContentsAll n'1 Global Sisterhood meeting 29 October 2013; Dorm Decor TGIF 16 September 2013; Fall 2013 RAD Women's Self Defense; Knit and Crochet TGIF 13 September 2013; Alan Berkowitz "Best Practices in Sexual Assault Prevention for Student Affairs Staff and Student Leaders" 20 September 2013; Cell Phone Drive October 2013; Women's Issues Caucus Meet and Greet 1 October 2013; After School TGIF 4 October 2013; Gharba and Bollywood Dance Lessons 8 October 2013; Dandiya Stick TGIF 11 October 2013; Make a Mask, Be a Goddess TGIF 25 October 2013; Empowered Halloween 31 October 2013; Christina M Martinez 4 November 2013; Knit and Crochet TGIF 15 November 2013; Friendship Bracelets TGIF 31 January 2014; Spring 2014 RAD Women's Self Defense; Mehndi Hands and Friends TGIF 7 February 2014; Dr. Aisha Durham "Hip Hop Feminism" ECCE speaker 26 February 2014; 10 Paper Cranes to Heal the Violence TGIF 4 April 2014; Maquilapolis: City of Factories showing 8 April 2014; Take Back the Night 25 April 2014; Bollywood Dance TGIF 2 May 2014AY 2014-15Folder 138010413Scope and ContentsHappy Fridays TGIF General Flyer; Women's Center Open House 25 August 2014; Dandiya Stick TGIFs 19 &amp; 26 September 2014; Durga Dance Night 3 October 2014; Cross Stitch TGIF 17 October 2014; Make a Mask Be a Goddess TGIF 31 October 2014; Dating Shouldn't Hurt 11 November 2014; Knit and Crochet TGIF 14 November 2014; Holiday Crafts TGIF 5 December 2014; Spring 2015 RAD Women's Self Defense; UIS Global Sisterhood Open House 30 January 2015; Chess TGIF 6 February 2015; Lunar New Year TGIF 13 February 2015; Knit and Crochet TGIF 20 February 2015; Mehndi Hands and Friends TGIF 27 February 2015; Learn to Meditate General Flyer; Kokeshi Dolls TGIF 6 March 2015; Brunch With Global Sisterhood March 2015; Atty. Jody Raphael "Sex Trafficking in Illinois" ECCE speaker 24 March 2015; Paper Cranes and Clothesline Project TGIF 17 April 2015; Quotation flyer, 13 January 2015; Quotation flyer, 20 January 2015; Quotation flyer, 27 January 2015; Quotation flyer, 3 February 2015; Quotation flyer, 10 February 2015; Quotation flyer, 17 February 2015; Quotation flyer, 9 March 2015AY 2015-16Folder 148011514Scope and ContentsTGIF: Make Dorm Decor 28 August 2015; My Dream of Peace Whiteboard Campaign 11-21 September 2015; TGIF: Mehndi Hands and Friends 18 September 2015; Peace Day 21 September 2015; Durga Dance 23 October 2015; TGIF: Make A Mask, Be A Goddess 30 October 2015; Mindfulness- Loving Kindness 11 November 2015; TGIF: Craft Your Finals Stress Away 4 December 2015; RAD Women's Self Defense Training February 2016; Quotation flyer, 2 September 2015; Quotation flyer, 2 September 2015; Quotation flyer. 16 September 2015; Quotation flyer, 23 September 2015; Quotation flyer, 30 September 2015; Quotation flyer, 7 October 2015; Quotation flyer, 14 October 2015; Quotation flyer, 27 October 2015; Quotation flyer, 4 November 2015; Quotation flyer, 11 November 2015; Quotation flyer, 18 November 2015; Quotation flyer, 25 November 2015; Quotation flyer, 2 December 2015; Quotation flyer, 9 December 2015; Quotation flyer, 16 December 2015; Quotation flyer, 23 December 2015; Quotation flyer, 24 February 2016; Quotation flyer, 2 March 2016; Quotation Flyer, 23 March 2016; Quotation flyer, 30 March 2016; Quotation flyer, 6 April 2016; Quotation flyer, 13 April 2016; Quotation flyer, 20 April 2016; Quotation flyer, 27 April 2016; Quotation flyer, 11 May 2016; Quotation flyer, undated.AY 2016-17Folder 158180915Women's Center meditation flyers, AY 2015-2016Folder 168181316Women's Center &amp; TARA Meditation Club flyers, fall 2016Folder 178181717Women's Center &amp; TARA Meditation Club flyers, spring 2017Folder 188182118Box 2Box 283436Women's Center miscellaneous documents and publicationsFolder 1834411996-20171Women's Center event photographsFolder 283446c. 1998-20032Women's Center videos: slideshow and One Billion Rising DanceFolder 38345120133Scope and ContentsThe slideshow disc may be corrupted.Women's Center event flyers and event postingsFolder 483456n.d.4Women's Center office hours postingsFolder 583461n.d.5Box 3Box 383466Poster: Elevate the VoteItem 18347120171Illinois Equal Rights Amendment (ERA) scrapbook and photograph albumItem 28347619822Scope and ContentsThis scapbook was created by SSU/UIS employee Sherri Boner. It includes a folder with unused clippings, 1982-2003.Bundle containing oversize postersItem 4834814Poster: Zarai and Nestora, 48" x 82"Item 183486201341Poster: UIS Chancellor Susan J. Koch, 48" x 111"Item 283491201342Poster: Stephanie, 24" x 99"Item 383496201343Poster: Carmelita, 48" x 102"Item 483501201344Poster: Bridget, 48" x 88"Item 583506201345

