<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.82Archon Finding Aid Title MC.82UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:02:41 -0400.engother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC82. Chandler Family Letters, 1850-1874
    
      Chandler Family
    
    MC.82
    2
    
      0.16 Cubic Feet
    
    1850-1874
    Date acquired: 00/00/1981
    MC82
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Letters of the Chandler family of Chandlerville, Illinois, largely between Louisa Chandler Frackleton and members of her family.  Correspondents include Louisa's father, Dr. Charles Chandler (1806-1879); her mother Clarysa Chandler; her brothers Charles E. and Harrison T. Chandler; and her cousin Calvin E. Child. Also included is one page from an account ledger,  a newspaper article, a photograph of Dr. Chandler, and a "Historical Vignette" on Dr. Chandler, the founder of Chandlerville, Cass County, Illinois. 
25 items  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Mrs. O. Dorr, Dr. Emmet Pearson  
  
    Existence and Location of Originals
The Chandler Family Letters (MC 82) have been added to the CARLI Digital Collections.  They have been scanned and uploaded to be viewed in their original state.  A transcript of each letter is displayed next to the original document.  A link to the collection is listed below.http://www.uis.edu/archives/chandler.php.htm  
  
    Letters
  
  Box 1Box 11470Folder 1Folder 114711Item 1Item 1148411Scope and ContentsCharles Chandler to Emma and Louisa Chandler, ALS, Chandlerville, 23 Dec 1850.  Chandler discusses his health, the possible sale of his store, church activities and religious teaching, and the family. 2 leaves, 4 pp.Item 2Item 2148512Scope and ContentsClarysa Chandler to Louisa Chandler, ALS, Chandlerville, 26 January 1851.  Chandler discusses hired help, her children's education, family, and the Preacher's Sunday sermon.  4 pp.Item 3Item 3148613Scope and ContentsCharles Chandler to Emma and Louisa Chandler, ALS, Chandlerville, 1 May 1851.  Chandler discusses the arrangements for his daughters to come home at the end of the school term. 1 pp.Item 4Item 4148714Scope and ContentsAunt Lucy to Louisa Chandler, ALS, Fredonia, 30 June 1851.  Aunt Lucy discusses her son Thomas' health, recalls meeting Louisa, her move and house in Fredonia, Illinois, and her plans for the 4th of July.  4 pp.Item 5Item 5148815Scope and ContentsCharles and Clarysa Chandler to Louisa Chandler, ALS, Chandlerville, 30 Nov 1851.  Chandlers discuss church services and religion, family and home, missing Louisa, new school teacher, and proposed visits to Louisa.  4 pp.Item 6Item 6148916Scope and ContentsCharles Chandler to Louisa Chandler, ALS, Chandlerville, 27 Dec 1851.  Chandler discusses his cold.  1 pp.Item 7Item 7149017Scope and ContentsCharles E. Chandler to Louisa Chandler, ALS, Palmyra, 2 Apr 1852.  Chandler discusses having friends, the horse father gave Louisa, her being sad, and not having written longer letters.  2 pp., envelope.Item 8Item 8149118Scope and ContentsCharles and Clarysa Chandler to Louisa Chandler, ALS, Chandlerville, 20 Apr 1852.  Chandlers discuss Louisa's illness, her studies at Monticello Seminary, their not writing more often, and that they love Louisa. 3 pp., envelope.Item 9Item 9149219Scope and ContentsCharles E. Chandler to Louisa Chandler, ALS, Palmyra, 22 Jan 1853.  Chandler discusses Louisa's illness, weather and mail, and his studies.  2 pp., envelope.Item 10Item 101493110Scope and ContentsCharles Chandler to Louisa Chandler, ALS, Chandlerville, 18 Feb 1853.  Chandler discusses his trip to Springfield, fire in Beardstown, and his friends and family's health.  3 pp.Item 11Item 111494111Scope and ContentsCharles E. Chandler to Louisa Chandler, ALS, Palmyra, 25 Mar 1853.  Chandler discusses his father's visit to him at school in Palmyra, Mo., pies and cakes, and church.  2 pp., envelope.Item 12Item 121495112Scope and ContentsCharles Chandler to Louisa Chandler, ALS, Chandlerville, Sept 1853.  Chandler discusses illnesses, Louisa spending the winter in New York and Lowell, and his peaches and apples.   3 pp.Item 13Item 131496113Scope and ContentsClarysa Chandler to Louisa Chandler, ALS, Chandlerville, 25 Oct ca. 1853.  Chandler discusses her trip into Beardstown, the death of a friend, family and friends visits, church and religious feelings, and Louisa's trip to New York.  4 pp.Folder 2Folder 214722Item 1Item 1149721Scope and ContentsCalvin E. Child to Louisa Chandler, ALS, New York, 25 Jan 1854.  Child discusses his illness, spring vacation, his visit to cousin Julia, snowstorm and sleigh rides, and his slippers.  2 leaves, 7 pp., envelope.Item 2Item 2149822Scope and ContentsHarrison T. Chandler to Louisa Chandler, ALS, Chandlerville, 2 Feb 1854.  Chandler discusses the family, Jane's baby, religion, and his hope to see Louisa soon.  3 pp., envelope.Item 3Item 3149923Scope and ContentsCharles and Clarysa Chandler to Louisa Chandler, ALS, Chandlerville, 5 Feb 1854.  Chandlers discuss their trip to Beardstown, Jane's baby, and the new houses and church in Chandlerville. 4 pp.Item 4Item 4150024Scope and ContentsCharles E. Chandler to Louisa Chandler, ALS, Chandlerville, 16 Mar 1854.  Chandler discusses the Gage family's concert, mother and father's trip to St. Louis, and Jane's baby.  3 pp., envelope.Item 5Item 5150125Scope and ContentsOne page of ledger of accounts, 1858Item 6Item 6150226Scope and ContentsCharles Chandler to Louisa Chandler, ALS, Chandlerville, 15 Jan 1871.  Chandler discusses his illness and remedies, his trip to Springfield, and the death of a friend.  2 leaves, 4 pp.Item 7Item 7150327Scope and ContentsCharles Chandler to Louisa Chandler, ALS, Chandlerville, 10 Nov 1874.  Chandler discusses his family and their health, obtaining photographs of all his grandchildren, and being sad and lonely.  4 pp.Item 8Item 8150428Scope and ContentsCharles Chandler to Louisa Chandler, ALS, Chandlerville, 6 Dec 1874.  Chandler discusses sending a box of goblets and a silver pitcher to Louisa, how lonely and sad he is by his wife's death and the support of children and grandchildren, his health, and the family.  4 pp.Item 9Item 9150529Scope and ContentsAunt to Nephew, ALS, Chandlerville, 27 Mar ca. 1870s.  Aunt discusses her nephew's previous letter, the Scaggfamily, Aunt's cousins, Aunt Emma, and Grandpa, and her trip to Jacksonville.  2 leaves, 6 pp.Item 10Item 101506210Scope and ContentsHistorical Vignette, Dr. Charles Chandler of Chandlerville, Illinois, n.d., photocopyItem 11Item 111507211Scope and ContentsNewspaper article, "The Cenotaph at Chandlerville: Last Summer in a Cemetery Jim Krohe Found a Spot for Dreamers," Illinois Times, January 6-12, 1978 (photocopy)Folder 3Folder 314733Photograph of a Picture of Dr. Charles Chandler, n.d.Item 1148331

