<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>N.03.0Archon Finding Aid Title N.03.0Stephen GiffordUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:53:17 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    N03. Springfest Flags and Posters
    N.03.0
    1871
    
      12.00 items
    
    2007-2017
    Date acquired: 04/26/2017
    Items 8-11
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The collection includes flags produced by student teams participating in Springfest for the years 2011-2017, as well as posters created from photos taken during Springfests from 2007-2011. Since 1992 Student Life has hosted Springfest, an annual team competition as a pre-finals week stress release event. Springfest competitions include several events, including: Flag and Chant, Scavanger Hunt, and Sports Day, which culminates with a tug-of-war tourney. Flags are produced by teams and follow annual Springfest themes and also typically include photographs and names of students on each team. The flags were used as part of Springfest's competetion where teams were judged based on flag design and construction. Teams accumulate points based on competitions of the week and winners are announced at the end of the week.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Individual flags are wrapped in acid free paper and placed on shelves. Posters are filed in oversize drawers.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Mary Umbarger, Student Life  
  
    Accruals and Additions
Added Springfest 2017 flag (item 12), 11/16/17.  
  
    Custodial History
Student Life 2007-2017, UIS Archives 2017  
  
    Processing Information
Flags wrapped in acid free paper, folded, stored flat on shelves in LIB 140C.  
  Killer Kirby Squad FlagItem 18166620111Scope and Contents48 x 36, One SidedAquaholicman and his 14 Fantastic Locos FlagItem 28167120112Scope and Contents41 x 36, one SidedX-Men in Black FlagItem 38167620113Scope and Contents50 x 38, one sided, includes electric lightsPlayer 1 FlagItem 48168120UU4Scope and Contents40 x 42, one SidedSwagger Jackers FlagItem 58168620135Scope and Contents46 x 36, one SidedTracker Jackers FlagItem 68169120136Scope and Contents50 x 36, one SidedThe Nostalgia Squad FlagItem 78169620117Scope and Contents48 x 36, two SidedSpringfest PosterItem 88170120078Scope and Contents20 x 30Springfest PosterItem 98170620099Scope and Contents20 x 30Springfest PosterItem 1081711201110Scope and Contents20 x 30Springfest PosterItem 1181716201011Bubble Buddies FlagItem 1285891201712Scope and ContentsOne-sided. Winning flag Springfest 2017.

