<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.52.Ayers, M.Archon Finding Aid Title J.52.Ayers, M.UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:08:35 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J52/Ayers, M. Student Papers, Public Affairs Program, 1973-1977
    
      Ayers, Michael
    
    J.52.Ayers, M.
    648
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1973-1977
    Date acquired: 03/17/1980
    1
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The papers in this series are centered on Springfield, Illinois.  Topics include: desegregation of schools, operation of the Regional Planning Commission; housing; hospital care; the Park District; planning for Southwest High School; coal mining; Lake Springfield; Sangamon Electric;  the Exposition and Auditorium Authority; Concordia Seminary; City, Water Light &amp; Power ,  massage parlors.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Michael Ayers  
  
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 141358Ceperich, Pat, The Monitoring Commission and Desegregation in the Springfield SchoolsFolder 141359July 19771Finch, David L., The Springfield-Sangamon County Regional Planning CommissionFolder 2413601973-08-172Gasparin, S. Rick, Housing in SpringfieldFolder 3413613Hall, Jeffrey P., The Availability of Hospital Care in Springfield, Illinois, PAC 416Folder 441362August 19774Hoffman, Jim, The Springfield Park District, PAC 416Folder 5413631977-07-315Klickna, Marjorie A., Southwest High School - An Improbability, PAC 416Folder 6413641977-08-016Kushak, Marilyn A., An analysis of Springfield Vocational Training Opportunities, PAC 416Folder 7413651977-07-077Lewis, Sheila, Massage Parlors: Influence on the CommunityFolder 8413668Maggio, Patricia Ann, A History of Coal Mining in Springfield, PAC 416Folder 9413679Reinhard, Harry, Lake Springfield II, PAC 416Folder 104136810Robb, Emmett T. Jr., Sangamo--Its History and Place in Our Community, PAC 416Folder 11413691977-08-0311Rudin, A.C. Jr., Springfield Metropolitan Exposition and Auditorium AuthorityFolder 124137012Schroader, Elbert I., The History of Concordia Theological Seminary, Springfield, IllinoisFolder 134137113Sporte, Susan E., A Brief Survey of People's Attitudes Toward Public Education in SpringfieldFolder 144137214Vu, Hung Manh, Income Distribution for Springfield, PAC 416Folder 15413731977-08-0115Waters, David J., City Water, Light and Power Electric ServiceFolder 164137416

