<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.01.01/05 Series IIArchon Finding Aid Title J.01.01/05 Series IIChris SchnellUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 17:58:14 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J1/1/5. John Keiser Papers, 1970-1995. Series II
    J.01.01/05 Series II
    1898
    
      0.50 Cubic Feet
    
    1970-1995
    1971-1978
    Date acquired: 04/19/2017
    1 Box
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Papers of John Keiser, member of SSU History faculty, 1970-1978, and Vice-President for Academic Affairs, 1971-1978.Speech drafts, official memos, letters, tenure self-evaluations, and clippings concerning Keiser's career as a SSU history professor and in SSU administration. Includes Keiser's hard-bound compilation of his addresses to faculty (1971-1978), a hard-bound, unpublished manuscript describing faculty unrest at Eastern Illinois University (where Keiser taught before his career at SSU), as well as his remarks presented at each of SSU commencements, 1972-1978 (tipped into each respective commencement booklet).Three anti-Keiser faculty protest placards are included in this collection are foldered on the shelf next to box 1. A commemorative paperwieght (Lincoln Land Community College groundbreaking, 1970) included in the donation was transferred to V1 Artifacts Collection.See also J1/1/6  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronoglogical  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Nancy Keiser (widow)  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Unsolicited donation.  
  
    Custodial History
Nancy Keiser had identified among her husband's personal effects these items specific to John H. Keiser's career at SSU. She called and obtained permission to send them to be processed and housed at UIS Archives/Special Collections. The donor placed no requirements or restrictions upon the collection.  
  
    Papers
    Speeches
    Reports
    Posters
    Newspaper Clippings
  
  Box 1Box 182134Personal Clippings from SSUFolder 1821381970-19951Tenure documents and self-evaluationsFolder 2821421972-19772Commencement remarksFolder 3821461972-19783The Trouble at Ambraw UniversityFolder 48215019704Scope and ContentsAt the back of this bound volume are several original poems written by Keiser.Opening addresses to Sangamon State Univeristy FacultyFolder 5821541971-19775Scope and ContentsThis hard-bound compilation also includes Keiser's one "State of the University" address while he was acting president in 1978.Speeches and memosFolder 68215819716Speeches and memosFolder 78216219727Speeches and memosFolder 88216619738Speeches and memosFolder 9821701974-19759Speeches and memosFolder 1082174197610Speeches and memosFolder 1182178197711Speeches and memosFolder 1282182197812Anti-Keiser, faculty protest placardsFolder 1382186n. d.13Scope and ContentsThese items are foldered and located next to Box 1 on the shelf.

