<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.52.Breiseth, C. Series IArchon Finding Aid Title J.52.Breiseth, C. Series IUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:08:37 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J52/Breiseth, C. Student Papers, Interracial Education Program (Summer) 1974 Series I
    
      Breiseth, Christopher
    
    J.52.Breiseth, C. Series I
    649
    
      0.66 Cubic Feet
    
    Date acquired: 08/26/1974
    1
    2
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Student papers produced for Summer Institute on Interracial Education, PAC 425. Taught by Chris Breiseth, Judy Everson, Gus Stevens, and James Pancrazio during the summer semester, 1974.  Areas of study and research included athletics, minorities, Afro-American studies, black history, black poetry, Springfield Illinois, Washington Middle School,  and interracial education.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Chris Breiseth, Marilyn Davis  
  
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 141375Adams, Rosia Lee.   Promoting Cross-Cultural Insights Through Sewing at Washington Middle SchoolFolder 1413761Athoff, John; Bradshaw, Jerry and Nelson, Richard.   Introduction to Jacksonville, Illinois:  A High School Teaching UnitFolder 2413772Anderson, Wm. "Joe".   Athletic Activities and Human Dynamics on an Interracial Basis After SchoolFolder 3413783Banks, Edna.   Guidance Program for TeachersFolder 4413794Betts, Pauline.   Helping Minority Students to Become Aware of Vocational Courses and Work Programs Available at the High School LevelFolder 5413805Bundy, Wilma.   Introduction to Middle School Via ScienceFolder 6413816Bynum, Ray L.   Early African and Afro-American HistoryFolder 7413827Cadagin, Sally.   Multi-Racial/Multi-Ethnic MathematicsFolder 8413838Carswell, Evelyn.  I and Mine, You and Yours, We and OursFolder 9413849Coffman, Ronald C.   Facilitating Equalitarian Attitudes in the Uniracial Secondary SchoolFolder 104138510Colburn, Patrece and Hoech, Marvin.   Resource Information to Help Meet the Health Concerns of "Minorities" in the ClassroomFolder 114138611Conner, Susan and Rowe, Larry.  Employment GuideFolder 124138712Cruzan, Walter.   Career Education in an Elementary SettingFolder 134138813Davis, Zyronious B.   Introducing to Washington Middle School Girls the Most Acceptable Sports by Females and How They BeganFolder 144138914Scope and ContentsClassroom UnitDeimel, Gilbert F.   A Catalogue of Available Materials Relevant to Providing a Racially Integrated K-5 Educational ProgramFolder 154139015Elliott, Lillie S.   Discovery, Slaves, and Economics: A Unit PlanFolder 164139116Ford, Thomas.   Racial Minority Membership in the Lanphier Band - A Critical ViewFolder 174139217Fox, Marion F.   Some Guidelines for Teacher Speech/Attitudes in Interpersonal Relationships with StudentsFolder 184139318Garber, Albert L. and Garber, Muriel G.   Proposal for Demostration of and Use of Simulation Games in the Classroom to Achieve Objectives Discussed in the InstituteFolder 194139419Gieseking, Allan R.; Pool, Frances J.; Webster, Charles M. and Young, Robert A.   Interpersonal CommunicationFolder 204139520Gipson, Virginia Jeffries.   Interracial Education Project, Supplementary UnitFolder 214139621Goodwin, Margaret J.   A Unit on Black History for Black History WeekFolder 224139822Grammer, Bobbie and Noland, Anne.   Brotherhood and Understanding - The BeginningFolder 234139923Greenwood, Cherie.   Examining the "White Supremacy" Theory in the United States History ClassFolder 244140024Gumble, Jane M.   Cross Cultural Education Curriculum Focused for Grade 2Folder 254140125Harlan, Linda Faye.   Selected Materials Relevant to Social Studies and Interpersonal Relations for Integrated Elementary SchoolsFolder 264140226Box 2Box 241403Hawkins, Lester.   An Attempt to Produce a Multi-Ethnic Audio/Visual Presentation by Combining Mono-Ethnic Visual MaterialsFolder 1414041Heiss, Marjorie.   Poster Media Project, Famous AmericansFolder 2414052Hudson, Shirley.   The Use of Black Biographies - A BeginningFolder 3414063Johnson, Frances C.   Who Am I?Folder 4414074Scope and ContentsSelf-Awareness and Personal Identity in Primary School ChildrenKnapp, Colleen and Drake, Majel.   Improving Interracial Understanding at Jonathan Turner Junior High SchoolFolder 5414085Marquette, Nancy.   The People BookFolder 6414096Scope and ContentsPurpose of the book is to promote racial understanding among K-5 children with learning disabilitiesMcCord, Robert P.   The Black Experience in the United States ArmyFolder 7414107McGee, Constance.   Black American History to be Used in Connection with Fifth Grade Social StudiesFolder 8414118McGinnis, Robert C.   Trolley History of Springfield (Illinois)Folder 9414129Meyer, Pam.   Communication: A Set of Lesson Plans for Use in the Secondary SchoolFolder 104141310Nelson, Annette.   Untitled Interracial Institute ProjectFolder 114141411Page, Joyce.   A Unit to Teach Some of the Contributions of BlacksFolder 124141512Parienti, Max V.   Participation in Student Government at Springfield High School: A Study in ContrastFolder 134141613Parson, K.R.   Sixteen Black Female Poets - Ebonized InkFolder 144141714Robinson, Jean J.   Great Blacks of the Past and PresentFolder 154141815Rodes, Janice and Cain, Rodney.   A Catalogue of Audio/Visual Materials, Records, and Books Relevant to Black MusicFolder 164141916Schultz, Marvin L.   Academic and Vocational DecisionsFolder 174142017Stephenson, Karen.   Raging Cries/Whisper of LoveFolder 184142118Sullivan, Gary G.   A Survey of Attitudes of Parents Toward Withrow Elementary School and the Formation of a Parent Advisory CommitteeFolder 194142219Szabo, Charlotte.   A Photographic Slide Presentation of Selected People and Events in the History of Black AmericansFolder 204142320Terrell, Joan F.   Autour Du Monde on Parle FrancaisFolder 214142421Tillman, Caroline.   Selected Annotated Bibliography of the Black Experience for Edison Middle SchoolFolder 224142522Toland, Rosemary K.   Enhancing the Self Concept of Elementary Age ChildrenFolder 234142623Westwater, Jack.   The Afro-American in United States HistoryFolder 244142724Williams, K.S.   Helping to Understand Oneself Through SongsFolder 254142825Woijeck, Cindy.   A Nine Week Unit Plan in MinoritiesFolder 264142926Woods, Doris R.   A Study of Black PoetryFolder 274143027Zobrist, Larry.   An Enrichment for Fifth Grade Social StudiesFolder 284143128

