<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>O.D618Archon Finding Aid Title O.D618UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:08:47 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    Dinsmore, R.T. (Robert Truman)  (1885-1982): Interview and memoir
    
      Dinsmore, R.T. (Robert Truman)
    
    
      Boren, Michael
    
    O.D618
    1084
    
      18.00 items
    
    Dummy Date
    Tapes et al
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Dinsmore, central Illinois newspaperman and printer, discusses his work on small weekly newspapers he owned and edited in central Illinois and Missouri and his experiences working as a printing foreman for Springfield newspapers the Journal, the Register, the Citizens Tribune, and the Journal Register. He recalls late 19th century life in Nebo, Illinois, including the citizens, businesses, social activities, and transportation including train service, buggies, steamer and packet services; education, religion, and social customs including the use of tobacco and liquor; family issues, relationship of husband and wife, home life, homemade foods, childbirth, and childrearing; health issues, medicine, and dentistry. He also discusses his experiences with a band on the Chautauqua circuit and on an excursion boat, service during WWI with the U.S. Treasury Department, the Depression, U.S. presidents, technological changes, Civil War Veterans, people in New Canton, 1899 fire at Nebo and reconstruction, Farmer's Ridge, automobiles, Springfield in the 1920's, and Illinois politicians. 17 tapes, 930 mins., 4 vols., 304 pp. 
Interview by Michael Boren, 1979 
OPEN 
See collateral file: interviewer's notes, photographs, and newspaper articles about Dinsmore  
  
    Related Materials
Interview and Memoir in Illinois Digital Archives.http://www.idaillinois.org/u?/uis,1869  
  

