<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.52.Breiseth, C. Series IIArchon Finding Aid Title J.52.Breiseth, C. Series IIUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:08:54 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J52/Breiseth, C. Student Papers, Black History/Race Issues, 1971-1979 Series II
    
      Breiseth, Christopher
    
    J.52.Breiseth, C. Series II
    650
    
      0.49 Cubic Feet
    
    1971-1979
    Date acquired: 07/10/1980
    1
    2
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The student papers in this series were prepared for "Toward Racial Equality" (1972), "Personalities of Revolutionaries" (1972), History Colloquium (1972), and "Melting Pot Reconsidered" (1972,1975, 1976).
Subjects include ethnic cultures (Mexican Americans, Indians, blacks, etc.), racism, Illinois and U.S. history, and biographies of revolutionaries (Castro, Marx, etc.).  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical by author  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Chris Breiseth  
  
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 141502Anderson, Steven E.   Freedom vs. Organized LaborFolder 1415031Anker, Hans.   Senior Learner (History of Anker Photo Studio, Springfield, IL)Folder 2415042Bates, Alice Frances.   Indian Education in AmericaFolder 3415053Benton, William E.   Cultural Heritage of the American IndianFolder 4415064Bosen, Ann Elizabeth.   Toward Racial EqualityFolder 5415075Burke, Janet G.   The White Man's Contribution to the Culture of the Plains IndianFolder 6415086Bunn, Deborah.   Red PowerFolder 7415097Bunn, Deborah.   The Redemption of the Radical Republican: Thaddeus StevensFolder 8415108Cavallo, Angela.   The "Little Yellow Men" and Their 742 MilesFolder 9415119Collins, Margaret.   NegroFolder 104151210Compton, Dave E.   Karl MarxFolder 114151311Damashek, Lois.  Trends in the Education of Mexican-American ChildrenFolder 124151412Davenport, Lott.  Black Economic Disparity and the American Power StructureFolder 134151513Davies, Susan L.   Educational Programs Offered by the Department of CorrectionsFolder 144151614Scope and ContentsEmphasis on New Salem School CampDiamond, David R.   These, too, Must be Equal:  America's Needs in Habilitation &amp; Employment of the Mentally RetardedFolder 154151715Flowers, Curt.   Simon Bolivar-The LiberatorFolder 164151816Gardiner, Gerry.   Industrial Working Conditions in Springfield circa 1920Folder 174151917Garvey Jr., Hugh J.   Untitled (Assimilation)Folder 184152018Geick, Cindy.  Frederick DouglassFolder 195021319Greenwood, Cherie.   Cesar Chavez and the United Farm Workers AFL-C10Folder 204152120Hammond, Paul.   Economic OpportunityFolder 214152221Harris, Carrie.   NegroFolder 224152322Harris, Carrie.   A Political Biography of Angela DavisFolder 234152423Hayes, Jay F.   Public Housing ProjectsFolder 244152524Hill, Robert.   Ending Racism in American Education: Proposals for ActionFolder 254152625Hoffman, Kathy.   Available WelfareFolder 264152726Holcomb, Virginia.   Blacks in America: A Revolutionary SituationFolder 274152827Holroyd, Bruce.   Project History ColloquiumFolder 284152928Hopkins, Dottie.   Unrest and Tragedy (Mormons in Illinois)Folder 294153029Kazeliski, Jon C.   Springfield Race Riot, 1908Folder 304153130Keating, William G.   The Third ReichFolder 314153231Koltun, Michael J.   DOBRY: An Examination into the Contemporary Situation of a Slovak-American FamilyFolder 324153332Kording, Robert Louis.   The Strange Career of C. Vann WoodwardFolder 334153433Lake, Clark.   Scottsboro CaseFolder 344153534Lake, Clark.   The White School District and Its Role in the Changing WorldFolder 354153635Lanich, Alice.   You've Come a Long Way, Baby: A Personal Discussion of the Effects of the Melting Pot ReconsideredFolder 364153736Lanich, Alice.   Springfield in Black and White: Housing Patterns in 1907Folder 374153837Lowe, Richard.   Fidel CastroFolder 384153938Lowe, Richard.  The Negro Soldier During the Civil WarFolder 394154039Lowe, Rick.   The Battle on the Little BighornFolder 404154140Lozano, Norma J.   Prisons and the Need for ReformFolder 414154241Mack, Gerald O'Connor.   Racism in the ClassroomFolder 424154342McGrath, Mary Evelyn.   One Hundred Years of Conflict, The Negro versus the Labor FederationsFolder 434154443McGuire, Judith Mary Becker.   The Vietnamese Refugees in AmericaFolder 444154544Meyer, Unknown.   Untitled (People's Republic of China and Mao Tse-tung)Folder 454154645Miller, Debbie.   The Black Experience and the Role of the Black MinisterFolder 464154746Moore, Bill.   The Black Experience in the Civil WarFolder 474154847Nelson, Errol P.   Business Leadership:  Make Room for BlacksFolder 484154948Osler, Roynold.   Jim CrowismFolder 494155049Penn, Wallace A.   The Puerto Rican-American ExperienceFolder 504155150Box 2Box 241552Pensoneau, Judith L.   The Mexican-American StruggleFolder 1415531Peters, Connie.   Untitled (German Heritage)Folder 2502142Poole, Brenda.   The Black Union Soldier in the Civil WarFolder 3415543Ransford, Charles E.   Attitude Changes Needed in Teacher RetrainingFolder 4415554Roberts, Diana.   The Beginning of Christ's RevolutionFolder 5415565Rountree, Georgia.   The Racial Issue and Busing in Springfield, Illinois District 186Folder 6415576Ruwe, Marie.   A Progress Report: Public Housing in Springfield, Illinois, 1961-1971Folder 7415587Sarff, Meg.   Suppression and Censorship: The Velikovsky Controversy in the McCarthy EraFolder 8415598Schussele, Michael J.   The Necessity of Freedom: A Limited Essay into the Philosophy of G.W.F. HegelFolder 9415609Siebert, Sonia V.   An Analysis of Changing Perceptions, Europe 1870-1910Folder 104156110Scope and ContentsWho Was That "Weltanschauung" I Saw You With Last Night?Smith, Robert E.   A New SocietyFolder 114156211Taylor, Michael.   The waiting Wanting (Welfare)Folder 124156312Taylor, Thomas T.   A Policy for EmploymentFolder 134156413Thomas, Judith P.   Untitled (Autobiography of Immigration from Denmark to the United States and Illinois)Folder 144156514Washington, Gwen.   What the White Man has Made of the Black ManFolder 154156615Watts, Gary.   Educational ObjectivesFolder 164156716Watts, Gary.   The Menominees - Death of a NationFolder 174156817Webster, Louis.   White Racism in AmericaFolder 184156918Wood, Kathy.   A Revolution for Human Dignity (Cesar Chavez)Folder 194157019Zeidler, Carl.   Welfare ExperienceFolder 204157320Author Unknown.  Examples of Political PrisonersFolder 214157221Author Unknown.   Low to No Income Housing (Springfield, Illinois - John Hay Homes)Folder 224157122

