<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.52.Brown, B.Archon Finding Aid Title J.52.Brown, B.UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:08:59 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J52/Brown, B. Student Papers, Economics, 1970-1974
    
      Brown, Bernard
    
    J.52.Brown, B.
    651
    
      1.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1970-1974
    Date acquired: 06/12/1975
    1
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Student papers produced for Public Economics, Economics of Development, School and Community,  the Budget of the U. S Government, Economics of Education and other courses taught by Bernard Brown, SSU  Professor of  Economics, 1970-74.  See detailed boxlist for particular subjects.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical by author  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Bernard Brown  
  
    Accruals and Additions
Approximately 140 student papers  
  
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 141574Ale, Benjamin K. - Search for Consumer Interest:Folder 1415751Scope and ContentsThe Availability and Quality of Information, Public Economics, Fall 1973. 	14 pg.Atteberry, Bill -Macroeconomic Theory Final Exam. 12 pg.Folder 2415762Atteberry, Bill - Research and EvaluationFolder 3415773Scope and ContentsEconomic Development, Spring 1972, 8 pg.Austiff, Kay - Field Experience: Ball Elementary SchoolFolder 4415784Scope and ContentsSchool and Student, Fall 1971, 23 pg.Austin, Stephen E. - Public School Finance vs. Private School Finance: Who is in the Best Position?Folder 5415795Scope and ContentsEconomics of Education.  11 pg.Bailey, Vincent R. - 1974 and 1973 United States Budget as it Pertains to:Folder 6415806Scope and ContentsNatural Resources and Environment, The Budget of the United States Government, Fall 1972, 12 pg.Becker, Brian - Macroeconomics Theory Final Exam. 11 pg.Folder 7415817Bednar, Leomard Ladislav - Canal Building and Regional Development:Folder 8415828Scope and ContentsA Case Study of the Erie Canal,  A Thesis presented to the Department of Economics, University of Huston, Spring 1970, 73 pg.Boesdorfer, Debbie - Field Experience:Folder 9415839Scope and ContentsAshland Grade School (2nd Grade), School and Student, Fall 1971, 8 pg.Bogart, Clair Marie - Field Experience: Mary Bryant HomeFolder 104158410Scope and ContentsSchool and Community, Spring 1972, 11 pg.Borough, R. L. - O.S.H.A. and Construction MachineryFolder 114158511Scope and ContentsPublic Economics, Fall 1973, 8 pg.Braker, Mary - Head Therapist: A journal, 1972, 8 pg.Folder 124158612Brick, Tom - LLCC East Side Center, 14 pg.Folder 134158713Brick, Tom - Income Security, 10 pg.Folder 144158814Brown, Joe - The Value of a College Degree, 6 pg.Folder 154158915Bullerman, Donald A. - Lincoln Land Community Concert Association,Folder 164159016Scope and ContentsPublic Economics, Fall 1973, 13 pg.Burnett, Emily - Log, School and Community, Fall 1972, 7 pg.Folder 174159117Cinotto, Dale - Transportation Planning for the Urban Area, 16 pg.Folder 184159218Clark, Alonzo - Team Teaching at Decatur-Lakeview High SchoolFolder 194159319Scope and ContentsEconomics of Education, 10 pg.Cleary, Janet - Views of Child Care by the United States Federal GovernmentFolder 204159420Scope and ContentsThe Budget of the United States Government, 10 pg.Crain, Frank J. - I'm Almost There- Was it Worth It?Folder 214159521Scope and ContentsEconomics of Education, Spring 1973, 5 pg.Decar, Dan - Macroeconomics Theory Final Exam, 6 pg.Folder 224159622Daugherty, Mary E. - The Financing of University Student HousingFolder 234159723Scope and ContentsPublic Economics, Spring 1973, 16 pg.Davenport, Cheryl S. - Income Security Programs-Fiscal Year 1974Folder 244159824Scope and ContentsThe Budget of the United States Government, 12 pg.Davis, Linda - Federal and State Governments and Their Relationship to the UniversityFolder 254159925Scope and ContentsStudent, University and Society Class, Fall 1972, 16 pg.Dawson, David D. - The Regulation of Economic Power: A Historical Search for BalanceFolder 264160026Scope and ContentsPublic Economics, Fall 1973, 14 pg.Dooling, L. F. - The Union Baptist Church, Public Economics, 34 pg.Folder 274160127Drennan, Deborah - Field Experience: Child and Family Services of Sangamon CountyFolder 284160228Scope and ContentsSchool and Community, 16 pg.Ealy, Susan - Field Experience: Bunn Elementary SchollFolder 294160329Scope and ContentsSchool and Student, Fall 1972, 16 pg.Eddy, Ralph H. - Field Experience: Dubois Elementary School, 14 pg.Folder 304160430Ellrich, Phillip H. - Economic Stabilization ProgramsFolder 314160531Scope and ContentsPublic Economics, Spring 1973, 17 pg.Enlow, Susan - The First Presbyterian Church, Public Economics 1973, 30 pg.Folder 324160632Esmond, Martha - School and Student, 1971, 15 pg.Folder 334160733Feagan, Jan - Field Experience: Pleasant Plains High SchoolFolder 344160834Scope and ContentsSchool and Student, Fall 1971, 18 p.Ferry, Jack - An Analysis of the Retired Senior Volunteer Program, 100 pg.Folder 354160935Flipper, Carl F. - Marketing of Services of the Federal Highway AdministrationFolder 364161036Scope and Contentsby the Urban League of Springfield, Illinois, Public Economics, 1973, 25 pg.Foss, Linda - School and Student Log: Hazel Dell, Fall 1971, 24 pg.Folder 374161137Fricke, John M. - The Provision of a Modern LotteryFolder 384161238Scope and ContentsPublic Economics, 1973, 28 pg plus 8 related brochures.Geicke, Cindy - A Different Drummer, 11 pg.Folder 394161339Geiser, Bill - Organizations in the Future, Spring 1973, 25 pg.Folder 404161440Goff, Julie - Field Experience: Study of Truancy ProblemsFolder 414161541Scope and ContentsSchool and Community, 	22 pg.Goodman, Stephen - Log: Illinois Youth CommissionFolder 424161642Scope and ContentsSchool and Community, 1972, 	17 pg.Goudy, Frank - Statement of Purpose, 25 pg.Folder 434161743Graw, Greg - Boy Scout, 5 pg.Folder 444161844Grimes, Ann - Stonebelt Center, 8 pg.Folder 454161945Gupta, Satinder Nath - India: Economic Development, 14 pg.Folder 464162046Haberaecker, Heather - A Comparative Analysis of Organizations and Their EffectivenessFolder 474162147Scope and ContentsPublic Economics, 1974, 21 pg.Haberaecker, Heather - Survey of Public Economics, 5 pg.Folder 484162248Handel, Larry - Macroeconomics Final Exam, 1972, 4 pg.Folder 494162349Hendrickson, John W. - Tovey Education: Yesterday, Today, and TomorrowFolder 504162450Scope and ContentsEconomics of Education, 1974, 12 pg.Herndon, William - Macroeconomics Final Exam, 1972, 3 pg.Folder 514162551Herndon, William - Riverton Rebuild Project, Public Economics, 1973, 12 pg.Folder 524162652Hickerson, Bill - School and Student, 5 pg.Folder 534162753High, Ralph - Illinois Appaloosa Association, 5 pg.Folder 544162854Hines, George - History, Problems and Personal Views of Catholic Education, 19 pg.Folder 554162955Hiskes, Edward - Economic Sketches of RiversideFolder 564163056Scope and Contentsand St. Mary's Hospitals in Kankakee, Illinois, Public Economics, 1973, 19 pg.House, Ed - Latin America, The Economics of Development, 10 pg.Folder 574163157Hudson, Tim - Macroeconomics Final Exam, 6 pg.Folder 584163258Jackson, Clarence - Black Muslims, Where do some of their funds Come From?, 1972, 7 pg.Folder 594163359Jackson, James - Externalities of the Post-Freeze Economic Stabilization ProgramFolder 604163460Scope and ContentsPublic Economics, 11 pgJaniak, Thomas - Notes of Boy Scout Work, 1972, 44 pg.Folder 614163561Jensen, Curtis - Macroeconomics Theory Final Exam, 1972, 5 pg.Folder 624163662Jones, Robert - The Balanced Transportation System, Public Economics, 1973, 20 pg.Folder 634163763Kadow, Roger - Field Experience: Wilcox School, School and Student, 1971, 8 pg.Folder 644163864Keefner, H. E. - Purpose of Education, 32 pg.Folder 654163965Keith, Don - Macroeconomics Final Exam, 14 pg.Folder 664164066Ketchum, Charles - The Economics of Alternatives, Economics of Education, 14 pg.Folder 674164167King, Norman - An Introduction to Planning, Programming, Budgeting SystemFolder 684164268Scope and ContentsBudget of the Federal Government, 1973, 9 pg.Kiska, Alois - Goodwill Industries, Public Economics, 10 pg.Folder 694164369Lane, George - Sunset Lake Association, Public Economics, 1973, 20 pg.Folder 704164470Leone, Tony - The Externalities of the Roman Cultural Society, 9 pg.Folder 714164571Liles, Philip - Congressional AppropriationsFolder 724164672Scope and ContentsThe United States Federal Budget, 1973, 10 pg.McClure, John - Field Experience: Boy's Club, School and Community, 1972, 7 pg.Folder 734164773McGrady, Michael - Specialized Education, Economics of Education, 1973, 9 pg.Folder 744164874McGrath, Dan - Comments on the Budget of the U. S. Government, 1974, 7 pg.Folder 754164975McGrath, Daniel L. - The Impact of Change in Federal Aid on the Elementary and Secondary Education System in IllinoisFolder 764165076Scope and ContentsEconomics of Education, 1973, 14 pg.Maloney, John - The Effect of the Externality of O.S.H.A. on the Construction Equipment IndustryFolder 774165177Scope and ContentsPublic Economics, 1973, 18 pg.Matheis, Steve - A Report on Catholic Charities, Public Economics, 1973, 13 pg.Folder 784165278Mayerle, Charles -Achievement Determinants in EducationFolder 794165379Scope and ContentsEconomics in Education, 1973, 22 pMelton, Larry - Macroeconomics final Exam, 1972, 9 pg.Folder 804165480Menard, Rene - The Mickey Mouse Game, 14 pg.Folder 814165581Miller, Win - A.A. Berle and the New Deal, Management ProgramFolder 824165682Millis, W. E. - A Legacy of Responsibility, Economics of Education, 12 pg.Folder 834165783Monke, Tom - Agricultural Extension Service, Public Economics, 1973, 9 pg.Folder 844165884Mowery, John - The Rodriguez Decision: Impact and MeaningFolder 854165985Scope and ContentsEconomics of Education, 1973, 20 pg.Neat, Bill - Retail Trade- The Benefits and CostFolder 864166086Scope and ContentsPublic Economics, 1973, 14 pg.Nelson, Errol - Economic Stabilization Program, Public Economics, 18 pg.Folder 874166187O'Brien, David - The National Debt, Budget of the U.S. Government, 1973, 13 pg.Folder 884166288Owen, John - The Chandlerville Community Unit District #62 AnalysisFolder 894166389Scope and ContentsEconomics of Education, 1973, 12 pg.Pack, Rebecca -The Animal Protective League of Springfield and Sangamon CountyFolder 904166490Scope and ContentsPublic Economics, 1973, 12 pg.Ping, Janice - Auburn Elementary, School and Student, 1971, 22 pg.Folder 914166591Ping, Janice - Tottle Town, Schol and Student, 1972, 9 pg.Folder 924166692Pohlman, Mary - Analysis of the Economy of a Single School, Economics of Education, 1973, 11 pgs.Folder 934166793Pritchett, Terry - Field Experience: Fairview School, School and Student, 1971, 21 pg.Folder 944166894Quisenberry, C. W. - Economic Development, 1972, 12 pg.Folder 954166995Ragan, John - Industrial Combination and Its Impact on the Individual, Public Economics, 1973, 7 pgs.Folder 964167096Rajaski, John - Continuing Education, Economics of Education, 1973, 13 p.Folder 974167197Redding, Nancy - United Methodist Church, 1972, 8 pFolder 984167298Reddy, Enagala  - Marketing Tortilla In Delhi, Public 	Economics, 1973, 19 pg.Folder 994167399Riemer, James - Illinois Conference of Churches, 1973, 14 pg.Folder 10041674100Roberts, Gary A. - Highlights of the Defense BudgetFolder 10141675101Scope and ContentsThe Budget of the United States Government, Spring 1973, 8 pg.Sartorb, John  8 pg.Folder 10241676102Sasbirca, James A. - Macroeconomics Theory Final exam, 10 pg.Folder 10341677103Scaife, Steven - An Economic Analysis of the Sangamon County Medical SocietyFolder 10441678104Scope and ContentsPublic Economics, Fall 1973, 13 pg.Schmitt, Charles - The Use of Public Economics to Describe Market Inefficiencies in the Labor Market SectorFolder 10541679105Scope and ContentsPublic Economics, Spring 1973, 14 pg.Scott, Don E. - Macroeconomics Theory Final Exam, 12 pg.Folder 10641680106Scott, Don E. - Mexico, Economic development, 13 pg.Folder 10741681107Senkus, Joseph R, - Economic Development, Summer 1972, 8 pg.Folder 10841682108Shellock, Boniface - Log, School and Student, Fall 1971, 42 pg.Folder 10941683109Shower, Claire - Log, On Campus Ministry , 9 pg.Folder 11041684110Sidhu Charanjit S. - Higher Education in America, 17 pgFolder 11141685111Sisney, Tom - Some Monetary Aspects, Relations, and Recent Changes in a High SchoolFolder 11241686112Scope and ContentsEconomics of Education, Spring 1973, 19 pg.Staley, Mary - Field Experience: Lincoln Memorial Gardens, Spring 1971, 11 pg.Folder 11341687113Stewart, David J. - Cooperative Student Employment Programs in IllinoisFolder 11441688114Scope and ContentsEconomics of Education, Spring 1974, 46 pg.Stout, Ray - Macroeconomic Theory Final Exam, 8 pg.Folder 11541689115Student Progress Reports on Research Topics, Public Economics, 1973Folder 11641690116Taylor, Don - Portugal, Economic Development, Summer 1972, 12 pg.Folder 11741691117Taylor, Don - The Externalities of Driving While Intoxicated, Public Economics, Spring 1973, 9 pg.Folder 11841692118Taylor, Thomas - Macroeconomics Theory Final Exam, Fall 1972, 13 pgFolder 11941693119Tebrugge, David J. - Analysis of the Catholic School System in the United States and in IllinoisFolder 12041694120Scope and ContentsEconomics of Education, Spring 1973, 15 pg.Tepe, Donna -Journal 29 pg.Folder 12141695121Thomas, Don - Enternalities Created by the Coal IndustryFolder 12241696122Scope and ContentsPublic Economics, Spring 1973, 15 pg.Tick, Robert M. - Brazil and Economics of DevelopmentFolder 12341697123Scope and ContentsEconomic Development, Summer 1972, 7 pg.Traylor, Caren - Log, School and Student. Fall, 12 pg.Folder 12441698124Van Alstine, Larry L. - Illinois Teacher Surplus: Fact of Fiction, Spring 1973, 11 pg.Folder 12541699125Vaughn, Gary L. - Macroeconomic Theory Final Exam, 7 pg.Folder 12641700126Walter, Barbara - Innovative Teaching (Log), Social Psychology, Fall 1972, 30 pg.Folder 12741701127Walter, Barbara - Innovative Teaching Student, University and Society Class, Fall 1972, 17 pg.Folder 12841702128Waugh, Duane W. - Efficiency in Educational Finance in California, Spring 1973, 8 pg.Folder 12941703129White, Christine - Field Experience: Blessed Sacrament Elementary School, School and Student, 31 pg.Folder 13041704130Wilken, A. W. Jr. - Research Report on a Non-Profit Organization:Folder 13141705131Scope and ContentsThe Flying 20 Club, Inc., Public Economics, Fall 1973, 23 pg.Williams, Betty Jean - Hill-Burton Act for the Construction and Modernization of Health FacilitiesFolder 13241706132Scope and ContentsPublic Economics, Spring 1973, 17 pg.Williams, Craig - The Porsche Club of America: Lincoln Trail RegionsFolder 13341707133Scope and ContentsPublic Economics, Fall 1973, 8 pg.Wood, David M. - School Desegregation: Past and PresentFolder 13441708134Scope and ContentsEconomics of Education, 15 pg.Woods, Martha - The Second Womb? A Social Essay on the Private SchoolFolder 13541709135Scope and ContentsEconomics of Education, Spring 1974, 11 pg.Wright, Jim - Manpower and the BudgetFolder 13641710136Scope and ContentsThe Budget of the United States Government, Fall 18 pg.Wright, Jim - Overview of Child and Family Services of Sangamon CountyFolder 13741711137Scope and ContentsPublic Economics, 8 pg.Zuehl, Tom - Field Experience: Ridgey School, School and Student, 7 pg.Folder 13841712138

