<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.52.Danhof, C.Archon Finding Aid Title J.52.Danhof, C.UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:09:10 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J52/Danhof, C. Student Papers, Entrepreneurship &amp; Organization, 1973-1974
    
      Danhof, Clarence
    
    J.52.Danhof, C.
    654
    
      0.80 Cubic Feet
    
    1973-1974
    Date acquired: 08/21/1973
    1&amp;2
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Student papers prepared for Entrepreneurship and Organization classes, 1973-74, taught Clarence Danhof.  Each paper is a history of a corporate industry or a comparison of industries in an identical market.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Arranged by instructor and time of class  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Clarence Danhof  
  
    Papers
    Reports
  
  Box 1Box 141730Allen, Elliott M.Folder 1417311Scope and ContentsThe Construction Machinery IndustryArcese, JosephFolder 2417322Scope and ContentsSamuel Gosdwyn and The Golden TouchAtteberry, BillFolder 3417333Scope and ContentsMontgomery Ward &amp; Sears, Roebuck A Comparison in growth and decision makingBastion, Fred M. Jr.Folder 4417344Scope and ContentsEntrepreneurship in Franchising from Burgers to BlocksBayne, RichardFolder 5417355Scope and ContentsThe Big Five in Industry: Caterpillar, Komatsu, Fiat-Allis, John Deere, International HarvesterBerry, Mames MichaelFolder 6417366Scope and ContentsAn Analysis of Anheuser-BuschBoyer, GaryFolder 7417377Scope and ContentsAnalysis of the Strategy and Tactics of the John Hobbs Division of Stewart WarnerChevalier, RandyFolder 8417388Scope and ContentsEmployee to Owner, A Springfield Printing BusinessChristensen, BarryFolder 9417399Scope and ContentsEntrepreneurshipCovey, Donald F.Folder 104174010Scope and ContentsStudy of the Archer-Daniels-Midland Company &amp; Anderson,Clayton &amp; CompanyCrain, Frank J.Folder 114174111Scope and ContentsStrategy and Structure, Woodland Acres Mobile Home Park in SpringfieldCrown, Scott R.Folder 124174212Scope and ContentsStrategy &amp; Structure in the Aluminum IndustryDelaney, ThomasFolder 134174313Scope and ContentsComparison of the basic marketing strategy of Allis-Chalmers Construction Machinery Division, in releasing the world's largest Crawler tractor into the world market, to the basic strategy of Komatsu, Ltd., who is entering in to the world Crawler Tractor field, with emphasis on the United StatesDeweese, Richard L.Folder 144174414Scope and ContentsComparative Analysis of J.C. Penny and Myers BrothersDonnelly, JamesFolder 154174515Scope and ContentsState Farm Auto Insurance CompanyDooling, L.F.Folder 164174616Scope and ContentsAT &amp; TElder, B.K.Folder 174174717Scope and ContentsComparative Study of the Marketing function structure of the medical diagnostic X-Ray equipment manufacturing firms of the Picker X-Ray Division of Commercial Investment trust Corp. (CIT) and the Medical System Division of the General Electric Co.Gardner, GeorgiaFolder 184174818Scope and ContentsComparative Strategies of Franklin Life Insurance Company &amp; Horace Mann Educators Corp.Garland, Robert E.Folder 194174919Scope and ContentsMcDonnell Co. &amp; Douglas Aircraft MergerGleason, Luke Jr.Folder 204175020Scope and ContentsGulf American Land Corp. &amp; GAC Corp.Griffith, Franklin L.Folder 214175121Scope and ContentsGeneral Motors Corp.&amp; Ford Motor CompanyHarper, DonaldFolder 224175222Scope and ContentsThe Pillsbury Company History &amp; Business Strategy Followed by a Brief Comparison with its Competitor, General MillsHatcher, JackFolder 234175323Scope and ContentsThe Corp. Innovators, Janes J. LingHerndon, William H.Folder 244175424Scope and ContentsEnvironment is the DifferenceHigh, RalphFolder 254175525Scope and ContentsThe Rise of GiantsHopper, David J.Folder 264175626Scope and ContentsStrategy and Structure of the Illinois National BankHudson, TimFolder 274175727Scope and ContentsStrategies and Organizations within the Television Industry LeadersJenveja, Ashok K.Folder 284175828Scope and ContentsIBM vs. Sperry-RandBox 2Box 241759Lefebvre, AlainFolder 1417601Scope and ContentsA Challenge in Small BusinessLeone, AnthonyFolder 2417612Scope and ContentsLeone and Leone, Inc., A Springfield Floor Covering BusinessMansfield, Betty A.Folder 3417623Scope and ContentsStrategy &amp; Structure comparison of federal funeral Directors of America &amp; AmedcoMatheis, Steve J.Folder 4417634Scope and ContentsComparative Study--Swift &amp; Company-Armour &amp; CompanyMelton, Lawrence C. Jr.Folder 5417645Scope and ContentsIncorporation in the State of  IllinoisMerritt, David L.Folder 6417656Scope and ContentsA Comparison of the Strategy of  Commonwealth Edison Company &amp;  the Tennessee Valley AuthorityNarasimham, Ayyadevara Y.Folder 7417667Scope and ContentsRoss Perot and Wall StreetO'Conner, TerryFolder 8417678Scope and ContentsDatamann IncorporatedPavelick, R.A.Folder 9417689Scope and ContentsSangamo and Sanders AssociatesPavlisin, MichaelFolder 104176910Scope and ContentsEmerson Electric Company &amp; Sangamo Electric Company An Organizational and Structural AnalysisPerry, DickFolder 114177011Scope and ContentsEDS vs. FDS ... A Comparative AnalysisPeterson, RayFolder 124177112Scope and ContentsBoise Cascade-A Study of a FailurePhelps, JimFolder 134177213Scope and ContentsAmerican Machine and Foundry (AMF)Pietsek, Carl W.Folder 144177314Scope and ContentsA Study in the Organization and Strategy of the Eli Lilly CompanyReddy, E.P.Folder 154177415Scope and ContentsIndependent Successful RetailersReddy, E.P.Folder 16417751973-7416Scope and ContentsIndependent Successful RetailersRhodes, Rexford C.Folder 174177617Scope and ContentsA Comparative Study of Two CompaniesSchmitt, CharlesFolder 184177718Scope and ContentsHenry S. BrooksSidhu, CharanjitFolder 194177819Scope and ContentsIBM CorporationSmith, HalFolder 204177920Scope and ContentsAT &amp; T Early DevelopmentSvienty, ThomasFolder 214178021Scope and ContentsThe Taylor Wine Company &amp; E &amp;  J Gallo Wine CompanyTapscott, Robert H.Folder 224178122Scope and ContentsWinnebago Industries Inc.Taylor, DonFolder 234178223Scope and ContentsThe Toy Industry Mattel Inc. and Topper Corp. (Missing 6/8/78)Taylor, LeonFolder 244178324Scope and ContentsHorace Mann Educators CorporationWilkin, A.W. Jr.Folder 254178425Scope and ContentsUnited Air Lines

