<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.52.Davis, C.Archon Finding Aid Title J.52.Davis, C.UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:09:13 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J52/Davis, C. Student Papers, History of Springfield, 1973-1978
    
      Davis, G. Cullom
    
    J.52.Davis, C.
    655
    
      1.16 Cubic Feet
    
    1973-1978
    Date acquired: 02/11/1975
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Student papers prepared for History of Springfield classes taught at SSU by Cullom Davis and others.  Papers cover a variety of subjects and periods of Springfield &amp; Sangamon County History including histories of institutions, civic groups and politics in Springfield.  See detailed boxlist for more specific authors, titles, and subjects.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical by author  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Collum Davis  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Classes of Fall, 1973; Spring 1974; Summer 1974; and Fall 1974
Also received from Chris Breiseth  
  
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 141788Alexander, AnnFolder 141789Fall 19741Scope and ContentsPills, Platitudes and Politics: the Diller Drugstore in 1850-1860Bandor, BobFolder 241790Fall 19732Scope and ContentsSpringfield Riot of 1908Bean, StephenFolder 341791Fall 19743Scope and ContentsThe First Presidential Campaign of Adlai E. Stevenson, Illinois: The Springfield ConnectionBergen, BillFolder 441792Summer 19744Scope and ContentsThe Springfield Street Car Strike of 1917Boren, MichaelFolder 541793Spring 19785Scope and ContentsPatriotism and Politics: Springfield and the Grand Army of the RepublicBostick, ConstanceFolder 641794Summer 19746Scope and ContentsEducating Springfield's Black Children, 1859-1873Bregstone, SteveFolder 741795Spring 19747Scope and ContentsThe Heavy-Inked Message (1st draft) (Springfield Newspapers) And Here is Springfield (Collection of Anecdotes)Clark, MikeFolder 841796Fall 19738Scope and ContentsSocialist Party in Springfield, Illinois: 1904 and 1908Collins, WandaFolder 941797(Spring 1974)9Scope and ContentsSusan Lawrence, Dana, Joergen-Dahl, Gehrmann and Her Frank Lloyd Wright House (1st) copy 1---Copy 2Conlon, WillardFolder 1041798Fall 197410Scope and ContentsThe Life of Reservoir ParkConner, William H.Folder 1141799Fall 197411Scope and ContentsLand Barons and Tenants: Agricultural Patterns in the Sangamon River BasinBox 2Box 241800Debolt, DeanFolder 1418011Scope and ContentsPostal Politics, Patronage, and Reform: A History of the Springfield, Ill.  Post Office, 1823-1973Dehart, Richard E.Folder 241802Fall 19732Scope and ContentsTrail of Death: A Brief Focus on the Forced Migration of the Menominee Band of the Potawatomi Indian Tribe from IndianaDixon, ElizabethFolder 341803Spring 19783Scope and ContentsThe Parade through and Views from the Tinsley BuildingHeim, Jay G.Folder 441804Spring 19784Scope and ContentsBuilding Men in the Lincoln Tradition. Conveys how the founders of the Abraham Lincoln Council made a deliberate effort to link the Qualities of Abraham Lincoln with the Mission of Scouting.Heriot, Ruth AnneFolder 541805Summer 19745Scope and ContentsThe Lincoln Neighborhood from 1845-61Herndon, BobbeFolder 641806Spring 19726Scope and ContentsSangamon State-Behind the Barricades or behind the BooksHerndon, CalistaFolder 741807Summer 19747Scope and ContentsElijah IlesHuntley, NancyFolder 841808Spring 19788Scope and ContentsThe Springfield Social SocietyKlusmeyer, MargaretFolder 941809Fall 19739Scope and ContentsWhen Billy Sunday came to Springfield, 1909Kwedar, Melinda F.Folder 1041810Fall 197410Scope and ContentsOutstanding Women of SpringfieldKyes, Robert HenryFolder 1141811Spring 197411Scope and ContentsSeeing a Bit of the past with C.H. Lanphier (1st draft) C.1---Copy 2Kyes, Robert HenryFolder 124181212Scope and ContentsDemocrat Charles Henry Lanphier: A Man of Principles, Foresight and Patriotism or a Super Imposition on the Uni-personal Aspects of Spring-ield's Antebellum HistoryMcEvoy, Chris A.Folder 134181313Scope and ContentsHistory of St. John's Hospital, Springfield Ill. (1st draft), Copy 2McGinnis, Robert C.Folder 1441814Fall 197314Scope and ContentsTrolley History of SpringfieldBox 3Box 341815McLaughlin, Goerge E.Folder 141816Spring 19741Scope and ContentsHistory of Workingmen's Singing Society of Springfield (1st Draft) ---final draft includes pictures Supplement to the Final draft, Programs and AdvertisementsMendelsohn, Syma R.Folder 241817Spring 19742Scope and ContentsHistory of the Temple B'rith Sholom (1st rough draft)---copy 2--- Final draftMetzroth, JanFolder 341818Fall 19733Scope and ContentsMiner's Riot in Springfield, 1932Meyer, StevenFolder 441819Summer 19744Scope and ContentsA Short History of Springfield's Graham-Rosenwald HouseO'Brien, MaryFolder 541820Spring 19745Scope and ContentsHistory of Reisch Brewery and Family (1st draft) c. 1, copy 2Reid, John J.Folder 641821Fall 19746Scope and ContentsThe Portuguese in SpringfieldRice, JamesFolder 741822Spring 19787Scope and ContentsThe CIMCO Saga with photograph section Chicago &amp; Illinois MidlandRodgers, M.G.Folder 8418238Scope and ContentsLand Distribution and Settlement Patterns in New Salem Precinct, Sangamon County, Illinois 1825-1837Russo, EdFolder 941824Fall 19739Scope and ContentsHelmle and Helmle, ArchitectsSarff, MegFolder 1041825Fall 197310Scope and ContentsCamp Butler: Civil War PrisonSchanbacher, MelindaFolder 1141826Fall 197411Scope and ContentsThe story of Sangamon TownBox 4Box 441827Schanbacher, Sally B.Folder 141828Fall 19731Scope and ContentsSpringfield Art AssociationShiroda, JudyFolder 2418292Scope and ContentsThe Bettie Stuart Institute, the history of a private school for girls which existed in Springfield from 1868 to 1935Snopko, JamesFolder 341830Summer 19743Scope and ContentsHail to the Chief: A History of Presidential Visits to SpringfieldStock, JonelleFolder 441831Fall 19734Scope and ContentsSpringfield's Years as a Gambling Mecca, 1948-1950Suttles, DennisFolder 541832Spring 19785Scope and ContentsJames Rutledge of New SalemSuttles, DennisFolder 641833Spring 19786Scope and ContentsThe Stephan A. Douglas Klan No. 72 of Winchester Illinois: A Problem in HistorographyWaggoner, Horace Q.Folder 741834Fall 19747Scope and ContentsLong in Labor: The birth of  Commercial Aviation at Springfield, IllinoisWaldmire, DeniseFolder 841835Summer 19748Scope and ContentsBrief History of the Local Chapter of the League of Women Voters

