<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.52.Johnson, W.Archon Finding Aid Title J.52.Johnson, W.UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:09:23 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J52/Johnson, W. Student Papers, Veterans Affairs Seminar (Winter), 1972-1973
    
      Johnson, Walter
    
    J.52.Johnson, W.
    658
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1972-1973
    Date acquired: 02/17/1995
    1
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Student papers and projects of Walt Johnson's Veterans Affairs Seminar held in the winter of 1972-1973.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Walt Johnson  
  
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 141850Barbas, DonaldFolder 1418511Scope and ContentsA Comparative Study Concerning Vietnam Veterans and Some Aspects of Veterans' Benefits as Viewed by Government and Non-government EmployeesBernahl, Normal P.Folder 2418522Scope and ContentsFederal Benefits for VeteransBertrand, Joseph R.Folder 3418533Scope and ContentsU. S. and Illinois State Veterans BenefitsBertrand, Joseph R.Folder 4418544Scope and ContentsRacism in the Service: Historical OverviewChevalier, RandyFolder 5418555Scope and ContentsThe V. A. Guaranteed LoanCovey, Donald F.Folder 6418566Scope and ContentsGI LoansFerguson, Franklin L.Folder 7418577Scope and ContentsAssignment: Institutional Racism -- Military StyleFerron, Joseph M.Folder 8418588Scope and ContentsThe Second CareerFranklin, Kenneth L.Folder 9418599Scope and ContentsEmployment: Fact or FictionFranklin, Kenneth L. and Stapleton, DonFolder 104186010Scope and ContentsAn Observation of  Readjustment (Psychological) and Employment Problems Facing the Vietnam VeteranHess, John E., Jr.Folder 114186111Scope and ContentsRehabilitation for the Returning Vietnam VeteransKerske, John D.Folder 124186212Scope and ContentsVeterans With Less than an Honorable DischargeLeamons, Leslie L.Folder 134186313Scope and ContentsA Program to Assist in the Re-socialization of Offending and Ex-Offending VeteransLiehr, David R.Folder 144186414Scope and ContentsReadjustment for the Viet Nam VeteranLilly, Dallas B.Folder 154186515Scope and ContentsReadjustmentMcCormick, DanFolder 164186616Scope and ContentsThe Black Veteran: From Vietnam to Civilian LifeMcGrath, Dan L.Folder 174186717Scope and ContentsEducational Needs of the Vietnam-Era VeteranMefford, MichaelFolder 184186818Scope and ContentsThe Uniqueness of the Vietnam War and the Related Problems of Psychological ReadjustmentNeuber, RickFolder 194186919Scope and ContentsVeterans With Less Than an Honorable DischargePapp, Stanley J.Folder 204187020Scope and ContentsVeterans' Affairs, Division of Mental Retardation, Department of Mental Health, State of IllinoisPierce, Patrick E.Folder 214187121Scope and ContentsProposal for the Establishment of a Clearing House to Alleviate the Problem of Unemployment of the Returning Vietnam Era VeteranPierce, Patrick E.Folder 224187222Scope and ContentsThe Study of Attitudes Facing Vietnam Era Veterans in Springfield, IllinoisRyan, Michael G.Folder 234187323Scope and ContentsCauses for Psychological AdjustmentSwem, RichardFolder 244187424Scope and ContentsCausative Factors for Drug Abuse in VietnamTate, Michael J.Folder 254187525Scope and ContentsWill Johnny Come Marching Home Again?  (The Question of Amnesty)Thomas, Gary C.Folder 264187626Scope and ContentsPsychological Sexual Re-Adjustment for the Returning VeteranZini, Harry J.Folder 274187727Scope and ContentsPsychologically Disabled Veterans(no author named), (no title given), subject: Ex-Offending VeteranFolder 284187828

