<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>LHC.##7ooArchon Finding Aid Title LHC.##7ooUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:09:52 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    LHC. Local History Collection
    LHC.##7oo
    664
    
      1.66 Cubic Feet
    
    Date acquired: 04/14/1978
    1
    2
    3
    4
    Some Items
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The Local History Collection (LHC) consists of small groups of papers and items relating to local history and the Central Illinois Region.  Each item or group is assigned an LHC number based on accession and cataloged by title, name, and subject.  A full listing of the items in this collection is available in the box list under LOCAL HISTORY COLLECTION.  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
Some Restrictions apply - see individual files for specific restrictions  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Ongoing  
  
    Audio Tapes
    Correspondence
    Letters
    Newspaper Clippings
    Photographs
  
  Box 1Box 1497LHC1. Automobile Insurance PolicyFolder 149819221Scope and ContentsIssued to the City of Havana, Illinois by the Maryland Motor Car Insurance Company, September 6, 1922LHC2. Cass County Specification for Courthouse AdditionFolder 2499ca. 19362Scope and ContentsSpecifications for additon to Cass County Courthouse to be built for Virginia, Cass County, Illinois.  P.W.A. Project No. Illinois 2234. Raymond G. Johnson, Architect, Jacksonville, Illinois. 83 p. Blueprint copy. No drawings or illustrations.LHC3. Chandlerville, IL Cemetery FileFolder 35001937-19453Scope and ContentsRecords of the Chandlerville, Illinois Cemetery Board, 1937-1945 including newspaper clippings and by-laws of the Cemetery Board of Managers.LHC4. Havana, IL Toll Bridge ReceiptFolder 450119284Scope and ContentsMarch 1928 receipt states, "$5.00 fine for driving Auto more than 10 miles per hour or horses and cattle faster than a walk over this bridge."LHC5. "How to Count Ballots" ManualFolder 5502ca. 19285Scope and ContentsCass County, Illinois, "How to Count Ballots" Manual. Virginia, Illinois: County Clerk of Cass County, Leo Fitzgerald. Circa 1928. 22 p.LHC6.Folder 65036Scope and ContentsTransferred to Special Collections, see SB 191.M2P7. Prairie Farmer magazine. Centennial Corn Number, October 18, 1941. Special issue during Prairie Farmer magazine's centennial year devoted to corn - the history of the crop, technology, science and the future.LHC7. Burlington, Cedar Rapids, and Northern Railway, 1893-1894Folder 750418977Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, telegrams, and letters of G.A. Goodell, Superintendent, regarding complaints and investigations of station agents at Oasis and Grundy Center, Iowa and the United States Express Company agent at Cedar Rapids. 40 photocopies.LHC8. "Who Shall Be Vice-President?" BroadsideFolder 850518648Scope and ContentsPublished by the National Union Executive Committee, Astor House, New York. Contrasts the political stand of George H. Pendleton of Ohio and Andrew Johnson of Tennessee as Vice Presidential candidates in the 1864 presidential election.LHC9. Draft of Speech Mourning Lincoln's AssassinationFolder 950618659Scope and ContentsWritten on an indenture form from Bond County, Illinois. Author unknown. Dated June 1, 1865.LHC10. Morgan County, IL SchoolsFolder 10507197610Scope and ContentsJacksonville (Illinois) Genealogical Journal. Volume 4, Number 2 (June 1976). Mimeograph. 9 p. Excerpt contains a plat map of Morgan County showing township and range sections, with an index to Morgan County schools by name and location.LHC11. "Illinois Observer" magazineFolder 115081975-197611Scope and ContentsThe only two issues of the Illinois Observer magazine which ceased publication in 1976. Oct-Nov, 1975 and Dec-Jan, 1976.LHC12. Havana Public Library Annual ReportsFolder 125091899-190112Scope and ContentsAnnual reports for the years 1899-1900 and 1900-1901. Covers salaries, income, gifts, expenditures for books, statistics, and negotiations for a new building funded by Andrew Carnegie.LHC13. Waldo Story Reed, "Glimpses of Springfield, 1881-1894"Folder 13510192913Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of typescript personal reminiscence of Springfield. 15 p. legal size, 1929. Excerpt published in A Springfield Reader, edited by James Krohe, Jr., 1976.LHC14.Folder 1451114Scope and ContentsConverted to MC46.LHC15.Folder 1551215Scope and ContentsTransferred to 2nd Level, see DOC.IL H1.2:L63/6. "Lincoln's Springfield: A Guide Book and Brief History", Springfield Illinois: Illinois State Historical Library, 1955. Booklet, 30 p.LHC16.Folder 1651316Scope and ContentsDoes Not ExistLHC17. "Newscenter," publication of Memorial Medical CenterFolder 17514197717Scope and ContentsA publication of Memorial Medical Center with news of staff, new equipment, department changes, and related hospital information.  Vol. 3, No. 5 (May 1977); Vol. 4, No. 6 (June 1977) SIU Medical School issueLHC18.Folder 1851518Scope and ContentsTransferred to Special Collections, see F549.S7Y68. Greater Springfield Chamber of Commerce.  "You'll Love Living in Springfield." Springfield Illinois: Philips Brothers Printers, 1975. 48 p., illustrated. A promotional booklet covering all aspects and living conditions available in Springfield.LHC19. Child and Family Services of Sangamon County RecordsFolder 195161973-197419Scope and ContentsRecords and papers of the Child and Family Service of Sangamon County, Illinois, 1973-1974 including minutes of the Board of Directors, monthly reports of services provided (family counseling, foster care, adoption services, counseling to unmarried parents, day care centers, homemaker services, and legal aid cases), and financial statements.LHC20.Folder 2051720Scope and ContentsConverted to MC47.LHC21. Quincy, IL Industrial ListFolder 21518197221Scope and ContentsIndustrial List of Quincy, Illinois, January 1972, 11 p. Lists companies, founding dates, names of executives, products, and number of employees.LHC22. Peoria, IL "Directory of Manufactures"Folder 225191972-197322Scope and ContentsDirectory of Peoria member manufacturers, listing company names, address, telephone numbers executives, products, affiliate or parent companies, sales and number of employees.LHC23. Jacksonville, IL "Major Employers and Financial Institutions" and "Membership Roster, Jacksonville Area Chamber of Commerce"Folder 23520197223Scope and ContentsBoth businesses and companies, addresses, names of executives, products, and numbers of employees.LHC24. Dr. Henry C. Barrell Estate InventoryFolder 24521187724Scope and ContentsInventory includes medical instruments and books, operating equipment, and a listing of office furnishings, May 27, 1877.  27 photocopies from Sangamon County, Record of Inventories, Book No. 8, 1877-1879, p. 24-37.LHC25. Elijah Iles, Estate InventoryFolder 25522187725Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois, October 1, 1883.  6 photocopies from Sangamon County, Record of Inventories, Book 10, 1883-1886, p. 235-237.LHC26. Abraham Lincoln Association Annual BanquetFolder 26523198026Scope and ContentsAnnual banquet, February 12, 1980.  Held in restored Springfield Marine Bank.  Program featured 1860 photograph of bank and 1860 photograph of Lincoln by Preston Butler of Springfield.  Mary Frances Berry was the guest speaker.LHC27. "Springfield's Railroad Relocation Plan"Folder 27524197927Scope and ContentsCapital City Rail Road Relocation Authority.  Springfield, Illinois: Harland Bartholomew and Associates, Inc. December 1979. 15 p., illustrated pamphlet.LHC28. "City Water Light and Power: A History of Progress and Public Service: 1845-1979"Folder 28525197928Scope and ContentsLargest municipally-owned water and electric utility in Illinois.  Statements on the history of CWLP from its origins as a well and four public water pumps on Springfield's public square in 1845; and the purification of water from Lake Springfield.LHC29. Springfield Water Treatment: "Where Does Springfield Water Come From?"Folder 29527197929Scope and ContentsLargest municipally-owned water and electric utility in Illinois. Statements on the history of CWLP from its origins as a well and four public water pumps on Springfield's public square in 1845; and the purification of water from Lake Springfield.LHC30.Folder 3052830Scope and ContentsTransferred to MC78.LHC30. Concordia Theological Seminary CatalogsFolder 315291969-1970; 1970-197131Scope and Contents2 booklets from Concordia Theological Seminary, Springfield, Illinois. Issues available: 1969-1970, 1970-1971.LHC32. "Paul Simon for Governor"Folder 32530197232Scope and ContentsBooklet. Chicago, Illinois: Paul Simon for Governor Committee, 1972. Illustrated.LHC33. John H. Pollmann, "A Structural and Functional Analysis of the Clinton County [Illinois] Democratic Party"Folder 33531197033Scope and ContentsA thesis in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the degree of Master of Arts. Department of Government, Southern Illinois University, Carbondale, Illinois. By John H. Pollmann. August 1970, 160 p.LHC34. Sangamon County, Illinois Board of ReviewFolder 34532189934Scope and ContentsRules and Regulations governing the Board of Review and its transaction of business. Adopted July 7, 1899.LHC35. Biographies: Bradley B. Taylor and Charles KirchnerFolder 35533197935Scope and ContentsBiographical information and vitas of prominent Springfield people who applied for positions at SSU.LHC36. History of Elijah Iles and the Elijah Iles HouseFolder 3653436Scope and ContentsEssay regarding the home of  Elijah Iles, one of the founders of Springfield, at 1825 South Sixth Street. The oldest surviving house in Springfield, constructed ca. 1827. Author unknown.LHC37.Folder 3753537Scope and ContentsTransferred to Special Collections, see DS 108.5 P3. Palestine Photographed. A Collection of Picturesque and Historic Spots in the Holy Land. New York: N.D. Thompson Publishing Company, 1894. Owned and inscribed by Catherine F. Lindsay (the mother of the poet Vachel Lindsay).Box 2Box 2536LHC38. Great Springfield Chamber of Commerce: 1972 Annual ReportFolder 38537197238Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois, 10 p.LHC39.Folder 3953839Scope and ContentsTransferred to Special Collections, see F 549.S7S64. "Springfield, Illinois: All American City." Bloomington, Illinois: Mullins Publication Corporation, 1970.  Published under the direction of the Greater Springfield Chamber of Commerce through its Public Affairs Council and its Public Relations Committee, 72 p. A general guide to the newcomer about Springfield and services available.LHC40. Peoria Historical SocietyFolder 40539198040Scope and ContentsMonthly newsletter and press releases of the Peoria Historical Society, Peoria, Illinois.LHC41.Folder 4154041Scope and ContentsTransferred to MC46.LHC42. "Capitol Complex Development"Folder 42541197642Scope and ContentsCapital Development Board, July 1976. Background data, comprehensive planning, regulatory guidelines and design criteria.LHC43. Abraham Lincoln Association Annual BanquetFolder 43542198143Scope and ContentsAnnual Banquet, February 12, 1981.  Hosted by Sangamon State University as the first event in the new Public Affairs Center. Included New Hutchison Family Singers and Genny Brown as "Mrs. Lincoln".  Program brochure, programs, and tickets.LHC44. Springfield, Illinois Special Study Commission on PlanningFolder 44543197644Scope and ContentsReport to the Springfield City Council on regional planning and the responsibilities of the Springfield Plan Commission and the Springfield-Sangamon County Regional Planning Commission. Report, October 14 1976, 39 p.LHC45. "Lincoln Heritage Trail" brochureFolder 4554445Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois Office of Tourism.  Map and explanation of Lincoln Heritage Trail through Kentucky, Indiana, and Illinois.LHC46. "Funeral Scene at Home of Lincoln," Illinois State Journal-RegisterFolder 4654546Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of newspaper article, 1 p. Includes reminiscences of a member of the honor guard for Lincoln's funeral procession and a photograph of the Lincoln home draped for the services taken by S. A. Rice of Carlinville.LHC47. Springfield Convention and Tourism Commission, "Schedule of Conventions, Meetings, and Special Events: January thru December 1978Folder 47546197847Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois: The Commission, 51 p.LHC48. Illinois Historic ChronicleFolder 48547197648Scope and ContentsNewspaper, featuring Sangamon County, November 15, 1976, 20 p. Includes articles about the early history of Springfield and Sangamon County.LHC49.Folder 4954849Scope and ContentsDoes Not ExistLHC50. "Fall Music Festival"Folder 50549198050Scope and ContentsProgram with pictures of the performers at a festival held September 5-7, 1980 in Douglas Park, Springfield, Illinois, 15 p.LHC51. "Seventh Annual International Carillon Festival"Folder 51550196851Scope and ContentsSpringfield Park District, June 22-30, 1968, Thomas Rees Memorial Carillon. Program with pictures of the festival performers and including a 1 page announcement from Springfield Junior College concerning its music curriculum.LHC52. "Visitor's Guide to the Illinois General Assembly"Folder 52551197352Scope and ContentsIllinois Legislative Council, Springfield, Illinois. 1 pamphlet.LHC53. Chicago, Illinois Department of Development and PlanningFolder 53552197653Scope and Contents"The People of Chicago:  who we are and who we have been." Includes census data on foreign born, foreign stock and race in Chicago, 1837-1970, and an addendum on residents' mother tongue, 1910-1970.LHC54. Transferred to Special Collections, see PS 3523.158V5Folder 54553197054Scope and ContentsSangamon State University and Sangamon Poets, "The Village Magazine", 1979, 50 p. Poems published in honor of the centenary of the birth of Vachel Lindsay.LHC55. "Springfield: Captial City and Everytown"Folder 55554197755Scope and ContentsSpringfield, Illinois: Sangamon State University, 1977, 8 p. Written by G. Cullom Davis, taken from Illinois History Newspaper.LHC56. "Newscenter"Folder 56555197556Scope and ContentsMemorial Medical Center (Springfield, Illinois), Special Issue, Fall 1975, 30 p. A brief illustrated history of Memorial Medical Center and its School of Nursing with comments from seven alumni.LHC57. "Springfield, Illinois Walk/Drive Tours"Folder 57556197557Scope and ContentsSpringfield Convention and Tourism Commission, 1 brochure.LHC58. "Lincoln Library Bulletin"Folder 58557197658Scope and ContentsSpringfield Illinois, Vol. 27, No. 9, 4 p.  Includes a brief history of Lincoln Library on its 90th anniversary.LHC59. "Theaters of Springfield, Illinois"Folder 5955859Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of magazine article, 6 p., by Leo A. Kikendall.  A brief history of Springfield's theaters including the Orpheum.LHC60.Folder 6055960Scope and ContentsDoes Not ExistLHC61. Springfield-Sangamon County Regional Planning CommissionFolder 615601974-198061Scope and ContentsAccommodating Tourist Movements (1974),  including maps, tables, charts and narrative concerning Springfield historic sites, tourist parking needs, and plans for the accommodation of visitors; Springfield-Sangamon County, Illinois, 1970 Census Analysis (1975), consisting of tables and graphs illustrating general social composition of the population, income and housing characteristics, and employment structure; and A Guide to the City Services (1980), a directory of municipal functions, services, and phone numbers.LHC62. "Classified Membership Roster and Buyer's Guide"Folder 62561198062Scope and ContentsThe Greater Springfield Chamber of Commerce, 54 p.LHC63. "Directory of Illinois Oral History Resources"Folder 63562198163Scope and ContentsCompiled and edited by Kathryn Wrigley. Springfield, Illinois Oral History Office, Sangamon State University, 54 p. Includes a county index, a repository index and a subject index.LHC64. Sangamon State UniversityFolder 64563197564Scope and ContentsMajor Street Access Study and Corridor Environmental Assessment: Springfield Southeast Sector Study.  Prepared for City of Springfield and Sangamon County by Sangamon State University and Lincoln Land Community College. Includes several proposals to improve traffic access to SSU and LLCC. New access roads, similar to those proposed in this study, were constructed in 1997-1998. 67 p. with maps.Box 3Box 3564LHC65. "Accommodating Tourist Movements"Folder 65565197465Scope and ContentsPrepared by Springfield-Sangamon County Regional Planning Commission for U.S. Department of Interior - National Park Service. 15 leaves, photocopy.LHC66. "Springfield College in Illinois"Folder 665661974-197566Scope and ContentsBrochure, SCI: A Two-Year Liberal Arts College, Catalog no. 41, 58 p.LHC67.Folder 6756767Scope and ContentsTransferred to MC 41.LHC68.Folder 6856868Scope and ContentsTransferred to MC17.LHC69. "Science and the Illinois General Assembly: A Case Study of a Project"Folder 69569197469Scope and ContentsJuly 1974, Illinois Legislative Council, Springfield, Illinois.LHC70. Springfield-Sangamon County Census AnalysisFolder 70570197070Scope and ContentsThis report, issued by the Sangamon County Regional Planning Commission, utilizes tables and graphs to illustrate some of the information presented in the 1970 census about Springfield and Sangamon County.LHC71. Sangamon County, Illinois Juvenile Probation DepartmentFolder 71571ca. 1965, 197371Scope and Contents"A Study of the Family Division of the Circuit Court in Sangamon County, Illinois," ca. 1965, covering Court and Probation Services, Detention Services and Police Services. Also a carbon typescript of the annual report of the Juvenile Probation Department, 1972-1973.LHC72. Land of Lincoln Progress ReportFolder 72572198272Scope and ContentsFirst quarter edition. A Springfield, Illinois publication focusing on Black contributors to science and energy technology.LHC73. Progressive Miners of America, Illinois Women's AuxiliaryFolder 73573193373Scope and ContentsOrganized at the State Convention in Gillespie in 1932. Dedicated to providing strike relief and advocating labor legislation, labor education, a youth movement, and "independent working class political action." First annual report prepared by president, Agnes Burns Wieck. Describes history, objectives and activities of the Auxiliary. Topics include Mulkeytown March, Battle of Kincaid, American Civil Liberties Union, Governor Henry Horner, Staunton Conference, Mt. Olive and the United Mine Workers.LHC74. National Association for the Advancement of Colored PeopleFolder 74574192374Scope and ContentsReprinted 8" x 10" photograph of the NAACP's Lincoln Banquet in Springfield, 1923.LHC75. Liberation NewsFolder 75575198475Scope and ContentsA publication of the Springfield Black Islams.LHC76. Southern View, IllinoisFolder 76576197976Scope and ContentsGeneral code of the Village of Southern View.  Also contains "ordinance Adopting a Revision and Codification of the Ordinances of the Village of Southern View, Illinois."  Passed and approved October 8, 1979.LHC77. Middletwon, Illinois Sesquicentennial CelebrationFolder 77577197977Scope and ContentsContains history of the oldest village in Logan County, Illinois - Middletown, 1832-1982.  Celebration was held on October 8, 1979.LHC78. Sangamon County, Illinois Poor FarmFolder 78578ca. 190078Scope and ContentsList of Sangamon County Board of Supervisors; reprinted photograph of a meeting if county officials at the Poor Farm near Buffalo, Illinois, including Superintendent William Sprinkel; and a book of recipes for food and medicine used at the Poor Farm. Photocopies.Box 4Box 4579LHC79. Joseph Porter's Manuscript Arithmetic Exercise BookFolder 79580ca. 1800-183079Scope and ContentsThirty-page, handwritten exercise book containing practical arithmetic problems covering measures, weights and currencies, including the exchange of New England, Virginia, Federal and English monies. The problems are derived from a textbook by Michael Walsh and Richard Turner "A New System of Mercantile Arithmetic: Adapted to the Commerce of the United States..." which went through many editions between 1800 and 1830.LHC80. Another Village MagazineFolder 8058180Scope and ContentsTransferred to Special Collections, see PS 3523.158V5 1942.  One of seventy copies of "Another Village Magazine," published by two college students in May 1942.  Inspired by Vachel Lindsay's "Village Magazine," the booklet (42 p.) discusses and makes recommendations regarding Vachel Lindsay, music, art, literature, education, commercialism, religion, politics, and the commission form of government in Springfield.LHC81. Jerome C. Spangler ReminiscenceFolder 81583190981LHC B4/F081. Jerome C. Spangler Reminiscence: 1909Scope and ContentsSecretary and manager of the Walnut Milling Company, Walnut, Iowa.  Signed typescript written by former Civil War soldier recalling meeting Abraham Lincoln, Ulysses Grant and Simon Cameron in Washington, DC in 1864, and regarding his memories of Lincoln's death and wake in 1865.  Entitled, "My Recollection of Lincoln as a Boy - By J. C. Spangler in 1865."  Typed on Walnut Milling Company letterhead.LHC82. Sangamo Electric Company and Illinois Watch FactoryFolder 825821913, ca. 196682Scope and ContentsIncludes photocopied typescript of a history of the Illinois Watch Factory, written by Robert Carr Lanphier in 1913; a Sangamo Electric Company brochure describing the two companies' interlocking histories with an accompanying brochure of exemplary watch and meter products, n.d.; and a photocopy of a 1966 Springfield Sun clipping regarding Sangamo's history.LHC83. Sangamon Valley Radio Club, Inc.Folder 835841975-197683Scope and ContentsOrganization dedicated to amateur "HAM" radio. Incomplete set of the club's mimeographed newsletter, SangRadNuz, containing minutes, reports, officer lists, announcements, and letters to the editor. Includes vol. 5, nos. 7-12 and vol. 6, nos. 1-5.LHC84. "Hollywood Community Center"Folder 84585ca. 195084Scope and ContentsHistorical account by Munel Ruyen that describes the creation and development of the "Hollywood Community Center", erected on Springfield's west side in 1946. Class conflict, local politics and the local conditions in Springfield during the mid-twentieth century are clearly described. 57 p.LHC85. Illinois State Journal-Register, Springfield, IllinoisFolder 85586189885Scope and ContentsReprinted photographs from Illinois Capital Illustrated, "an art album of Springfield," published by the Illinois State Register newspaper in 1898. Includes shots of the Illinois Watch Factory, Franklin Life Insurance Association Building, City Hall, the Sangamo Club, Springfield High School, the post office, the Governor's Mansion, Myers Brothers Store, the German Methodist Episcopal Church Orchestra, Cokey's Mill, surgery at St. John's hospital, the agricultural museum in the Capitol building, and an electric trolley party.LHC86. "The Functions and Responsibilities of Council-Manager Government of the City of Peoria"Folder 86587197186Scope and ContentsThird edition, prepared by the City Manager's Office of Peoria, Illinois. 15 p.LHC87. League of Women Voters of Springfield IllinoisFolder 87588196987Scope and ContentsStudy examining the availability of low and moderate income housing in Springfield and the factors controlling the supply.LHC88. Springfield, Illinois Department of Public PropertyFolder 88589197888Scope and ContentsMemorandum from the Commissioner of Public Property, James M. Henneberry. to Mayor Telford and members of City Council regarding electric rates outside Springfield's city limits; and "A Report," submitted by Jim Henneberry, "To the City Council and the People of the City of Springfield, Illinois on the Question of a Future Water Supply for the City of Springfield, Illinois". Photocopies.LHC89. Dean DeBoltFolder 89590197989Scope and Contents"A Directory of City Officials for Springfield, Illinois: 1832-Present," compiled by DeBolt.  Includes a brief history of city government, and alphabetical and chronological listings of city mayors, aldermen and commissioners.LHC90.Folder 9059190Scope and ContentsTransferred to Special Collections, see KFX2503.V5 A35 1900.  Revised Ordinances of the City of Virden and the Rules and Order of Business of the City Council (Virden: Record Printing House, 1900), 125 p.  Ordinance Book belonging to James Campbell, Justice of the Peace. Additional ordinances dating from 1901-1903 pasted onto rear fly leaves.LHC91. Jane Stout, Chatham Prairie VillageFolder 91592198691Scope and ContentsJane Stout's sesquicentennial history of Chatham, Illinois, 1836-1986 includes the story of early settlers, pictures and illustrations of early Chatham and its historic sites, and information on early transportation, businesses and churches. (author, 1986). 62 pp. 8.5" x 11".LHC92.Folder 9259392Scope and ContentsTransferred to Special Collections, see LH 1. C32X.  Springfield High School, "The Capitoline," vol. XI, no. 3 (May 1909).  Literary and humor magazine, including poetry, short stories, satire, school news and alumni notices.  Staff included Robert E. Smith (editor), Nelli T. Viera, John Jones, Russell Rotger, Grace Frame, etc.LHC93. Illinois State University, Springfield, Illinois. Annual Catalogue of the Officers and StudentsFolder 93594185993LHC B4/F093. Illinois State University, Springfield, Illinois. Annual Catalogue of the Officers and Students: 1858-1859Scope and ContentsAnnual catalogue of Illinois State University, including lists of trustees, faculty, students (including Robert T. Lincoln), and alumni; also descriptions of the courses of instruction and the academic calendar for 1859-60 (Springfield: B.A. Richard &amp; Co., 1859), 16 p. Illinois State University opened in Springfield in 1852 and closed in 1867. It has no connection with the current university in Normal, Illinois.LHC94. Illinois State University, Springfield, Illinois. Program of the Third Annual Literary Contest of the Utilior and Philomathean SocietiesFolder 94595186094LHC B4/F094. Illinois State University, Springfield, Illinois. Program of the Third Annual Literary Contest of the Utilior and Philomathean Societies of the Illinois State University: 1860-02-29Scope and ContentsThe program of the "Third Annual Literary Contest of the Utilior and Philomathean Societies of the Illinois State University,  Feb. 29, 1860" (Springfield: Booraem, Bacon &amp; Co., 1860) showing the order of events, topics of speeches and debates and names of participants of an event held in Springfield's First Presbyterian Church. 2 p. Illinois State University opened in Springfield in 1852 and closed in 1867. It has no connection with the current university in Normal, Illinois.LHC95. A. W. Mack SpeechFolder 95596186595Scope and ContentsSpeech of Hon. A. W. Mack on the Slavery Question in the State Senate. (Springfield: Baker and Phillips, 1865). Published speech of Illinois State Senator Alonzo W. Mack of Kankakee County, urging "the complete destruction of the military power of the rebel government" and "the complete abolition of the system of domestic slavery," delivered in the State Senate on January 20, 1865. 20 p.LHC96.Folder 9659796Scope and ContentsTransferred to Special Collections, see JS 1460.4A1 S7 1898.  Report of Officers of the City of Springfield, Illinois for the fiscal year ending February 28, 1898. Contains information on city officials and offices, including the Mayor, City Council, Board of Education, Chief of Police, City Engineer, Water Works Department, etc.  Includes lists of street improvements, arrests made, fire runs, library circulation statistics, causes of death and burials, and financial statements. 224 p., 8.5" x 6".LHC97.Folder 9759897Scope and ContentsTransferred to Special Collections, see UG 854.I3S68 1988.  Lt. Col. Vince Looby, 183rd Tactical Fighter Group, 40th Anniversary, 1948-1988 (Dallas, Texas: Taylor Publishing Co., 1988). Pictorial history of the Illinois Air National Guard, stationed at Capitol Airport in Springfield, federalized as the 183rd Tactical Fighter Group and the 170th Fighter Squadron in 1948.  The book includes a narrative history of the group, plus photographs of past and present personnel, significant events, and deployments. 116 p., 11.5" x 9".LHC98. Ruth Ellis ReminiscenceFolder 98599198998Scope and ContentsAfrican American woman born in Springfield, Illinois in 1899. Moved to Detroit, Michigan in 1937. Ellis' reminiscence  "Ruth's Story," issued as a program for her 90th birthday dance, held in Detroit, July 16, 1989. Discusses memories of Springfield's black community, including family life, racial discrimination in the public schools, and the race riot of 1908. 4 p., 8.5" x 11"LHC99. William Loyd Clark, "Hell at Midnight in Springfield/Or a Burning History of the Sin and Shame/Of the Capitol City of Illinois"Folder 99600191099Scope and ContentsTract denouncing the moral effects of the brothels, bars and gambling dens of the "Levee" in Springfield. Includes vivid descriptions of the red-light district in Springfield and the corrupt city government that allowed it to exist. Includes an account of the race riot of 1908 and a sympathetic portrait of alleged murderer Joe James. Clark also denounces the Roman Catholic Church for encouraging the operation of bars and the production of distilled liquors. Also includes an account of the horrors of venereal disease and an account of the visit of evangelist Billy Sunday to Springfield in 1909. (Milan, Ill.: the author, 1910). 196 p., 7.5" x 5.5." Photocopy.LHC100. Paul M. Angle, The Marine Bank/The Story of the Oldest Bank in IllinoisFolder 1006011931100Scope and ContentsHistory of the Springfield Marine Bank, chartered in 1851, written by the noted historian Paul Angle. Includes accounts of the bank's founding as the Springfield Marine and Fire Insurance Company, its connections with the river trade, its connections with Abraham Lincoln, its continuance through financial crises of the 1850s and 1870s, and its role in the Civil War. Long the oldest continuously operating bank in Illinois, it was sold to Banc One in 1991. (Springfield, Ill.: Springfield Marine Bank, 1931). 21 p., 7.5" x 5.5."  Photocopy.LHC101.Folder 101602101Scope and ContentsTransferred to Special Collections, see F 549.S7 L43 1976.  Debbie Lee Troxell, Cat Houses of Lincolnland (Springfield: 1976).  A bicentennial salute to the history of Sangamon County and Springfield, Illinois, houses of ill repute.  Historical account of prostitution in Springfield, 1830-1976. Illustrated. 44 p., 8.5" x 5.5".LHC102.Folder 102603102Scope and ContentsTransferred to Special Collections, see PS 3523.158Z755 1968.  Frances S. Ridgely, A City is Not Builded in a Day (Springfield: Vachel Lindsay Association, 1968).  Story of Vachel Lindsay's background in the city of Springfield, Illinois, interweaving the early life of Vachel Lindsay, his poetry, and the history of Springfield.  Includes pen and ink drawings of Springfield historical scenes by the author. 34 p., illustrated, 8.5" x 5.5".LHC103.Folder 103604103Scope and ContentsDoes not exist.LHC104.Folder 104605104Scope and ContentsTransferred to Special Collections, see F 549.B43S3B 1925. Mrs. T. J. Schweer, History of Beardstown and Cass County (Beardstown, Illinois, 1925).  History of founding of Beardstown in 1827 by Thomas Beard, pioneer families of Cass County, and Dr. Charles Chandler of Chandlerville.  Includes accounts of pioneer customs, life in log cabins, conflicts with Indians, the Black Hawk War, the "Deep Snow" of 1830-31, the "sudden freeze" of 1836, the founding of churches, commerce on the Illinois River, attacks by wolves, and Abraham Lincoln and the Duff Armstrong "almanac" trail.  Written for use as a text book in the third grade, Beardstown Public Schools. 22 p., 9" x 6".LHC105. J. J. Thon, "Necrology and Chronicle"Folder 1056061823-1945105Scope and ContentsFarmer and long-time resident of New Berlin, Illinois. Thon recorded of deaths of local and public figures and significant local and national events that occurred between 1823 and 1945 in one line, handwritten entries. Entries include name, date and cause of death, location and age of the deceased. Dates of national significance include the death of presidents, the end of Prohibition, and the outbreak of war in Europe. Local incidents such as the Springfield race riot of 1908, severe weather, and the opening of businesses are recorded. Also included are records of the Thon family, and diagrams of the Wild Wood and Reynolds Coal Companies mines near New Berlin.LHC106.Folder 106607106Scope and ContentsTransferred to Special Collections, see F 549.A815H37 1994.  
William Harmening, Athenian Memoirs: Reflections of a Common Boy (s.l.: Author, 1994).  William Harmening, an alumnus of Sangamon State University, recalls life in Athens, Illinois 1961-1991, his childhood friends, townspeople, Athens businesses, grade school activities, Halloween pranks, high school activities, various sports and recreations such as  wrestling and bowling, dating, proms, and the Abraham Lincoln Long Nile Museum.
The strange-sounding title for this museum comes from the nickname given to Abraham Lincoln and eight others who represented Sangamon County in the Illinois General Assembly during the 1836-37 legislative session. All these men were at least six feet tall and shared similar political principles, hence the "long nine" appellation.LHC107. Caldwell Mansion, Chatham, IllinoisFolder 1076081979107Scope and ContentsTowered Italianate style mansion constructed in 1879 by Ben F. Caldwell, located north of Chatham, Illinois. The Caldwell family moved to Sangamon County from Greene County, Illinois in 1848. The anonymous essay discusses the Caldwell family and the architecture of their home and its imposing barn. Includes bibliography of sources. 8 p., 8.5" x 11."  Photocopy.LHC108. Illinois State Journal-Register, Springfield, IllinoisFolder 1086091956108Scope and ContentsAnniversary editions of Springfield newspaper which began as the Sangamo Journal in 1831: October 7, 1956, "125 Years of Publication," featuring "The Growth and Development of Springfield's Transportation and Finance," including articles on the establishment of railroads, the rise and decline of the streetcar, the rise of the automobile and associated problems, and the growth of Springfield banks.  20 p.
Located in Oversize Cabinet, drawer 5.LHC109. Illinois State Journal-Register, Springfield, IllinoisFolder 1096101981109Scope and ContentsAnniversary editions of Springfield newspaper which began as the Sangamo Journal in 1831.  November 10, 1981: "Our 150th Anniversary Edition": includes the news of the day, as well as sections devoted to the history of Springfield, the history of the presidency from Lincoln to Nixon, WWII, and the construction of the Illinois Statehouse. Includes are numerous reprints of photographs and articles from early issues of the newspaper. 146 p.
Located in Oversize Cabinet, drawer 5.LHC110. City Day School of SpringfieldFolder 1106111985110Scope and ContentsAlternative school founded by Joan Gillespie and Carolyn Oxtoby in Springfield, Illinois in 1969, initially offering grades 6-9, but eventually offering a complete program in grades 1-12. Later offered pre-school through elementary programs. The school closed ca. 1986. "Overview," compiled by Kathleen Hawks, detailing the history, accreditation, admissions policy, philosophy and curriculum of the City Day School. Also includes a listing of faculty members, the Board of Trustees, and several pages of student comments. 18 p., 8.5" x 11."LHC111.  Lions Club of Springfield, IllinoisFolder 111612ca. 1970111Scope and ContentsIncludes brief histories of Lions International and the Lions Club of Springfield, a chronology of club activities, rosters of officers and board members, and the constitution and by-laws of the club.  Lions International is a service club founded by Melvin Jones in Chicago in 1917. The Lions of Springfield was formed in October, 1919. 94 p., 8.5" x 11".LHC112. Historic Encyclopedia of Illinois and Sangamon CountyFolder 1126131912112Scope and ContentsPaul Selby, editor, Vol. II (Part 1), Illustrated. Chicago: Munsell Publishing Co., 1912. 34 plates, 8" x 10.5".  Plates show public buildings and churches in Sangamon County, Chicago, and elsewhere. Also some depict prominent people from Sangamon County and Illinois.LHC113. Capital and Bicentennial Commission, Springfield and Sangamon County, IllinoisFolder 113614ca. 1977113Scope and Contents"The Chairman's Scrapbook, 519 Days." Publication documenting celebrations of the U.S. Bicentennial in Springfield and Sangamon County, Illinois, 1975-1976. Includes photographs, newspaper clippings, lists of events and their participants. 56 p., 10" x 13".
2nd copy located in OVERSIZE book shelf.LHC114. Improved Order of Red Men, Great Council of IllinoisFolder 1146151912-1915114Scope and ContentsThree panoramic group photos taken at conventions of the Improved Order of Red Men, Great Council of Illinois, in Springfield, Jacksonville, and Mattoon in 1912, 1913 and 1915 respectively. The Improved Order of Red Men is a patriotic fraternal organization founded in Baltimore in 1834, tracing its origins to secret liberty societies formed before the American Revolution, such as the Sons of Liberty who dressed as Indians and dumped English tea into Boston Harbor in 1773. The I.O.R.M peaked around 1920, when its membership included over a half-million men in 46 states. Photo 1: outside the Illinois Statehouse in Springfield, May 21, 1912,  44" x 8", by Vermillion Photo of Springfield. Photo 2: in the Public Square in Jacksonville, May 20, 1913, 44" x 8", by Vermillion Photo. Photo 3: in Mattoon, May 18-19, 1915, 32" x 8", "Cirkut" by Rembrandt Studios, Decatur.LHC115. Ancient and Accepted Scottish Rite, Springfield (IL) ConsistoryFolder 1156161918115Scope and ContentsPoster showing photographic portraits of Freemasons belonging to the Springfield Consistory of the Ancient and Accepted Scottish Rite, printed in association with a meeting of the Springfield Valley of the AASR, November 25-27, 1918. The black and white portraits of 197 individual members, taken by Kessberger Photo of Springfield, are identified by name. The Scottish Rite, one of the two major branches of Freemasonry, traces its American origins to Charleston, South Carolina in 1802.LHC116. Virginia, Illinois Sesquicentennial Pageant ProgramFolder 1166171986116Scope and ContentsProgram of pageant performed at the high school in Virginia, Illinois on June 4 and 5, 1986 to celebrate the 150th anniversary of the founding of Virginia. Program for the eight-act pageant include a description of the historical and events enacted, and the names of the performers, stage crew, and sponsors. Also included is an inserted map of Virginia, showing the locations of events connected to the town's Sesquicentennial festival.LHC117. Journal-Courier, Jacksonville, IllinoisFolder 1176182000117Scope and ContentsA special supplement to the Journal-Courier, "A Journey Through Time: Jacksonville, 1825-2000", published September 3, 2000,  commemorating the 175th anniversary of the founding of Jacksonville, Illinois in 1825. The 156-page illustrated newspaper includes thirteen sections covering the history of Jacksonville in the 19th and 20th centuries, the 10 most important events in the town's history, public institutions, businesses, fires and other disasters, the town's historic architecture, churches, educational institutions, sports, and the 10 most influential persons in the town's history. 13 sections, 156 pages.LHC118. Illinois State Register, Springfield, IllinoisFolder 1186191845118Scope and ContentsIssue of the Illinois State Register, dated Friday, January 17, 1845. Included are the minutes and constitution of the Illinois Colonization Society, proceedings of the Illinois State Legislature, a listing of lands in Montgomery County on which taxes were due, legal notices, notices of escaped livestock, and advertisements for Springfield businesses, public events, and entertainments. 1 sheet, 4 pages.LHC119. "Celebrate: Historic West Springfield"Folder 1196202003119Scope and ContentsProgram outline a two day festival occurring in Springfield on October 10 and 11, 2003.  An "Events Schedule" is displayed inside the front cover.  Highlighted events include tours of historic homes, Civil War reenactors, and a period costume ball.LHC120. Alpha Iota SororityFolder 120514171940120Scope and ContentsThree photos; one group photo of the Lambda Chi Chapter; two panoramic group photos of the 10th National Convention held at the Hotel Stevens in Chicago, IL on July 4 to 7, 1940.
Located in Oversize, Drawer 9.LHC121. Office of Price Administration, Springfield DistrictFolder 121514188/18/1945121Scope and ContentsTwo photos; one group photo and one panoramic group photo.
Donated by Mike Townsend.
Located in Oversize, Drawer 9.LHC122. Illinois State Journal-Register, Springfield, IllinoisFolder 122514222006122Scope and Contents175th Anniversary edition of Springfield newspaper which began as the Sangamo Journal in 1831: November 10, 2006, "A Prairie Capital: 175 Years." This edition chronicles the historical story of the capital city from muddy frontier town of about 700 people to 2006 modern city of 115, 500.Section 1, 38 p., Section 2 divided into 18 sections in ten year increments.Located in Oversize Cabinet, drawer 5.LHC123. Map of Camp Butler, Sangamon County, IllinoisFolder 123742571863123Scope and ContentsMap, 1 item, 21.5" x 17." Copy.&#xD;
"Plan showing Lands occupied for Camp Butler also lands trespassed upon by troops &amp;c situate in Sangamon Co. Illinois &amp; in Township 16 N. R. 4 West of 3rd P.M. -1863- ." &#xD;
A hand drawn map, author unknown, showing the location of the Civil War era Camp Butler on the Sangamon River, south of James Town (now Riverton, Illinois). The map shows the location of the camp's barracks, headquarters at the Clear Lake Hotel, first cemetery, as well as the course of the Sangamon River, roads, the Great Western Railroad, and wooded areas.&#xD;
 &#xD;
Camp Butler, named after state treasurer William Butler, was established as a muster-in and training camp in the summer of 1861. It became the second-largest military camp in Illinois after Camp Douglas in Chicago. In February, 1862 the Camp began to be used to hold Confederate prisoners. Soon after they arrived a smallpox epidemic killed 700 prisoners and a cemetery was established. On 17 July 1862 President Lincoln designated Camp Butler as one of 16 original National Cemeteries, and it began to be used for the burial of Union soldiers as well. By the end of the war 1,642 soldiers were buried at Camp Butler. Camp Butler has continued as a military cemetery to the present.&#xD;
Copy of an original map located in the Abraham Lincoln Presidential Library.&#xD;
Gift of Arlyn Booth and Ron Peddicord, 2012. LHC 123.&#xD;
Located in Oversize Cabinet, drawer 10.OVERSIZE cabinet 1OVERSIZE cabinet 150367LHC72Folder 726901272Scope and ContentsLand of Lincoln Progress Report, 1982
In drawer 2.LHC108Folder 10851419108Scope and ContentsIllinois State Journal-Register, 1956
Springfield, Illinois
125th anniversary edition
In drawer 5.LHC109Folder 10951420109Scope and ContentsIllinois State Journal-Register, 1981
Springfield, Illinois
150th anniversary edition
In drawer 5.LHC120Folder 12050368120Scope and Contents10th Annual Convention of the Alpha Iota Sorority held at Hotel Stevens in Chicago, Illinois July 4 to 7, 1940.  Also includes Lambda Chi Chapter of Alpha Iota (no date).
Collection consists of 3 pictures: 20 in. x 10 in., 28 in. x 10  in., and 14.5 in. x 14 in.
In drawer 9.LHC121Folder 12150432121Scope and ContentsOffice of Price Administration, Springfield District, August 18, 1945.  Collection consists of 2 pictures: 20 in. x 8 in. and 13.5 in. x 11.5 in. (matted)  by Herbert Georg Studio.
In drawer 9.LHC122Folder 12251421122Scope and ContentsIllinois State Journal-Register, 2006
Springfield, Illinois
175th anniversary edition
In drawer 5.LHC123Folder 12374258123Scope and ContentsMap of Camp Butler, Sangamon County, Illinois, 1836
1 item, 21.5" x 17." Copy. 
In drawer 10.

