<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>M.09Archon Finding Aid Title M.09UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:10:26 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    M9. Meteorological Records, Springfield, Illinois, 1879-1994
    M.09
    673
    
      23.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1879-1994
    Date acquired: 09/07/1990
    1
    2
    3
    4
    5
    6
    7
    50
    51
    52
    53
    54
    55
    56
    57
    8
    9
    10
    11
    12
    13
    14
    15
    16
    17
    18
    19
    20
    21
    22
    23
    24
    25
    26
    27
    28
    29
    30
    31
    32
    33
    34
    35
    36
    37
    38
    39
    40
    41
    42
    43
    44
    45
    46
    47
    48
    49
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Daily weather observation records compiled in Springfield, showing barometric pressure, temperature, daily highs and lows, relative humidity, dew point, wind direction and velocity, amounts of sunshine, cloud types, precipitation amounts, and sunset observations. Also includes sums and means of observations, and monthly and annual summaries. 

In the years before 1948, written descriptions of unusual phenomena (frosts, halos, heavy precipitation, droughts, auroras, meteor showers, earthquakes, etc.) are often included, as well as narrative accounts of severe storms, and newspaper clippings of weather-related stories. Also included are descriptions and plans of the locations of the recording stations, and information on recording equipment used. 

The daily observation records consist of bound volumes, 1879-1948;  ledger sheets, 1948-1988; and computer print-outs after 1989. Also included are Means Books, Climatological Records and Local Climatological Data, which summarize and compare weather data on a monthly and annual basis.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Charles Finley, Nationial Weather Service  
  
    Records
    Reports
  
  U.S. War Department, Signal Service, 1879-1881; U.S. Army, Division of Telegrams and Reports for the Benefit of Commerce and Agriculture, 1881-1889Series 11761Box 1Box 11758Meteorological Record, Springfield, IllinoisItem 117645 July 1879-22 October 18811Scope and ContentsDaily record of temperature (including maxima and minima), barometric pressure, hygrometer readings, wind velocity and direction, cloud types, and precipitation. Readings taken four to six times a day. I volume.Box 2Box 21767Monthly Meteorological Report, Springfield, Illinois.Item 11769September 1881-January 18861Scope and ContentsDaily record of barometric pressure, temperature (including maxima and minima), relative humidity, dew-point, wind direction and velocity, cloud types, precipitation amounts, and sunset observations. Also includes sums and means of observations and comments on unusual phenomena (frosts, halos, heavy precipitation, etc.) Readings taken three times a day.Monthly Meteorological Report, Springfield, IllinoisItem 21770February 1886-January 18892Monthly Meteorological Report, Springfield, IllinoisItem 31771February 1889-June 18893U.S. Department of Agriculture, Weather Bureau, 1889-1940Series 21772Box 2Box 21773Scope and ContentsThe Original Monthly Record of Observations (1889-1943) is a monthly compilation of a daily record of barometric pressure, temperature (including maxima and minima), relative humidity, dewpoint, wind direction and velocity, amounts of sunshine, cloud types, precipitation amounts, and sunset observations. Also includes sums and means of observations, monthly and annual 	summaries, and comments on unusual phenomena (frosts, halos, heavy precipitation, auroras, meteor showers, earthquakes, eclipses, heat prostrations, etc.) Readings summarized twice daily, 1889-1904. From 1905 a "Daily Local Record" is included, showing hourly observations. 		Written narratives of weather observations, and especially of severe storms, are often included, as well as newspaper clippings of weather-related stories. The Meteorological Record (1944-1948) is similar.Original Monthly Record of Observations at Springfield, IllinoisItem 417761889-18924Original Monthly Record of Observations at Springfield, IllinoisItem 517771893-18965Original Monthly Record of Observations at Springfield, IllinoisItem 617781897-19006Original Monthly Record of Observations at Springfield, IllinoisBox 317791901-1910Item 117811901-19041Daily Journal; Sunshine, Wind Direction, Wind VelocityItem 217821900-19042Scope and ContentsBound volume of onion skin carbon copies of daily narrative journal of weather conditions, including descriptions of thunderstorms, fog, solar halos, snowstorms, and other weather phenomena. Also included are hourly observation records of wind velocity and direction, and sunshine. The daily journal includes a subject index.Original Monthly Record of Observations at Springfield, IllinoisItem 3178319053Item 4178419064Item 5178619075Item 6178719086Item 7178819097Item 8179019108Scope and ContentsIncludes clipping and comments on feared effects of Halley's Comet.Original Monthly Record of Observations at Springfield, IllinoisBox 417911911-1920Item 1179519111Scope and ContentsIncludes report and newspaper clippings on severe thunderstorms of 6 and 13 September.Item 2179619122Item 3179719133Item 4179819154Item 5179919165Item 6180019176Item 7180219187Scope and ContentsIncludes brief account of snowstorm of 10-14 January.Item 8180319198Item 9180419209Original Monthly Record of Observations at Springfield, IllinoisBox 518071921-1930Item 1180819211Item 2180919222Scope and ContentsIncludes report on severe thunderstorm of 13 June.Item 3181019233Item 4181119244Scope and ContentsIncludes clippings on ice storm of 17-18 December.Item 5181219255Scope and ContentsIncludes report on severe thunderstorm of 13 April.Item 6181319266Item 7181419277Scope and ContentsIncludes clipping on tornado of 19 April.Item 8181519288Item 9181619299Scope and ContentsIncludes clippings on snowstorms of 23 October and 20-22 December.Item 101817193010Original Monthly Record of Observations at Springfield, IllinoisBox 618181931-1939Item 1181919311Item 2182019322Item 3182119333Scope and ContentsIncludes report on hailstorm of 9 May.Item 4182219344Item 5182319355Scope and ContentsIncludes clipping on severe thunderstorm of 8 May.Item 6182419366Scope and ContentsIncludes clipping on dust storm of 9 June.Item 7182519377Scope and ContentsIncludes clippings on ice storms of 7-8 January and 12-21 December.Item 8182719388Item 9182819399Scope and ContentsIncludes clippings on winter storms in February, severe thunderstorms of 15 April and 6 August, and earthquake of 23 November.Box 7Box 71848Original Monthly Record of Observations at Springfield, IllinoisItem 1185019401U.S. Department of Commerce, Weather Bureau, 1941-68Series 31843Box 7Box 71852Original Monthly Record of Observations at Springfield, IllinoisItem 2185319412Scope and ContentsIncludes clippings on tornadoes of 19 April and 3 October.Item 3185419423Item 4185519434Scope and ContentsIncludes clipping on severe thunderstorm of 4 July.Meteorological Record, Springfield, IllinoisItem 5185619445Item 6185719456Scope and ContentsIncludes clipping on severe thunderstorm of 11 August.Item 7185819467Scope and ContentsIncludes report on aurora of 26 July.Item 8185919478Scope and ContentsIncludes clipping on severe thunderstorm of 15 May.Item 9186019489Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, Illinois (4 folders)Box 81862September-December 1948Scope and ContentsSurface Weather Observations (1948-1992) are carbon copies of ledger sheets recording hourly observations of barometric pressure, temperature (including maxima and minima), relative humidity, percentage of sky cover, cloud types, precipitation amounts, wind direction and velocity, visibility, and minutes of sunshine. Also includes daily and monthly sums and means of observations, and brief notes of unusual phenomena. Beginning in 1989, the record takes the form of computer 	print-outs.Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 918671949Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 1018681950Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 1118691951Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 1218701952Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 1318711953Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 1418721954Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 1518731955Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 1618741956Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 1718751957Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 1818761958Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 1918801959Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 2018811960Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 2118821961Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 2218831962Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 2318841963Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 2418861964Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 2518871965Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 2618881966Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 2718891967Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 2818911968Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Environmental Science Services Administration, Environmental Data Service, 1969-1973Series 41844Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 2918921969Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 3018931970Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 3118941971Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 3218951972Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 3318961973Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, National Weather Service, 1974-1994Series 51845Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 3418971974Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 3518981975Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 3619391976Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 3719401977Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 3819411978Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 3919421979Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 4019431980Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 4119441981Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 4219451982Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 4319461983Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 4419471984Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 4519481985Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 4619491986Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 4719501987Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 4819511988Scope and ContentsJan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 4919521989Scope and ContentsComputer printouts, Jan - Dec (12 folders)Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 5322101990Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 5422111991Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 5522121992Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 5622131993Surface Weather Observations, Springfield, IllinoisBox 5722141994Means Books, Climatological Data, and Miscellaneous Records, 1879-1992Series 61953Means Books &amp; Climatological RecordsBox 5019541879-1970U.S. Department of Agriculture, Weather Bureau.  Means Book, Springfield, IllinoisItem 119551879-18981Scope and ContentsMeans Books are monthly and annual summaries of maxima, minima, and means of temperature, 	wind direction and velocity, precipitation amounts, cloud cover, barometric pressure, dates of first and last frosts, relative humidity, and 	occurrence of thunderstorms and foggy days. Also includes remarks on unusual weather occurrences, such as severe thunderstorms, blizzards, 	floods, and droughts. 2 vols.U.S. Department of Agriculture, Weather Bureau.  Means Book, Springfield, IllinoisItem 219561899-19042Scope and ContentsVol. 2 of 2U.S. Department of Agriculture, Weather Bureau: Illinois Weather Service, Monthly Section PublicationsItem 31957November 1891-November 18943Scope and ContentsStatewide summary of means and extremes of temperature, barometric pressure, and precipitation; also averages of clear days and prevailing wind direction, and dates of occurrences of thunderstorms, hailstorms, rainbows, fog, frost, halos and auroras. Also included are means and extremes of 	temperature and precipitation and occurrences of clear days at about 65 	stations around Illinois.U.S. Department of Commerce, Weather Bureau. Climatological Record, Springfield, IllinoisItem 419581879-19104Scope and ContentsDetailed comparative monthly and annual summaries of means and extremes of 	barometric pressure, temperature, precipitation, wind direction and velocity, cloudiness and sunshine, and numbers of days with fog, hail, thunderstorms, halos and auroras. Also included is information on the 	types and placement of measuring instruments, and location and layout of 	the recording station. 5 vols.Climatological Record, Springfield, IllinoisItem 519591911-19305Scope and ContentsVol. 2 of 5Climatological Record, Springfield, IllinoisItem 619601930-19506Scope and ContentsVol. 3 of 5Climatological Record, Springfield, IllinoisItem 719611931-19507Scope and ContentsVol. 4 of 5. Inserted documents:Quantity of Rain and melted Snow, in inches, abstracted from the Meteorological Observations of JOEL HALL, kept at Athens, Ill. from January, 1st 1843 to the present time [1861.]Easter Sunday minimum temperatures, 1882-1965Degree Days, 1895-1951Newspaper clipping showing old Post Office and Government Building, where 	Weather Bureau was located, 1879-1905Plans of Weather Bureau Office in Federal Building at Seventh and Monroe, showing locations of recording devices and rooms, 1932Pressure, Highest and Lowest, in inches and hundredths...extremes for entire record of 61 years, 1946Percentages of directions from which the wind blows as determined from the 	Springfield Airport records for the period 1929-1942Description of Topography and Exposure of Instruments at Weather Reporting 	Station, 1943Index of Earthquake Tremors at Springfield, Illinois, 1905-1947Climatological Record, Springfield, IllinoisItem 819621951-19708Scope and ContentsVol. 5 of 5Station Meteorological SummariesItem 919721949-19549Scope and ContentsIncludes duplicate of Surface Weather Observations, 1949Local Climatological Data, Springfield, IllinoisBox 5119771947, 1949-1980Scope and ContentsPublished monthly and annual summaries of temperature averages and extremes, precipitation, relative humidity, wind direction and velocity, cloudiness and sunshine. Also included are tables comparing average temperatures, precipitation totals, heating and cooling degree days, and snowfall for 40-year periods.Springfield: Daily Normal of temperature and degree daysFolder 119811931-19601Annual Meteorological Summary, 1947; Monthly Climatological Summary, 1949Folder 219822Station Meteorological SummaryFolder 3216619503Station Meteorological SummaryFolder 4216719514Local Climatological DataFolder 5216819525Local Climatological DataFolder 6216919536Local Climatological DataFolder 7217019547Local Climatological DataFolder 8217119558Local Climatological DataFolder 9217219569Local Climatological DataFolder 102173195710Local Climatological DataFolder 112174195811Local Climatological DataFolder 122175195912Local Climatological DataFolder 132176196013Local Climatological DataFolder 142177196114Local Climatological DataFolder 152178196215Local Climatological DataFolder 162179196316Local Climatological DataFolder 172180196417Local Climatological DataFolder 182181196518Local Climatological DataFolder 192182196619Local Climatological DataFolder 202183196720Local Climatological DataFolder 212184196821Local Climatological DataFolder 222185196922Local Climatological DataFolder 232186197023Local Climatological DataFolder 242187197124Local Climatological DataFolder 252188197225Local Climatological DataFolder 262189197326Local Climatological DataFolder 272190197427Local Climatological DataFolder 282191197528Local Climatological DataFolder 292192197629Local Climatological DataFolder 302193197730Local Climatological DataFolder 312194197831Local Climatological DataFolder 322195197932Local Climatological DataFolder 332196198033Local Climatological Data, Springfield, IllinoisBox 5221971981-1992Local Climatological DataFolder 1219819811Local Climatological DataFolder 2219919822Local Climatological DataFolder 3220019833Local Climatological DataFolder 4220119844Local Climatological DataFolder 5220219855Local Climatological DataFolder 6220319866Local Climatological DataFolder 7220419877Local Climatological DataFolder 8220519888Local Climatological DataFolder 9220619899Local Climatological DataFolder 102207199010Local Climatological DataFolder 112208199111Local Climatological DataFolder 122209199212Scope and ContentsJan - Oct only

