<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>E.01.01/20Archon Finding Aid Title E.01.01/20UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:12:23 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    E1/1/20. President's Office, Grants and Contracts File, 1969-1978
    
      President/Chancellor
    
    E.01.01/20
    204
    
      3.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1969-1978
    Date acquired: 00/00/1981
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Grants and Contracts File of Wilbur F. Moulton, Executive Assistant to the President (1973-82), containing correspondence, memos, grant applications, balance sheets, budget and financial statements, and contracts with state and federal agencies.  The grants originate from Illinois Agencies as the Environmental Protections Agency, Illinois Arts Council, Department of Personnel, Department of Conservation, and Federal agencies such as the National Endowment of the Humanities, National Science Foundation, U.S. Army, and the Corporation of Public Broadcasting and funds for university research projects, fellowships, internships and the development of radio station WSSR.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Wilbur F. Moulton  
  Box 1Box 130511Advanced MGT Study Grant - Corporation for Public BroadcastingFolder 13051219771Algae Test and Odor Problems (Goins) - EPAFolder 23051419752Allied Health Baccalaureate Degree Program Planning Division of Natural ScienceFolder 3305151972-743Bicentennial Oral History Project - Cullom DavisFolder 4305161974-754Blues Concerts &amp; Workshops in the Community - Illinois Arts CouncilFolder 53051719775Breaking Barriers in Public Trust - Illinois Humanities CouncilFolder 63051819746Broadcasting Facilities Program - HEWFolder 7305191969-757Center of Excellence for Education in Criminal Justice, Department of JusticeFolder 83052019728College Library Resources Program - Howard DillonFolder 9305211975-769College Library Resources Grants - C. Davis - DHEWFolder 10305221975-7610College Library Resources Program - Howard DillonFolder 11305231973-7511Community Arts Management - David Sennema (Humanities)Folder 12305241974-7612College Library Resources Program - Howard DillonFolder 13305251974-7513College Library Resources - Howard Dillon – LibraryFolder 14305261974-7514College Work-Study Program - J. AllisonFolder 15305271975-7615Community Arts Resource Program - SennemaFolder 16305281976-7716Community Arts Resources - Illinois Arts CouncilFolder 17305291976-7717Community College Frontiers - Illinois Board Of Higher EducationFolder 18305301972-7518Communications, the Arts &amp; Aging - Training Workshop for the ProfessionsFolder 19305311977-7819Community Service Incentive Project – Corporation for Public BroadcastingFolder 20305321975-7620COPE - Illinois Department of Children and Family Services - John MillerFolder 2130533197721COPE Renewal - Illinois Department of Children and Family ServicesFolder 22305341975-7622Community Opportunity Program Effectors - Public Services Children and Family ServicesFolder 23305351973-7423Community Opportunity Program Effectors - Public Services Children and Family ServicesFolder 24305361974-7524Comparative Evaluation of Police Cadet - Illinois Law Enforcement CommissionFolder 25305371974-7525COPE Satellite Contract Agreement - Illinois Department of Children and Family ServicesFolder 26305381974-7526Coping With Loss in Later Life - Illinois Department on AgingFolder 2730539197727Criminal Justice Awareness Project - Crime Prevention CommissionFolder 28305401976-7728Criminal Justice, Illinois-Information, Local Government Office - Illinois Law 	Enforcement CommissionFolder 2930541197829Curricular Support Material for Urban League – Bob Crowley (Division of Public 	Service)Folder 30305421973-7430Delinquency Prevention, Planning and Evaluation Model (Milner), Illinois Commission on Delinquency PreventionFolder 31305431976-7731Demographic Analysis - Black Community of Springfield Human Relations Commission - Division of Social ScienceFolder 3230544197332Developmental Training Needs Assessment, Instruction (CETA)Folder 3330545197833Development for Classifiers - Applied Studies - Illinois Department of PersonnelFolder 3430546197334Education Policy Fellows Program - Bunnell – Illinois Office of EducationFolder 35305471976-7735Education Policy Fellows Program - IBHE - Bob BunnellFolder 36305481976-7736Educational Opportunity Grant - Vince ChiaroFolder 3730549197437Educational Opportunity Grant - Vince ChiaroFolder 38305501973-7438Energy Awareness Film - Illinois Humanities CouncilFolder 39305511977-7839Energy Legislation Conference - Illinois Resources CommissionFolder 4030552197740Energy Reorganization Research - Illinois Energy Resources CommissionFolder 41305531976-7741Environmental Affairs Fellowship - Rockefeller FoundationFolder 42305541976-7742Evaluation of CARE for Headstart Teachers - Ohio State University Research FoundationFolder 4330555197443Evaluation of the Childrens ListingFolder 4430556197644Evaluation of Process and Impact of Anti-Terrorism Training (Milner) - State PoliceFolder 45305571977-7845Expanded Adult Opportunity Planning and Development for Women (J. Everson), IBHEFolder 46305581976-7746Exxon Impact Program guided design Project – Exxon Education FoundationFolder 47305591975-7647Faculty Institute for High School Teachers – Energy (Al Casella) Energy Research and AdministrationFolder 4830560197748Box 2Box 230561Farmers' Attitudes toward Deer Hunt - Illinois Department of Conservation, D. 	JohnsonFolder 1305621977-781Federal Student Financial Aid ProgramsFolder 230563FY 19762Scope and ContentsNational Direct Student Loan, College Work-Study, Supplemental Education Opportunity GrantFellowships for Community Arts Management Program National Endowment Arts - KatzFolder 3305641977-783Fellowships for Community Arts Management Program National Endowment Arts - SennemaFolder 4305651976-774Fellowships for Community Arts Management Program National Endowment ArtsFolder 5305661975-765Fellowships for Community Arts Management Program National Endowment Arts - George Schurr (David Sennema)Folder 6305671974-756Forecasting Water Use in Department of Conservation Parks (Pinkus), Illinois Department of ConservationFolder 73056819777Gerontology Institute (Kindschi) - Lt. Governors OfficeFolder 83056919758Graduate Public Service Interns - Various State Agencies KuceraFolder 9305701977-789Graduate Public Service Interns - Illinois Dept. of PersonnelFolder 10305711973-7410Graduate Studies Center (Millikin) - Board of Higher Education, Wilbur MoultonFolder 11305721973-7411Health Resources Administration Evaluation (DHEW)Folder 12305731977-7812Program for the National Endowment of the HumanitiesFolder 1330574197513Human Development Counseling - Human Relations Workshop Robert ZellerFolder 1430575197314Human Resource Inventory and Information System for Alternative System (D. Johnson)Folder 1530576197615Illinois Issues - Ford FoundationFolder 16305771976-7716Illinois Issues - A Magazine on Illinois State Government and PoliticsFolder 17305781974-7617Illinois Legislative Staff Internship Program – Illinois Legislative Council, CohenFolder 18305791977-7818Illinois Legislative Staff Internship Program – Illinois Legislative Council, CohenFolder 19305801976-7719Howard E. Jensen Research Fund, Dan JohnsonFolder 2030581197520IREC Internship - Leon Cohen - Illinois Energy Resources CommissionFolder 2130582197721Illinois Arts Council Scholarships (Sennema)Folder 22305831972-7522Illinois Intergovernmental Personnel Development Center David Day - Division of Professional and Applied StudiesFolder 23305841972-7323Illinois Legislative Science Internship Program Leon Cohen (Reid,Sames) Social 	ScienceFolder 24305851973-7524Master Plan Convocation, Working FileFolder 2530586197525Illinois Master Plan for University Environmental Education, F. Smith, Illinois Institute for Environmental QualityFolder 2630587197526Illinois Private Sector Legislative Internship Program Leon CohenFolder 27305881976-7727Illinois State Theater, Illinois Colleges &amp; Universities KendallFolder 2830589197728Institute for Lab Experiment with Exceptional Children MacMurray College (D.R. 	Buckley, Wilbur Moulton)Folder 29305901973-7429Institutional Renewal Project, Project on Institutional Renewal - RollinsFolder 30305911977-7830Inter-institutional Development of Competency Certification - Upper &amp; Lower Division Liberal Arts Core, Sipe, BreisethFolder 31305921975-7631An Inter-Institutional Effort to Establish a Competency Based Bachelor of Arts Degree in HistoryFolder 32305931974-7532Scope and ContentsCharles Strozier (Division of Humanities) ICC PeoriaInterracial Training Institute, Title IVFolder 3330594197533Intro to Gerontology (Lesnoff-Caravaglia), Illinois Department of AgingFolder 3430595197734IPA Assignment Agreement (ERDA) RauckhorstFolder 35305961976-7735Labor Market Survey - Central Illinois – Government Office of Manpower and Human Development Murray - Public ServiceFolder 36305971975-7836Law Enforcement Internship Program - Vince ChiaroFolder 3730598197337Scope and ContentsDivision of Financial Aid, U.S. Department Of EducationLaw Enforcement Education Program - Law Enforcement Assistance 	AdministrationFolder 3830599197538Law Enforcement Education Program (LEED) - Chiaro - Financial AidFolder 3930600FY 197539Law Enforcement Assistance Adm. Grant (Crane) U.S. Department of JusticeFolder 40306011976-7740Law Focused Education Project - Kindschi - Law in American Society FoundationFolder 4130602197541Leadership Training Workshop - Illinois Department of Aging- Department of Aging (Lesnoff Caravaglia)Folder 4230603197742Lincoln Intersession (Strozer) Humanities – Illinois Bicentennial CommissionFolder 43306041975-7643Long Range Budget Model (IBHE)Folder 4430605197844Management Communication - City of Urbana Illinois L. MillerFolder 4530606197845Management Counseling (Small Business Administration) BowmanFolder 4630607197546Mid-Illinois Computer Cooperative, IECCS (Goins)Folder 47306081975-7647Midwest Conference on State VR Ag. Program EvaluationFolder 48306091972-7348Nursing Capitation (DHEW)Folder 49306101977-7849Nursing Capitation Grant Program (DHEW)Folder 50306111976-7750Nursing Scholarships - Doughterty, HEWFolder 51306121976-7751Personnel System Development - Illinois Secretary of StateFolder 52306131977-7852Poets on Film (Damashek) - Illinois Arts CouncilFolder 53306141975-7653Performance Evaluation, City of Champaign IllinoisFolder 5430615197854Performance Evaluation Workshops, City of DecaturFolder 5530616197755Box 3Box 330617Performance Evaluation, City of Rock Island - L. MillerFolder 13061819781Planning, Grant-Establishment in New Baccalaureate Degree Program in NursingFolder 2306191972-732Potential Impact of Solar Energy Technology, Lassella (Physical Science)Folder 33062019753Probation Officer Training, Illinois Law Enforcement CommissionFolder 43062119774Probation Officer Training, Illinois Law Enforcement CommissionFolder 5306221977-785Probation Officer Training, Illinois Law Enforcement CommissionFolder 6306231976-776Probation Service Training (Crane), Public ServiceFolder 73062419767Probation Services Council - Crane, File #1Folder 8306251975-768Scope and ContentsSocial Sciences Illinois Law Enforcement 	CommissionProbation Services Council - Crane, File #2Folder 9306281975-769Scope and ContentsSocial Sciences Illinois Law Enforcement 	CommissionRegional Coordinator for the ArtsFolder 10306261974-7510Science &amp; Ethics (Schurr), National Science FoundationFolder 11306271975-7611Public Opinion Poll on Open Burning, K.G. Janardan National Science Foundation (Sames)Folder 1230629197312Quality of Life among Asian Americans in Middle Sized CitiesFolder 13306301977-7813Radio Coverage Expansion Project, Corporation for Public BroadcastingFolder 14306311975-7614Radio Development - Corporation for Public Broadcasting OuztsFolder 15306321975-7615Regional Coordinator for the Arts (NEA) Bertha MasorFolder 16306331976-7716Regional Coordinator for the Arts (NEA) Bertha MasorFolder 17306341975-7617Program Evaluation (Pinkus), Center for Program Development &amp; Handicapped, Chicago City CollegesFolder 1830635197718Public Administration in Higher Education, Illinois Department of Personnel, Geoffery Cornog, Applied StudiesFolder 1930636197319Public Affairs Development - Sciences, Sames (Kellett) Division of Natural SciencesFolder 20306371973-7420Scholarships for Arts Administration, Sennema – Illinois Arts CouncilFolder 21306381974-7521School of Finance Research Project, Illinois Office Of EducationFolder 22306391977-7822Science &amp; the Public Process, National Science FoundationFolder 23306401975-7623Secondary Teacher Energy Education Workshop (ERDA) - StevensFolder 2430641197824Sex Discrimination in Insurance- Illinois Insurance Laws Study Commission &amp; Department of InsuranceFolder 2530642197725Social Justice Planning Workshop (Milner) Illinois Law Enforcement CommissionFolder 2630643197526Social Rehabilitation, Training Seminar, HOC, HEW - Office of Long Term CareFolder 27306441975-7627Solar Energy applications To Home Heating John Drabanski, Al CasellaFolder 28306451974-7528Speakers Office, Additional Intern, Speaker of the Illinois HouseFolder 29306461976-7729Springboard - Illinois Arts Council, SennemaFolder 30306471975-7630Springfield Desegregation Monitoring Committee Illinois Office of EducationFolder 31306481977-7831Springfield Desegregation Monitoring Commission  KendallFolder 3230649197732Springfield Desegregation Monitoring System KendallFolder 3330650197733Springboard - Sennema - Illinois Arts CouncilFolder 3430651197434Springfield Electrical Usage Study, City of Springfield, (D. Johnson)Folder 3530652197735Streetside Boosters '78, City Of Springfield (City Water Light &amp; Power), TownsendFolder 36306531977-7836Streetside Boosters (Townsend), Illinois Commission on Delinquency PreventionFolder 37306541976-7737Streetside Boosters Neighborhood Organization (Townsend) Illinois Commission on Delinquency PreventionFolder 3830655197638Student Legislative Aide, Trinity Christian College CohenFolder 3930656197739Study of Energy Conservation Programs (Charles Pinkus) Illinois Institute for Environmental QualityFolder 4030657197740Study of Reorganization for Energy Policy, Illinois Energy Resource CommissionFolder 4130658197641Study of Scientific and Technological Information and Knowledge, Richard SamesFolder 42306591973-7442Summer Internship - Robert Vaughn - Sennema NEAFolder 4330660197543Summer Internship (Angus Randolph) George Schurr (Division of Humanities)Folder 4430661197444Scope and ContentsNational Foundation for the ArtsSupport Network for Facilitating School Integration in SpringfieldFolder 45306621973-7645Scope and ContentsAn Adult Interracial Education Program (Gus Stevens) Phil KendallSupport Network for Facilitating School Integration in SpringfieldFolder 4630663FY 1975-7646Scope and ContentsAn Adult Interracial Education Program (Gus Stevens) Phil KendallTeam for Institutional Renewal, Project for Institutional Renewal, JohnstonFolder 4730664197647Undergraduate Research Participation, William Rauckhorst (National Science Foundation)Folder 48306651974-7548Title IV, Grant to continue Summer Institute StevensFolder 49306661974-7549Box 4Box 430667Title VI - An Application Grant Equipment and Materials, File # 1Folder 1306681972-761Title VI - An Application Grant Equipment and Materials, File # 2Folder 2306691969-722Touring Artists Program, Illinois Arts Council, BURPEEFolder 33067019783Tuition Assistance to Military Persons, Department of ArmyFolder 4306711975-764Undergraduate Research Participation, Rauckhorst (National Science Foundation)Folder 53067219765Undergraduate Research Participation William Rauckhorst (National Science Foundation)Folder 63067319756Veterans Cost-of-Instruction Payments, Ray Bess Admissions and RecordsFolder 7306741973-747Veterans Cost-of-Instruction Payments, Ray Bess Admissions and RecordsFolder 8306751974-758Veterans Cost of InstructionFolder 930676FY 1976-779Veterans Cost of Instruction (Allison)Folder 1030677FY 197710Washington Internship Program (Applied Studies) George Washington UniversityFolder 11306781974-7511Washington Internship Program (Applied Studies) George Washington UniversityFolder 12306791975-7612Washington Internships in Education (Bob Bunnell, Kendall, Curl), Public Affairs, Applied Study - Ford FoundationFolder 13306801973-7413Water Quality Control through Manipulation (R. Haynes) Petersburg AssociationFolder 14306811977-7814Water Quality Control through Manipulation (R. Haynes) Petersburg AssociationFolder 15306821977-7815Where Will You Be When the Lights Go Out Lynda Toth - Humanities CouncilFolder 1630683197716Wingspread Conference (Leon Cohen)Folder 1730684197717Workshop: Med./Aging (Gerontology Institute) Illinois Dept. on Aging, Lesnoff- CaravagliaFolder 18306851977-7818Workshop: Retirement - Lesnoff Caravaglia Illinois Department on AgingFolder 1930686197719Work-Study:  Department of Local Government Affairs HUDFolder 20306871975-7620Writing Environmental Science News for the Rural Illinois Perspective - KakelaFolder 21306881977-7821

