<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>K.08.02/01Archon Finding Aid Title K.08.02/01UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:13:25 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    K8/2/1. International Affairs, SSU/UIS Model UN Records, 1991-1999
    
      Student Services
    
    K.08.02/01
    695
    
      0.66 Cubic Feet
    
    1991-1999
    Date acquired: 10/27/2003
    1
    2
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The SSU/UIS Model UN Records consist of various aspects of involvement in the Model UN program. Included in the record series are meeting agendas, correspondence, conference schedules, press releases, attendance sheets, and papers concerning fund raising activities such as bake sales and pledge drives.

Subjects include: Model UN Day Declaration by President Naomi Lynn, Midwest Model UN Country Assignments 1994, Milestones in the History of the UN, and 1993 Position papers in which the SSU delegation represented the nation of Luxembourg.

The Model UN is a nationwide organization of college students and faculty members who participate in regional and national conferences simulating the actions of the actual UN. A College or University adopts a nation, studies the nuances of that nation, and portrays the nation at the regional and national conferences.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronologically  
  
    Correspondence
    Papers
    Press Releases
    Reports
    Agendas
    Records
    Photographs
  
  Box 1Box 145222MUN Activities &amp; St. Louis ConferenceFolder 1452231992-941Scope and ContentsMUN Delegate Phone List
MUN Student Interest Form
SSU-MUN Agendas, 1992-1993
SSU-MUN Candy Sales Agreement
SSU-MUN Phon-a-thon information
SSU-MUN to New York City Press Release April 23, 1993
MUN Day Declaration by President Naomi Lynn
Bake Sale newspaper clippings October 1992-1994
MUN Conference Fees for New York 1993
IL Department of Revenue exemption material
Special Activities Grant Request January 15, 1993
SSU Evaluation of Club ActivityMUN Activities &amp; St. Louis ConferenceFolder 2452281991-922Scope and ContentsMidwest MUN Delegate Handbook
32nd Midwest MUN Conference Topics
Midwest MUN 1992 Conference Schedule
Network News Newsletter Fall 1990
Invoices from Hyatt Regency Hotel St. Louis March 1992
Midwest MUN Delegate Assignments
32nd Midwest MUN Awards ListMUN Activities &amp; New York TripFolder 3452271993-943Scope and ContentsDelegate Registration Form 1993
Midwest MUN International Press Delegation Application November,1992
Midwest MUN, 33rd Conference, March, 1993, Staff Schedule
Midwest MUN, Agenda Topics For 1993
Midwest MUN, Country Assignments, 1993
Annotated Agenda Topics For 1994
Midwest MUN, Country Assignments, 1994
UN News &amp; World Report, March 1993
Receipts, invoices from Hyatt Regency Hotel, St. Louis, 1993
National MUN 1993 Nation Assignment, SSU- Luxembourg
National MUN 1993 New York, papers, correspondence, etc.
Invoice vouchers, tax exemption forms
National MUN Luxembourg Position Paper
SSU MUN Club- expense reports on trip to New York April, 1992MUN ActivitiesFolder 4452251991-944Scope and ContentsExecutive Letter, Fund Raising Letter, 1993
Conference Topics, Conference Schedule, 1994
Method of Research
Position Papers
Resolutions
Current Campus Publicity-1993 SSU News, SSU Weekly, Recruitment
Past Campus Publicity- 1991-1992 SSU News, SSU Weekly
Special Campus Publicity- Press Releases, MUN Day Resolution
Community Publicity- Newspaper articles 1991-1993
Award CertificatesMUN ActivitiesFolder 5452291995-965Scope and ContentsUIS MUN Membership List Fall 1995
UIS MUN Spring 1996 Officers
Special Activities Grant Request 1996
UIS MUN Fall 1995 Officers
UIS MUN Student Interest Forms
Notes from Meetings, Agendas, 1995-1996
Student Request and Approval to Reserve Space Forms, 1995
Press Releases
Events, Flyers
Campus Publicity1995-1996
Publicity, news clippings
Memorandums, incoming, outgoing
Mission Correspondences
UIS MUN Simulation on Rules and Procedure
SSU MUN Method of ResearchMUN Activities &amp; New York TripFolder 64522419986Scope and ContentsUIS Weekly- Campus News, several editions from 1998
Train schedules and costs for trip to New York, 1998
Resolutions-What is a Resolution? hand out
UIS MUN 1998 Schedule
1998 National MUN Committee Topics
UIS MUN Method of Research
Campus Senate Meeting, Agenda January 30, 1998
Campus Newspapers- highlighting UIS MUN activities 1997-1998
The UN-50 Years of Achievement
Some Facts About the UN
The MUN in Brief
Milestones in the History of the UN
Various news clippings and flyers concerning UIS MUNMUN ActivitiesFolder 74522619997Scope and ContentsTwo 8x10 Color photos (same picture) of nine people in front of the United            Nations Building in New York, holding an Ecuador MUN sign. No names or date.
UIS MUN UN Background Study Source
Schedule of Events- November 1998-January 1999
Constitution of the UIS-MUN
General Information
Position Paper Examples
Resolution Information and Examples
United Nations Charter- Statute of the International Court of Justice
International Covenant of Civil and Political Rights
International Covenant on Economic, Social, and Cultural Rights
Universal Declaration of Human Rights
UIS MUN 1998-1999 Delegation List
UIS MUN Meeting Attendance Sheet 1998-1999

