<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>K.08.02/02Archon Finding Aid Title K.08.02/02UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:13:29 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    K8/2/2. International Affairs, SSU/UIS International Studies Office Records, 1989-1999
    
      Student Services
    
    K.08.02/02
    696
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1989-1999
    Date acquired: 10/31/2003
    1
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Involvment of colleges and universities in off-campus community education on international security issues.  The second fourteen folders in this record series concern other aspects of the International Affairs Office including course offerings, correspondence, graduate assistantships, and meeting agendas.
Subjects include: UIS-China Faculty Exchange Program, BA in International Studies, audience evaluation forms, speaker evaluation forms, "Russian Women's Forum" 1992, "Politics and Change in the Middle East" 1992, and a PAC 415 Geopolitics Syllabus.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  
    Correspondence
  
  Box 1Box 145230Lists of Speaking Engagements, Speakers, TopicsFolder 1452311989-921Scope and ContentsOptions ProgramOPTIONS Annual ReportsFolder 2452321990-912Scope and ContentsOptions ProgramNational Evaluation QuestionnairesFolder 3452331990-91, 1991-923Scope and ContentsOptions ProgramOPTIONS CorrespondencesFolder 4452341991-954Scope and ContentsOptions ProgramOPTIONS Directors and CoordinatorsFolder 5452351991-925Scope and ContentsOptions ProgramMidwest Regional Conference Packet, IndianapolisFolder 645236Sept. 27-28, 19916Audience Evaluation FormsFolder 7452371992-957Scope and ContentsOptions ProgramSpeaker Evaluation FormsFolder 8452381993-958Scope and ContentsOptions ProgramFaculty Interest SurveyFormsFolder 9452391991-959Scope and ContentsOptions ProgramListings of Clubs and OrganizationsFolder 104524010Scope and ContentsOptions ProgramNewslettersFolder 11452411991-9211Scope and ContentsOptions ProgramRequests For SpeakersFolder 12452421993-9412Scope and ContentsOptions ProgramFaculty ResumesFolder 134524313Scope and ContentsOptions ProgramPress, News Releases, FlyersFolder 144524414Scope and ContentsOptions ProgramRussian Women's ForumFolder 15452451992-09-2515Scope and ContentsInternational Studies Office - GeneralPolitics and Change in the Middle EastFolder 16452461992-11-1716Scope and ContentsInternational Studies Office - GeneralInternational Studies FacultyFolder 17452471992-9417Scope and ContentsInternational Studies Office - GeneralInternational Studies Graduate AssistantshipFolder 18452481992-9418Scope and ContentsJob Description, Evaluations, Other Papers;
International Studies Office - GeneralCorrespondences to International Studies Faculty From Director Steve SchwarkFolder 19452491992-9719Scope and ContentsInternational Studies Office - GeneralAgendas for International Studies MeetingsFolder 20452501992-9320Scope and ContentsInternational Studies Office - GeneralPAC 415 Geopolitics SyllabusFolder 2145251Spring 199321Scope and ContentsInternational Studies Office - GeneralInternational Studies Faculty Course OfferingsFolder 22452521993-9522Scope and ContentsInternational Studies Office - GeneralSpecifications For Conference Center EventsFolder 23452531997-9823Scope and ContentsInternational Studies Office - GeneralUIS-China Faculty Exchange ProgramFolder 24452541997-9824Scope and ContentsInternational Studies Office - GeneralB.A. Minor in International StudiesFolder 254525525Scope and ContentsInternational Studies Office - GeneralPolitical StudiesFolder 264525626Scope and ContentsInternational Studies Office - GeneralCampus Newspapers, Press, Flyers, Relating to International StudiesFolder 274525727Scope and ContentsInternational Studies Office - GeneralCorrespondenceFolder 2845258199728Scope and ContentsInternational Studies Office - General

