<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>K.09.45Archon Finding Aid Title K.09.45UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:13:34 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    K9/45. Black Awareness Week, Papers &amp; Tapes (Spring), 1973
    
      Student Services
    
    K.09.45
    697
    
      0.80 Cubic Feet
    
    Date acquired: 05/11/1973
    1
    2
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Papers and tapes including schedules, programs, posters and other materials of Black Awareness Week (Spring 1973) which was held March 24-31, 1973.  
Sponsored by the Black Student Union,  the week was subtitled,  "A Journey Into the Black Culture."  Speakers  and groups included the Tony Zamora Combo, Alex Haley, Dick Gregory, and Aliza Thnadeka Ngono.  Other group participants were: a panel discussion on affirmative action with Arnold Jones, Lowell Turley,  John Flamer, William Jacobs and Edyth Cole discussing the "Future of Affirmative Action;" a panel discussion on the "Black Politician and His Role in the Culture" with Illinois Rep. Eugene Barnes, Rep. Peggy Smith Martin, Rep. Corneal Davis, and Harold Washington; and a combined performance of the Black Writer's Workshop, the Black Dance Workshop, and the Black Lab Band of the Afro-American Cultural Program of the University of Illinois.  Black Awareness week focused on the political, economic and social issues relating to the black community.

Also included is a paper by Horace E.D. Martin that discusses the 1973 Black Awareness week and the origins of this event in 1971.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological according to schedule of events  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Acquired piecemeal  
  
    Audio Tapes
    Posters
    Programs
    Flyers/Brochures
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 145304Julian Bond SpeechFolder 14531519711Scope and ContentsText of speech made at first Black Awareness Week event.Programs, Flyers, and Schedules of EventsFolder 24530619732Announcements, Schedules of Events, and correspondenceFolder 34531619733Releases and Restrictions on Audio tapes &amp; VideotapesFolder 4453074Journey into the Black Culture by Horace E.D. MartinFolder 54531719735Scope and ContentsA Report on the creation of Black Awareness Week at SSU in 1971 and subsequent yearly events.Tony Zamora Ensemble Concert, March 24Audiotape 1453091973Scope and Contentsthree reels audiotape
Jazz bank includes SSU student Ben Ale.
NO DUBS WITHOUT PERMISSION OF TONY ZAMORALecture by Alex Haley, March 26Audiotape 2453101973Scope and Contentsone reel, audio tape and
two audiocassette copies (2 copies)
Haley is the author of The Autobiography of Malcolm X.
RELEASE SIGNED BY HALEY AUTHORIZES TAPING ONLY; NO DUBS WITHOUT HIS PERMISSION.The Black Politician and His Role in the CultureAudiotape 4453121973Scope and Contents1 reel, audio tape
Panel discussion by black Illinois politicians:
Rep. Eugene M. Barnes, Rep. Peggy Smith Martin, Rep. Corneal A. Davis, and Harold Washington.  Sen. Richard H. Newhouse, Jr. was scheduled to attend.
NO RESTRICTIONS[Closed] Speech by Dick Gregory, March 28, 8:00 pmAudiotape 5453131973Scope and Contentstwo reels, audio tape
TOTAL RESTRICTION.  
THERE IS NO WRITTEN RELEASE AUTHORIZING THE RECORDING; A CLAUSE IN THE GREGORY/SSU CONTRACT PROHIBITS BROADCASTING AND REPRODUCTION; GREGORY HOLDS LITERARY RIGHTSTony Zamora Ensemble Concert, March 24, 8:00 p. m.Videotape 1453081973Scope and Contents(1 of 2) two 30-minute videotapes 
NO DUBS WITHOUT PERMISSION OF TONY ZAMORATony Zamora Ensemble Concert, March 24, 8:00 p. m.Videotape 2453141973Scope and Contents(2 of 2) two 30-minute videotapes
NO DUBS WITHOUT PERMISSION OF TONY ZAMORABox 2Box 245305The Future of Affirmative Action by a panel of Affirmative Action OfficersAudiotape 145318March 29, 1973Scope and Contentstwo reels, audio tape
Focus on the hiring practices in higher education.
NO RESTRICTIONSThe Journey presented by Univ. of Illinois dance &amp; drama groupAudiotape 245319March 30, 1973Scope and Contentstwo reels, audio tape
NO DUBS WITHOUT PERMISSION OF RAYMOND JOSEPH.Aliza Thandeka Ngono performs Abadingi, which means The SearchersAudiotape 345320March 31, 1973Scope and Contentsone reel, audio tape
NO DUBS WITHOUT PERMISSION OF NGONO.
Ngono is a folk singer born in South Africa.The Journey presented by Univ. of Illinois dance &amp; drama groupVideotape 145321March 30, 1973Scope and Contentsone hour, videotape
NO DUBS WITHOUT PERMISSION OF RAYMOND JOSEPH.Aliza Thandeka Ngono performs Abadingi, which means The SearchersVideotape 245322March 31, 1973Scope and Contentstwo hours, videotapes
NO DUBS WITHOUT PERMISSION OF NGONO.
Ngono is a folk singer born in South Africa.

