<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>E.01.05/03Archon Finding Aid Title E.01.05/03UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:16:10 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    E1/5/3. President's Office, North Central Assoc. Self-Study Library Committee Files, 1973-1974
    
      President/Chancellor
    
    E.01.05/03
    243
    
      0.73 Cubic Feet
    
    1973-1974
    Date acquired: 07/29/1974
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Reports and working papers of the Committee on the Library of the North Central Association Self-Study Committee.  Including drafts, final reports, library statistics, library security, library usage, collection development, comparative statistics with other university libraries, minutes of the committee, and other university libraries, minutes of the committee, and other materials; chaired by Judy Everson.
NOTE: The committee was active 1973-74, but its working papers include documents dated 1969-1982.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Committee's own working arrangement  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Judy Everson, Committee Chairman  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Added to on 06/29/1990  
  Box 1Box 131585Report, Draft and Finished ProductFolder 131586Feb 19741Downs Report (Report of Library Committee of IBHE)Folder 23158719692Library Cabinet Meeting MinutesFolder 331588Aug-Nov 19733NCA Self-Study Library Committee MinutesFolder 431589Sept-Dec 19734Worthy Staff Study (Employee Survey)Folder 531590Fall 19735Questionnaires from 4 Library DivisionsFolder 631591Oct-Nov 19736Excerpt from SCAP (Steering Committee for Academic Planning) ReportFolder 7315921971-727Internal BudgetFolder 831593FY 19748Financial ReportsFolder 9315941971 &amp; 19729Student Library Use QuestionnairesFolder 1031595197210Material on SSU Library SecurityFolder 1131596197411SSU Librarian's Report to Tenure Decision CommitteeFolder 1231597May 197312Organization Chart, SSU LibraryFolder 133159813Material on Comparative Status of SSU Library StaffFolder 143159914Sample NCA Report on Library (Florida State U)Folder 153160015Annual Reports of LibrarianFolder 16316011971, 1972, 197316Report on NCA Visit to SSUFolder 1731602197217Library Evaluation SeminarsFolder 1831603197218Memos on Library FundingFolder 1931604Nov 197319Box 2Box 231605Student Questionnaire and Interpretation of Responses, NCA Self-StudyFolder 1316061Faculty Questionnaire and Interpretation of Responses, NCA Self-StudyFolder 2316072Print-Outs of Raw Data from Responses to QuestionnairesFolder 3316083

