<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>E.01.05/06Archon Finding Aid Title E.01.05/06UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:16:15 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    E1/5/6. President's Office, North Central Association Self-Study Records
    
      President/Chancellor
    
    E.01.05/06
    246
    
      1.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1968-2007
    Date acquired: 06/30/2004
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This series contains SSU and UIS self-study records in preparation for North Central Association re-accreditation and to clarify its plans for improving and enhancing its programs and operations. Included in the series are the working files of the North Central Association Self-Study Committee, the University President or Chancellor, and other members of the university community relating to the development of self-study reports and to North Central Association visits. Records include memos, correspondence, meeting minutes, reference material, institutional data, visit reports, and self-study reports.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  
    Accruals and Additions
UIS Institutional Self-Study Report, October 2007, added/donated by Barbara Ferrara. Chris Schnell, 9/6/2017  
  Box 1Box 151715Meeting MinutesFolder 1517181Self-Study Report, SSUFolder 25171919772NCA Criteria for Accreditation and SSU, institutional responses, correspondence, memosFolder 3517203Self-Study Report, Sangamon State UniversityFolder 45172119814Self-Study Report, Sangamon State UniversityFolder 55172219815NCA Quarterly, memos, NCA Site Reports, NCA Visit Preliminary EvaluationFolder 6517231981-826Visit report, correspondence, memosFolder 751724October 5-7, 19817Box 2Box 251716Memos, NCA publicationsFolder 1517281Scope and ContentsA Guide for Self-Study and Evaluation, A Handbook of Accreditation, A Manual for Visiting Teams, NCA Quarterly (vols. 56, 57, 58), Council of Postsecondary Accreditation's organization and membership listsCorrespondence, memos, Program for Review Committee MeetingFolder 2517299-11-19822Scope and ContentsProposed Five year Comprehensive Review, NCA publication - A Discussion Prepared for the Assistance of North CentralNCA Commission on Institutions of Higher Education BriefingFolder 3517303Scope and ContentsNCA publication-Rules of Procedure of the Commission on Institutions of Higher EducationMemos, correspondenceFolder 4517314Scope and ContentsConsultant Report from Robert L. Ewigleben to Ad Hoc CommitteePreferences Regarding Courses and Class Schedules for a Possible Downtown LocationFolder 5517325Scope and ContentsPhase I, A Survey of Downtown Employers, 1985; and Phase II, A Summary of Preliminary ResultsSelf-Study Report, draftFolder 65173319866Scope and Contentsletter regarding draft copySSU Accreditation Self-Study Report Vol. I and Vol. IIFolder 7517341986-19877Scope and ContentsBasic Institutional DataCorrespondence, memos, Schedule of NCA Visiting TeamFolder 8517358Scope and ContentsNCA Report Preparations/Writers, Accreditation: The Criteria for AccreditationSurveys Conducted During April/MayFolder 95581619869Scope and ContentsFaculty, staff, and students survey resultsBox 3Box 351717Memos, correspondence, NCA 1987 Annual Meeting agenda, programs, and receiptsFolder 1517251Scope and ContentsNCA Briefing (November 1986), Evaluation Summary Sheet ( 8/14/1986), Professional Data for Consultant EvaluatorsMemos, correspondence, visit reports, self-study reportsFolder 2517262Memos, correspondence, visit reports, self-study reportsFolder 3517273Scope and ContentsTranforming a Liberal Arts Curriculum: Alverno College by Thomas Ewens (chapter from book)Insitutional Self-Study Report to NCAFolder 45173619974Executive Summary of 1997 Institutional Self-Study Report to NCAFolder 5517375Scope and ContentsAlso Vision Statement brochureReport of a Focused Visit to UIS of the NCAFolder 6517382/12-13/20016Scope and ContentsFocused visit to UIS for the Higher Learning Commission of the North Central Association of Colleges and Schools.
Evaluation team: Dr. Joel E Anderson, Dr. Stephen C. Hedman, Dr. Joseph B. MillerUIS Institutional Self-Study ReportFolder 783131October 20077

