<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.01.01/25Archon Finding Aid Title J.01.01/25Chris SchnellUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:16:35 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J1/1/25 Vice President Academic Affairs Program Administration Records
    
      Vice President for Academic Affairs (VPAA)
    
    J.01.01/25
    1907
    
      0.50 boxes
    
    1978-1995
    Date acquired: 09/14/2016
    1 box
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Records include correspondence, memos, meeting minutes, notes, reports, and plans related to several committees and initiatives bearing on the management of SSU academic programs and academic affairs writ large. These records cover the reorganization of academic affairs including policy matters covering staffing and office space; the duties, qualifications, and compensation of program coordinators/convenors; academic program profiles, assessment, deletion, and creation; and academic cluster organization (clusters at SSU predated the adoption of a traditional schools model). These records span the VPAA administrations of Sue A. Dezendolet, Dennis C. Foss, G. Cullom Davis, Michael Ayers, David E. Payne, and A. Wayne Penn.  
  
    Arrangement Note
chronological and by committee or initiative  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Monica Croft, Provost's office  
  
    Method of Acquisition
donation  
  
    Correspondence
    Minutes
    Reports
  
  Box 1Box 182262Reorganization of Academic AffairsFolder 18226719781Reorganization of Academic AffairsFolder 2822721974, 19792Reorganization of Academic Affairs: office space, staffing, compensationFolder 38227719793Cluster organizationFolder 4822821982-19844Program deletionFolder 5822871982-19875Committee on Program Relationships: Minutes and reportsFolder 6822921983-19866Committee on Program RelationshipsFolder 7822971985-19867Program Administration: Reorganization and program coordinatorsFolder 8823021986-19878Program administration: Coordinator / convenor responsibilitiesFolder 9823071988-19899Program administration: Coordinator / convenor compensation and responsibilitiesFolder 10823121991-199210New program requestsFolder 11823171988-199311Program profiles: Degrees awarded, heacount majors, cost / credit hourFolder 12827711987-1993, 1989-199512

