<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.106Archon Finding Aid Title MC.106Chris SchnellUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:16:37 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC 106. American Association of University Women Springfield, IL Branch records
    MC.106
    1902
    
      0.50 Cubic Feet
    
    2007-2016
    2014-2016
    Date acquired: 08/12/2016
    1 box
  
  
    Scope and Contents
American Association of University Women Springfield Branch (AAUW-S) records 2007-2016, including meeting minutes, budget documents, membership lists, by-law revisions, branch publicity and publications, lobbying records, and the branch president's email communications. Also documented are the AAUW-S's efforts to get the Equal Rights Amendment ratified in Illinois (2014) and publications of the national AAUW organization, 2014-2016, including the magazine Outlook and annual reports. There are some earlier branch records (2007-2010) stored on CD-R.These records were collected by Mary Lou McLaughlin during her term as AAUW-S branch president (2014-2016).  
  
    Arrangement Note
chronological and by record type  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Mary Lou McLaughlin  
  
    Method of Acquisition
donation  
  
    Correspondence
    Newsletters
    Reports
    Programs
    Newspaper Clippings
    Letters
  
  Box 1Box 182210Miscellaneous AAUW-S recordsFolder 1822142007-20101Scope and ContentsExpanding Your Horizons records, 2007; AAUW-S president's records, 2008-2010Joint AAUW-S board meeting minutes, president's notes, associated documentsFolder 2822182014-20162AAUW-S president's miscellaneous recordsFolder 3822222014-20153Scope and Contentsmembership lists, meeting agendas, correspondence, contracts, invoices, budget documentsEmails to president AAUW-SFolder 4822262014-20154Documents concerning AAUW-S 110-year anniversaryFolder 5822305Equal Rights Amendment Illinois ratification lobbyingFolder 68223420146AAUW-S newsletter BranchlineFolder 7822382014-20167AAUW-S by-laws, drafts and revisionsFolder 8822422014-20168AAUW-S news clippings and publicityFolder 9822462014-20169AAUW-S publications and event flyersFolder 108225010Scope and ContentsIncludes a centennial history of AAUW-S by Mary Beaumont, printed in 2007.AAUW national publicationsFolder 11822542014-201611AAUW magazine OutlookFolder 12822582014-201612

