<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>D.01.03/01Archon Finding Aid Title D.01.03/01UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:17:26 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    D1/3/1. Fred J. Patton Park Photos and Memorabilia, 1977-1990
    
      Patton, Fred J.
    
    D.01.03/01
    255
    
      0.16 Cubic Feet
    
    1977-1990
    Date acquired: 00/00/2000
    1
    Oversize Items
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Fred J. Patton and his wife, Kathryn, were avid supporters of Sangamon State University and made many contributions to the school through generous endowments.

This collections consists of primarily photographs that document the construction and dedication of Patton Park (October 25, 1990).  Also included are newspaper clippings about the park and the flyer and invitation for the dedication of the park.  

Some of the noted dignitaries who attended the dedication include:  Kathryn Patton, Brewster Parker (then chairman of the IL. State Board of Regents), the student president of SSU, Attorney Robert Stuart (SSU), Governor Jim Thompson, Dr. Durward Long (then President of the University), William Ebert (banker), and Springfield mayor Ozzie Langfelder.

Also included are a 1977 map of the long-range development plans for the SSU campus, a map of the planting schematic for the park, and a framed color architect's rendering of the park.

Mr. and Mrs. Patton were supporters of the founding of SSU, and made many contributions to the college and the campus over the years through their endowments.  The memorabilia includes a photograph album containing newspaper articles about the park, the flyer and invitation for the dedication of Patton Park, photographs documenting its construction, and photographs of the completed park and its dedication.  Other memorabilia include additional photographs of Fred J. Patton during the time when the park was first being planned (1977)  
  
    Arrangement Note
By subject  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Kathryn Patton Estate  
  
    Photographs
    Memorabilia
    Newspaper Clippings
    Note Cards
    Correspondence
    Flyers/Brochures
  
  Box 1Box 120396Photo album of the Kathryn Patton family, 2000Item 1203971Scope and ContentsPhoto album- A gift of the Kathryn Patton Estate (2000)- Contains pictures, flyers, invitation,  and newspaper articles pertaining to the construction and dedication of the Fred J. Patton Park, held on October 25, 1990.Photographs and one "get well card"Item 2203982Scope and ContentsPlastic photo album page containing nine photographs and one "get well card" which had been sent to Mrs. Patton from Alex Lacy, n.d. (SSU).Ten photographs of the dedication of the park, 9/26/1990Item 3203993Scope and ContentsPlastic photo album page containing ten photographs of the dedication of the park, dated 9/26/1990.Photographs of Kathryn PattonItem 4204004Scope and ContentsBrown envelope with the SSU logo addressed to: "Mrs. Kathryn Patton, Price Avenue, Springfield."  Envelope contains 15 color photographs (3"x5"), mostly of Mrs. Patton at the park, both during construction, and after its completion.Map of the long-range development plans for SSU, 1979Item 5204015Scope and ContentsMap of the long-range development plans for SSU, approved in 1977 by Robert C. Spencer, President of SSU, 36" x 50," revised July, 1979.  Architects were Murphy, Downey, Wofford &amp; Richman.  Landscape architects were Royston, Hanamoto, Beck, and Abey.Map, planting schematic for the Fred J. Patton ParkItem 6204026Scope and ContentsMap, planting schematic for the Fred J. Patton Park, 22" x 24," July 9, 1980.  McKinley Nance, consultant, revised 4/1/85, per Mrs. Patton.

