<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>E.01.01/31Archon Finding Aid Title E.01.01/31Chris SchnellUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:17:41 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    E1/1/31. Chancellor's Office, Subject Files
    E.01.01/31
    1916
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    2001-2004
    Date acquired: 08/09/2006
    1 Box
  
  
    Scope and Contents
These records consist of data and supporting documents compiled for UIS Chancellor Richard Ringeisen for his testimony before the Illinois General Assembly regarding annual appropriations for higher education (both House and Senate Higher Education Appropriations Committees). Included are prepared texts of University of Illinois President James J. Stukel, letters of Stukel to various members of the Illinois General Assembly, communications among members of UIS administration, information about members of the Illinois General Assembly appropriation committees, and handwritten notes taken during meetings and during appropriations testimony. These records appear to have been compiled by Emily Schirding, executive assistant to UIS Chancellor Richard Ringeisen. They have been organized by ficsal year (FY) and cover FY 2002 through FY 2005. Each FY is organized with one main file (usually containing testimony for the appropriations committees) followed by several subject files containing data studied for that particular year.  
  
    Arrangement Note
chronological, subject  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Emily Schirding(?)/ Chancellor's Office  
  
    Method of Acquisition
donation  
  
    Agendas
    Correspondence
    Reports
    Speeches
  
  Box 1Box 182391FY 2002 Appropriation and Budget MattersFolder 1823961Budget RecommendationFolder 282401FY 20022Teacher EducationFolder 382406FY 20023Capital ScholarsFolder 482411FY 20024Capital BudgetFolder 582416FY 20025National Higher Education Report CardFolder 682421FY 20026Abraham Lincoln Presidential LibraryFolder 782426FY 20027Miscellaneous SubjectsFolder 882431FY 20028Scope and ContentsIncludes: faculty recruiting and retention, tuition waivers, high school graduate counts, student retention, a pornography incident on campus, the Doctor of Public Administration program, and sabbaticals.FY 2003 Appropriation and Budget MattersFolder 9824369Budget Summary DataFolder 1082441FY 200310Rescission / cutsFolder 1182446FY 200311Fee IncreasesFolder 1282451FY 200312Captial ScholarsFolder 1382456FY 200313Abraham Lincoln Presidential Library and MuseumFolder 1482461FY 200314Teacher EducationFolder 1582466FY 200315Illinois Board of Higher EducationFolder 1682471FY 200316Staffing Levels (1997-2001)Folder 1782476FY 200317Faculty Tenure (1999-2001)Folder 1882481FY 200318Tuition and Fee WaiversFolder 1982486FY 200319Scope and ContentsData is specific to FY 2001 and 2002.Miscellaneous FilesFolder 2082491FY 200320Scope and ContentsSubjects include: international students, the classroom building, tuition waivers, post- 9/11 security, diversity, enrollment, public university general funds, faculty workloads.302--House Appropriatiions HearingFolder 2182496FY 200321FY 2004 Appropriation and Budget MattersFolder 228250122Miscellaneous FilesFolder 2382506FY 200423Scope and ContentsSubjects include: FY 2003 budget rescission impact, capital priorities and projects, student headcount, faculty salaries, minorities on campus, sabbaticals, staffing, tuition increases and waivers, and captial scholars.FY 2005 Appropriation and Budget MattersFolder 248251124Enrollment DataFolder 2582516FY 200525Minority DataFolder 2682521FY 200526Administrative Cuts (FY 2003 and FY 2004)Folder 2782526FY 200527Miscellaneous FilesFolder 2882531FY 200528Scope and ContentsSubjects include: tuition revenue, FY 2004 income fund, and FY 2005 income fund.

