<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.01.01/26Archon Finding Aid Title J.01.01/26Chris SchnellUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:17:43 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J1/1/26 Strategic Planning and Institutional Values Committee Records
    
      Vice President for Academic Affairs (VPAA)
    
    J.01.01/26
    1912
    
      0.50 Cubic Feet
    
    1991-1997
    1991-1992
    Date acquired: 00/00/2016
    1 box
    1 large folder
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Records include committee reports, report drafts, minutes, memos, and supporting documents for Institutional Values Committee, Strategic Planning Task Force Committee, and the NCA Faculty Scholarship Committee. Included are numerous sources on strategic planning referenced by these committees as well as resources collected by survey, including an institution-wide survey compiled by Education Testing Services (ETS) in 1991.These records were collected by Lynn Pardie, UIS Provost (2011-2016), while she was a a committee member of the Task Force on Strategic Planning and professor in the psychology department, 1991-1992. Pardie also collected records of the NCA Faculty Scholarship Committee (1996-1997).  
  
    Arrangement Note
chronological and by committee  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Lynn Pardie  
  
    Method of Acquisition
donation  
  
    Custodial History
The two copies of ETS Institutional Goals Inventory (survey results) were too large to box-- they are foldered and shelved alongside Box 1.Sangamon State University Accreditation Self-Study Report transferred to Q1, fild under "Self Study."  
  
    Newsletters
    Reports
    Resolutions
  
  Box 1Box 182322Institutional Values CommitteeFolder 1823271991-19921Strategic Planning: surveys, instructions, goal statements, draftsFolder 2823322Scope and ContentsIncludes drafts ofToward 2000: A Strategic Plan for Sangamon State University and a presentation by consultant Robert C. Shirley, "Stategic Planning: A Presentation to the Strategic Planning Task Force, Sangamon State University."Institutional Values Survey: planningFolder 3823371991-19923Scope and ContentsPreperatory materials for the Educational Testing Service (ETS) survey.Task Force Update: Strategic Planning Task Force Committee newsletterFolder 48234219914Strategic Planning Task Force Committee: Robert C. Shirley materialFolder 58234719915Strategic Planning Task Force CommitteeFolder 6823521991-19926Scope and ContentsIncludes a copy of Toward 2000: A Strategic Plan for Sangamon State University, Phase one (March 1992).Strategic Planning background informationFolder 7823577Scope and ContentsIncludes copies of "Sangamon State University Academic Plan, 1991"; "Sangamon State at Twenty and a Look Ahead," Illinois Board of Regents, June 13, 1990; and Campus Life: In Search of Community, A Special Report of the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, forward by Ernest L. Boyer (1990).Educational Testing Services (ETS) informationFolder 8823628NCA Faculty Scholarship CommitteeFolder 9823671996-19979NCA Faculty Scholarship CommitteeFolder 10823721996-199710Educational Testing Services (ETS) Institutional Goals Inventory (survey results)Folder 18237719911Scope and Contents2 copies

