<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>G.01/01/15Archon Finding Aid Title G.01/01/15UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:18:15 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    G1/1/15. University Relations, Slides and Cassettes, 1973-1982
    
      University Relations
    
    G.01/01/15
    265
    
      1.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1973-1982
    Date acquired: 11/00/1988
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This record series contains three slide carousels and a box of cassette tapes.  Box A is a slide show of WSSR,  Box B  slides of Rock Valley College, Box C slides of SSU.  The cassettes involve intersessions, WSSR interviews, ads, and University Convocations.  The cassette dates are 1973-82.  
  
    Arrangement Note
N/A  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Records
    Slides
    Audio Tapes
  
  Box 1Box 123423Slides of WSSRBox 1.1023424Scope and ContentsSlide carouselSlide Show of WSSR Public Radio 92 FM StereoItem 1238091Piano playingItem 2238102The news officeItem 3238113The D.J.'s and secretariesItem 4238124Pledge cardsItem 523813540 % of the supporting income comes from grants and contributionsItem 6238146United Press International News ReleasesItem 7238157The Legislature and the CapitolItem 8238168Public Affairs News is 42 hours per weekItem 9238179VolunteersItem 102381810Lincoln LibraryItem 112381911Piano TuningItem 122382012Musical instrumentsItem 132382113The record collectionItem 142382214Live musiciansItem 152382315ListenersItem 162382416Program schedulesItem 172382517Planning the newsletter for supportersItem 182382618Dale K. Outz, Director of Broadcast ServicesItem 192382719Slides of Rock Valley CollegeBox 1.2023783Scope and ContentsSlide carouselInterim campus constructionItem 1238281GroundbreakingItem 2238291966-04-062YWCAItem 3238303Winnebago CountyItem 4238314School LabsItem 5238325Art display at a mallItem 6238336FarmersItem 7238347RegistrationItem 8238358Campus scenesItem 9238369GraduationItem 102383710Mechanical classesItem 112383811Special eventsItem 122383912Art classesItem 132384013Dramatic productionsItem 142384114Nurses, candy stripers, and dental traineesItem 152384215Typing classItem 162384316Counselor with a "Guide to SSU"Item 172384417LLCC Interim CampusItem 182384518Halloween pictures (witch with pumpkin)Item 192384619Slides of Sangamon State UniversityBox 1.3023784Scope and ContentsSlide carouselThe legislatureItem 1238471GraduationItem 2238482ClassesItem 3238493WorkshopsItem 4238504Proposed buildingsItem 5238515Santa visits SSUItem 6238526BBQItem 7238537Lounge AreaItem 8238548DaycareItem 9238559Dramatic productionsItem 102385610Guy RomansItem 112385711ClayvilleItem 122385812Construction of campusItem 132385913Robert SpencerItem 142386014Paul Simon with a classItem 152386115Aerial view of campusItem 162386216Musical productionsItem 172386317Red Lion TavernItem 182386418The library circulation deskItem 192386519CassettesBox 1.4023785Intersession Feeds: Big Business and AgribusinessItem 12378619781Scope and ContentsFrances Fonce Piven, Political 	Science Professor at Boston University, "Individual Freedom and the State"; also 	speaking are Russell Kirk, Author; Neier, Stokes, and Genety.Intersession: The President's Guidelines for the Mandatory Wage Increase CeilingsItem 2237871976-01-0627th annual Intersession "Confronting Inequality"Item 3237883Scope and ContentsInvolves Episcopal Minister Candidate Brenda Rivera speaking on homosexuality, peace, changing sexuality, and Jose La Liu speaking on bilingual education.  Also addressed by Prof. Bill 	Liu are Asian Immigrants."Confronting Inequality"Item 4237894Scope and ContentsCeals with prejudice, racism, cultural role discrimination, and income and resource inequality.  This is the 4th day of the Intersession.The University ConvocationItem 5237901982-09-205"Confronting Inequality" IntersessionItem 62379119806Scope and ContentsDeals with inequality of opportunity 	depending upon race, income, etc."Confronting Inequality" IntersessionItem 72379219807National Junior College Athletic Association Football CoachItem 8237938Scope and ContentsNational Junior College Athletic Association Champions for 6 out of 8 years, the Viking's Football Coach is interviewedReasons to voteItem 9237949Scope and ContentsReasons to vote and improper reasons to choose a candidate; political movements and 	the Civil Rights Movement/Prejudice against race or handicap, support of hiring quotas, Medicare.University WeekItem 102379510Scope and ContentsCelebration of University Week involved a time capsule ceremony. The tape, photographs, and published materials were put in a Marine Bank vault. The speaker was Attorney George Hoffman, Chairman of the Springfield Committee on Higher Education.Central Illinois Jazz FestivalItem 112379611Gun Control, Welfare, Quality Public EducationItem 122379712Scope and ContentsThe W. Russell Arrington Endowment in Public Affairs is established at SSU. The politics of Mr. Arrington are discussed; he was a State Senator for 28 years.SSU RelationsItem 13237981973-07-0313Scope and Contents4 weekly broadcasts reflecting SSU activities. Tom Curtis, former Public Broadcasting Network Chairman is the speakerAddress for Black History MonthItem 14237991980-02-1314Scope and ContentsAlex Poinsett on side 2SSU-Clayville ad for Crafts Festival (approx. 2 minutes long)Item 152380015The Adverse Affects of Psychological and IQ TestingItem 162380116Scope and ContentsMr. Mitchell Edwards, Larry Golden, and Sid Barrell are all mentioned by the speaker on The Adverse Affects of Psychological and IQ Testing.Clarence Mitchell speaks on prejudiceItem 172380217Scope and ContentsClarence Mitchell, Civil Rights leader, speaks on prejudice; this is the WSSR news announcement of this eventCreation of the SSU campusItem 182380318Scope and ContentsWICS 20 News recording concerning the creation of the SSU campus (approx. 2 	minutes long)Crisis in Confidence: Corporate AmericaItem 1923804Jan. 197519Scope and ContentsFour news feeds given to radio stationsGun Control Debates in the LegislatureItem 202380520

