<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.107Archon Finding Aid Title MC.107Chris SchnellUIS Archives/Special Collections08/08/2017Archives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:18:58 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC 107. Grayton Mansion (Taylorville, IL) Photos
    MC.107
    1926
    
      0.50 Cubic Feet
    
    1915-1960
    Date acquired: 05/22/2017
    1 box
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This collection includes a wide variety of interior and exterior views of Grayton, a mansion that stood in Taylorville, Illinois, from 1911 to 1962. Grayton was built (1911-1913) by Taylorville banker Eugene A. Vandeveer (1853-1915) and designed by Chicago architect Frederick Wainwright Perkins (1866-1929).The three story, 27-room, stucco and timber Tudor style house stood on twenty acres, including formal gardens, a swimming pool, biergarten, garage house, carriage house, and stables. Grayton was furnished with reproductions of English Regency and French Empire style furniture. Vandeveer died in 1915 leaving the estate to his wife Eudora G. (Atwood) Vandeveer and three daughters Yolande, Vida, and Eugenia. In 1940 Eugenia married Edward W. Vollintine of Taylorville, and they resided at Grayton when they were not traveling or in residence at one of their other homes. After Eugenia's death in 1958, Edward continued to own Grayton, but after he remarried he moved into first the restored stables and carriage house and then a nearby townhouse. Vollintine had Grayton razed in 1962 and later sold the land to Wal-Mart Stores, Inc.The collection is composed of photographic prints dating from as early as 1915 and as late as 1960. A few views show gardeners and groundskeepers, and one includes an unidentified man and woman in formal attire, but most feature interior views with furniture, or exterior views of Grayton and its gardens and statuary. There are several prints made by renowned Viennese photographer Arthur Benda, that may be interior views of Eugenia Vollintine's home in Munich. There is also a single architectural drawing featuring an early draft of Grayton's front elevation.  
  
    Arrangement Note
By original order, print group, and chronology.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Roger Hickman, trustee of Vollintine Estate  
  
    Method of Acquisition
donation  
  
    Biographical or Historical Information
Note written by Christopher Schnell  
  
    Photographs
    Blueprints
  
  Box 1Box 182781Exterior views: Pope Studio (Taylorville, IL)Folder 182786c. 1915-19161Scope and ContentsThis group contains a photo of an unidentified man and woman in the gardens.Exterior and garden views from album: Pope Studio (Taylorville, IL)Folder 282791c. 1915-19162Interior views: Arthur Benda (Vienna) photographsFolder 382796c. 1915-19303Scope and ContentsThis group may be interior views of Eugenia Vanderveer's homes in Munich or Vienna. The date range is derived from the photo label and based upon the the period in which Arthur Benda worked in partnership with Madame D'Ora.Interior views: Wasson Studios (Decatur, IL)Folder 482801n. d.4Exterior views: Wasson Studios (Decatur, IL)Folder 582806n. d.5Scope and ContentsThis group includes views of the carriage house and the town house.Exterior views: Unattributed color snapshotsFolder 682811n. d.6Interior views: Edward A. Taubert Architectural PhotographyFolder 78281619607Scope and Contentsproof sheetsInterior and exterior views: Unattributed, miscellaneous printsFolder 882821n. d.8Scope and ContentsSome in this group could be prints from the Pope Studio group. This group includes several winter scenes.Architectural drawing: Front elevation for "first plan" for GraytonItem 182826c. 19111

