<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>P.CrowleyArchon Finding Aid Title P.CrowleyChris SchnellUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:19:27 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    P/Crowley. Robert Crowley, Personal Papers. RESTRICTED
    
      Crowley, Robert
    
    P.Crowley
    1931
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1970-1994
    1 box
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Personal papers of Robert Crowley, Emeritus Professor of Human Development Counseling, 1970-1994. Crowley recieved his PhD in psychology from University of Michigan and was a founding faculty member of Sangamon State University. This collection is composed Crowley's day planners and journals roughly covering a portion of his service at SSU from 1973-1989. These booklets briefly note the topics of meetings and their attendees, notes about courses and student activities, titles of books he read, and travel. Of special note are his notes regarding faculty tenure and union issues. Also, Crowley's 1989 journal records his visit to the People's Republic of China during the months leading up to and including the student protests at Tiananmen Square. The collection also includes Crowley's student grade books, 1970-1994 and include some of the first faculty-recorded grades given by SSU. These grade books are RESTRICTED.  
  
    Arrangement Note
chronological  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
Grade books: archived student records are restricted and student privacy protected under FERPA. These records should not be used for research on any individual student nor should they be copied for such purposes.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Robert Crowley  
  
    Custodial History
Dr. Crowley dontated these records at some point after 1994, possibly at the time of his retirement around 2001.  
  
    Records
    Diary
  
  Box 1Box 183076Day planners and journalsFolder 1830811973-19791Day planners and journalsFolder 2830861980-19892RESTRICTED: Grade bookFolder 3830911970-19773RESTRICTED: Grade bookFolder 4830961977-19794RESTRICTED: Grade bookFolder 5831011980-19845RESTRICTED: Grade bookFolder 68310619846RESTRICTED: Grade bookFolder 7831111985-19907RESTRICTED: Grade bookFolder 8831161990-19948

