<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>P.Knoepfle. Series IIIArchon Finding Aid Title P.Knoepfle. Series IIIChris SchnellUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:19:42 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    P/Knoepfle. John Knoepfle, Personal Papers, Series III
    
      Knoepfle, John
    
    P.Knoepfle. Series III
    1936
    
      6.42 Cubic Feet
    
    1943-2017
    Date acquired: 09/13/2017
    1
    2
    3
    4
    5
    6
    7
    8
  
  
    Scope and Contents
John Knoepfle's papers include manuscript drafts of several of his published works as well as individual poems. His correspondence files include communications with several important Midwestern regional authors and editors of the late twentieth century. Also included in the papers are several reviews about his work, reports Knoepfle wrote as a correspondent for the Upward Bound project during the 1960s, audio tapes of poetry readings, and several publications to which he contributed poetry. For many of Knoepfle's full-length publications see UIS Archives/Special Collections. To access a unified list of correspondents in this collections open the following file and conduct a name search.https://uofi.box.com/s/1chsowfsf1vhlpefi6k9w99zm73udxu9  
  
    Source of Acquisition
John and Peggy Knoepfle  
  
    Method of Acquisition
donation  
  
    Biographical or Historical Information
John Ignatius Knoepfle is a professor emeritus of literature from Sangamon State University (UIS), poet, author of prose, oral historian, translator, and specialist in Midwestern literature and folklore. He was born in Cincinnati, Ohio, on February 4, 1923, and served as a lieutenant in the U.S. Navy during WWII, participating in the amphibious assaults upon the Japanese-held islands of Iwo Jima and Okinawa. Knoepfle was wounded in battle requiring a long recovery period during which he began pursuing a university education. He earned a Ph.B. (1947) and an M.A. (1949) from Xavier University, and subsequently, a Ph.D. in Medieval and Renaissance English literature from Saint Louis University (1967). While working for a Cincinnati television station in the 1950s Knoepfle interviewed rivermen of the Ohio River, eventually conducting over forty-two oral histories about life on the river. He taught English literature and creative writing at Ohio State University (1956-1957), Southern Illinois University, East St. Louis campus (1957-1961), Maryville College (1961-1965), Saint Louis University (1966-1972), and Washington University (1966-1972). Knoepfle ended his career at SSU, where he taught from 1972 to 1991. His scholarship has bridged several languages including translations of Hungarian poetry, the Peruvian poet Cesar Vallejo, in collaboration with Wang Shouyi, T'ang and Song Dynasty poetry, and the long-form poetry of the Miami-Peoria people. He has also published fifteen books and chapbooks of poetry including Rivers into Islands (1965) and poems from the sangamon (1985). In 1989 Knoepfle published a series of folktales set in the Midwest titled Dim Tales. In 1986 Knoepfle won the Mark Twain Award for distinguished contributions from the Society for the Study of Midwestern Literature and the same year he was designated Illinois author of the year by the Illinois Association of Teachers of English.Note written by   
  Biographical material, reviews of JIK's work, JIK's workBox 183566Biographical information and bibliographiesFolder 1835711Photographs of JIKFolder 2835761977-1997, n.d.2Reviews, interviews, commencements, and readingsFolder 3835811991-2013, n.d.3Newspaper articles and interviewsFolder 4835861957-20134Scope and ContentsOriginal newspaper clippings filed in box 1, folder 5.Newspaper clippingsFolder 5835911957-20135Scope and ContentsOriginal clippings filed separately for preservation purposes. Most are copied in box 1, folder 4, but several others from other parts of collection.Peggy Sower Knoepfle: poetry, newspaper articlesFolder 6835961999-20016Genealogy materials and correspondenceFolder 7836011992-19957Scope and ContentsPrimarily concerning the Brickley family genealogy (JIK's mother's family); includes a 1906 cemetery plot deed; includes signed JIK poem "reclaiming the light"Sangamon State University faculty appointments and agreements on termsFolder 8836061978-19828Student Poetry; poetry about or dedicated to JIKFolder 9836111968-20049Peter Stitt, "Robert Bly's World of True Images,"Folder 1083616196310Scope and ContentsMentions JIKJames Scott, "The Metropolitan Sensibility: Notes on Four Poets of St. Louis,"Folder 1183621196511Scope and ContentsMentions JIKJohn Knoll, "Crisis in the Voice: An Interview with John Knoepfle"Folder 1283626196612Scope and ContentsIncludes JIK poem: "Aeschylus in East St. Louis"James Scott, "Critique of 'Lines for Men of the Greater Interior'"Folder 1383631196713Scope and ContentsIncludes JIK poem: "Lines for Men of the Greater Interior"Robert Bly, drawings for James Dickey, The Suspect in PoetryFolder 1483636c. 196714Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of farcical illustrations with notation by JIK.Glenn LePrevost, "Comic Strip Students"Folder 1583641196715Scope and ContentsQuotes JIKLloyd Goldman, "Masks of Self-Deception"Folder 1683646196816Scope and ContentsAbout JIKRaymond Benoit, "The Reflective Art of John Knoepfle"Folder 1783651196817John Gordon Burke, "An Interview with John Knoepfle"Folder 1883656196918Peter L. Simpson, "Missouri Poetry, 1971"Folder 1983661197119Eads Bridge Review, "John Knoepfle Talks about Poetry"Folder 2083666197120John Garmon, "John Knoepfle: Someone for Everyone"Folder 2183671197221Pamela Klipsch, "Thoughts and Reflections of John Knoepfle, Poet in Residence"Folder 2283676197222Gary Nelson,The Incarnate Word: Literature as Verbal Space, 250-53Folder 2383681197323Scope and ContentsMentions JIK and his poetry.Passing references and dedications to JIK, various publicationsFolder 24836861973-198624Harry Cargas, "What is Poetry? Harry Cargas Interviews John Knoepfle"Folder 2583691197425John Judson, "Regionalism and Contemporary Poetry"Folder 2683696197426Scope and ContentsCites JIKPatricia Takemoto, Illinois Poets: An ExhibitFolder 2783701197527Scope and ContentsShort interview of JIKDuane Ackerson, "Knoepfle, John" in Contemporary PoetsFolder 28837061975, 198028Helen Mandeville, "New Poems by John Knoepfle: The Sacramental View of Reality" in Late Harvest: Plains and Prairie PoemsFolder 2983711197729Ralph Mills, "Some Notes on John Knoepfle's Poems"Folder 3083716197930John Garmon, "Aspects of Place in the Poetry of John Knoepfle," diss., Ball State UniversityFolder 3183721197931David Pichaske, ed., Beowulf and Beyond: The Varieties of PoetryFolder 3283726198132Scope and ContentsIncludes JIK poem, "Farmer and the Owl"Paul Hendrickson, "Fear of Faggotry: Growing up in the Seminary"Folder 3383731198233Scope and ContentsMentions JIKClark Spencer, "'I am, for a poet, in a very good place': John Knoepfle" The State Journal RegisterFolder 3483736March 4, 198434Norman Hinton, "The Poetry of John Knoepfle"Folder 3583741198535Dave Etter, "John Knoepfle," in Home State: A Prose PoemFolder 3683746198536Rachel Faries, "John Knoepfle: Author of the Year, 1986"; James Scott, "Cleansing the Valleys: John Knoepfle's Vision of the American Heartland"Folder 3783751198637Scope and ContentsThis is a 1997 reprint.Patricia Rice, "Poet Finds Fertile Ground in the Farm Belt," St. Louis Post-DispatchFolder 38837565/20/198638David Pichaske, "The Midwest Village, 1986: A Progress Report"Folder 3983761198739Scope and ContentsMentions JIKPeggy Knoepfle, "Interview with John Knoepfle" (unpublished)Folder 4083766198840Charles Morris, "Pride, Hope, and Purpose in Frost's 'Death of the Hired Man' and Knoepfle's 'man in overalls' and the Effects of Time" (unpublished)Folder 4183771198841John Hallwas, "Introduction" in Studies in Illinois PoetryFolder 4283776198942Scope and ContentsMentions JIKDaniel Guillory, "Tradition and Innovation in 20th-Century Illinois Poetry," in Studies in Illinois PoetryFolder 4383781198943Scope and ContentsMentions JIK, includes JIK's poetryRobert Bray, "The Regionalist in Midwestern Poetry: Minor Leagues or Minor Key?" in Studies in Illinois PoetryFolder 4483786198944Scope and ContentsMentions JIK and includes poetryBob Hastings, "Melodic Voice Recalls Shawnee Heritage"Folder 4583791199245Scope and ContentsQuotes JIKSteven Spearie, "John Knoepfle: The Language of the Everyman," Catholic TimesFolder 4683796February 13, 199446Todd Moore, "The Language of Prairies: The Poetry of John Knoepfle"Folder 4783801199547Kevin Stein, "A Dark River of Labor: Work and Workers in James Wright's Poetry," in Private Poets, Worldly ActsFolder 4883806199648Scope and ContentsMentions JIKTheodore Haddin, "John (Ignatius) Knoepfle" in Encyclopedia of Midwestern LiteratureFolder 4983811199749Pete Sherman, "Irish Roots: How Poet John Knoepfle Lost his Family and Found his Voice in Ireland," Illinois TimesFolder 5083816March 16, 200050Nancy Perkins, UIS (interview), "Teacher to Teacher, Poet to Poet"Folder 5183821November 20, 200851Scope and ContentsDVD videoNancy Perkins, "John Knoepfle's Early Poetry: Taking the 'wide slow waters' of the Sangamon to the Rest of the World"Folder 5283826May 9, 200952Scope and ContentsPaper presented at the 39th Annual Symposium for the Study of Midwestern Literature. Includes letter of JIK to Perkins, October 6, 2009.Reviews of anthologies JIK contributed toFolder 53838311959-1990, 200453Reviews of Twenty Poems of Cesar VallejoFolder 54838361962-1964, n.d.54Reviews of Rivers into IslandsFolder 55838411965-196655Reviews of The Intricate LandFolder 56838461970-1976, n.d.56Reviews of Our Street Feels Good: Poems for ChildrenFolder 57838511972-197357Reviews of Neruda and VallejoFolder 58838561972, 197458Review of thinking of offerings: poems, 1970-1973Folder 5983861197659Review of A Gathering of VoicesFolder 6083866197960Reviews of Reader's Guide to Illinois LiteratureFolder 61838711985-198661Reviews of Poems from the SangamonFolder 62838761985-198962Reviews of Poems from the Sangamon and Selected PoemsFolder 63838811986-198763Reviews of Selected PoemsFolder 64838861986-198764Reviews of T'ang Dynasty Poems and Song Dynasty PoemsFolder 65838911986, 198965Reviews of Dim TalesFolder 6683896199066Reviews of Begging an AmnestyFolder 6783901199467Publicity and mailing lists for Begging an AmnestyFolder 6883906c. 199468Review of The Chinkapin OakFolder 6983911199569Review of From the Hungarian Revolution: A Collection of PoemsFolder 7083916n.d.70Scope and ContentsJIK contributed translations to this anthology.JIK essay and poetry: "River Poems"Folder 7184121196171Scope and Contents"Sons of Kanawha" and "Hay piles" included in articleJIK, "Thoughts on Cesar Vallejo," in Twenty Poems of Cesar VallejoFolder 7283921196272JIK, PhD comprehensive written exam answersFolder 7383926196473Scope and ContentsSaint Louis University, Department of EnglishJIK, "The use of Renaissance Formulas for Praise in the Dramas of Christopher Marlowe," Dissertation, Saint Louis UniversityFolder 7483931196674JIK essay: "Crossing the Midwest," in Regional Perspectives: An Examination of America's Literary HeritageFolder 7584126197375JIK, typed ms, the intricate land (revised 2nd ed.)Folder 7683936197776JIK, typed ms, Selected PoemsFolder 7783941197977JIK, edited typed ms, Poems from the SangamonFolder 7883946198578JIK, typed ms, Poems from the SangamonFolder 7983951198579Scope and Contents"press copy"JIK ms: Dim stories, transcripts, editsFolder 80864361985-198980JIK's workBox 283956JIK: "John Knoepfle Memoir" (oral history interview transcript)Folder 18640119871JIK typed ms: Dim stories (corrections)Folder 28396619892JIK typed ms: Dim StoriesFolder 38397119893JIK (rejected) ms: Dim StoriesFolder 4839764JIK poem: "some words for the lighting of the christmas tree in the auburn illinois town square 26 november 1989"Folder 58398119895JIK essay: "Shakespeare's Henry V and the Geneva Bible"Folder 68421619896JIK self interview #1: "Memories of Kansas"Folder 78398619907JIK self interview #2: "Speaking of a Vibrant Woman"Folder 88399119908Scope and Contentsincomplete copyJIK: "poem for a time of distress"Folder 98399619929Scope and Contentsfarewell party for Elziabeth WeirJIK self interview #3: "A Green Snake Interview: Speaking of Robert Bly"Folder 1084001199210JIK self interview: "Green Snake Interview: Girl Scout Cookies"Folder 1184006199211JIK essay and translation: "An Illinois-Miami Our Father"Folder 1284131199212JIK haikai no renga (collaborative poetry): drafts, notes, and correspondenceFolder 13840111992-1993, 199613Scope and ContentsMost of the correspondence deals with reaction to "Illinois Fields in Summer."JIK and others, haikai no renga: "Illinois Fields in Summer"Folder 1484016c. 199314JIK and others, haikai no renga: "Daffodils Wink and They're Gone"Folder 1584021c. 199315JIK and others: "a modest haikai renga for jael and her husband and their new daughter"Folder 1684026c. 199316JIK self interview: "Green Snake Interview: 'poetry happening'"Folder 1784031199317JIK essay: "Peoria-Miami Narratives and Cult Hero Tales"Folder 1884221199318JIK poem: "circle chant for a spring field earth day"Folder 19841411993, 199519Scope and ContentsIncludes letter of JIK to Kenneth Guentart, 6/4/93.JIK self interview: "Green Snake Interview: 'lost in East St. Louis'"Folder 2084036199420JIK short story: "Abigail Dim's Rose of Sharon Quilt"Folder 2184041c. 199421JIK poem: "at lincoln library"Folder 2284046199522JIK poem: "Keepsakes: lines from a residency and a festival of poets"Folder 2384051199523JIK poem: "October Keepsakes: lines from a residency and a festival of poets"Folder 2484056199524JIK self interview: "a green snake interview: 'east st louis again'"Folder 2584061199525JIK poem: "confluence" (for Episcopal food pantry)Folder 2684136199526JIK poem: "one last time: taps for ssu"Folder 2784146199527JIK ms: "Poems Selected and New, 1985-1995"Folder 2884066March 9, 199528Scope and Contentssubmitted to Iowa Poetry Press, University of IowaJIK ms: "Poems Selected and New, 1985-1995"Folder 2984071(March 9, 1995)29Scope and ContentsIncludes letter of editor Paul Zimmer to JIK, 7/24/95, returning ms.JIK poem: "poet for cats"Folder 3086406c. October 30, 199530Scope and ContentsSheet includes James McGowan poem dedicated to JIK: "Poetical Pussycat, McLean County Festival"JIK self interview: "A Green Snake Interview: 'passes and drums'"Folder 31840761996?31JIK and others, haikai no renga: "Out by the back fence"Folder 3284081c. 199632JIK and others, haikai no renga: "We are ready now"Folder 3384086199733JIK self interview: "a green snake interview: 'psalm six'"Folder 3484091199834JIK ms (master copy): "The Irish Poems"Folder 35840962002-200335JIK poems: drafts from prayer against famine and othersFolder 36864112003-200436Scope and ContentsSome drafts are dated.JIK ms: "The Irish Poems"Folder 3784101c. 200437JIK ms: prayer against famine and other Irish poemsFolder 3886416c. 200438Scope and ContentsThree copies, slight differences, one is marked up.JIK: "The Early Days of the Verbal Arts Festival"Folder 3986421200439JIK ms: "Draft for Autobiography"Folder 4084106c. 200740Scope and ContentsIncludes a CD-R with containing a single Word doc of I Look Around for my Life dated, January 12, 2008.JIK ms (galley proof): Walking in SnowFolder 4184111200841JIK poem: "lines for pat" in "A Celebration of the Life of Cynthia Patricia 'Pat' Hilton Smith"Folder 4284116December 19, 200942JIK poems: Pat Smith celebration of life, poetry reading, book promotionFolder 4384151November 28, 201043Scope and ContentsIncludes JIK poems: "it was a good day" and "it is that thanksgiving time again"JIK poems: Interfaith poetry reading, Ethical Society of St. LouisFolder 4484156May 28, 201144Scope and ContentsIncludes JIK poems: "prayer room poem," "hearing dorothy day,"gray saturday lines," "james gerard," "winter miracle," "justina," "teach in," "something to live by," "prayer against famine," "once when we were all the same," "poet as shaman"JIK essay: "Tuesday Mornings at the Trout Lily"Folder 4584161March 26, 201245Scope and ContentsIncludes a Word doc copy of the essay on CD-R.JIK poems and notes: rhetorical tropes and schemes classFolder 4684166201246Scope and ContentsIncludes several poems to provide examples of different rhetorical tropes and schemes.JIK poem: "see the holy women"Folder 4784171April 201447Scope and ContentsHandwritten msJIK poem: "lines for our highschool anniversary"Folder 4884176n.d.48JIK poem: "reclaiming the light"Folder 4984181n.d.49JIK poem and notes: un-namedFolder 5084186n.d.50Scope and Contentshandwritten msJIK notes on Macbeth and the Penitential PsalmsFolder 5184191n.d.51JIK and Peg Knoepfle review essay: "Garcia Lorca: The Achievement of Tragedy"Folder 5284196196052JIK review: "Poemas Humanos/ Human Poems," by Cesar VallejoFolder 5384201196853JIK review: Sleepers Joining Hands, by Robert BlyFolder 5484206197454JIK review: The People Called Apache by Thomas E. MailsFolder 5584211c. 197455JIK: jacket comments for Jane Morrel, This Paradox ShadowFolder 5684226198256JIK: jacket comments for Jerry Dillon Pratt, Shooting Snake Eyes on SundayFolder 5784231198657JIK: jacket comments for Joan Yeagley, The Studs of McDonald CountyFolder 5884236198758JIK review essay: "Some Thoughts on Sandburg's Poems"Folder 5984241199259JIK review of Theodore Haddin's writing for tenure assessmentFolder 6084246199260JIK review: James Ballowe ms "A Southern Illinois Medley: Bloddy Williamson, 1922-1928"Folder 6184251199261JIK review essay: "New Poems and Stories from Sandburg"Folder 6284256199462JIK critical notes on Kevin Stein, Bruised ParadiseFolder 6384261199563JIK review of Steve Schreiner's writing for tenure assessmentFolder 6484266199664JIK and Shouyi Wang, translations: Tang and Song Dynasty PoemsFolder 6586441c. 201665JIK and Shouyi Wang translations: Tang and Song Dynasty poemsFolder 6686446c. 201666Scope and ContentsMarked up by JIKJIK and Shouyi Wang translations: editsFolder 6786451June 11, 201667JIK and Shouyi Wang, translations: poems of later dynasties (Yuan and after)Folder 6886456c. 201668Shouyi Wang: Preface draftsFolder 6986461c. 201769JIK and Shouyi Wang: Biography draftsFolder 7086466c. 201770Shouyi Wang: "Dancing with Culture: Translating Chinese Classical Poems into English" (epilogue drafts)Folder 7186471c. 201771JIK and Shouyi Wang translations, ms: Voyage Home: Poems from the Yuan and Ming and Qing Dynasties (draft)Folder 7286476c. 201772Scope and ContentsMarkup and notes by JIK.CorrespondenceBox 384271JIK: Miscellaneous letters and documentsFolder 1842761984-20151Correspondence about Begging an AmnestyFolder 2842811994-19952Correspondence and promotional material about The Chinkapin OakFolder 3842861994-19963Correspondence and promotional material about KeepsakesFolder 48429119954Correspondence and script for Inland VoyagesFolder 5842961995, 19975Correspondence and promotional material for prayer against famine and other irish poemsFolder 6864312003-2004, n.d.6Miscellaneous correspondents, B-SFolder 7843011960s-1980s, n.d.7Miscellaneous correspondents, S-WFolder 8843061960s-1980s, n.d.8Miscellaneous correspondents, W-YFolder 9843111960s-1980s, n.d.9Miscellaneous correspondence (chronological)Folder 10843161980-199010Miscellaneous correspondence (chronological)Folder 1184321199111Miscellaneous correspondence (chronological)Folder 12843261992-199712Miscellaneous correspondence (chronological)Folder 13843312002-201713Scope and ContentsBulk of correspondence 2010 and after.Calcagno, Anne: correspondence, contractFolder 1484336199114Scope and ContentsIllinois Arts CouncilHollahan, Patricia: correspondence, notes, translationsFolder 15843411988, 199415Scope and ContentsOld English translationsKincaid, Michael: correspondence, poetryFolder 16843461987-1989, 199616Lau, Barbara: correspondenceFolder 17843511987-199217Morrel, Jane: correspondence, poetry, publicity for This Paradox ShadowFolder 18843561976-198418Mueller, Lisel: correspondenceFolder 19843611975-1977, n.d.19Scope and ContentsIncludes: JIK to Mueller, January 28, 1976.Nemanic, Jerry: correspondenceFolder 20843661975-197620Scope and ContentsIncludes: JIK to Jerry Nemanic, March 11, 1976.Nemec, Phil: correspondenceFolder 2184371197521Scope and ContentsIncludes JIK to Phil Nemec, February 20, 1975.Newberry Library: correspondenceFolder 22843761982-198522Scope and ContentsIncludes: Terry Sullivan, Richard H. Brown, Frances Kao.Ohio River Valley Project: pamphlets, conference participant listFolder 2384381c. 199023Osburn, Tim: correspondenceFolder 2484386198524Pearn, Victor: correspondence, poetryFolder 25843911976-198825Pichaske, David: correspondenceFolder 26843961980-199226Scope and ContentsSpoon River Poetry PressPlains Distribution Service, Inc.Folder 27844011977-197927Pratt, Jerry: correspondenceFolder 28844061983-198628Quinlan, Caroline: correspondenceFolder 29844111983-198429Ray, David: correspondenceFolder 30844161963-198330Scope and ContentsIncludes correspondence about JIK's contribution to From the Hungarian Revolution: A Collection of Poems (1966).Read Illinois Literacy Heritage ConferenceFolder 3184421198531Readings: invitations, arrangements, thank yousFolder 32844261985-198632Scope and ContentsIncludes poetry of JIK written on back of Gary Novak to JIK, Feburary 21, 1986.Readings: invitations, arrangements, thank yousFolder 3384431198733Rejection lettersFolder 3484436198134Scope and ContentsIncludes 4 letters of JIK to different presses soliciting a collection of his poetry for publication: JIK to Barney Rosset, May 20, 1981; JIK to R. L. Blackmore, May 20, 1981; JIK to Ross Claiborne, May 22, 1981; JIK to Jacek K. Galarzka, June 1, 1981.Revard, Carter: correspondence and poetryFolder 35844411972, 199335Scope and ContentsIncludes ms of Revard's "Walking with Friends on Skye."Review copy requests and responsesFolder 36844461985-198636Ridland, John: correspondence and poetryFolder 37844511968-1987, 201537Riseman, Sandra: correspondenceFolder 38844561979, n.d.38River Styx, Big River Association: pamphlets and correspondenceFolder 39844611984-198539Scope and ContentsIncludes letter of Jan G. Castro to JIK, May 15, 1985.Robinson, Forrest: correspondenceFolder 40844661974-198640Rothenberg, Jerome: correspondenceFolder 41844711974, n.d.41Rotter (Siderfin), Julie: correspondenceFolder 42844761975-197642Scope and ContentsIncludes letter of JIK to Julie Rotter, February 20, 1976.St. James Press: correspondence regarding JIK's entry in Contemporary Poets (1980)Folder 4384481197943Saner, Reginald: correspondenceFolder 4484486199644Scheele, Roy: correspondenceFolder 45844911972-197645Scope and ContentsIncludes: JIK to Roy Scheele, February 26, 1976; JIK chapbook Deep Winter Poems (October 1972) moved to special collections.Schmitz, Dennis: correspondenceFolder 46844961970-197546Schuler, Robert: correspondenceFolder 47845011977-199247Scope and ContentsIncludes correspondence about publication of Poems for the Hours with Uzzano Press.Schwartz, Howard: correspondence and poetryFolder 48845061969-1986, 1996, n.d.48Scope and ContentsIncludes letter of JIK to William C. Hamlin, October 17, 1975Scrimgour, James: correspondenceFolder 49845111976-198549Scope and ContentsIncludes correspondence about Pikestaff Forum.Seator, Lynette: correspondenceFolder 50845161982-1985, n.d.50Silesky, Barry: correspondenceFolder 51845211983-1985, 1990, 199451Scope and ContentsIncludes correspondence about Thunder Mouth Press and Another Chicago Magazine.Simpson, Peter L.: writing, reviews, poetry, biographical materialFolder 52845261972-1985, n.d.52Smith, David J.: correspondenceFolder 53845311969-198853Stafford, William: correspondence and poetryFolder 5484536198154Starbuck, George: correspondenceFolder 55845411967-196955Stefanik, Ernest: correspondenceFolder 56845461977-197856Scope and ContentsCorrespondence regarding publication of A Gathering of Voices (Rook Press). Includes letter of JIK to Ernest Stefanik, February 5, 1978.Stein, Kevin: correspondenceFolder 57845511987-200457Scope and ContentsIllinois Writers Review; includes JIK to Stein, December 19, 2003 and November 11, 2004Steingass, David: correspondenceFolder 58845561969-197558Stern, Frederick C.: correspondenceFolder 59845611983-198459Stewart, Robert: correspondenceFolder 60845661980-198360Stryk, Lucien: correspondenceFolder 61845711966-198461Sugarman, Molly Sower: correspondenceFolder 6286426200362Scope and ContentsIncludes email of JIK to Sugarman, enclosing the poem "come to the wedding"Sullivan, Tom: correspondenceFolder 63845761970-197563Sward, Robert: correspondence and poetryFolder 6484581196764Takemoto, Patricia (Northern Illinois University Press): correspondenceFolder 6584586197565Scope and ContentsNIU publicity for exhibit on IL poets. Also includes correspondence of Michael C. McDermott and Michael J. Cuyjet.Truesdale, C. W. "Bill": correspondenceFolder 66845911968-197166Scope and ContentsIncludes correspondence on publication of The Intricate Land (New Rivers Press).Turner, Myron: correspondenceFolder 67845961972, 197767Scope and ContentsThe Far Point Press, The Four Humans PressUniversity of Chicago Press: correspondence, reports, contractsFolder 68846011964-198568Scope and ContentsPrimarily correspondence of editor Maurice English and regarding publication and royalties for Rivers into Islands. Includes letter of JIK to John G. Ryden, February 5, 1978.University of Illinois Press: correspondence, contract, publicityFolder 69846061983-198669Scope and ContentsPrimarily regarding the publication of Poems from the Sangamon (1985); correspondence with editor Richard Wentworth and assistant editor Patricia Hollahan.Urdang, Constance: correspondenceFolder 70846111976, 197970Scope and ContentsRegarding SSU Spring Verbal Arts Festival, 1976, including pubilcity and photo.Van Duyn, Mona: correspondenceFolder 71846161964, 1981-198471Vayo, Joan: correspondence and poetryFolder 72846211975-198672Verbal Arts Festival and other SSU literary events: correspondence and flyersFolder 73846261974-1988, n.d.73Scope and ContentsIncludes several form letters by JIK to Thomas McGrath, Wendell Berry, Stanley Plumly, Walter Bradford, Lisel Mueller, Ruth Whitman, Peter Harleman, and Grace Butcher, many of them bearing personal messages. Also includes correspondence of David Etter, Ruth Whitman, Ron Deverman, Rosalyn Drexler, and Ralph J. Mills.Veteran's Administration: records, insurance, job information, correspondenceFolder 74846311943-1977, n.d.74Scope and ContentsIncludes letter of JIK to Disbursement Officer, December 9, 1957.Vinson, James: correspondenceFolder 7584636197275Scope and ContentsRegarding JIK entry in Contemporary Poets of the English Language (1973)Vinz, Mark: correspondenceFolder 76846411974-198676Wagner, Linda: correspondenceFolder 77846461976, 1978, n.d.77Scope and ContentsIncludes JIK to Linda Wagner, January 17, 1978.Walsh, Chad: correspondenceFolder 7884651198578Scope and ContentsRegarding reviews of Poems from the Sangamon and Selected Poems.Walt Whitman Center for the Arts and Humanities: correspondence and pamphletsFolder 79846561979-198479Wang, Shouyi: correspondence and translationsFolder 80846611984-1990, 201580Scope and ContentsIncludes JIK to Wang Shouyi, July 15, 1986 and July 17, 1986.Warden, Ray: correspondenceFolder 81846661969-197581Warner, Elizabeth: correspondenceFolder 8284671197782Scope and ContentsIncludes JIK to Elizabeth Warner, November 15, 1977.Weber, Jessica: correspondenceFolder 83846761981-198583Weir, Elizabeth: correspondenceFolder 8484681200984Whitman, Ruth: correspondenceFolder 85846861968-198685Scope and ContentsIncludes JIK to Ruth Whitman, March 1, 1976.Winning, Rebecca: correspondence and poetryFolder 86846911976-1990, n.d.86Scope and ContentsIncludes JIK letter of recommendation to Colorado Arts Council, March 9, 1983. While primarily correspondence of Rebecca Winning this file also contains correspondence of Cathy Abner, August 15, 1971; Mike Strelow, February 4, 1975; Sheila Sears, January 15, 1979; Lynn E. Man, November 19, ??Wright, Annie: correspondence and poetryFolder 87846961972-199187Scope and ContentsIncludes a poem by James Wright.Yeagley, Joan: correspondenceFolder 88847011970-199188Young, Geoff: correspondenceFolder 89847061971-197589Zimmer, Paul: correspondenceFolder 90847111970-199390PublicationsBox 484716The Xavier Athenaeum 19, No. 1 (winter 1947): 18, 23-32.Item 1847211Scope and ContentsIncludes JIK poem "Song of the Village Beggar" and short story "Carnival at St. George"The Yale Review 43, No. 1 (Autumn 1953): 117.Item 2847262Scope and ContentsIncludes JIK poem: "On a Fall Night"The Massachusetts Review 3, No. 3 (spring 1962): 539.Item 3847313Scope and ContentsIncludes JIK poem: "Mexican Independence Day, Fairmont City, Illinois"Poets at the Gate (St. Louis, MO: Arts Festival of Washington University, 1964), 37-47.Item 4847364Scope and ContentsIncludes JIK poems: "Prodigal, "Perspectives of the Moon", "Children in the Leaves", "Noah", "Moon Mask", "Fourth of July", "Late Shift in the Mill", "Time's Out", "Little Harpe's Head"Heartland: Poets of the Midwest Lucien Stryk, ed. (DeKalb: Northern Illinois University Press, 1967), 92-100.Item 5847415Scope and ContentsIncludes the following JIK poems: "St. Louis Midday", "Hampton Road", "Late Shift in the Mill", "Old Moon Planter", "Church of Rose of Lima, Cincinnati", "Night Fire", "Edwardsville before Sunrise", "North on One-Eleven", "Heman Avenue Holiday", "June Night on the River"Neruda and Vallejo: Selected Poems, Robert Bly, ed., and trans., John Knoepfle and James Wright, trans. (Boston: Beacon Press, 1971), 185, 193, 195, 207, 213, 215, 249.Item 6847466Scope and ContentsIncludes the following Cesar Vallejo poems translated by JIK: "Babble", "Twilight", "Agape", "The Weary Circles", "The Distant Footsteps" (translation with James Wright), "To My Brother Miguel" (translation with James Wright),  "Black Stone Lying on a White Stone" (translation with Robert Bly)Between People: A Reader for Open Learning, Stephen Berg, et al., eds. (Glenview, IL: Scott Foresman &amp; Co., 1972), 153-54.Item 7847517Scope and ContentsIncludes the following Cesar Vallejo poems translated by JIK:  "The Weary Circles," "Agape"Prairie Voices: A Collection of Illinois Poets, Lucien Stryk, ed. (Peoria: Illinois Arts Council, 1980), n.p.Item 8847568Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK poem "Vachel Lindsay."From A to Z: 200 Contemporary American Poets, David Ray, ed. (Athens, OH: Swallow Press, 1981), 136.Item 9847619Scope and ContentsIncludes the following JIK poems: "At the Roadside", "Those Who Come What Will They say of us"The Spoon River Quarterly 10, No. 2 (spring 1985): 21-36.Item 108476610Scope and ContentsIncludes the following JIK poems: "decatur". "lunch room new berlin", "bath", "confluence", "soundings in glacial drift", "lincoln tomb, a report", "late winter in menard county", "poem for scott lucas"Essays in Medieval Studies: Proceedings of the Illinois Medieval Association 6 (1989): 94-101.Item 118477111Scope and ContentsIncludes the following JIK essay: "Shakespeare's Henry V &amp; the Geneva Bible"Nimrod: International Journal of Prose &amp; Poetry 34, No. 2 (spring/summer 1991): 54-55.Item 128477612Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK poem: "once when we were all the same"New Virginia Review 8 (spring 1991): 266-68.Item 138478113Scope and ContentsIncludes the following JIK poems: "what else was there worth talking about", "this day that was summer", "nuns", "beneath kennesaw mountain"Annette Hayne, Poems of a German Jewish Childhood (New York: The Poet's Press, 1994), 17.Item 148478614Scope and ContentsIncludes a portion of JIK translation of César Vallejo poem, "Agape," (epigraph).The Centennial Review 39, No. 2 (spring 1995): 302-8.Item 158479115Scope and ContentsIncludes the following JIK self interview: "a green snake interview: 'psalm six'"Molly Sower Sugarman, Choices: Living with Cancer, Dying with Dignity, 2nd ed. (Cool, CA: n.p., c. 1999), 27.Item 168479616Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK poem: "Love is like a Bowl"Natural Bridge: A Journal of Contemporary Literature 5 (spring 2001): 157-58.Item 178480117Scope and ContentsIncludes the following JIK poems: "Clare Festival of Traditional Singing", "Where were you in the Silence"The Prairie Star: A Literary Review (summer 2001): 92.Item 188480618Scope and Contents"Cantico from Spain"The Shop: A Magazine of Poetry 6 (summer 2001): 51.Item 198481119Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK poem: "Saint Brigids Well"Fresh Water: Poems from the Rivers, Lakes, and Streams, Jennifer Bosveld, ed. (Johnstown, OH: Pudding House Publications, 2002), 96.Item 208481620Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK poem: "Driftwood fire"I Have My Own Song for it: Modern Poems of Ohio, Elton Glaser and William Greenway, eds. (Akron, OH: University of Akron Press, 2002), 105, 130.Item 218482121Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK poems: "At Marietta, Ohio", "Church of Rose of Lima, Cincinnati"New Letters: A Magazine of Writing &amp; Art 73, No. 1 (2006): 134-38.Item 228482622Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK poem: "poems shaped from the liebeslieder waltzes"The MacGuffin 23, No. 2 (winter 2007): 65-72.Item 238483123Scope and ContentsIncludes the following JIK poems: "by the cold waterfall", "the bench", "blue beads", "waiting for dawn", "loves remunerations", "a distant voice", "last sunday in january"Quiddity: International Literary Journal 1, No. 2 (fall/winter 2008-2009): 47-52.Item 248483624Scope and ContentsIncludes the following JIK poems: "Lincoln Tomb, A Report", "Old State Capitol", "Bath", "Presidential Election with Blackbirds and Swallows"The MacGuffin 25, No. 3 (spring/summer 2009): 59-62.Item 258484125Scope and ContentsIncludes the following JIK poems: "wednesday, march 18", "friday the thirteenth", "friday", "saturday"Fifth Wednesday Journal: Defining Literature in Real Context 7 (fall 2010): 13-22.Item 268484626Scope and ContentsIncludes James Ballowe, "Looking Back and Ahead: An Interview with John Knoepfle" and the following JIK poems: "Early in the Week Complaint", "And Whose Day is this", "Thursday Well yes May Fourteenth", "Brooding on a Friday Morning", "Gray Saturday Lines", "A Farewell to August"Pat Smith, Collected Poems, John F. Knoll, ed. (Berkeley, CA: Ariel Books, 2010), v.Item 278485127Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK poem: "lines for pat" (epigraph)Quiddity: International Literary Journal 4, No. 1 (spring/summer 2011): 118-19.Item 288485628Scope and ContentsIncludes the following JIK poems: "Easter Monday", "A Farewell to August"New Letters: A Magazine of Writing &amp; Art 78, No. 2 (2012): 120-26.Item 298486129Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK poem: "thinking back these eighty years"Peter L. Simpson, Stealing Home (Kansas City, MO: BKMK Press, 1985) (photocopy)Item 308486630Scope and ContentsDedicated in part to JIK.Cynthia Gallaher, Night Ribbons (Chicago: Polar Bear Press, 1989)Item 318487131Scope and ContentsInscribed to Peggy Knoepfle by the author.Tu Li, The Way of Eternal Recurrance, trans. Robert P. Dickey (New York: 21st Century Press, 1994)Item 328487632Scope and ContentsInscribed by the translator to both JIK and Peggy Knoepfle.Poems of Hope Vilsick-GreenwellItem 3384881200133Scope and ContentsLoose pages containing assorted poems including "Hope at the Wall" inscribed to JIK and Peggy Knoepfle, November 18, 2001.John Garmon and Sandra Garmon, West by Southwest: Verbal and Visual Snapshots from the High Plains (Chapel Hill, NC: Professional Press, 2005)Item 348488634Scope and ContentsInscribed by John Garmon to JIK and Peggy Knoepfle.David Bengston, This Fragile Moment (n.p.: winter 2005-2006)Item 358489135Scope and ContentsInscribed by the author to JIK and Peggy Knoepfle, July 2008.Dan Guillory, The Lincoln Poems (Mahomet, IL: Mayhaven Publishing, 2008) (loose printing)Item 368489636Scope and ContentsPrint of ms apparently sent to JIK for comment.PublicationsBox 584901The Village Magazine 1979: Published in Honor of the Centenary of the Birth of Vachel Lindsay (Springfield, IL: Scarritt Associates and Sangamon Poets, 1979), 44.Item 1849061Scope and ContentsIncludes the following JIK poem: "Two Poems by John Knoepfle"A Reader's Guide to Illinois Literature, Robert Bray, et al., eds. (Springfield: Office of the Illinois Secretary of State, 1985), 63-81.Item 2849112Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK essay: "Poetry"Springhouse 5, No. 4 (August 1988): 15.Item 3849163Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK story: "Dim's Catalog of Dust"Springhouse 5, No. 5 (October 1988): 22-23.Item 4849214Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK story: "The Hannibal Frogs"Springhouse 5, No. 6 (December 1988): 12.Item 5849265Scope and ContentsIncludes JIK story: "Sheep Production"Springhouse 7, No. 1 (February 1990): 6.Item 6849316Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK story: "Wind and the Tomcats"Tennessee Folklore Society Bulletin 54, No. 2 (1990): 49-55.Item 7849367Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK interview: "Johnny Dobbs: A Pilot's Memories""Kickapoo Volunteer Stewardship Network," The Nature Conservancy, Illinois, pamphlet, c. May 28, 1994.Item 8849418Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK poem: "Hill Prairie"IWI Newsletter: A Publication of Illinois Writers, Inc. 14, No. 4 (May 1994): 2.Item 9849469Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK poem: "Hearing Kathleen Battle Singing"AMI—Illinois Stateline, Alliance for the Mentally Ill of Illinois newsletter (June 1994), 4.Item 108495110Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK poem: "AMI at the Hilton"Behold: Arts for the Church Year (November 27, 2005-February 26, 2006): 19.Item 118495611Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK poem: "Here is this Offering"Your Voice Now Raise: New Solos for the Church (Webster, NY: Zimbel Press, 2005), 55-57.Item 128496112Scope and ContentsIncludes lyrics by JIK: "Prayer" (after "prayer against famine"; music written by Mark Siebert); and CD.Jerome (IL) Bulletin, newsletter (February 2010): n.p.Item 138496613Scope and ContentsIncludes: "tornado watch"For the People: A Newsletter of the Abraham Lincoln Association 16, No. 1 (spring 2014): 6.Item 148497114Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK poem: "Abraham Lincoln Walks in the Morning"River King: Poetry Supplement 1, No. 2 (summer 1995), 1.Item 158497615Scope and ContentsIncludes the following JIK poems: "recovering the angelic past", "a little song for sugar cubes", "after epiphany and all", "goethes dog would have been sublime"River King: Poetry Supplement 1, No. 3 (fall 1995), 1.Item 168498116Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK self interview: "a green snake interview: 'east st louis again'"River King: Poetry Supplement 9, No. 1 (spring 2003): 10.Item 178498617Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK poems: "misdirection", "study in gray and black", "river with evergreens", "footprints",  "ruins", "leaves with campouts", "beginning the day", "the old priest says"State Journal Register (Springfield, IL), special edition, First Night '95, December 27, 1994, 6A.Item 188499118Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK poem: "now the last is the first again"Times Out: Illinois Times' Weekly Guide to What's Happening (Springfield), December 29, 1994, 22.Item 198499619Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK poem: "now the last is the first again"Illinois Times (Springfield) 27, No. 14 (November 22-28, 2001): 12.Item 208500120Scope and ContentsIncludes the JIK poem: "Autumn in Illinois"Illinois Times (Springfield) 39, No. 30 (February 27-March 5, 2014): 3.Item 218500621Scope and ContentsIncludes JIK poem: "meeting mr Lincoln"Upward Bound reports and Shakespeare research materialBox 685011Upward Bound: correspondence and documentsFolder 1850161966-19691JIK: Upward Bound report, Murray State UniversityFolder 285021January 30, 19672JIK: Upward Bound report, Southern State CollegeFolder 385026February 1, 19673JIK: Upward Bound report, Ouachita Baptist UniversityFolder 485031February 3, 19674JIK: Upward Bound report, Kentucky schoolsFolder 585036June 16, 19675Scope and ContentsKentucky State College, Southeast Community College, Alice Lloyd College, Morehead State UniversityJIK: Upward Bound report, North Dakota State UniversityFolder 685041July 17-18, 19676JIK: Upward Bound report, Wisconsin State University--Eau ClaireFolder 785046July 21-22, 19677JIK: Upward Bound report, University of IowaFolder 885051August 1-2, 19678JIK: Upward Bound report, Carleton CollegeFolder 985056August 5, 19679JIK: Upward Bound report, Wisconsin State University--WhitewaterFolder 1085061August 13, 196710JIK: Upward Bound report, Wisconsin State University--Eau ClaireFolder 1185066March 8-9, 196811JIK: Upward Bound report, Black Hills State CollegeFolder 1285071July 26-27, 196812JIK: Upward Bound report, Creighton UniversityFolder 1385076November 8-9, 196813JIK: Upward Bound report, Kentucky State CollegeFolder 1485081October 16, 196914JIK: Upward Bound report, Morehead State UniversityFolder 1585086December 5-6, 196915JIK: Upward Bound report, Fisk UniversityFolder 1685091December 10-11, 196916JIK: Upward Bound report, Carson-Newman CollegeFolder 1785096December 12-13, 196917JIK: Upward Bound report, Central CollegeFolder 1885101January 23-24, 197018JIK: Upward Bound report, Berea CollegeFolder 1985106January 30-31, 197019JIK: Upward Bound report, Middle Tennessee State UniversityFolder 2085111February 20-21, 197020JIK: Upward Bound report, Northeast Missouri State CollegeFolder 2185116February 26-27, 197021JIK: Upward Bound report, Graceland CollegeFolder 2285121March 13-14, 197022JIK: Upward Bound report, Coe CollegeFolder 2385126July 14-15, 1969; July 10-11, 197023JIK ms: "John Fisher's 'a poore man cometh to a prince' and its use in MND, 2H4, H5, and WT"Folder 2486481c. 198024JIK ms: "Shakespeare's Henry V and the Geneva Bible Isaiah"Folder 2586486c. 198925Scope and ContentsArticle was published in Essays in Medieval Studies, vol. 6 (1989)-- see box 4, item 11.JIK ms: "John Fisher's Good Friday Sermon and Shakespeare's Henry V" (also notes and partial draft)Folder 2686491c. 200026JIK ms: Henry V and Geneva BibleFolder 2786496n.d.27JIK ms: "John Fisher's All Saints' Day Sermon and Shakespeare's Henry VIII"Folder 2886501n.d.28JIK ms: John Fisher, Shakespeare, and reconciliation (incomplete draft)Folder 2986506n.d.29JIK ms: John Fisher and "Henry V text" (incomplete draft)Folder 3086511n.d.30JIK translation: "Saint John Fisher's Translation of Psalm 6"Folder 3186516n.d.31JIK: Comments and notes on Fasciculus Morum: A Fourteenth Century Preacher's HandbookFolder 3286521198932JIK: Notes and sources on Henry V and Rogation Day HomiliesFolder 3386526c. 200033JIK: Notes and bibliographies on Shakespeare's Henry VFolder 3486531c. 200034JIK: Notes on scripture quotationsFolder 3586536n.d.35JIK: Meditation on Macbeth (also notes and articles)Folder 3686541n.d.36JIK translation: "praise is an oration, enumerating the goods of various things"Folder 3786546n.d.37JIK: Notes comparing texts of prescribed homilies on rogation days (also sources and index)Folder 3886551n.d.38Rogation Day Homily, passages from two editionsFolder 3986556n.d.39Sermons of St. John Fisher (unknown edition)Folder 4086561n.d.40John Hooper, "A Funeral Sermon" (1549) and "Exposition upon Psalm XXIII" (1562)Folder 4186566n.d.41"An Homily Against Disobedience and Wilful Rebellion" from Book of Homilies (1571) (1844 edition)Folder 4286571n.d.42"A Fruitful Dialogue Declaring These Words of Christ: 'This is my Body'" from William Nicholson, ed., The Remains of Edmund Grindal... (1843)Folder 4386576n.d.43Richmond Noble, Shakespeare's Biblical Knowledge... (1935)Folder 4486581n.d.44Shakespeare's Henry V and research articles (1945-1988)Folder 4586586n.d.45Thomas W. Cunningham, "Saint John Fisher's 'A Godlie Treatisse Declaryeg the Benefits and Great Commodities of Prayer...': The Text, its History, and Pertinent Critical Notes," (Diss. Fordham University, 1950)Folder 4686591n.d.46Research articles on Falstaff (1955-1976)Folder 4786596n.d.47Sister Denise Sullivan, "A Critical Edition of 'Two Fruytfull Sermons' of Saint John Fisher, Bishop of Rochester" (Masters Thesis, University of Notre Dame, 1961)Folder 4886601n.d.48Research articles on Shakespeare's Henry VI (1961-1980)Folder 4986606n.d.49Marlowe Society of America, newsletter and book reviewsFolder 50866111984-198650Various materials on John FisherFolder 51866161986, n.d.51Student Papers: Thomas Middleton's A Mad World, My MastersFolder 52866211986, 198852Roberta Bux Bosse, Norman D. Hinton, "Cynewulf and the Apocalyptic Vision"Folder 5386626199053"The York Crucifixion" (Verbal Arts Festival)Folder 5486631200054Shakespeare's Henry V bibliographiesFolder 5586636n.d.55Miscellaneous research articles on Shakespeare's Julius Caesar and Otto Wermullerus, Treatise on DeathFolder 5686641n.d.56Biblical references, research and passagesFolder 5786646n.d.57Diskettes, audio and video tapes and discsBox 785131Diskette: Christmas EveItem 18513620021Scope and ContentsIncludes JIK poem: "Christmas Eve"; other files on disc were corrupted and cannot be accessed.Diskette: Unnamed yellow (invitation list for JIK poetry reading)Item 28514120042Diskette: John's lettersItem 38514619993Scope and ContentsLetters and emails, mostly of a personal nature, sent and recieved.Diskette: Rogation Days HomiliesItem 485151August 20014Scope and ContentsSeveral files regarding a study of Shakespeare's Henry V.Diskette: John's Files ... up to February 21 2000Item 5851561998-19995Scope and ContentsContains subfiles. Numerous files including documents having to do with a study of Shakespeare's Henry V, poetry, JIK's biography, speeches, and correspondence.Diskette: John's files from Peg's ComputerItem 6851611999-20016Scope and ContentsIncludes poetry (haiku) and correspondence.Diskette: John #2Item 78516620007Scope and ContentsSeveral duplicate files and one letter of JIK to Catherine McKenna, May 11, 2000.Diskette: Irish Poems IItem 8851711999-20028Scope and ContentsPoetry, primarily drafts for prayer agains famine &amp; other irish poems.Diskette: John Knoepfle website and proseItem 98517620039Scope and ContentsDrafts of two essays and a short story.Diskette: Knoepfle: Prayer Against Famine Part VItem 1085181200310Scope and ContentsPoetry primarily drafts from part V of prayer against famine &amp; other irish poems.Diskette: Irish Poems: Prayers Against Famine IIItem 11851861999-200711Scope and ContentsPoetry, drafts for prayer against famine &amp; other irish poems.Diskette: Irish Poems IIItem 12851911999-200212Scope and ContentsPoetry, drafts for prayer against famine &amp; other irish poems.Diskette: John Knoepfle website poetryItem 1385196200313Scope and ContentsPoetry, copies from verious pubications for website.Diskette: Christmas PoemItem 1485201200614Scope and ContentsChristmas card poem.Diskette: John Knoepfle websiteItem 1585206200315Scope and ContentsSelected bibliography and biographical essay.Diskette: Irish book announcementItem 1685211200416Scope and ContentsAnnouncement, publicity, and poem samples from prayer against famine &amp; other irish poems.Diskette: Wrestling with AngelsItem 1785216200117Scope and ContentsPoetry.Diskette: John Knoepfle #1 for websiteItem 1885221200318Scope and ContentsWebsite content.Cassette: Curtis Marshall interview (by JIK)Item 1985226May 20, 195719Scope and ContentsPart of riverman collection.Cassette: JIK on Carl Sandburg, Knox CollegeItem 2085546January 15, 197820Cassette: JIK poetry reading, Itaska Community College, KAXE FM, Grand Rapids, MNItem 2185581October 25, 197921Scope and ContentsA: "A Gathering of Voices," (Rivers into Islands selection) "Country sweat," "June 9th on the River"Cassette: JIK poetry reading, SSU, "Sangamon Valley: A Sense of Place Day"Item 2285601May 7, 198122Scope and ContentsA: JIK intro about his preliminary work on poems from the sangamon, readings follow.Cassette: JIK poetry reading, "New Letters on the Air," New Letters Magazine, David Ray (host)Item 2385616198123Scope and ContentsA: Intro, "Land of a Thousand Flowers," "Pilgrim's Day," found poem (unnamed), "The First of January," "20th of January," "Feast of St. Angnes," others.Cassette: JIK poetry reading, Poets Corner, Newberry LibraryItem 2485636May 12, 198324Scope and ContentsA: Selection from poems from the sangamonCassette: JIK reading, Dim story (poor audio)Item 2585651September 198425Scope and ContentsA: Conversation, "Dim and Girl in Bed" (with comments from others).Cassette: JIK interview by Forrest Robinson, WIU radioItem 2685656September 19, 198526Cassette: JIK reading, "Dim and Hannibal Frogs"Item 2785666September 20, 198527Cassette: JIK poetry reading, poems from the sangamon, for Burton WeberItem 2885681July 19-20, 198628Scope and ContentsA: Introduction, "it has to be any yes," and sections 1-4.B: sections 5-8Cassette: JIK poetry reading, poems from the sangamon, for Burton WeberItem 2985691July 19-20, 198629Scope and ContentsA: Section 9, beginning with "princess candidate, sangamon county fair"Cassette: JIK poetry reading, University of Missouri St. Louis,Item 3085696April 2, 198730Scope and ContentsA: Introduction; poems inspired by river interviews: "Rose of Lima," "North on 111," "Country Sweat;" "Gathering of Voices;" selected readings from Tang Dynasty Poems, Song Dynasty Poems, poems from the sangamon (through "bulldog crossing").B: Continues selected poems from the sangamon ("lincoln tomb, a report" through "confluence")Cassette: JIK interview with Lorin Cuoco, KWMU radioItem 3185701April 2, 198731Scope and ContentsA: Introduction, interview, various readings throughout including: "June Night on the River," and "lincoln tomb, a report."Cassette: JIK poetry reading, Guild Bookstore, WFMT radio,Item 3285706June 22, 198732Scope and ContentsA: Selected readings from selected poems, Tang Dynasty Poems, Song Dynasty Poems, poems from the sangamon, starting with "after gray days"B: selection of poems from the sangamon continued, beginning with "circuit preacher, lines after cartwright"Cassette: JIK poetry reading, "Word of Mouth," Loyola University, WFMT radio,Item 3385711March 198833Scope and ContentsA: Introduction, selection of readings from poems from the sangamon, includes: "east in mclean county," "father marquette," "tamaroa prayer," "old settlers day," "circuit preacher," "Kickapoo dance," "hill prairie," "technology," "farm auction," "lunch room," "bulldog crossing," "old name, old river," "soundings," "lincoln tomb," "clocks of mason city," "man looking for his wife," "sandalwood poems," "princess candidate"B: "late winter in menard county," "primroses and meadowlark eggs," "confluence"Cassette: JIK conversation with Peggy KnoepfleItem 3485716September 11, 198834Scope and ContentsA: Wide-ranging subject-matter, various writing projects discussed, including the Peoria-Miami Collection, Ohio River Valley associationCassette: JIK at Eureka College,Item 3585721March 30, 198935Scope and ContentsA: Introduction, poetry reading selections from poems from the sangamon; beginning discussion of Peoria-Miami language material, Peoria free-form poetryB: Continued discussion (slideshow) of Peoria-Miami language material, Peoria free-form poetryCassette: JIK conversation with Peggy Knoepfle,Item 3685726February 17, 199136Scope and ContentsA: Continued conversation to end.B: Beginning of conversation, Minnetrista Council for Great Lakes Native American Studies, Annual Conference, Muncie, IN, 1991.Cassette: Peter L. Simpson memorial service, Saint Louis University, College Church,Item 3785731January 18, 199237Scope and ContentsA: "A Patchwork for Pete: A Eulogy" (eulogy)Cassette: JIK reading, Rural Route 3, WSSU (WUIS) radioItem 3885741July 24, 199438Scope and ContentsA: "lincoln tomb, a report," "illinois river pilot," "back county musician," "lunch room new berlin, " "Christmouse" (Dim story), "princess candidate, sangamon county fair"Cassette: Illinois Wesleyan Poetry Festival,Item 3985746October 21, 199539Scope and ContentsA: Eugene Redmond and James McGowan readingsB: JIK reading "new year's day poem,"Cassette: Illinois Wesleyan Poetry FestivalItem 4085751October 21-22, 199540Scope and ContentsSide A: JIK intro but his reading has been erased, Paul Zimmer and Lucien Stryk readingsSide B: Lucien Stryk (contd), Lucia Getsi readingCassette: An Illinois Portfolio: Poets and Painters, Bradley UniversityItem 4185756April 9, 199841Scope and ContentsA: Introduction; Fred Jones, art discussion; James Ballowe reading; art discussion; Lisel Mueller (by Margaret Carter) reading; art discussion; Forrest Robinson reading; art discussion; David Etter readingB: Fred Jones, art discussion; JIK reading: "east in mclean county," "primroses and meadowlark eggs;" art discussion; Kevin Stein readingCassette: Tom Linneman to JIK (poor audio quality)Item 4285761June 200842Scope and ContentsA: Reminiscences of youth, school, war stories.Cassette: JIK and Wang Shouyi readings, Song Dynasty PoemsItem 4385766n.d.43Cassette: JIK poetry reading, Poetry Radio, WGLT radio and IL State University English Dept., tape # 19,Item 4485771n.d.44Scope and ContentsSide A (320-325): "watching a haircut"Side B (205-250): "now the last is first again"Cassette: JIK poetry reading, Poetry Radio, WGLT radio and IL State University English Dept., tape # 21,Item 4585776n.d.45Scope and ContentsA (254-67): "Tamaroa Prayer"Cassette: JIK poetry reading, Poetry Radio, WGLT radio and IL State University English Dept., tape #22Item 4685781n.d.46Scope and ContentsB (52): "Talent Show"Cassette: JIK short story readings, Dim Stories (With Bill R., SSU)Item 4785786n.d.47Scope and ContentsA: "Dim and the Phone Call," "The Night Sugar Creek got Lost," "The Sugar Creek Mud Turtles," "Sleuth &amp; Rabbit," "Easter Dinner and the Ducks," "Wind &amp; the Tomcats," "The Lake Springfield Rat Float," "The French-Intensive Method," "Saved by the Mouse King"Cassette: Peggy Knoepfle critiquing Cesar Vallejo poetry and translationItem 48857911960s48Scope and ContentsIncludes some input from JIK. Side B includes a recording of the documentary Images of Indians: The Great Movie Massacre.Cassette: SSU Verbal Arts Festival: JIK, Jonathan Katz, Ed Dorn readingItem 4985796April 6, 197849Cassette: SSU Verbal Arts Festival: Lyn Lifshin readingItem 5085801April 7, 197850Cassette: SSU Verbal Arts Festival: Robert Bly reading tape #1Item 5185806March 9, 197951Cassette: SSU Verbal Arts Festival: Robert Bly reading, tape #2Item 5286651March 9, 197952Cassette: SSU Verbal Arts Festival: Don Finkel readingItem 5386656198253Cassette: SSU Verbal Arts Festival: William Gass readingItem 5486661198254Cassette: JIK: Dim Stories with Ross Hulvey, Jessica Weber, Peggy KnoepfleItem 5586666March 8, 198555Scope and ContentsIncludes readings of Mouse King, Louie Defleese, othersCassette: Coyote Stories: Stories from the Earth retold by Dr. CricketItem 5686671199056Scope and ContentsNative American traditions. Dr. Cricket was a pen name for SSU professor David Hilligoss.Cassette: JIK's retirement party and roastItem 5786676April 13, 199157Scope and ContentsSSU English professor Jackie Jackson MC'd and includes statements and recollections by several SSU faculty members (Norman Hinton, Ron Ettinger and others).Cassette: Bob Bray poems dedicated to JIK on his retirementItem 5886681199158Cassette: JIK: Dim Tales ("Dim Tape #1")Item 5986686April 20, 199259Cassette: Prairie Home Companion radio show featuring Robert Bly and Alan GinsbergItem 6086691May 30, 199260Cassette: JIK on WGLT radio (Bloomington, IL), interview and readingItem 6186696November 2003(?)61Scope and ContentsPromoting a reading at Illinois Wesleyan University 11/19/2003(?). Reads "princess candidate, sangamon county fair."Cassette: JIK: Dim Tales readingItem 6286701n.d.62Scope and ContentsReads "Tiny Tarts" with friends.Cassette: Mattilou Catchpole's recollections of "Play Parties" in rural Arkansas (1937-1940)Item 6386706n.d.63Scope and ContentsCatchpole was a SSU/UIS professor in nursing and women's studies.Cassette: John Sutherland reading anglo-saxon Psalm 6 and gnomic versesItem 6486711n.d.64Cassette: Keith Clark sings Ballads of LaSalle County, ILItem 6586716n.d.65DVCAM videotape: JIK: World in Progress poetry reading #1 &amp; #2Item 6686721February 21, 200766DVCAM videotape: JIK: World in Progress poetry reading #3 &amp; #4Item 6786726June 15, 200767DVCAM videotape: JIK: World in Progress poetry reading #5 &amp; #6Item 6886731October 3, 200768DVCAM videotape: JIK: World in Progress, remembering World War II, #1 &amp; #2Item 6986736October 26, 200769DVCAM videotape: World in Progress unknown content, "HUC" and "Poetry"Item 7086741April 1, 200870Scope and ContentsPossibly JIK poetry reading.DVCAM videotape: JIK: World in Progress, "Mr. Lincoln" poetry readingItem 7186746October 27, 200871Scope and ContentsTape also includes unknown content: "Performance Poets" which may include JIK.1/4" audio tape on 7" reel (Scotch/3M): JIK: SSU poetry readingItem 7286751May 7, 198172Scope and ContentsSee Item 22 cassette copy of the same reading.Slides: Historical riverboat, steamboat, and river scenesItem 7386756n.d.73Scope and Contents38 slides; possibly Ohio RiverSlides: JIK: documents from Peoria-Miami free form poetry presentationItem 74867611989(?)74Scope and ContentsSee Dickson Mounds/Prairie Grapevine presentation, VHS tape (box 8)Slides: JIK: photos of family and trips to IrelandItem 7586766c. 200475Scope and ContentsSeveral slides relevant to Prayer Against Famine and other Irish Poems.Diskettes, audio and video tapes and discsBox 886771CD: JIK statement about Illinois poets on Illinois Edition, WUISItem 186776September 10, 20041Scope and ContentsIncludes statement of Marcellus Leonard and poetry reading by Kevin Stein.CD: JIK interview and poetry reading, New Letters on the Air, University of Missouri Kansas CityItem 286781June 8, 20052CD: JIK poetry reading University of Missouri St. Louis (2 copies)Item 386786September 14, 20093Scope and ContentsIncludes: (selections from) walking in snow "walking in snow," "tornado watch," "thoughts on my birthday," "valentine," "second prayer room poem," "blue beads from the dirt floor," "betty boop suspenders"(?), "nightfire," "coal sells a bushel a week," "winnebago chief," "a gathering of voices," (selections from) Song Dynasty Poems (translations), Cesar Vallejo (translation) "Agape," (selections from) prayer against famine "skibereen the famine pit," "clare festival of traditional singing," "hearing tommy sands in kilkeel," "prayer against famine," "rope yarn sunday," (selections from) poems from the sangamon "wwii veteran," "lines for the tribe of ben Ishmael," "princess candidate, sangamon county fair"DVD: JIK poetry reading for Illinois PortfolioItem 486791April 9, 19984Scope and ContentsThis dvd is an interactive collection of audio and still images from the event. Includes "east in mclean county" and "primroses and meadowlark eggs"; also readings by Dave Etter, Kevin Stein, and others, see box 7, item 41, audio cassette of the same event.DVD: JIK World in Progress, poetry reading parts #1-#4Item 58680620075Scope and ContentsReadings in Native American poetry, Irish poems. See DVCAM copy of same event, box 7 items 66 and 67.DVD: JIK World in Progress, poetry reading parts #5 &amp; #6 and recollections of World War IIItem 68680120076Scope and ContentsReadings from Rivers into Islands and Poems from the Sangamon. See DVCAM copy of same event, box 7 items 68 and 69.VHS videotape: Documentary: Lights Breaking: Ethical Questions about Genetic EngineeringItem 786811c. 19847Scope and ContentsJIK is one of several contributing experts.VHS videotape: JIK: lecture, poetry and prose readings for Prairie Grapevine, Dickson Mounds MuseumItem 886816October 7, 19898Scope and ContentsPoetry program with live music accompaniment and includes readings by Ron Deverman. JIK lectured on Peoria-Miami free form poetry, read "poem for scott lucas," "confluence," and the Dim Tale "The Little Green Man."VHS videotape: WILL Awards: John Knoepfle (the arts)Item 98682120029Scope and ContentsBrief story tracing JIK's career as a writer and poet. Includes statement by SSU/UIS english department emerita professor Jackie Jackson.VHS videotape: JIK poetry reading on Works in Progress (Springfield Access 4)Item 1086826199710Scope and ContentsIncludes "Lines for my Grandfather," Illinois Wesleyan University residency poems: "There you have it," "An easy puzzle," "Prayer room," Irish poems, and poems written after going to Anchorage, Alaska to see the birth of a grandchild.VHS videotape: JIK poetry reading on Works in Progress (Springfield Access 4)Item 1186831200011Scope and ContentsWorks in Progress (#196): (selections from) prayer against famine "reclaiming the light," "vinegar hill," "where were you in the silence," "peacock feather," "something to live by," "on flattop mountain, lines for a miscarried child," "tory island primitive," "meditation on the book of kells," "saint brigid's well," "dancing with the inupiaq," "saturday in dublin"Works in Progress (#197): (Poems selected for 3rd Annual Springfield Liturgical Arts Festival) (selections from) poems from the sangamon "old priest and his blessing," "after sundown," "in the country," "circuit preacher, lines after peter cartwright," "tamaroa prayer," "marquette in winter camp, chicago river 1675," (selections from) the chinkapin oak "in the december gallery," "a little song for sugar cubes," "polycarp," "AMI at the hilton," "hearing kathleen battle singing," "recovering the angelic past," (selections from) begging an amnesty "at the head of mcallister," "san Francisco in the museum," "sun burning through this," "old man on the street corner," "old woman in her knit cap," "wolf's howl wears us"

