<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>E.02.01/20Archon Finding Aid Title E.02.01/20UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:20:04 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    E2/1/20. Paul Findley Manuscript, "They Dared Speak Out," 1983-1984
    
      Findley, Paul
    
    
      President/Chancellor
    
    E.02.01/20
    282
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1983-1984
    Date acquired: 11/30/1992
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Former U.S. Representative from Illinois, Paul Findley's manuscript for his 1985 book "They Dared Speak Out", and related grant material involving SSU and the American Middle East Peace Research Inst., contains statements of objectives of the book, letter funding estimates, lists of expenses already incurred, photo copies of cancelled checks, correspondence between President Durward Long and Leonard M. Lieberman of the B'nai Brith.
Mr. Findley corresponded with John Munlirs, Director of Budget and Planning, in publishing his book.  Objections expressed by B'nai Brith resulted in the withdrawal of University support from his book, which eventually published by Lawrence Hill of Westport, Conn. In 1985.
The book concerns the Pro-Israeli lobby in the United States, and how lobbyist for AIPAC (American Israeli Public Affairs Committee) influenced U.S. military planning and foreign aid for Israel and third world countries.  Also included are examples of professional and political pressure brought to Pro Israeli lobbyist against elected officials and others who oppose Israeli interests.  
  
    Arrangement Note
By Chapter  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Paul Findley &amp; Judy Everson  
  Box 1Box 126859Outline of Chapters, "They Dared Speak Out"Folder 1268601Letters, vouchers, statements and photocopies of cancelled checksFolder 2268611983-19922Introduction to book, 1983 letter to J. MunkirsFolder 3268623President Long - invitation to speak to B'nai B'rithFolder 4268631983-08-084Introduction to "They Dared Speak Out"Folder 5268645Chapter 1: "King of the Hill," Chapter 2: "Stilling the Still, Small Voices"Folder 6268656Chapter 3: "The Deliberative Body Fails to Deliberate"Folder 7268667Chapter 4: "The Lobby and the Oval Office"Folder 8268678Chapter 5: "Penetrating the Defenses at Defense--- And State"Folder 9268689Chapter 6: "The Assault on Assault"Folder 102686910Chapter 7: "Challenges to Academic Freedom"Folder 112687011Chapter 8: "Tucson: Case Study in Intimidation"Folder 122687112Chapter 9: "Church and State"Folder 132687213Chapter 10: "Nor All Jews Toe the Line"Folder 142687314Chapter 11: "Beyond the Banks of the Potomac"Folder 152687415Epilogue:  "Repairing the Damage"Folder 162687516Notes for Chapter One Through EpilogueFolder 172687617Chapter 6- Part II: "Assaulting Free Speech in the Heartland"Folder 182687718

