<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>H.06.##rxaArchon Finding Aid Title H.06.##rxaUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:21:19 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    H6. Clayville Rural Life Center, 1970-1992
    
      Clayville Rural Life Center
    
    
      Business and Administrative Services
    
    H.06.##rxa
    299
    
      18.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1970-1992
    Date acquired: 07/01/1992
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The Clayville Rural Life Life center records contain daily accounts of Clayville Administration, maintenance,  student workers, volunteers schools programs,  tours,  restoration,  festivals, HABS reports, Dr. &amp; Mrs. Pearson gifts &amp; interviews; also educational programs, including "Mornings at Clayville, Discovery, Life in the 1850's",  inventories of Clayville Collections, site calendars, site attendance registers, Interpreters Notebooks, children's letter, exhibit material, research papers, History notes, visitor comments, teachers evaluations; Historic preservation, music, and children's games, correspondence, SSU foundation contracts, Master plans and material dealing with the Clayville Folk Art Guild.  
  
    Arrangement Note
By subject  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Elizabeth Weir  
  
    Records
  
  Box 1Box 153335Clayville Catalog Inventory Worksheet. Folder 1, C1760-C1801, Book VIIFolder 1533361Collection Information, folder 2Folder 2533372Collection WorkbookFolder 3533381990-913Collection Information, folder 1aFolder 4533394Collection information, folder IIIaFolder 5533405Clayville - Estate Inventory ProjectFolder 6533411840-18536Collection Development, folder 1Folder 7533427Collection Development, folder 2Folder 8533438Clayville CollectionsFolder 9533449Very Important Collections Material (worksheets)Folder 105334510Collections WorksheetsFolder 115334611Clayville Collections: Procedures for Inventory and Registration C1 to C99tFolder 125334712Clayville Collections, C99t to C199tFolder 135334813Clayville Collections, C200t to C299tFolder 145334914Clayville Collections, C300t to C399tFolder 155335015Clayville Collections, C400t to C499tFolder 165335116Clayville Collections, C500t to C599tFolder 175335217Clayville Collections, C600t to C699tFolder 185335318Clayville Collections, C700t to C799tFolder 195335419Clayville Collections, C800t to C899tFolder 205335520Clayville Collections, C900t to C1032tFolder 215335621Clayville Collections, C1051 to C1198tFolder 225335722Clayville Collections, 1200t to C1348tFolder 235335823Clayville Collections, C1350t to C1499Folder 245335924Clayville Collections, C1500 to C1648Folder 255336025Clayville Collections, C1650 to C1740Folder 265336126Collections PhotosFolder 275336227Box 2Box 253363Site CalendarFolder 153364July-September 19831Site CalendarFolder 253365October-December 19832Site CalendarFolder 353366May-June 19833Site CalendarFolder 453367January - April 19834Site Calendar folder 1Folder 55336819845Site Calendar folder 2Folder 65336919846Site Calendar folder 3Folder 75337019847Site Calendar folder 1Folder 85337119858Site Calendar folder 2Folder 95337219859Site Calendar folder 1Folder 1053373198610Site Calendar folder 1Folder 1153374198611Site Calendar folder 3Folder 1253375198612Site Calendar folder 1Folder 1353376198713Site Calendar folder 2Folder 1453377198714Site Calendar folder 3Folder 1553378198715Scope and ContentsNote: 1988 calendar missingSite CalendarFolder 16533791989, January - May16Site CalendarFolder 17533801989, October - December17Site CalendarFolder 18533811989, June - October18Site CalendarFolder 19533821990, January - May19Site CalendarFolder 20533831990, May - July20Site CalendarFolder 21533841990, July - December21Box 3Box 353385Site CalendarFolder 153386 1991, January - June1Site CalendarFolder 2533871991, June - September2Site CalendarFolder 3533881991, September - December3Site CalendarFolder 4533891992, January - June4Clayville Guest Register SheetsFolder 55339019905Clayville Guest Register SheetsFolder 6533911988, January - June6Clayville Guest Register SheetsFolder 7533921988, June - August7Clayville Guest Register SheetsFolder 8533931988, September - December8Clayville Guest Register Sheets, folder 1Folder 95339419889Clayville Guest Register Sheets, folder 2Folder 1053395198810Clayville Guest Register Sheets, folder 1Folder 1153396199111Clayville Guest Register Sheets, folder 2Folder 1253397199112Clayville Guest Register Sheets, folder 3Folder 1353398199113Site UsageFolder 1453399199114Guest Register, folder 1Folder 1553400198715Guest Register, folder 2Folder 1653401198716Guest Register, folder 3Folder 1753402198717Guest Register, folder 1Folder 1853403198618Guest Register, folder 2Folder 1953404198619Guest Register, folder 3Folder 2053405198620Guest Register, folder 1Folder 2153406198521Guest Register, folder 2Folder 2253407198522Guest Register, folder 3Folder 2353408198523Box 4Box 453409Mornings at Clayville EvaluationsFolder 153410Spring 19771Mornings at ClayvilleFolder 25341119752Mornings at ClayvilleFolder 3534121987 &amp; 19883Mornings at ClayvilleFolder 4534134Scope and ContentsInterpreters Notes: textiles, Wood on the Farm, and Play Party Games.Mornings at ClayvilleFolder 5534145Scope and ContentsAnnotated Bibliography for Games and ToysMornings at ClayvilleFolder 653415Spring and Fall 19786Mornings at ClayvilleFolder 753416Fall 1976, Spring 19777Scope and ContentsInterpreters List and ApplicationsMornings at ClayvilleFolder 85341719748Mornings at ClayvilleFolder 95341819759CalendarFolder 1053419October 197910Visitor Record, file 1Folder 1153420197911Teaching Plan: Eight Months In Illinois (1843), by WM. OliverFolder 125342112Scope and ContentsFolder 1Teaching Plan: Eight Months In Illinois (1843), by WM. OliverFolder 135342213Scope and ContentsFolder 2Eight Months In Illinois (1843), by WM. OliverFolder 145342314Scope and ContentsObservations of a TravelerPearson Article, State Journal RegisterFolder 155342415Pearson GiftsFolder 1653425198116Pearson CorrespondenceFolder 17534261983-8417Dr. and Mrs. Mary Pearson, Recognition AwardFolder 185342718Copley PressFolder 195342819Education FeesFolder 205342920News Papers of the 1850's, Interpretive Material Relating to WoodFolder 215343021Paper on "Peter Cartwright and the Methodist Church" by Sonia SiebertFolder 225343122Guide to Curatorial Operations, 1 of 3Folder 235343223Guide to Curatorial Operations, 2 of 3Folder 245343324Guide to Curatorial Operations, 3 of 3Folder 255343425Curatorial Methods, Ethics for CuratorsFolder 265343526Clayville Inn Guest RegisterFolder 2753436May 6 thru June 28, 199227Clayville Guest RegisterFolder 2853437October – December 198828Clayville Guest RegisterFolder 2953438May to August 198929Clayville Guest RegisterFolder 3053439August to December 198930Box 5Box 553440Interpreters Notebook, The Broadwell Kitchen, FoodwaysFolder 1534411Interpreters Notebook, Farming Tools and CropsFolder 2534422Interpreters Notebook, Broadwell's Kitchen, Time Language for ChildrenFolder 3534433Interpreters Notebook, Eastern Kitchen, Activity AreasFolder 4534444Interpreters Notebook, Nothern Gardens, Masters FileFolder 5534455Interpreters Notebook, Southern Gardens, Masters FileFolder 6534466Interpreters Notebook, Southern Kitchen, Masters File, Including Burgoo PaperFolder 7534477Interpreters Notebook, Textiles on the Farm, Master CopyFolder 8534488Interpreters Notebook, Wood on the Farm, Master CopyFolder 9534499Interpreters Notebook, Wood on the Farm, Master FileFolder 105345010Published Series Report #5 Inns and Taverns In the Midwest:Folder 115345111Scope and ContentsTypical Functions, Forms and Layouts.Published Series III, Clayville History:Folder 125345212Scope and ContentsTradition and Change in the Mid-Nineteenth CenturyPublished Series III, Clayville History:Folder 135345313Scope and ContentsTradition and Change in the Mid-Nineteenth 	Century, Master CopyBroadwells of Clayville and their Roots, 4 parts, Part 1 of Master CopyFolder 145345414Report #3, Broadwells of Clayville and Their Roots, Part IIFolder 155345515Scope and ContentsFamily Land Dealings In IllinoisBroadwells of Clayville and Their Roots (Four Parts)Folder 165345616Scope and ContentsPart III The Roots In Ohio and New JerseyPublication Series II, The Broadwells of Clayville, Part IV, and Their RootsFolder 175345717Scope and ContentsOhio and 	New JerseyPublication Series II, Broadwells of Clayville and Their Roots, Part IFolder 185345818Scope and ContentsThe Family and Its Activities In IllinoisPublication Series II, Report #1, Trades and Professions in Rural Sangamon County, 1850Folder 195345919Publication Series II, Report #7 Historical Landscape Recovery Through Research, Master CopyFolder 205346020Publication Series, Resource List #14, The Historic Landscapes of the Midwest:Folder 215346121Scope and ContentsMaterials For Determining Their Appearance Over Time and for the Preserving and 	Reconstructing ThemPublication Series I, Living History Resource List #13, Farming and Inns In The Midwest to 1860Folder 225346222Publication Series II, Report # 8, Midwest Foodways and Their RootsFolder 235346323Publication Series II, Report # 9, Rural Trades and Businesses In Central Illinois in 	1850:Folder 245346424Scope and ContentsA Compilation of DataPublication Series I, Resource # 8, Food and Food Habits Bibliography, The Midwest and Its RootsFolder 255346525In My Opinion, by Ed Hawes.  Museums And The Marketplace: The Reality PrincipleFolder 265346626Revitalizing An Archaelogical Past:  A Museum Program For ChildrenFolder 275346727Do Children Learn On School Field TripsFolder 285346828Henry Field Museum - Greenfield Village Herald.  Vol. 12, # 1Folder 2953469198329ACTA Museorum Agriculturae PragaeFolder 3053470197930Scope and ContentsClayville InterpretersThe Broadwells of Clayville by Ed Hawes Part I &amp; IIFolder 315347131The Broadwells of Clayville and Their Roots. Part IIFolder 325347232Scope and ContentsFamily Land Dealings in IllinoisClayville Original Interpretive Plan by Ed HawesFolder 335347333Publication Series I, Living History Resources List # 5Folder 345347434Scope and ContentsMetal Trades and CraftsClayville Development, Physical Planning Evaluaion, Preliminary Cost EstimateFolder 3553475June 198235Clayville Student WorkersFolder 3653476199136Clayville Rural Life Center, General Interpretive Plan MASTER COPY. Folder 1Folder 375347737Clayville Rural Life Center, General Interpretive Plan MASTER COPY. Folder 2Folder 385347838Clayville Rural Life Center, General Interpretive PlanFolder 395347939Clayville Interpreters Notebook: Tools and CropsFolder 405348040Scope and ContentsSuch as Hemp, Corn, etc.; Manure, To Muck or Not to Muck; Field Crops; LumberBox 6Box 653481Foodways Material, Horseradish, - Food Common To Eastern Regional BackgroundFolder 1534821Scope and ContentsResearch On The Broadwells Foods, Foods At Festival TimesInterpreters: Food and FoodwaysFolder 2534832Food recipes - Pioneer Cooking. Food Preservation MaterialsFolder 3534843Foodways Programs At Living Historical Farms by Jay A. AndersonFolder 4534854Scope and ContentsFood and Kitchen; Utensils - 1850's; Educational Program Presentation - A Basic OutlineCheese Making.  Fireplace Cooking.  Food PreservationFolder 5534865Scope and ContentsMeat; Amadama Bread; Home Remedies; CosmeticsFoodways Support Material: Food PreservationFolder 6534876Scope and ContentsDouble Faced Character from Springfield DirectoryNotes on Gardening Research, Kristal Brazatis' ASTFolder 7534887Interpretive Notebook - Orchards and Fruit BushesFolder 8534898Interpretive Notebook - Master Copy, Gardening: 19th Century SourcesFolder 9534909Interpretive Notebook - Master Copy, Gardening: 19th Century SourcesFolder 105349110Vegetable Gardens at Clayville: 1850, Nothern and SouthernFolder 115349211Gardening Research: Corneau and Diller, DruggistsFolder 125349312On Practical Gardening in IllinoisFolder 135349413Scope and ContentsTransaction of the State Agriculture Society of 1857The Garden, Yard and Orchard from Amos LongFolder 145349514Scope and ContentsThe Pennsylvania German Family Farm.Herb Garden, Garden Research Project by Marilyn AndersonFolder 1553496198715Early American Life, Special House and Garden IssueFolder 165349716Recommendations for Clayville GardensFolder 175349817Scope and ContentsSource of Seeds, Flowers. Companion PlantingOnstat Family Material. A Tour Through North America by Patrick Shirreff, FarmerFolder 185349918Scope and ContentsSugar; New Salem's Original ArtifactsEuclid Broadwell, Interpretive MaterialFolder 1953500185019Wm. Broadwell, Interpretive MaterialFolder 2053501185020The Story of My Life by Captain George Baxter EveringhamFolder 215350221Scope and ContentsA Century of History - Galatia.  A Tale That Was ToldExhibit Material:  Lighting - Candle Making - LampsFolder 225350322Exhibits: Interpretive MediaFolder 235350423Exhibit Material: Wood - Self Interpretive Barn DisplayFolder 245350524Woods Exhibit: Roy Underhill photosFolder 255350625Exhibit: CabinFolder 265350726Exhibit: Photos and the Magazine Traveling ExhibitionsFolder 275350827Scope and ContentsAn Overview of Not For Profit Traveling Exhibition servicesExhibit: Pedlars and Pedlar DollsFolder 285350928Exhibit Material on Food Preparation and PreservationFolder 295351029Exhibit: Table Basics ResearchFolder 305351130Exhibits: Harness MakersFolder 315351231Menard and Cass County 1850 Census: Harness MakersFolder 325351332Education Program: Carpentry; Explanation and Census material of 1850'sFolder 335351433Scope and ContentsEssay, The Cooper's TradeEducation Program: BrickmakingFolder 345351534Education Program: BlacksmithsFolder 355351635Education Program:  Clayville Education Handbook, Part I and IIFolder 365351736Scope and Contentsby Ed Hawes and Kay MacLean.  Living History Farms Teachers GuideEducation Program CensusFolder 37535181991: Spring, Summer, Fall37Education Program:  Interpretive Plan Well Water And Its Uses by Mary LockhaiserFolder 385351938Scope and ContentsWater Sources, Letters To Teachers, Vocabulary ListEducation Program:  Research Item, The Washington Hand PressFolder 395352039Scope and ContentsInterpretive Plan, The Printshop.  Nineteenth  Century Printing.  Vocabulary For Printing.  Technical Terms Of The Printing Craft. (Grades K-8)Education Program: Interpretive Material, Using Newspaper Ads of the 1850'sFolder 405352140Scope and ContentsDecode Messages, Color the Boy Milking a Cow, Time Machine Essay and Worksheet.Education Program: Foot Prints to Color From the 1850'sFolder 415352241Scope and ContentsWord Circles, Word Search, Patchwork QuiltEducation Program: Match Items, Match Up Puzzle Pieces, Build A ScarecrowFolder 425352342Education Program: Cut and Paste the Kitchen at ClayvilleFolder 435352443Scope and ContentsPictures and Words, The InnInformation:  Pipes of Clay by Parker Melvin. Wooden PumpsFolder 445352544Research Items Not Covered In N.E.H.Plan:  What Newspaper Ads Tell UsFolder 455352645Scope and ContentsRural Trades And Occupations In Four Central Illinois Counties In 1850.  IndentureHistory Notes:  How To Understand the Place the Broadwell's BuiltFolder 465352746Scope and ContentsThe Broadwells of Clayville, by Ed Hawes.  Inns And Their Farms In The Central MidwestN.E.H. Research Projects.  Broadwells In Illinois. Broadwells In New Jersey.  Broadwells In OhioFolder 475352847Scope and ContentsProbated Estate Records. Inns In The Central Midwest: Layout And Functioning.Education and Interpretation Forms:  Discovery and 1850'sFolder 485352948Clayville Rural Life Center School Programs DescriptionFolder 495353049Form Letters To Teachers Concerning Education ProgramsFolder 505353150School Evaluations and LettersFolder 515353251History Notes:  Family Networks In Economic DevelopmentFolder 525353352Scope and ContentsIrwin Cemetery. Article On the Floating Museum At PeoriaHistory Note: Defining Typical Inns: Functions and Inventories. Licensing Of Inns, Taverns And HotelsFolder 535353453Box 7Box 753535Obernagel Cabin, file 1Folder 1535361Obernagel Cabin, file 2Folder 2535372Obernagel Cabin, file 3Folder 3535383Programs For Handicapped PeopleFolder 4535394Teachers' EvaluationsFolder 55354019875Teachers' EvaluationsFolder 65354119886Teachers' EvaluationsFolder 753542Spring 19897Scope and ContentsChildren's Notes1980 Contacts:  Made In IllinoisFolder 853543February 19888Scope and ContentsAspects. Crafts 'n Things, (Clayville Artifacts Photoed)Education Information:  The Broadwells' FarmsFolder 9535449Education Program Material, Childrens EvaluationsFolder 105354510Research Paper: Folk Traditions In Pottery and Painting, by Bernadine BarnesFolder 115354611Visitor Comments and Evaluations of Clayville. Visitor QuestionaireFolder 125354712AST report of Viginia Hosking, statistical and descriptive look at Clayville Education ProgramsFolder 1353548198713Copies of Old Photos: Victorian Women, Babies, George WashingtonFolder 145356514Proposal for a Living History and Museum Studies Cooperative ProgramFolder 155356615Scope and ContentsOn site SSU Classes. Library Resources For Living History. Museum Related Courses. Workshop In Rural Life.  Historic Crafts Workshop. Library Resources For Living 	History. Sowbelly and Seedbanks:  The Living History Museum as a Process Repository.  Wm Batts estate. Jan. 13, 1634.  Rural Life Studies and Living History.  Historic Clothing.  Midwest Rural Life and Its American Regional Background.HABS Report on the Fink houseFolder 165356716Scope and ContentsSmall Milk house Information.  Article on Ice Houses.Clayville MaintenanceFolder 1753568199117Clayville MaintenanceFolder 1853569199218Clayville Administrative MaterialFolder 195357019Clayville Maintenance Records, folder 1Folder 205357120Clayville Maintenance Records, folder 2Folder 215357221Clayville Physical Plant Operations, Plans, Procedures and Records, folder 1Folder 225357322Clayville Physical Plant Operations, Plans, Procedures and Records, folder 2Folder 235357423Clayville Maintenance TasksFolder 24535751986-8724Clayville Maintenance TasksFolder 25535761988-8925Clayville Site MaintenanceFolder 2653577198126Clayville Maintenance Guide For Program AssistantsFolder 275357827Clayville UtilitiesFolder 28535791989-9228Clayville Property Control, Various Years AuditsFolder 295358029Historic Methods Workshop, by Kathy MandusicFolder 305358130Historic Preservation, Some Topics and Resources by Ed HawesFolder 315358231Scope and ContentsHistoric Environmental Research for Historic Preservation and Re-Creation With Examples of Resources from "Local History"Publication Series II, Research Report # 5:Folder 325358332Scope and ContentsInns and Taverns in the Midwest: Typical 	Functions, Forms and LayoutsFarming: Northern Collection of Machines and Tools 1850. (Master)Folder 335358433Education Program Material: Clayville Newspaper Article. Conservation WorkshopFolder 345358534Sources For Printing Information, an AST ProjectFolder 3553586199035Teachers Evaluations of Clayville ProgramsFolder 3653587198636Letters From The Children of Franklin School, Jacksonville: Miss Ford's ClassFolder 3753588198737Teachers EvaluationsFolder 3853589Spring 199038Box 8Box 853590Historical Geography of the American Landscape Since 1880, by John JakleFolder 1535911Clayville Newspaper ClippingsFolder 2535922Inquiries about ClayvilleFolder 35359319873Inquiries about ClayvilleFolder 45359419884Inquiries about ClayvilleFolder 55359519895Scope and Contentsand Promotional MaterialInquiries about ClayvilleFolder 65359619906Inquiries about ClayvilleFolder 75359719917National Parks Service Curatoral Methods, folder # 1Folder 8535988National Parks Service Curatoral Methods, folder # 2Folder 9535999Music and Children's games:Folder 105360010Scope and ContentsAli Ali in Free...  The Games Children Played in Colonial America. Folksong In the Classroom.  Broadwide Songs and Ballads: The 	Irishman's Epistle. Paul Jones's Victory. The Tea Tax. The Pied Fifer of Bean-Town Otherwise Known as Mr. Paul Cole: Why He Makes Such Music On the Streets of Boston. The Yankees Return from Camp.  Southern Mountain Folk Tradition and the Folksong Stars Syndrome. Folk Songs of Illinois. Music of Mornings At Clayville: Blue Tail Fly, etc.Traditional Music of America by Ira W.FordFolder 115360111Music of the 1850's, folder # 1Folder 125360212Music of the 1850's, folder # 2Folder 135360313Music and Folk Song:Folder 145360414Scope and ContentsThe Archive of Folk Song. Saturday Gig, by Doug Weaver.  Folk Recordings, Selected From The Archive of Folk Song.  An Inventory of the Bibiliography and other Reference Aids Prepared by the Archive of Folk Song, Library of Congress. Annihilating the Hillbilly: The Appalalchians' Struggle with America's Institutions.  Resources of American Music History from the University of Illinois at Urbana- Champaign. Folk-Legacy Records, INC., A complete Listing. Time and the Flying Snow, Songs of Gordon Bok. A Selected Bibliography On American Folklore, Folksong, and Balladry Copliled by Margret Hagler.  The Society for Ethnomusicology. Greek Folk Music and Byzantine Hymns.  International Folk Music Council.Religious Folk and Folklike Music in AppalachiaFolder 155360515Music About Museums/Music about IllinoisFolder 16536061830-185016Scope and ContentsMusic of a Young Illinois by 	Mary Ellen Pourchot. Mississippi Folk Voices by William Ferris.  Playing, by Patti Martinez, about Charlotte Williams. The Colonial Instrument Maker by Barbara and Raymond Taylor.  living High on the Horn: The Music Business in New England in the 1840s, from Henry Ford Museum and Greenfield Village Herald. Musicmakers, by Patricia FaustIllinois History by Newspaper by Sangamon State History DepartmentFolder 175360717Old book with presidential time line to be used with the Broadwell familyFolder 185360818General Administration and Museum ProgramFolder 195360919Clayville PlanningFolder 205361020Clayville Visitor Center Project by Becca MoserFolder 215361121Personnel applicationsFolder 225361222Pearsons' NotesFolder 235361323Thompson RestorationFolder 245361424Minutes of Special meeting of the Board of Directors of Sangamon State University FoundationFolder 25536151973 - 1974 - 1990 - 199225Scope and ContentsLetter to Dick Lofgren from Donna Dagnall concerning the Removing Antiques from Clayville Site.  Magazine: Sangamon state University at 20Information on Estate Survey, Conservation, chairsFolder 265361626Letters. Part 1 of 2 foldersFolder 275361727Scope and ContentsLetter: Mr. John P. Clarke from Thomas L. Goins,12/4/75.  
Letter: same... 12/11/75.  
Letter: Robert Sherman from Earlene Young concerning Kitchen at Clayville.  
Letter: from Franklin G. Matzler to Dr. Robert Spencer concerning Clayville, 	11/21/75.  
Letter:  Tom Goins from Dave Smith, concerning agreement classroom agreement 	at Clayville, 11/26/75.  Agreement.  
Letter: Thomas Goins from George Hoffmann, Final Agreement from Hoffmann 	plus Resolution, 11/7/75.  
Copy of revised memo of agreement for final review by Dave Smith, 12/1/75. 
Original extension agreement, 6/19/75. 
Clayville Country Kitchen, August, 1975.  
Analysis of Clayville Center, 74 - 75.  
Meetings: 3/27/75, 4/29/75, 5/16/75.  
Letter: Robert Spencer from Earlene K. Young, 5/12/75, concerning state of 	Clayville Kitchen management.  
Letter: Asa Ruyle from Jim Duda, concerning Clayville Septic Tank, Water Pressure 	and Stove. 
Letter: Dr. Asa Ruyle from T. Roy Thomas, 4/9/75.  
Letter: Robert Spencer from Asa Ruyle, concerning operation of Clayville Country 	Kitchen and Projected Profit and Loss Statement for 1975, 3/24/75. 
Letter: John Doyle from Asa Ruyle, concerning Kitchen Funds.  Conference Seating 	Clayville Rural Life Center.  S.S.U. Foundation - Clayville Country Kitchen, 	Profit and Loss Statement, 10/74.  
Letter:  Mr. Benton Weathers from Larry Korte concerning Clayville and the Folk 	Arts Guild, 7/19/74.  
Letter: Ed Hawes from T. Roy Thomas concerning expenditures,12/20/74.  
Letter:  Mr. George Duewer from Robert Spencer concerning work completed 	getting ready for the Festival, 10/14/74. 
Letter: Emmet Pearson M.D. from Asa Ruyle, concerning five donations, 4/23/74.  
Letter: Earlene Young concerning labor and kitchen costs 7/18/74.  
Letter: Asa Ruyle from Bob Bojarzin concerning cost of Physical Plant Operations, 	6/16/74. 
 Letter: Richard Sims from Asa Ruyle concerning Clayville Liability Insurance, 	7/29.74.  
Letter: Larry Korte from George Hoffmann agreement with Clayville Folks Arts 	Guild, 7/8/74.  
Clayville Financial Report, Spring 1974.  
Letter: Robert Sherman from Margret concerning restrooms and toilet paper, 3/1/74. 
Clayville expenditures, 73.  
Letter: Larry Kort concerning Blue Grass Festival at Clayville, 5/14/74.  
Letter: Asa Ruyle from Larry Korte concerning Clayville equipment needs, 3/25/74. 
Letter: Jim Duda from Larry Korte concerning Septic System at Clayville, 4/18/74.  
Letter:  Asa Ruyle from Larry Korte concerning Clayville opening expenses for the 	year 1974. 
Letter: Asa Ruyle from Larry Korte concerning Clayville Equipment needs, 4/17/74. 
Letter: Larry Korte from Bob Sherman concerning wedding.  
Clayville Calendar of Events, 1974.  
Third Annual Spring Festival, 5/5 74 posters.  
Letter: Jim Duda from Larry Korte concerning Clayville Kitchen, 3/20/74.  
Letter: Jim Duda from Larry Korte concerning Clayville Safety, 3/20/74.  		
Memo: Spencer and Bd of Dirs. of Foundation from Asa Ruyle concerning 	Clayville, 3/15/74.
Lease Agreement for Clayville, 4/1/73.  
Letter: Dr. Asa Ruyle from Crabb and Handy Consultants for review and evaluation 	of Clayville facilities, 2/ 20/ 73.  
Lease agreement between SSU and Margy Emerson Filo.Letters. Part 2 of 2 foldersFolder 285361828Scope and ContentsMemo: Jim Duda from Dr. Ruyle concerning the opening of Clayville restaurant. 
Proposed labor and hours and expenses for Clayville restaurant.  
Fall Festival Summary.  
Letter: Asa from Ed Hawes concerning Clayville, evaluation of living History 	Program.  
Board of Regents voucher from Champion gas and oil, 12/27/73.  		
Memo: Ruyle from D.A. Stenson concerning Clayville Restaurant Operation, final 	closing 73.
Memo: SSU Office of Financial Aid, Notice of Termination, Roxanne McCloud and 	Lou Takacs, Jr. 11/21/ 73.   
Pkt. Official cash receipt.  
Memo:  Jim Duda from Bob Sherman concerning Maintenance at Clayville.  
Minutes of Clayville Guild Meeting with Foundation, 9/24/73.  		
Memo:  Asa Ruyle from Bob Sherman concerning attendance at Clayville, 9/11/73.  
Clayville Center Projected budget 5/15/73.  
Memo:  Robert Sherman from Vincent Chiaro concerning excessive hour under 	student employment 10/8/73.  
Memo:  Jim Duda from Bob Sherman concerning inventory of Furniture in the 	Security Trailer at Clayville, 10/8/73.  
Student employment form.  
Memo: Asa Ruyle concerning The Old Truck at Clayville, 9/24/73.  
Student Employment termination, Ann Conley, 9/25/73.  
Correspondence concerning lease of Chessie Railroad Property, 9/14/73. 
Memo: Prs. Spencer from Asa Ruyle concerning Loan from Foundation General 	fund to Pay bills at Clayville 8/23/73.  
Lease Agreement for Clayville by SSU Foundation and Board of Regents 9/1/73.  
Memo:  John Doyle from Larry Korte concerning student help, 8/16/73.  
Letter:  Asa Ruyle from Dr. Pearson concerning membership in Springfield Rotary 	Club, 8/9/73. 
Memo: President Spencer from Asa Ruyle concerning Projected Clayville Budget, 	7/27/73. 
Memo: Asa Ruyle from Larry Korte concerning Minutes from Weekly Clayville 	Status Report7/31/73.  
Memo:  President Spencer from Asa Ruyle concerning Clayville financial Status, 	8/15/73.  
Letter:  Walt Kesselman from Asa Ruyle concerning Clayville budget, 8/13/73.  	
Memo:  Asa Ruyle from R.W. Sherman concerning Clayville Restaurant Operation, 	6/4/73.
Various lease agreements, including Champion Oil Co. tank.  
Memo: John Doyle from Larry Korte concerning Clayville Agreements, 11/26/73.  
Memo: Dave Smith from Tom Goins concerning copies of Agreement between BOR and SSU Foundation, 12/21/75.  
Tax report for Clayville Country Kitchen, 4/22/76. 
Resolution on use of Clayville Rural Life Center as classrooms, Agreement,9/2/75.  
Letter: George Hoffmann from Thomas Goins concerning agreement on Clayville, 9/2/75.Record of DepositsFolder 2953619198829Clayville Profit and Loss StatementsFolder 305362030Clayville and SSU Foundation ContractFolder 315362131Clayville and SSU Foundation Transition Material, Folder 1 of 3Folder 325362232Clayville and SSU Foundation Transition Material, Folder 2 of 3Folder 335362333Clayville and SSU Foundation Transition Material, Folder 3 of 3Folder 345362434Box 9Box 953625Master Plan Planning MaterialFolder 1536261977 - 19821Elizabeth Weir's Slides of Clarys' Grove Log HouseFolder 2536272Clayville: Agriculture Exhibit Material /InformationFolder 3536283Interpreting Of Historic Sites for School ToursFolder 4536294Scope and ContentsHarrows, Plows, Knives and Grass, Garden Tools/Plows, Tools Through the AgesLiving History Farms, Des Moines, Iowa, Teachers GuideFolder 5536305Pleasant Plains, Study of the AreaFolder 6536316Clayville Calendars &amp; Collections PolicyFolder 7536321984, 1991, 19927Scope and ContentsClayville Calendars, 1991;  Clayville Collections Policy and Procedures Manual 1992, 	Clayville Collections Policy and Procedures Manual, 1984Renshaw, Wiley P.  Bill of SaleFolder 8536338Penny, Hiram  InventoryFolder 9536349Purvines, Samuel 10/2. Farm Size - Land HoldingsFolder 105363510Gaines, Richard - Farm InventoryFolder 115363611David Davis Mansion Volunteer ManualFolder 125363712Engineers Reports on Bridges, Buildings at ClayvilleFolder 135363813Thanks To: Letters by Elizabeth WeirFolder 145363914Grant Proposals by Debra QuickFolder 155364015Museum Barn PlansFolder 165364116Research File on Sheep ShedsFolder 175364217Log Cabins: Preservation and Problem-Solving.  Amor BattertonFolder 185364318Technical Preservation Services Reading ListFolder 195364419Obernagel Cabin (Freeburg, IL Site)Folder 205364520Field Notebook for Clarys' Grove (Gum Cabin)Folder 215364621Scope and ContentsOriginal Documents, papers and negatives of the Photographs are already on file in SSU Archives, these are Elizabeth Weir's.Clarey's Grove: Community Study ProjectFolder 225364722. Repair of Hessey Cabin, PhotosFolder 23536481990-9123Clarey's Grove Log Cabin with PicturesFolder 245364924Historic Structures - The Cabins and SmokehouseFolder 255365025Winkleman Smoke HouseFolder 265365126Field Notes for Winkleman Smokehouse - E. WeirFolder 2753652197627Mathew Rogers' House - Menard CountyFolder 285365328The Gum Log HouseFolder 295365429The Broadwell FamilyFolder 305365530Travelers Accounts 1830'sFolder 315365631Interpretive Training Schedule Forms/Files/PhonesFolder 3253657198432Requests for InformationFolder 3353658198633Interpretive Notes on Broadwell Barn ExperienceFolder 345365934Directory of Archival Collections and Research ResourcesFolder 355366035Clayville Articles in Farm Bureau Magazine, Antique Traders, Dubuque, IowaFolder 365366136Contracts for Site UseFolder 375366237Site UsageFolder 3853663198938Resource List on Over - Land, Railway and Water TransportationFolder 395366439Clayville Furniture: ConservationFolder 405366540Restoring Antique Furniture.  Household Furniture and Furniture MakersFolder 415366641Localized Environmental History,  In Search of the CoreFolder 425366742Boy Scout Project with picturesFolder 4353668198943Census Info form McDonough and Fulton CountyFolder 445366944Folk Art, Jay NathanFolder 455367045Patterns of the pastFolder 465367146Letters RE: Robert Scherman - Ability as a CuratorFolder 4753672197647Clayville 1980:  Program Plans andPoliciesFolder 485367348Interpretive Guidelines:  Inn Historic Area by Ed HawesFolder 495367449On the Preservation of Hessey/Batterton cabins: History Note:Folder 505367550Scope and ContentsRugs, Bugs and Feathers.  Formula for whitewash.Interpretive Training: Backwoods PreacherFolder 515367651Education Program:  The Broadwells' Farms 1850Folder 525367752Box 10Box 1053678Site Calendar, folder 1Folder 15367919791Site Calendar, folder 2Folder 25368019792Site Calendar, folder 1Folder 35368119803Site Calendar, folder 2Folder 45368219804Site Calendar, folder 3Folder 55368719805Site Calendar, folder 1Folder 65368319816Site Calendar, folder 2Folder 75368419817Site Calendar, folder 1Folder 85368519828Site Calendar, folder 2Folder 95368619829Site Calendar, folder 3Folder 1053688198210Proposal: A Rural Life Center At ClayvilleFolder 1153689November 197211Clayville, Historic OverviewFolder 1253690September 197812Consultants' Report, 1st PanelFolder 1353691198013CalendarFolder 1453692August/September 197914Clayville Rural Life Center  It's First Two YearsFolder 155369315Clayville Pilot Interpretive PlanFolder 1653694198116Ruth Truett, Evaluation of Clayville Fall FestivalFolder 175369517Consultants Report, 1981.Folder 185369618Consultants Report, 1981.  Evaluation.Folder 195369719Clayville Master Plan - President's Circulation CopyFolder 205369820Preliminary Master Plan with Prospectus Prepared by E.L. Hawes, 7/ 76Folder 215369921Clayville Rural Life Center Pilot Interpretive PlanFolder 225370022Master Plan for Interpretation and DevelopmentFolder 235370123Clayville Rural Life Center - OverviewFolder 245370224Preservation of Clayville SiteFolder 255370325Visitors SurveyFolder 2653704198926Box 11Box 1153705Site AttendanceFolder 15370619751Site VisitationFolder 25370719852Site UsageFolder 35370819833Office Procedure for Hiring Student Workers and Training materialFolder 4537094Soap Drainage trough, Item # 22968, SSUFolder 5537105Insurance CoverageFolder 6537111979-846Student WorkersFolder 7537121987-887FY '92 SSU/ Foundation Contract - 82Folder 8537138SSU Foundation: Retirement of George StoneFolder 95371419909Clayville Misinformation MattersFolder 105371510Research Using Probate RecordsFolder 115371611SSU Lincoln Depot File II Part AFolder 125371712SSU Lincoln Depot File II Part BFolder 135371813Clayville Master Plan - Long Range and PreliminaryFolder 145371914Clayville Prospectus, Appendix IV, Operation PlansFolder 155372015Photo Masters and InformationFolder 165372116N.E.H. GrantFolder 1753722198017N.E.H. Master Plan and Planning PacketFolder 185372318N.E.H. Grant Planning Packet, 1 of 3Folder 195372419N.E.H. Grant Planning Packet, 2 of 3Folder 205372520N.E.H. Grant Planning Packet, 3 of 3Folder 215372621N.E.H. StudyFolder 2253727198122Site Usage and Geographical DistributionFolder 23537281978-8323Geographical Distribution of VisitorsFolder 2453729198024Clayville LeaseFolder 255373025Clayville AdvertisingFolder 265373126Clayville Committee: Request To foundation for Funds for Rebuilding StairsFolder 275373227Friends of ClayvilleFolder 285373328Clayville Land acquisitionFolder 295373429CorrespondenceFolder 30537351980-8130Scope and ContentsN.E.H. GrantMenard County History - Do You Know? Petersburg ObserverFolder 315373631Menard County Environment - Clary's GroveFolder 325373732Education Program:  Gum, Jesse (Cabin), Tallula Rural SiteFolder 335373833CorrespondenceFolder 345373934Scope and ContentsCorrespondence about Strawbridge - Shepherd House, ca 1845.  Schools: Schanbacher 	Offer 1982-.  Ripley Cabin: Charles Teel 1966Clayville BudgetFolder 3553740197835Education Program: Brickenridge Homestead 1876 Plat bookFolder 365374136Education Programs: Douglas, J.R. - Homestead 1876 PlatBookFolder 375374237History Notes: Rugs, Bugs and FeathersFolder 385374338Scope and ContentsTextiles in the Home,  Window Curtains 1848-52,  Filaments of FlaxInterpreters Notes Readings on Interpretation, a DigestFolder 395374439Scope and ContentsSun, Wind, and Climate Control and The Broadwell InnTeachers WorkshopsFolder 4053745197740Scope and ContentsEducation Program Mailing 1979. School Directories 1980-87.  Mornings At ClayvilleTime/Place - USA 1845-1855 Chronology, IllinoisFolder 41537461796-186341Education Program, History Note.  Potter: Interpretive Guidelines.Folder 425374742Scope and ContentsPainting and Prints in the Inn. Broadwells As a Typical Entrepreneurial Family. Foodways Excercise.  Bibliography of Sigh Painting and Decorative Arts of the 19th Century. Holidays or Special Meals. Blacksmithing in Sangamon Co. 1850-1870.  The Ethnogastromy of 	Thanksgiving.Newspaper Program - MastersFolder 435374843Museums and Agriculture in the 1980'sFolder 445374944Education Programs.  Site Usage.  VisitationFolder 4553750198345Clayville Schoolgroups-Attendance-Geographical DistributionFolder 46537511977 to 198246Holiday Notes and Bibliography with copies of EngravingsFolder 475375247Scope and ContentsChristmas at Clayville. Christmas Cookie RecipesBox 12Box 1253753Bee Keeping Management.  Maple SyrupingFolder 1537541P.A.C. Class Environmental Issues/MuseumsFolder 2537552Photography In the 1850's - Daguerreotypes.  The Spirit of the FactFolder 3537563Letters of Support To ClayvilleFolder 4537574Determining Functions of Inns Through Material CultureFolder 5537585Signs for Interpretive Events for Saturday and SundayFolder 6537596Soapmaking and Cleaning Furniture InformationFolder 7537617Prairie Farmer Articles on Farming, Crops, Care of LivestockFolder 8537628Fence Research Material.  Nail researchFolder 9537639Scope and ContentsIllinois Fence Laws by H. W. Hannah.  Date-	Nail Handbook and Price List by Robert L. Doud. History Note: Fencing In The 19th Century. Making Wattle and Other Portable Fences. Fencing - Rail - Zig zag - 	Menard County. Fencing File. Typical Farm enclosures, 1840 - 1870 by Gail Eck.  A Farm To Be Sold. The Stake and Rider Fence by Robert Steele Withers.  Collecting Old Barb Wire by Berkley McCollum. Preliminary Research Report:  Fencing. Our Homes by T.McWhorter, of Millersburg, Illinois. Fencing by Ed Hawes. When Good Fences Made Good Neighbors by John W. Voigt.  Illinois As 	It Is by Fred Gerhard. Essays on Hedging with Osage Orange. On Raising Horses 	and Mules. Grain, Grass and Stock in Central Illinois.Crafts and Trades In Sangamon County. Abstract of Industrial Census of Rural Sangamon County. 1850Folder 105376410School RequestFolder 1153765Spring 1979 - 198111Scope and ContentsMornings At Clayville and Teachers 	Workshops.Clayville Prospectus - Revised DraftFolder 1253760197612Types of Paint and Painters of Sangamon County, 1850'sFolder 135376613Midwest Rural Life and Its Roots - SyllabusFolder 1453767198414Clayville: Brick Ovens, Plans, Drawings, Articles.Folder 155376815Scope and ContentsConstructing An Early Fireplace And Bake Oven. Starting A Fire In a Brick Bake Oven by Micheal C. TurpakDepartment Of CorrectionsFolder 1653769199116Museum Historic Site MethodsFolder 175379817Historical Agriculture and MuseumsFolder 185379918Scope and ContentsLiving Historical Farms, Villages and Museums in the United States and Canada. Historical Agriculture At Old Sturbridge Village by Alan J. Krauss.Early Churches In Menard County by Doris D. NoblesFolder 195380019Scope and ContentsCorrespondence of Jeffery E. Allen to Elizabeth Weir concerning Peter CartwrightSale of Property of Wm. K. Broadwell, 1851.  Will of Moses BroadwellFolder 205380120Estate Sale of Baxter BroadwellFolder 2153802183321Clayville Country Kitchen restaurantFolder 225380322Scope and ContentsCorrespondence between Dr. Pearson and SSUEducation Program: Estate Records as Primary Sources and Appraisals. Tomlin, AlmarinFolder 235380423The Clayville Table Research Project by Brian AlexanderFolder 245380524Broom Corn:  Planting, Harvesting, and Curing InstructionsFolder 255380625Clayville Music and Storytelling FestivalFolder 2653807199026Lincoln and the Broadwells:  from Lincoln Day by DayFolder 275380827The Axe and the Pot, workshop - Ed HawesFolder 285380928Illiniwek, vol.5. #1Folder 2953810January/February 196729Scope and Contentsfeaturing Clayville Folk Arts FestivalClayville: Water Test by Dr. Pearson.  Energy Survey at ClayvilleFolder 305381130Excerpts From Illinois Journal concerning ClayvilleFolder 315381231Visitors to the Broadwell KitchenFolder 325381332General Information in the Clayville AreaFolder 335381433House Reading:  How to Study Historic Houses from History NewsFolder 345381534Glass Marbles:  German Spirals or Candy StripesFolder 355381635Presentation by Elizabeth Weir:  Macon County Conservation DistrictFolder 365381736Applicants for Helping Conduct Mornings At ClayvilleFolder 375381837Conservation: TextilesFolder 385381938Scope and ContentsAlso: Fiber from Wool/Flax. A Book of Hand Woven Coverlets. Carpeting Research. Articles on Fabrics for Historic Buildings. The Swift.Historic Furnishings:  Bedding In the 1850'sFolder 395382039Research Papers:  A Tentative Relocation and Some Aspects of Possible Farms in Clayville Vicinity 1850Folder 405382140Scope and ContentsA Look at Farms of N.M. Butler and G.M. Smith. Mid 19th Century Farm Houses and Farms. Popular Literature of the 1850'sM.O.M.C.C. Conference Schedule. MeetingsFolder 415382241School Ed Programs, Touring and Mornings At ClayvilleFolder 4253823197942Arkansas Mid-American Center, Hot Springs, Arkansas:  Please DO TouchFolder 435382443Life in the 1850'sFolder 4453825Spring and Summer 197844Movie Articles:  Awakening Land and ChisholmsFolder 455382645Clayville Staff TripsFolder 465382746Correspondence from Anne DennisFolder 475382847Scope and Contentsincluding newspaper article History Lesson, 1812 Homestead teaches Pioneer ValuesRequests for InformationFolder 48538291978-8348Interpretive Material:  Broadwells in Illinois, Broadwells in Ohio, Broadwells in New 	JerseyFolder 495383049Scope and ContentsOriginal Land Purchases. Historic Landscape. Leather Tanning. Irwin, 	Elijah Iles Personal Account Book, History Notebook: Tavern License, Sangamon County, Tavern Keepers Bond. Architecture of Inns in Illinois.Association of Living Historical FarmsFolder 505383150Prairie restorationFolder 515383251Coal Mining Unions in IllinoisFolder 525383352Chicago Tribune ArticleFolder 5353834197053Scope and ContentsLetters Written in ResponseIn the Smithsonian:  Horse Drawn VehiclesFolder 545383554Clothing Workshop. Correspondence with Ed Hawes from Maud Margret LyonFolder 555383655Interpreters Notes:  Hand SewingFolder 565383756Historic Clothing - Day Cap PatternsFolder 575383857Interpreters Notes:  Textiles.  How to Make A ShirtFolder 585383958Workshop ManagementFolder 5953840197859Clayville School Education Material: Guidelines for TeachersFolder 60538411978, 198860Scope and Contentsletter - 1988Box 13Box 1353842Music Festival and Festival InformationFolder 1538431Foundation AccountsFolder 25384419802Sangamon River Basin Project and Various Grant ProposalsFolder 3538453Clayville - Policies and ProceduresFolder 4538464Site Interpretations material in the Early StagesFolder 5538475Progress of Clayville by Business and Administration ServicesFolder 6538486Evaluation of Ed Hawes, by Tom GoinsFolder 75384919807Site DevelopmentFolder 8538508Menard County Inn on the National RegisterFolder 9538519Scope and ContentsBridges &amp; Culverts and Bridge at ClayvilleClayville Fourth of July and Christmas FestivalFolder 105385210Clayville Operations ReportsFolder 11538531982-8311Log Cabin ConservationFolder 125385412Clayville Consultants' ReportFolder 135385513Sue Dezendolet, V.P.A.A.Folder 145385614Alumni Association, SSU FoundationFolder 155385715SSU Foundation - Clayville CommitteeFolder 16538581984-8516Dr. SpencerFolder 175385917Clayville/Pearson'sFolder 185386018Clayville Highway Signage - DOTFolder 195386119Clayville Calendar MaterialFolder 2053862198420Clayville Guild Membership Canvass and GoalsFolder 2153863198121Clayville Rural Life Center Master Plan and Subsequent MaterialFolder 225386422Registration Policies and Correspondence and Mission StatementFolder 235386523Clayville General correspondence, Folder 1Folder 24538661975-198024Clayville General Correspondence, Folder 2Folder 255386725Operations/Project Reports, Registration Procedures, Registration ReportsFolder 2653868198026Clayville Porch construction NegotiationsFolder 275386927Regarding Water line From City of Pleasant PlainsFolder 285387028Fundraising and Contract AgreementsFolder 295387129Foundation/ClayvilleFolder 3053872197030Clayville Folk Arts GuildFolder 3153873197431Project ReportsFolder 3253874197932Box 14Box 1453875Master Copies for Children's Discovery TourFolder 1538761Mornings At Clayville Orientation GuideFolder 2538772Clayville Educational MaterialFolder 3538783Appreciation Correspondence from School ChildrenFolder 4538794Various Inquiries and Communications to ClayvilleFolder 5538805Clayville Barn ProjectFolder 6538816Labels for a Wheelwright ExhibitFolder 7538827European CorrespondenceFolder 8538838Clayville FestivalsFolder 95388419869Clayville FestivalsFolder 1053885198510Concerning Euclid Broadwell, John Broadwell, William BroadwellFolder 1153886183011Concerning the William/Cynthia Carson FamilyFolder 1253887185012Concerning David Broadwell, Charles BroadwellFolder 135388813Music FestivalFolder 1453889199114Documentation on Some ArtifactsFolder 155389015Thematic Education ProgramsFolder 165389116Clayville Classroom IdeasFolder 1753892197417Living History InterpretationFolder 185389318Toys: Student Papers, ClayvilleFolder 195389419Guild PhotosFolder 205389520Clayville FestivalsFolder 2153896198721Geographical Distribution of VisitorsFolder 2253897199122Interpretive Materials: The Broadwells In IllinoisFolder 235389823Jane Broadwell, Deceased, Sangamon County Probate RecordsFolder 245389924Interpretive Material: The Broadwells in New Jersey and OhioFolder 255390025Some Personal Recollections of Peter Cartwright by William EplerFolder 265390126Probate Records of Moses Broadwell, Sarah and William K.Folder 275390227Notations Concerning Statement of Emory Q. IrwinFolder 285390328Interpretive Training Notes: Probated Estate RecordsFolder 295390429Material on Broadwells and Peter CartwrightFolder 305390530Interesting Things Collected by Dr. PearsonFolder 315390631Dr. Pearson MemorabiliaFolder 325390732Scope and ContentsJournal Register, Illiniwek, St. Louis Post Dispatch...Iowa Living History Farms Interpretive MaterialFolder 335390833Photo Negative Files of ClayvilleFolder 345390934HABS Material and Photos on the Dr. Fink HouseFolder 355391035Recruitment - Ed HawesFolder 365391136Correspondence: Dr. PearsonFolder 375391237Clayville Program reviewFolder 38539131980-8138Photography, Negatives, etc.Folder 395391439Sangamon People Exhibit Prepared by Judy MeyerdierksFolder 40539151981-8240Scope and ContentsAn Exhibit Proposed to N.E.H.Box 15Box 1553916Clayville - ConfidentialFolder 1539171Scope and ContentsRe. Land Acquisition; Relations With Folk Arts Guild, Hawes Role; Operating Budget; etc.Clayville Reports, Folder 1Folder 2539181978-79-802Clayville Reports, Folder 2Folder 3539191978-79-803Clayville Reports, Folder 3Folder 4539201978-79-804Clayville - Space Usage, Plan, RecommendationsFolder 5539215ClayvilleFolder 6539221973-766Ed Programs: Guild Brochures &amp; 1985 CalendarFolder 7539237Concerning Guttering on the Inn at ClayvilleFolder 8539248President Long's Memo to Dr. Robert Crane, concerning the mission statement of ClayvilleFolder 9539251985/09/249Scope and ContentsCrane's answer and copy of the Clayville Rural Life Center Master PlanDescription of Clayville School Programs:Folder 105392610Scope and ContentsMornings At Clayville. Discovery Tours. And Life In The 1850'sClayville Grant Application MaterialFolder 11539271981-8511Clayville Newspaper Articles and Correspondence from Ed HawesFolder 125392812News Releases Concerning ClayvilleFolder 1353929198113Clayville Abstract of TitleFolder 145393014Merle Baker Letter concerning the donation of a chairFolder 1553931198715Book about Children's Games with MarblesFolder 16539321800s16Clayville Budget - file 1Folder 1753933197317Scope and ContentsFoundation Report, Treasurer Report, Clayville Country KitchenThe Natural Environment:Folder 185393418Scope and ContentsThe Western Journal of Medicine and Surgery, March 1845.  Animal Communities Of An Illinois Prairie by N.W.Shackleford.  The Vegetational History Of The Middle West by Henry Allan Gleason. Some Features Of Early Woodland And Prairie Settlement In A Central Iowa County. Botanical Features of the Prairies of Illinois in Ante-Railroad Days by Richard Woldemar Hilgard. Traveling In Illinois In 1819 by Ferdinand Ernst. Files Headings: Climate. Tree Cultivation. Native Trees. Prairies. Engleman. Hilgard. Soils.Inns and Their Farms in the Central Midwest:Folder 195393519Scope and ContentsToward an Interpretation of Farmstead Functions. Pub. Series 2, Research Report # 5:  Inns and Taverns In The Midwest:  Typical functions, Forms and Layouts, by Melinda Kwedar &amp; Ed Hawes. Rural Taverns, Part II.Broadwells and Their Roots.  The Roots In Ohio and New JerseyFolder 205393620Rural Resource List:Folder 215393721Scope and Contents# 12. Inns and Hotels in the Midwest.  #13.  Farming and Innkeeping in the Midwest to 1860. Historic Landscapes: Research and 	Preservation.Clayville Area Voting List for 1830sFolder 225393822Clayville Dinner Theater Articles and AdsFolder 235393923Correspondence, Requests of Clayville for Information, etc.Folder 245394024The Broadwells of Clayville and their Roots:Folder 255394125Scope and ContentsPart II, Family Land Dealings in IllinoisThe Broadwells of Clayville and Their Roots:Folder 265394226Scope and ContentsThe Antecedents of the Inn/Farmhouse in Ohio and New JerseyPilot Interpretive Plan For The Broadwell Inn/Farmhouse and Related Cultural LandscapeFolder 275394327Rural Trades and Businesses in Central Illinois in 1850: A Compilation of Census DataFolder 285394428Interpretive Materials:  Clayville Area in 1874Folder 295394529Moses Broadwell:  Probated Estate RecordsFolder 305394630Scope and ContentsNewspaper Ads for Almost everythingChildren's Letters to Clayville, folder 1Folder 315394731Children's Letters to Clayville, folder 2Folder 325394832Children's Letters to Clayville, folder 3Folder 335394933Children's Letters to Clayville, folder 4Folder 345395034Children's Letters to Clayville, folder 5Folder 355395135Localized Environmental History:  The Clayville Case, by Ed HawesFolder 365395236Box 16Box 1653953Ed Programs:  Photos, Bingham, C. - ElectionFolder 1539541Education: Historic Preservation, Restoring an Old HouseFolder 2539552Scope and ContentsSaving Ourselves: Our Rural Heritage. Illinois Architecture, Revolution on the Prairies.  Historic Preservation In Maine. A bibliography of Historic Preservation.  Magazine: Historic Preservation, April 1984.Ed Program:  1894 Sangamon County Plat book - Cartwright TownshipFolder 3539563Ed Program:  Prognostics Of The WeatherFolder 4539574Ed Program:  Advice To Children On Behavior At TableFolder 5539585Scope and ContentsFrom Farmers' Museum, Cooperstown, New YorkEd Program:  Prairie Farmer.  1848 AlmanacFolder 6539596Ed Program:  Photos, Homer, W. - ClassroomFolder 7539607Ed Program:  1855-56 Hall's Springfield City Directory and Sangamon County Advertiser:Folder 8539618Scope and ContentsAbraham Lincoln's Springfield - The First Printed Map Of Springfield, Illinois.Ed Program:  James L. Belden Offers For Sale, (seeds).Folder 9539629Ed Program:  Bingham, George - Riverboat photoFolder 105396310Ed Program:  1876 Plat book, Sangamon County, Cartwright TownshipFolder 115396411Ed Program:  1850 State Journal RegisterFolder 125396512Clayville Rural Life Publication Series, Brochures, Menus, Workshops, etc.Folder 135396613Master Copy of Pub. Series IIFolder 145396714Scope and ContentsResearch Report # 8:  Midwest Foodways and their RootsMaster Copy of Publication Series #II.  Research Report # 6, N.E.H.Folder 155396815Master Copy of The Broadwells of Clayville and Their RootsFolder 165396916Master Copy of Publication Series I, Living History Resource Lists:Folder 175397017Scope and Contents#1.  General technology:  The Midwest and Its Roots. #3. Textiles and textile Crafts. #10. Garden Seeds for The 1850's. #11. Museum and Historic Preservation MethodsMaster Copy - Part II - Family Land Dealings in IllinoisFolder 185397118Twentieth Century Homesteading Bibliograpy, 3rd EditionFolder 195397219Correspondence concerning Bradfordton signFolder 205397320Hawes Report:  Clayville...Preserving the Heritage of Change - School ProgramsFolder 215397421Masters Copy:  N.E.H. History NotesFolder 225397522Illinois General Stores, 1825-1845, a BibliographyFolder 235397623Object research.  (Palm Hats)Folder 245397724Categories of Store GoodsFolder 255397825Clayville and the C.E.T.A. Program.Folder 265397926Girl Scouts at ClayvilleFolder 2753980Saturday, October 18th, 198027AttendanceFolder 2853981197528Summer GroupsFolder 2953982197929River City Restorations/Preservation ProgramFolder 305398330Attendance ReportsFolder 31539841979-8131Receipts/DepositsFolder 3253985197932Visitor CountFolder 33539861978-7933Clayville Guild Posters and ProgramsFolder 345398734Box 17Box 1753988Festival Brochures and news clippingsFolder 1539891972-921SSU/Guild ContractsFolder 2539901988-912Spring Ed ProgramsFolder 35399119903Spring Festival PlansFolder 45399219924Festival Newspaper Clipping and PostersFolder 5539935Folk Art BrochuresFolder 6539946SSU Student employment Forms and Orientation MaterialFolder 7539957Personal Interpreter's Notebook, by Ed HawesFolder 8539968General Administration and Museum ProgramsFolder 9539979Pioneer Farming in IndianaFolder 105399810Scope and ContentsThomas Lincoln's Major Crops, 1816-1830, by Henry G. 	WaltmanIllustrated Handbook of Venacular Architectur by R.W. BrunskillFolder 115399911Mid-Ninteenth Century Prairie Farm HousesFolder 125400012Inquiries for 1979, Also Other Communication thru 1989Folder 135400113Illinois Rural Survey ManualFolder 1454002198714Clayville in 1980 a Report. Clayville at Close of Phase IV,1988Folder 155400315Clayville Craft:  Brickmaking InformationFolder 165400416The WhigFolder 17540051978-7917Media Coverage of the SiteFolder 1854006198918State Journal Register Articles About Illinois State Historical Society "Taking Over 	ClayvilleFolder 19540071987-198919Scope and ContentsState Journal Register articles: Encourage Donations To Museums in 1991. Agriculture Sees Benefit from Public Use Trust ActThe Clayville Education Handbook Part IFolder 205400820Scope and ContentsSome Useful History and Description of the 	Programs. Clayville School Programs:  1. The Discovery Tour.  II. Life In the 1850's.  III.Mornings at Clayville. Interpretation and EducationInternship Project Submitted for M.A. Degree by H. Robert Wilcox, Jr.Folder 215400921Bullock,Historic Restoration After Completion. Maintenance of the Restored BuildingFolder 225401022Meat Preservation and SmokehousesFolder 235401123Railroad Right of Way/ BrandtsFolder 245401224Requests for Ed. ProgramsFolder 2554013199225Clayville Photos Used in Magazines:  Made in Illinois and Crafts 'n ThingsFolder 265401426Workshop on Clayville:  Broadwells and Their RootsFolder 275401527Press Coverage of the Closing of ClayvilleFolder 2854016199228Interpretive Material on Clayville and BroadwellsFolder 295401729Education Program EvaluationsFolder 3054018Fall 199130Scope and ContentsList of School Participants, 1850sEducational Evaluations - DiscoveryFolder 3154019Spring 199131Educational Evaluations - DiscoveryFolder 3254020Fall 199132Clayville:  Articles about the Resident Craft StudiosFolder 335402133The House Book: A Manual of Domestic Economy, by Miss Leslie, folder 1Folder 3454022184434The House Book: A Manual of Domestic Economy, by Miss Leslie, folder 2Folder 3554023184435Ed. Information:  TinsmithingFolder 365402436Ed. Information: PewterersFolder 375402537Ed. Information: Paints and PaintingFolder 385402638Scope and ContentsTypes of Paint and Painters of Sangamon County in the 1850's. Paint Ads: Harrison Bros.&amp; Co. Town And Country with information. The American Life Foundation Study Institute, Edward Hazen's Panorama of Victorian Trades &amp; Professions. The Forgotten Arts:  Making Paints From ScratchResearch Reference:  PlowmakersFolder 395402739Exhibit Material:  Wagons - WheelwrightingFolder 405402840Ed. Information:  ShoemakingFolder 415402941Ed. Information: PrintingFolder 425403042Scope and ContentsThe Printer in Eighteenth-Century Williamsburg, An Account of His LIfe &amp; Times, and of his Craft. Word List of Printing Terms. Tasks in the Print Shop. The Story of the Alphabet.  A Specimen of Printing Types.  Clayville Stage Coach Stop, poem, author Unknown. Chicago: Interstate Publishing company, 1881: History of Sangamon County. Colonial Women Journalists by 	Robert U. Brown. Interpreting the PrintShop, from Mornings At Clayville.Education:  Harnessmakers and Saddlers, Springfield 1850s, some sourcesFolder 435403143Scope and ContentsAn Autobiography, by Edmund C. Vancil, copied from the Girard Gazette of May 15, 1890.Education:  Prairie Flowers, photos by Elizabeth WeirFolder 445403244Ed Programs:  School NotebooksFolder 455403345Clayville Library:   Universal Restoration of Man published by J. Broadwell, CincinnatiFolder 465403446Master copy:  Census data, Rural Trades and BusinessesFolder 475403547Student Farming Papers - Krauss, Ohare, WaittrobikFolder 485403648Interpreters Notebook - Traders Crafts:  BlacksmithingFolder 495403749Guild Meeting NotesFolder 505403850Interpretive Notebook - Farm:  Livestock.  Circular, by John S. HowardFolder 515403951Scope and ContentsAd: By John Deere for various types of Plows, Cultivators, Harrows and Ox-yokes. Interpretive Notebook with categories of General, Horses, Cattle, Sheep, Hogs, ChickensInterpretive Notebook: Farm Structures and Layout, Folder 1Folder 525404052Scope and ContentsFarm Layout, Farmstead, Houses, Barns, Smokehouses, Other, FencingBox 18Box 1854041Interpreters Notebook - Master File:  Social Background and ForegroundFolder 1540421Scope and ContentsInterpreters Notebook - Master File:  Social Background and Foreground.  A Discussion of Three Religions Which Influenced The Culture of the Midwest by Nancy Costello.  Local Government in Sangamon County, 1821-1861, A Short Bibliography by Siebert.  Care of Indigent, Handicapped and Insane to 1860, A Short Bibliography. Excerpt from History of Sangamon County. Proceedings of the 	Convention For the Organization of a State Agricultural Society. Transactions of the 	Illinois State Agricultural Society, Report of the Executive Committee for 1853-54. History of Sangamon county, Chapter XXV, Agriculture and Agricultural 	Societies.  Nineteenth Century Methodism in Illinois, A Methodological Essay (or The Incomplete Methodism by S.V. Siebert. American Women in Mid-Nineteenth 	Century Society, by Brenda Capranica. An Investigation of Early Textile and other 	Crafts and Skills in De Witt County, Illinois 1820-1860, by Edna Hildreth Rau. The 	Great Exposition.Original Inventory:  Very Important Collection Material, folder 2Folder 2540432Scope and ContentsInventory April '73. Exhibits, '75. Inventory, March '78.  Policy and Procedure RE. Removals. Audit Report, March 9, '79. Mary Pearson List.Historic Preservation and Conservation. Lumber in 19th Century Illinois by Ted SullivanFolder 3540443Scope and ContentsCorrespondence of Ed Hawes. Historic American Engineering Record List of Publications. The Prairie Farmer Articles on: Salt for Preserving Posts. A Cheap Paint. Composition Roofs. Hydraulic Cement (Water Lime) by Fames Clark. Our Agricultural Societies. Poll Evil. Cure for Rattlesnake Bites. Root and Bush Puller. Wetting Bricks. To Stop Bees From Fighting. Borers and Cankers Worms.  Log Structure Preservation At Conner Prairie Settlement In Indiana.  Clayville Tavern Restoration by Eldridge Pendleton. Barns by Bill Smith. Prairie Farmer Plan of Barn Basement.Clayville Interpretive Notebook, Farming:Folder 4540454Scope and ContentsCrops, Tools. Farming, Plowing, Planting, 	Cultivation, Harvest, Corn, Grains, Other CropsCollections:  Interviews with Mary Pearson on Their HistoryFolder 5540465Prior Archaeology at Clayville Wells: Photos, Newspaper articles, Educational Packet on Mid-nineteenth Century WellsFolder 6540476Scope and ContentsPrairie Farmer on Wells, Mid-nineteenth Century Wells in Central Illinois and the Clayville Archaeological Evidence by Mary 	Lokhaiser.  Water-Witching in Central Illinois by Warren S. Walker.  Wells and 	Cisterns as a Source of Supply.Clayville Pictorial Inventory, Part I, folder 1Folder 7540487Clayville Pictorial Inventory, Part I, folder 2Folder 8540498Clayville Appointment CalendarFolder 95405019779Clayville Appointment CalendarFolder 1054051197910Clayville Appointment CalendarFolder 1154052198011Clayville Appointment CalendarFolder 12540531981-8212Clayville Appointment CalendarFolder 13540541983-8413Clayville Appointment CalendarFolder 1454055199114Clayville Workshops:Folder 155405615Scope and ContentsLeatherwork, Blacksmith, Bargello, Quilling, Tinsmith, Wheatweaving, Counted Thread, Rug Hooking, Chaircaning, Costume MakingFree Publications from Clayville Research:Folder 165405716Scope and ContentsGeneral technology, Local Resources, Textiles, Wood Crafts, Metal, Food, Garden Seeds, Museums and Preservation, Inn, Tavern Hotels, Farming and Inns, Historic Landscapes, Trades and Professions, Land Research, Midwest foodways, Clayville Traditions, ChristmasGirl Scouts of America, Special Tour GroupsFolder 1754058198217Income From visitorsFolder 1854059198818The Association for Living Historical Farms and Ag MuseumsFolder 1954060198319Scope and ContentsHistorical Reproduction and Replica Source ListA Feasibility Study for the Historic Clayville Stage Coach StopFolder 2054061March 197320Report on the Planning Group on A Rural Life Center and Living Historical FarmFolder 2154062April 197221Guidelines for Land AcquisitionFolder 225406322Report on Household and Farm Implements.  Farm Tools Through the AgesFolder 235406423Student Report on Wood, by Ted SchullerFolder 245406524Insects:  Hessian Fly, Honey Bee, Lady Bug, SilkwormFolder 255406625A Tentative Relocation and some Aspects of possible Farms in Clayville VicinityFolder 2654067185026Research Report:  Correspondents to the Prairie FarmerFolder 27540681843-185527Plates, English Blue.  Engineers Report on Porch RestorationFolder 285406928Class Reports- History 409 by Roy UnderhillFolder 295407029Research Tidbits, History Notes by Linda Oelheim:Folder 305407130Scope and ContentsThe Inn, Gardens, Broadwells, Textiles, Farming, Landscape, Trades, Social/ economies, ResourcesStudent Papers - Broommaking, Ag &amp; Ag SocietiesFolder 315407231Scope and ContentsTypes of Paints and Papers of Sangamon County. Project Notes. Flowers as FoodSangamon County HogsFolder 32540731830-186032Furniture Making in Springfield and Sangamon CountyFolder 335407433Midwest Women's Clothing of 1850, by Doris KrakeFolder 345407534Student Papers on FencingFolder 355407635Movie:  Warner Bros. Awakening Land  -  The Chisholm'sFolder 365407736Estate Records/Will of Thomas Gum and wifeFolder 375407837Scope and ContentsNotes on Probate of Jessie F. Gum. Green Family RecordsJesse Gum - Inventory Records and Tax RecordsFolder 385407938M.F. Sheller:  Environment.  HousingFolder 395408039

