<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>O.W673Archon Finding Aid Title O.W673UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:23:19 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    Williams, James D. b. 1914: Memoir
    
      Williams, James D.
    
    
      Groves, Roderick T.
    
    
      Rivera, Philip
    
    O.W673
    1104
    
      1.00 items
    
    1984-1985
    Memoir
  
  
    Scope and Contents
INSTITUTE OF INTER-AMERICAN AFFAIRS COLLECTION
James D. Williams, civil and sanitary engineer for IIAA 1943-46 and 1956-61, married to Elvera Williams, discusses his experiences and work with the IIAA and successor agencies in Brazil, Guatemala, and Mexico: duties and  responsibilities, IIAA policies, organization, economics, and staff; each country's economics, government, society, climate, and culture; and U.S. policies, politics and involvement in foreign affairs. He discusses the Amazon Programs and Rio de Janeiro in Brazil: public health programs, medical care, health centers, U.S. Operations Mission, road system, industries, and the Brazilian people. In Mexico: water treatment plants, Indians, and his family. In Guatemala: revolutions, water supply programs, well drilling, and earthquakes. Discusses coming back to the U.S. to work on air pollution control and health planning for the U.S. Public Health Service in Cincinnati, Ohio. He also discusses his early life: childhood, education at Iowa State College and University of California at Berkeley, and work for the Illinois Department of Public Health. Also describes his life after retirement.3 vols., 209 pp.
Interview by Philip Rivera, 1984 and Roderick T. Groves, 1985
Donated by the Oral History Research Office, Columbia University, New York.
RESTRICTED: May be read but not quoted, cited or reproduced.  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
RESTRICTED: May be read but not quoted, cited or reproduced.  
  

