<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>Q.08Archon Finding Aid Title Q.08UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:26:52 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    Q8. Operations Research Unit Publications, 1976-1978
    Q.08
    711
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1976-1978
    Date acquired: 04/27/1979
    1
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This file contains brochures and publications of the Operations Research Unit of the Center for Policy Studies and Program Evaluation.  Subjects include; Municipal energy Management, PERT/CPM programs, Database Development for the Department of Children and Family Services, Budget model for funding new programs in higher education.  File also contains material on Public Affairs Research Centers, Water us in Illinois Department of Conservation Parks. (1976-78).  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical by title/date  
  
    Source of Acquisition
c. Pinkus  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Revised 3/10/1997  
  
    Flyers/Brochures
    Programs
  
  Box 1Box 119304Municipal Energy Management: A Study of the Energy Conserva¬tion Techniques Available to Local Governments and an Assessment of Their Use in Illinois, 1977Folder 1193051Scope and ContentsMunicipal Energy Management: A Study of the Energy Conservation Techniques Available to Local Governments and an Assessment of Their Use in Illinois, by Marcia A. Langsjoen, Barton J. Michaelson and Charles E. Pinkus, prepared for the State of Illinois Institute for Environmental Quality, May 31, 1977, 63 ppMunicipal Energy Management: A Plan for Preparing Energy Techniques, Evaluation Their Impact and Training Local Government Officials, 1977Folder 2193062Scope and ContentsMunicipal Energy Management: A Plan for Preparing Energy Techniques, Evaluation Their Impact and Training Local Government Officials, by Marcia A. Langsjoen and Charles E. Pinkus, prepared for the State of Illinois Institute for Environmental Quality, June 30, 1977, 45 ppPERT/CPM for State and Local Government, by Gary W. Moss and Charles E. Pinkus, 1976Folder 3193073A Budget Model for Funding New Programs in Higher Education, April 14, 1978Folder 4193084Data Base Development for Department of Children and Family Services Residential Care Program Evaluation, November 6, 1978Folder 5193095Water Use in Illinois Department of Conservation Parks, November 6, 1978Folder 6193106Municipal Energy Management: A Study of the Energy Conservation Techniques Available to Local Governments and an Assessment of Their Use in Illinois, November 9, 1977Folder 7193117Public Affairs Research Centers, Sangamon State University, (promotional booklet)Folder 8193128Brochures re Program EvaluationFolder 9193139

