<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>S.02.01Archon Finding Aid Title S.02.01UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:28:32 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    S2/1. Library Media Services Slides: SSU, Springfield sites and events
    
      Library Media Services
    
    S.02.01
    722
    
      1.20 Cubic Feet
    
    1957-1987
    Date acquired: 08/06/1989
    1&amp;2
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Slide sets produced by Library Media Services. The slides in this collection include photos related to Sangamon State University campus scenes, presentations for the Illinois Board of Education, a presentation by former SSU student Judith Haynes entitled "Good and Useful Lives: People of the Sangamon," the LGPA Rail Classic in 1983, various colleges in the area (including Millikin University, Blackburn College, Illinois College), Brookens Library, previous SSU Presidents (Dr. Durward Long, Dr. Alex Lacy, Dr. Robert Spencer), SSU construction, activities at the Clayville Rural Life Center, and the SSU sponsored Computer Camp in the mid-1980s.  
  
    Arrangement Note
By topic  
  
    Slides
  
  Box 1Box 179237Illinois Board of Education - Slide PresentationFolder 17923819771S2/1 B1/F001. Illinois Board of Education - Slide Presentation: 1977Good and Useful Lives: People of the SangamonFolder 27923919812S2/1 B1/F002. Good and Useful Lives: People of the Sangamon: 1981Scope and ContentsThe presentation premiered March 19, 1981, during SSU's Intersession. Judith Haynes based some of the presentation on interviews conducted of locals living along the Sangamon River while she was working on a master's degree in History at SSU.Good and Useful Lives - Oral HistoryFolder 379240ca 19803S2/1 B1/F003. Good and Useful Lives - Oral History: ca 1980Scope and ContentsMany of these slides were meant to accompany interviews Judith Haynes conducted of locals living along the Sangamon. Many were also in Good and Useful Lives: People of the Sangamon which premiered March 19, 1981 during SSU's Intersession.Board of RegentsFolder 479241ca. 1985-19864S2/1 B1/F004. Board of Regents: 1985-1986Springfield Air Rendezvous Air ShowFolder 57924219835S2/1 B1/F005. Springfield Air Rendezvous Air Show: 1983Springfield-Lincoln SitesFolder 6792431957-19856S2/1 B1/F006. Springfield-Lincoln Sites: ca 1957-1985LPGA Rail ClassicFolder 77924519837S2/1 B1/F007. LPGA Rail Classic: 1983Scope and ContentsThe Rail Charity Classic on September 5,1983. Lauri Peterson was the winner that year. From 1976 through 2006, the tournament was held at The Rail Golf Course in Springfield, IL.Semi trucks at loading dockFolder 87924419868Millikin UniversityFolder 9792461980-19849S2/1 B1/F009. Millikin University: 1980-1984Blackburn CollegeFolder 10792471967-198110S2/1 B1/F010. Blackburn College: ca 1967-1981Scope and ContentsVarious photos of Blackburn College from 1967 through 1981. Blackburn College is a four-year co-educational private liberal arts college located in Carlinville, Illinois.Illinois CollegeFolder 11792481965-198011S2/1 B1/F011. Illinois College: ca 1965-1980Scope and ContentsVarious photos of Illinois College from 1965 through 1980. Illinois College is a private, liberal arts college, affiliated with the United Church of Christ and the Presbyterian Church, and located in Jacksonville, Illinois.New Harmony, IndianaFolder 1279249no dates12S2/1 B1/F012. New Harmony, Indiana: no datesScope and ContentsVarious photos related to New Harmony, Indiana, dates unknown. New Harmony is a historic town on the Wabash River in Harmony Township, Posey County, Indiana, United States.Robert C. SpencerFolder 13792501970-197213S2/1 B1/F013. Robert C. Spencer: 1970-1972Scope and ContentsVarious photos of Robert C. Spencer from 1970 through 1972. Spencer is a previous president of Sangamon State University, 1969-1977.Sangamon State University CommencementFolder 14792511972-06-1014S2/1 B1/F014. Sangamon State University Commencement: 1972-06-10Scope and ContentsSanagamon State University commencement on June 10, 1972. Speakers included Adlai Stevenson (U.S. Senator), James Holderman (Executive Director, Illinois board of Higher Education), and SSU President Robert Spencer.Alex Lacey and Various SSU Photo, no datesFolder 157925215S2/1 B1/F015. Alex Lacey and Various SSU Photo: no datesScope and ContentsVarious photos, including construction of campus buildings, Sangamon Auditorium, and Dr. Alex Lacy. Dr. Lacy is a previous president of Sangamon State University, 1978-1984.SSU Auditorium ScenesFolder 1679253no dates16S2/1 B1/F016. SSU Auditorium Scenes: no datesSSU ConstructionFolder 17792541971-197817S2/1 B1/F017. SSU Construction: no datesScope and ContentsIncludes many photos of construction of Public Affairs Center (PAC) at Sangamon State UniversityCampus ScenesFolder 1879255ca 1972-197818S2/1 B1/F018. Campus Scenes: ca 1972-1978Scope and ContentsSlides include various photos related to SSU campus, including interim campus scenes and photos of Patricia Breivik, Dean of Library/University Librarian, 1977-1980.SSU BuildingsFolder 1979256ca 197719S2/1 B1/F019. SSU Buildings: ca 1977Scope and ContentsPhotos include Brookens Library and PAC.ObservatoryFolder 2079257197520S2/1 B1/F020. Observatory: 1975Scope and ContentsFeatures photos of Charles Schweighauser, Professor Emeritus of English, Astronomy/PhysicsVarious photos of SSU Brookens LibraryFolder 2179258ca 1977-197921S2/1 B1/F021. Various photos of SSU Library: ca 1977-1979SSU Student HousingFolder 22792591978-197922S2/1 B1/F022. SSU Student Housing: 1978-1979U.S. Senate Candidate ForumFolder 23792601983-10-0823S2/1 B1/F023. U.S. Senate Candidate Forum: 1983-10-08Scope and ContentsU.S. Senate Candidate Forum, October 8 1983 at PAC Auditorium. Main democratic contenders were Paul Simon and Philip J. Rock.PoliticiansFolder 24792611972-197324S2/1 B1/F024. Politicians: 1972-1973Scope and ContentsPhotos include Dan Walker and Ted Kennedy during the Dan Walker campaign in 1972.Illinois Supreme Court Law LibraryFolder 2579262no date25S2/1 B1/F025. Illinois Supreme Court Law Library: no dateBack to School Slide Presentation -  Slides by Harry BermanFolder 2679263no date26S2/1 B1/F026. Back to School slide presentation - Slides by Harry Berman: no dateScope and ContentsFeatures comics with the theme of older adults going back to schoolPublic Affairs Colloquium (PAC) IntersessionFolder 2779264198127S2/1 B1/F027. Public Affairs Colloquium (PAC) Intersession: 1981Scope and Contents"The Energy Decade: Food, Resources and the Environment in the 1980s" was the topic for Sangamon State's 1981 Intersession, which ran from March 14 to 21 in the Public Affairs Center. These are slides from that presentation.LAC 401Folder 28792651981-05-1328SSU Women's Tennis TeamFolder 2979266no date29S2/1 B1/F029. SSU Women's Tennis Team: no dateWSSR radio stationFolder 3079267197730S2/1 B1/F030. WSSR radio station: 1977Scope and ContentsIncludes photos of WSSR staff at the Illinois State Fair in 1977. SSU SoccerFolder 3179268ca. 1977-198631S2/1 B1/F031. SSU Soccer: ca. 1977-1986Scope and ContentsFeatures various photos of the SSU Men's Soccer team, circa 1977-1986.  Slides include team photos from 1981. Many of the other slides are not specifically dated.Clayville Rural Life CenterFolder 32792691973-197932S2/1 B1/F032. Clayville Rural Life Center: 1973-1979Scope and ContentsThe "Historic Clayville Stagecoach Stop," is located in the Pleasant Plains, IL area. From 1973-1992, SSU operated the site as a rural historical location known as the Clayville Rural Life Center and Museum.Clayville Arts and CraftsFolder 33792721973-198133S2/1 B1/F033. Clayville Arts and Crafts: 1973-1981Scope and ContentsThe "Historic Clayville Stagecoach Stop," is located near Pleasant Plains, IL area. From 1973-1992, SSU operated the site as a rural historical location known as the Clayville Rural Life Center.Various Photos: McClelland House; Gary Storm and Class; Archives displayFolder 34792731974-197834S2/1 B1/F034. Various Photos: McClelland House; Gary Storm and Class; Archives display: 1974-1978Scope and ContentsPhotos include McClelland House, 1974; Gary Storm and class, date unknown; Archives display, 1978. The McClelland house was previously situated where the President's house at Sangamon State University now stands.Classroom, Student, and Campus ScenesFolder 35792741970-198735S2/1 B1/F035. Classroom, Student, and Campus Scenes: 1970-1987Scope and ContentsPhotos of various scenes, including (but not limited to) students and instructors in class, the campus bookstore, and SSU Spring registration in 1984.Computer CampFolder 3679275ca 1984-198536S2/1 B1/F036. Computer Camp: ca 1984-1985Scope and ContentsDuring computer camps, SSU hosted children ages 9-12 for week long activities that included classes to improve computer skills. Recreation periods with activities were also part of the camp experience, and often included softball, soccer, volleyball, and gymnastics.United Fund SlidesFolder 3779276197537S2/1 B1/F037. United Fund Slides: ca 1975Scope and ContentsSlide deck consists of photos used for United Fund campaignIllinois Vocational Curriculum Center presentation slide deckFolder 3879277no date38S2/1 B1/F038. Illinois Vocational Curriculum Center presentation slide deck: no dateCriminals and Rehabilitation Rape and Counseling Services Instructional Slide ShowFolder 3979278no date39Marketing Presentation SlidesFolder 4079279no date40Visual Speechmaking by Barbra ScheiblingFolder 4179280no date41S2/1 B1/F041. Visual Speechmaking by Barbra Scheibling: no dateScope and ContentsBarbara Scheibling was a graphic designer for the Educational Production Services unit at Sangamon State. She later served as a member of the Board of Regents in the early 90s.SSU Media Services Slide PresentationFolder 4279281ca. early to mid 1970s42S2/1 B1/F042. SSU Media Services Slide Presentation: ca. early to mid 1970sMiscellaneous Art Works for Instructional Slide PresentationFolder 4379282no date43Miscellaneous Presentation SlidesFolder 44792831972-198044Loose SlidesBox 224686Misc Art Work Featuring American-Indians for Instructional PresentationItem 179284no date1PAC Auditorium Event: 1964...As The BeatlesItem 2792851987-052Scope and ContentsDuplicate slides found in S2/2 B1/F96.Various Photos of SpringfieldItem 379286ca 19803Scope and ContentsContains duplicate slides found in other parts of S2/1 and S2/2. In addition, the context of some slides and their relationship to Springfield and SSU is unclear.Misc Black and White Photography and Drawings for Instructional PresentationItem 479287no date4Scope and ContentsContains various black and white photography and drawings by unidentified artists.Misc Black and White Photography and Drawings for Instructional PresentationItem 579288no date5Scope and ContentsContains various black and white photography and drawings by unidentified artists.Various photos of SSU Campus ScenesItem 679289ca 1980-19846Scope and ContentsThese slides are duplicates of slides in S2/1 and S2/2Campus Exterior PhotosItem 7-979290ca late 1970s through mid 1980s7-9Scope and ContentsThese slides include exterior photos of both Brookens and PAC. The slides are duplicates found in S2/1 and S2/2Various Campus ScenesItem 1079291 ca late 1970s through mid 1980s10Scope and ContentsContains duplicate slides found in S2/1 and S2/2Various Campus ScenesItem 1179292 ca late 1970s through mid 1980s11Scope and ContentsContains duplicate slides found in S2/1 and S2/2

