<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>O.F381Archon Finding Aid Title O.F381UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:28:59 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    Ferguson, Margaret  (1904-1979): Interview and memoir
    
      McPherson, Negil L. (Reverend)
    
    
      Ferguson, Margaret
    
    O.F381
    1162
    
      8.00 items
    
    Dummy Date
    Tapes et al
  
  
    Scope and Contents
BLACK COMMUNITY PROJECT 
Ferguson, African-American resident of Springfield, discusses her family background, conditions for African-Americans, employment and unemployment, segregation and discrimination, the 1908 race riot, neighborhoods and businesses, Bunn Park, education and counseling students in the schools. She discusses changes in Springfield, attending the University of Illinois receiving a degree in Home Economics, marriage, and her husband's early death. She also recounts her family history, including relatives who took advantage of the Homestead Act. She also discusses issues and employment with the Illinois Department of Child and Family Services, employment opportunities for African-American teachers, experiences teaching in Metropolis and at Lincoln University, her second marriage and being stationed in Germany after WWII, Lincoln Home for Colored Children, African-American businesses, Civil Rights, early 20th century recreation, effects of the Depression, and the funerals of her parents. 6 tapes, 540 mins., 2 volumes, 154 pp. 
Interview by Reverend Negil L. McPherson, 1975 
OPEN 
See collateral file: interviewer's notes, photographs of Ferguson, her family members and the family home, photocopy of a land grant, and a photocopy of a newspaper article on the old club house at the Springfield Golf Club.  
  
    Related Materials
Interview and Memoir in Illinois Digital Archives.http://www.idaillinois.org/u?/uis,2039  
  

