<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>R.01Archon Finding Aid Title R.01UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:29:02 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    R1. Reference Collection, UIS Archives Vertical Files
    R.01
    730
    
      2.00 Cubic Feet
    
    Dummy Date
    File Drawer
  
  
    Scope and Contents
This is a collection of frequently-requested documentation, including fliers, posters, programs, newsletters, newspaper and magazine articles, commencement programs, and academic brochures. Topics are related to university logos, campus events and history, collective bargaining, the dedication of campus buildings, alumni, faculty and staff, degree programs, etc. There is also material dealing with local history and events and persons from the Springfield area. The material is filed alphabetically by subject.This is a collection of miscellaneous documentation including promotional flyers, posters, logos, programs, newsletters, articles, etc., on academic brochures, collective bargaining, Brookens library dedication, degree programs, individuals, etc.This file contains extra copies of most of the commencement ceremony programs at SSU and UIS, however the originals and a complete set are contained in K1.Located in Room 144, File Cabinet  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetically  
  
    Related Materials
Full copies of commencement programs located in Illinois Digital Archives.http://collections.carli.illinois.edu/u?/uis_cmparch,12  
  
    Flyers/Brochures
    Programs
    Newsletters
    Posters
    Journal Articles
  
  Reference File, Drawer 1Drawer 147963Scope and ContentsThis is a collection of miscellaneous documentation including promotional flyers, posters, logos, programs, newsletters, articles, etc., on academic brochures, collective bargaining, Brookens library dedication, degree programs, individuals, etc.  It is uncataloged, ever-growing, and in vertical file format.Located in Room 144, File Cabinet25th Anniversary Supplement: Rebirth of the UniversityFolder 1478051995 Sept 211Scope and Contents10 page supplement published in the State Journal Register, Springfield, ILAbraham Lincoln University (Springfield), ProposalFolder 279136ca. 1920-242Academic Brochures - SSUFolder 3478063Adams, Nina - Illinois Times articleFolder 4478071999-04-254Scope and ContentsRetiring UIS professor reflects on 25 years of teaching at UIS and three FulbrightsAdvising and Counseling, Office ofFolder 5478081979-19825Scope and ContentsIncludes Counseling ManualAIDS Awareness DayFolder 64780919936Anthem, Sangamon State AnthemFolder 747810May 19847Scope and ContentsMusic and lyrics by Dr. Lavern WagnerArchives Resource GuidesFolder 84781119978Scope and ContentsAuthored by David BowlbyAthletic Program Review and Coach Firing ControversyFolder 9478122004-20119Scope and ContentsFinal Report of UIS Athletics Review Task Force (7-8-2004).
Coach firing controversy, 2009.
Includes copies of Senate resolution and minutes of Senate meetings and articles from IL State Journal Register about UIS Athletics department controversiesAudio Visual ServicesFolder 10478131982-8310Bakalis, Michael - SSU instructor and Illinois gubernatorial candidateFolder 1182190197811Scope and ContentsIllinois Issues, June 1978 (vol.1, no.6) article about Democratic nominee Bakalis's campaign against Republican James Thompson.Board of Regents: Governing Policy and RegulationsFolder 12478141973-200512Governing Policy for the Regency Universities System of IllinoisItem 17102311/15/1973121Scope and ContentsBylaws of the Board of Regents, as amendedConstitution for Sangamon State UniversityItem 2710241975122Scope and ContentsAccepted by Sangamon Sate University Community-2/19/1975.
Adopted by the Board of Regents-2/20/1975
(2 copies)Amendments to Governing Policy for the Regency Universities System of IllinoisItem 37102512/15/1973123Board of RegentsItem 471026July 1981124Scope and ContentsGoverning Policy for the Regency UniversitiesConstitution for Sangamon State UniversityItem 571027March 1991125Scope and ContentsAccepted by SSU - 2/19/1975
Adopted by Board of Regents - 2/20/1975
Amended &amp; Accepted by SSU 1/18/1991
Adopted by Board of Regents - March 1991Faculty Senate By-Laws and Rules (SSU)Item 671028May 1994126Scope and ContentsRevised (2 copies)Good Ethical Practice: Handbook for Faculty &amp; Staff at UIS+Item 7710292005127Scope and Contents4th editionBoard of Regents DirectoryItem 8710301979128Notice to Students, Faculty &amp; Staff; RE: BOR BriefingsItem 9710311985129Brookens Library Annual Report FY10Folder 1363552April 201113Brookens Library Resource Guides, BrochuresFolder 14812761995-201014Brookens Library Thirtieth AnniversaryFolder 1547815200615Brookens Library Space Needs Assessment - Shawn Tonner, Library Building and Renovation Management, Kelly Jerome Monnahan, Monnahan DesignsFolder 1681281200316Butler, Homer L. - Student Commons Dedication ceremonyFolder 1781286April 30, 200017Campus Entrance MarkerFolder 18812911998-2001.18Campus MapsFolder 19812961984-200519Capital Scholars ProgramFolder 2081301199920Scope and ContentsIncludes newspaper articles, UIS press releases, memos, brochures, admission information, etc.Central America ReportFolder 2181306198421Chancellor SearchFolder 2281311200022Chief Illiniwek: Reports, etc.Folder 2386366200023Scope and Contents"The Chief Illiniwek Dialogue: Intent and Tradition vs. Reaction and History," moderated by Louis B. Garippo.Christmas Cards, Brookens LibraryFolder 248131624Chronology of Sangamon State University, 1920-1995.Folder 258132125Scope and ContentsCompiled by Linda Tatman (September 1995). Edited by Thomas J. Wood.  Updated 1997 with additional information.Chronology of UIS - formerly Sangamon State University, 1997-  (extended version)Folder 268132626Churchill, Ward (SSU Alumni) ControversyFolder 2781331200527Scope and ContentsIncludes newspaper articlesCivil Service Statutes and Rules for State UniversitiesFolder 2881336December 197728Clayville Rural Life CenterFolder 29813411975-29Scope and ContentsIncludes copies of The Clayville Courier, Annual Spring Festival fliers, craft festival brochures, school program fliers (Clayville Folk Arts Guild)Clayville: A Feasibility Study for the Historic Clayville Stagecoach StopFolder 3081346March 197330Clayville Rural Life Center Publication SeriesFolder 31813511978-198131Scope and ContentsLiving History Recource ListsClayville Rural Life Center Master PlanFolder 3281356December 197632Scope and ContentsAffiliated with Sangamon State UniversityClinton, Hillary - visit to UISFolder 3381361April 26, 199633Scope and ContentsNewspaper articles. Also see Photograph collection S1/1/2Collective Bargaining: American Federation of State, County &amp; Municipal Employees.Folder 348136634Collective Bargaining: American Association of University Professors.Folder 358137135Collective Bargaining: University Professionals of Illinois.Folder 368137636ColonnadeFolder 37819212005-37Commencement ProgramsFolder 38813811972-198038Scope and Contents    1972, June 10 (3)    1973, May 27 (missing) [Original in K1]    1974, May 12 (2)    1975, May 11 (2)    1976, May 9 (2)    1977, May 15 (1)    1978, May 14 (2)    1979, May 13 (3)    1980, May 11 (3)Commencement ProgramsFolder 39813861981-198539Scope and Contents    1981, May 17 (1)    1982, May 16 (copy) [Original in K1]    1983, May 14 (1)    1984, May 12 (3)    1985, May 11 (3)Commencement ProgramsFolder 40813911986-199140Scope and Contents    1986, May 17 (3)    1987, May 16 (1)    1988, May 14 (2)    1989, May 13 (1)    1990, May 12 (2)    1991, May 11 (2) [20th Anniversary]Commencement ProgramsFolder 41813961992-199841Scope and Contents    1992, May 16 (1)    1993, May 15 (2)    1994, May 14 (2)    1995, May 13 (1) [last Sangamon State Program]    1996 (missing) [Original in K1]    1997 (missing) [Original in K1]    1998 (missing) [Original in K1]Commencement ProgramsFolder 42814011999-200542Scope and Contents        1999, May 15 (1)    2000 (missing) [Original in K1]    2001, May 12 (1)    2002 (missing) [Original in K1]    2003, May 10 (1)    2004, May 8 (1)    2005 (missing) [Original in K1]Commencement ProgramsFolder 43814062006-201043Scope and Contents    2006, May 13 (1)    2007, May 12, (1)    2008, May 10 (1)    2009, May 16 (2)    2010, May 15 (2)Commencement ProgramsFolder 44814112011-201644Scope and Contents2011, May 14 (2)    2012, May 12 (2)    2013, May 11 (1)    2014, May 17 (1)    2015, May 16 (2)    2016, May 14 (1)Commencement ticketFolder 4581416200245Consultant Reports on SSUFolder 4681421197746Scope and ContentsReview of Governance &amp; ManagementCONVOCAMFolder 478142647Crystal RadioFolder 48814311982-198348Scope and ContentsCrystal Radio, Inc. was a non-profit independent production unit associated with a thematic option titled Studies in Social Change, which is an area of study in the Individual Option Program at Sangamon State University.  It was also a member of the National Federation of Community Broadcasters and aired programs on other radio stations around the country.Cyber Security, Internet/Computer VirusesFolder 49819172003-49DeBolt, Dean - Papers &amp; PhotographsFolder 50814411975-198150Scope and ContentsPapers sent to Archives 11/15/2011: letters from 1975 - 1981; .Photographs from Herbert Georg Studio in Springfield, ILDisaster Program ReferenceFolder 5181446200051Dunbar, MichaelFolder 5281451200552Scope and ContentsSculptor Michael Dunbar gave Artist's Lecture on April 7, 2005 at UIS Public Affairs Center. Dunbar's local works are located at LLCC and the Sangamo Club in SpringfieldEarly Sangamon State University FacultyFolder 5381456197253Scope and Contents"68 New Faculty Members at Sangamon State" - article in the State Journal-Register, Springfield, IL. Dated September 3, 1972Email Controversy - Tih-Fen Ting, Lisa TroyerFolder 5481461201254Scope and Contents    Illinois Times article 1/26-2/1/2012: Email-gate: UIS faculty leader leaked information to president's chief of staff who resigned.    State Journal-Register 1/27/2012: Head of UIS Faculty Senate steps down in email scandal    Illinois Times article 2/2-2/8/2012: Ting sent Packing: UIS faculty senate leader resigns    Two internal UIS emails InRe resignation of Senate Chair    Anonymous email 1    Anonymous email2    No Confidence Resolution    Investigative Report (dated 12/12/2011)Employee benefitsFolder 5581466198355Employees of the Month/YearFolder 568147156Everson, Dave (1941-1999)Folder 5781476Died April 20, 1999.57Scope and ContentsObituary, articles, memorial service program, etc. Everson was a founding faculty member at Sangamon State; also was associate chancellor, professor, scholar, and mystery writer.Faculty Index - to Faculty and Administrators at SSU (See also Current Spreadsheet), 1969-92.Folder 588148158Scope and Contents"A Record of Achievement...A Promise for the Future: An  Index to Faculty &amp; Administrators at SSU from 1969 to 1992"  Compiled by Sharon Helding, 7-24-1991Faculty Obituaries and Memorials (including administration)Folder 59820571970-59Scope and ContentsSee also individual files of faculty and administrators for obituaries and memorials (Dave Everson for example).Faculty Union, UIS - IFT - CertificationFolder 6082126February 201560Faculty Union Strike, UISFolder 6182130May 201761Feral Cats on CampusFolder 62814862002-200362Scope and ContentsFeeding stray animals on campus will no longer be permitted.Fight Song for UIS by Phil SnowFolder 6381491200063Scope and ContentsChancellor Naomi Lynn made this the official fight song of UIS. Includes audio CD of song.Foundation, Sangamon State UniversityFolder 64815261982-199464Founder's Day ProgramFolder 6581531198565Gripes of Wrath: A Review of the First AssemblyFolder 668153666Scope and Contentsby Todd DomkeHandy Writer's Colony article in the Illinois Times: "Lowney's Legacy; More than a love of writing drove the strange colony in Marshall, IL," by C.D. Stelzer.Folder 6781541February 2, 200867Scope and ContentsIncludes: "The Marshall Papers; UIS home to unique collection of writers' colony documents," by C.D. Stelzer. Features Thomas J. Wood, curator of the Handy Writers' Colony Collection at UIS.Haunted House near campus - Gatton House Article in Illinois TimesFolder 6881546October 30, 199768Scope and Contents" Gatton House Ghosts; True stories of restless spirits who might yet roam Springfield's south side," by William Furry.Health &amp; Sciences Building DedicationFolder 6981551April 16, 199269Housing, On-CampusFolder 70815561980-70Scope and ContentsIncludes book about Housing on campus at Sangamon State University.  Includes On-Campus Student Housing dedication ceremony on 8-28-1980.Illinois Innocence Project - 15th AnniversaryFolder 7181561April 21, 201671Scope and Contents"Righting Wrongs: Illinois Innocence Project Marks 15 Years." Illinois Issues, April 21, 2016. Also printouts from UIS website on anniversary celebration.Illinois State ArchivesFolder 72819292004-72Scope and Contents"For the Record" Newsletter of the Illinois State Archives, Spring 2004, Fall 2006, Fall 2008, Winter 2009, others.Inauguration of the Illinois House of RepresentativesFolder 73815662009, 2011, 201373Scope and ContentsHeld at Sangamon Auditorium. Includes program, CD, and Usher &amp; Staff IDs.Institutional Self-Study ReportFolder 7481571October 200774Scope and ContentsElectronic copy on CDIntersession: Computers &amp; SocietyFolder 7581576198475Scope and ContentsVisiting and Teaching Faculty involved:  Robert Proce, Rassule Hadidi, John Rankine, Mark Heyman, Donald Bitzer, Doh Shinn, Brian Alley, Jerry Troxell, Dennis Camp, William Warren, Mary Kate Yntema.Intersession: The Origin and Evolution of Human BeingsFolder 7681581198576Scope and ContentsVisiting and Teaching Faculty involved:  Peter Borgia, Michael Kitchen, Malcolm Levin, Mark McConaughy, Mark Pency, Christopher Schuberth, James Stuart, Bonnie Styles, David West, Charles Schweighauser.Intersession: Illinois Economic Development-Nature, Policies, ImplicationsFolder 7781586198677Jackson, Jackie -- Illinois Times articles, Wisconsin State Farmer articleFolder 7881591October 21, 2011; November 2, 2017; January 3, 201878je ne sais quoi &amp; The War BulletinFolder 7981596200079Scope and ContentsTwo newsletter type publications; includes articles by faculty - Ron Sakolsky, Dennis Fox, Michael Townsend.Reference File, Drawer 2Drawer 247964Scope and ContentsThis is a collection of miscellaneous documentation including promotional flyers, posters, logos, programs, newsletters, articles, etc., on academic brochures, collective bargaining, Brookens library dedication, degree programs, individuals, etc.  It is uncataloged, ever-growing, and in vertical file format.Located in Room 144, File CabinetKantako, Mbanna - Pirate Radio PioneerFolder 17704225 Apr 20131Scope and ContentsArticle by Bruce Rushton in Illinois Times: "Pirate Radio Pioneer: Mbanna Kantake Won't Shut Up"
Material gathered for article from UIS Special Collection MC 86: Michael Townsend, Micro-Radio Collection.
Also See MC 86, Box 8, Folder 107Knoepfle, John - Poems from Illinois TimesFolder 2478712003-20042Koch, Susan - Chancellor of UISFolder 3739682011-3Scope and ContentsIllinois Times article (13 Oct 2011) "Leading UIS into the Future" New faces and fresh ideas on Springfield's campus.State Journal Register article (24 Jan 2012) "After six months, UIS chief getting to know her way around"Lennon, J. Michael - article in State Journal-RegisterFolder 4478745 Nov 2007; 26 Dec 20134Scope and ContentsArticles about Lennon by Steven Spearie.Lennon: professor and administrator at SSU, founding editor and later publisher of Illinois Times, Executive Director of the Public Affairs Institute - left Springfield to collaborate with Norman Mailer and instructor at Wilkes University in Pennsylvania.Also, 26 Dec 2013 SJR article about Lennon's book about Norman Mailer.Letterhead, SSU - UISFolder 5478751970-19965Scope and ContentsLabels, envelopes and letterhead paper from both Sangamon State and UIS.
Includes envelopes with 25 anniversary logo.Library - Brookens Library at SSU/UISFolder 6478781971-19846Scope and ContentsMemos and list of employees, beginning of Brookens Library at SSULincoln Bicentennial Celebration - Events, Brochures &amp; CentFolder 75379720097Scope and ContentsBookmarks and brochures for events to celebrate the Lincoln Bicentennial (1809-2009). Lincoln Commemorative Cent Event with 2 new Lincoln pennies. Final Report of IL A. Lincoln Bicentennial Commission.
(From Joan Sestak)Lincoln - Papers of Abraham Lincoln / Lincoln Legal PapersFolder 8819252015-8Lincoln Presidential Library and Museum &amp; UIS ControversyFolder 9478762002-20059Scope and ContentsUIS - A. Lincoln Presidential Center for Governmental Studies was set to exist until the political climate changed and the the A. Lincoln Presidential Library and Museum was created.
Includes brochure for the Abraham Lincoln Presidential Center for Governmental Studies at the University of Illinois Springfield.Lincoln Presidential Library and Museum DedicationFolder 1047877November 200210Scope and ContentsIncludes Presidential Library dedication pull-out section from the State Journal-RegisterLincoln Presidential Library and Museum Grand OpeningFolder 1178485April 200511Scope and ContentsIncludes Presidential Library pull-out section from the State Journal-RegisterLincoln Home: Springfield's national treasureFolder 1278486June 198812Scope and ContentsIncludes pull-out section from the State Journal-RegisterLincoln, Abraham: Articles and Clippings donated by Dean DeBoltFolder 137783813Scope and ContentsIncludes copies of magazines, journal, and newspaper articles from various years.  Includes a couple of postcards. Includes a letter from Mark Neely to DeBolt about Lincoln's birthday and a letter from Mike Pearson, Jr. to DeBolt about an article in 1966 "Outdoor Illinois."Lindsay, Vachel (1897-1931)Folder 1477362198414Scope and Contents"Lindsay's home embarks on a third life" is the title of an article published in the State Journal-Register, Sunday, 3 Jun 1984 by Doug. Pokorski.Biography of Vachel Lindsay by Dennis Camp, former professor of Sangamon State University.Logos, old and newFolder 154788315Scope and ContentsIncludes CDLong, Durward - Hiring ofFolder 1647879198416Long, Durward - Sexual Harrassment ChargesFolder 17478801985, 198817Long, NinaFolder 184788118 Mar 198518Scope and ContentsState Journal-Register article about Long, wife of SSU President Durward Long.Long Range Development Plans for SSUFolder 1947882197019Scope and Contents3 volumes: 2 from 1970 and revised plan in 1973.
Architects: Murphy, Downey, Wofford &amp; RichmanLynn, Naomi, SSU PresidentFolder 20478841991-200120Scope and ContentsArticles from Illinois Times, State Journal-Register, and Illinois Association of Hispanic State EmployeesMacoupin County CourthouseFolder 214788721Scope and ContentsCentennial celebration 1867-1967, includes other Macoupin County informationMaster Plan for UIS CampusFolder 22801251998, 200022Scope and ContentsAlso known as Physical Master Plan: Phase One Summary ReportMeet Your UIS Police ForceFolder 23801261995-200023Scope and ContentsIn depth article about members of the UIS Police ForceMorse, Saul - UIS a True Asset for the Capital CityFolder 248012710 Oct 201424Scope and ContentsState Journal-Register Nature Trail - Guide to the Sangamon State University Nature TrailFolder 2580128197625Scope and ContentsIncludes article from Sangamon State Journal, October 13, 1976NCA ReportFolder 2680129197826Scope and ContentsVPAA Keiser: NCA Report on SSU.	North Central Association Evaluation Team report for reaccreditation of Sangamon State University.	Note:  See also E1/5/1 President's Office, NCA ReportsNORML - National Organization for the Reform of Marijuana LawsFolder 2780130March 199327Observatory, UISFolder 2880131200728Scope and Contents"Moon Men: A new lodestar will guide watchers of the Springfield sky" (featuring Charles Schweighauser and John Martin) -- Illinois Times, 5 Apr 2007Office of Financial AssistanceFolder 29801321978-198629Online Courses Changing College ClassroomsFolder 30801339 Apr 201330Scope and ContentsArticle in Chicago TribuneOpen House 15th Anniversary CelebrationFolder 31801344 Nov 198431Scope and ContentsEvent brochures, memosParking Tag for UISFolder 32801352009-201032Patton Park Dedication ProgramFolder 338013625 Oct 199033Peace RalliesFolder 34801371983-198634Physical Development of Sangamon State University, 1969-95 (2 copies) - by Richard R. WilliamsFolder 3580138199535Scope and ContentsAlso included: "The Campus Land Purchase and the McClelland Story" by Richard R.  Williams, January 2006"The Power Game: Who Rules Springfield." - People's Institute, 3rd EditionFolder 3680139ca. 197636Prairie Stars Name Change ControversyFolder 37801402013-201437Scope and ContentsContains email from Chancellor Koch with the decision to keep the Prairie Stars name, the UIS Nickname/Mascot Task Force: Final Reports, and related newspaper articles.President's Home, SSUFolder 3880141198438Scope and ContentsControversy and cleanup.Presidential ElectionFolder 3980142200039Scope and ContentsGore v. BushPublic Affairs Center, Brown Bag Lunch ForumFolder 40801431982-198440Public Affairs Center ConstructionFolder 41801441974-198141Scope and ContentsChronological timeline. Includes pull-out section from the State Journal-Register, 10 Mar 1981.Public Affairs Center Dedication and Open HouseFolder 4280145March 198142Scope and ContentsDedication brochures, PAC poster, Public Affairs Center Guide book, Sangamon State Auditorium Fun Guide	Includes pull-out section from the State Journal-Register, March 10, 1981.Quarter System changeFolder 4380146197343Radio Station, StudentFolder 4480147199944Scope and Contents"Graffiti Times" and flyers to promote the establishment of a student-operated radio station on the UIS campus.Research Park, SSUFolder 4580148198445Scope and ContentsAlso known as the Cooperative ComplexResidence Halls: design brochure, etc.Folder 4686361200746Scope and ContentsDorms, Dormitories, Lincoln and Founder's Halls.Ringeisen, Richard (Chancellor) Resignation ControversyFolder 4780149201047Ringeisen, Richard (Chancellor), Retirement ReceptionFolder 488015027 Sep 201048Scope and ContentsProgram, invitation and CD "Remembering a Decade of Leadership"Sakolsky, Ron (and Dennis Fox) ArrestFolder 49801511983-199549Scope and ContentsArrested for passing out leaflets in PAC for event with Karen Hasara as speaker; includes newspaper articles, actual flyer in question, and personal statement of event (1995). Also included is Illinois Times article about "Sakolsky: The Life of a Protester" (1989). Sakolsky was involved in an incident with County Sheriff Jim Purdon in 1983.Sangamon State Groundbreaking MaterialFolder 5080152June 197050Scope and ContentsInvitation to attend construction of interim facilities on Wednesday, 10 June 1970. Personal RSVPs from many dignitaries about their attendance at the event; Gov. Richard Ogilvie attended the groundbreaking of new senior university.	Removed from G1 boxlist folder, 18 Aug 1994.Sangamon State - U of I Merger - Memos to University CommunityFolder 51801531993-199551Sangamon State Picnic/Wake (transition to UIS)Folder 528015429 Jun 199552Scope and ContentsInvitation to the entire university community for the First/Last Alternative SSU Picnic/Wake and Funeral March to say goodbye to SSU and hello to UISSangamon State - U of Illinois Merger InformationFolder 5380155199553Scope and ContentsIncludes newspaper articles (Illinois Times), faculty resolutions, protest fliers, and House bill authorizing the merger.Sangamon Auditorium - Fatal accident (John Kremitzki)Folder 548165126 March 201754Satire, SSUFolder 55801771979-8455Satire, SSUFolder 56801781972-200256Scope and ContentsIncludes April Fool's edition, 1 Apr 2002Schweighauser, Charles - Star Parties at UIS ObservatoryFolder 57801795 Apr 200757Scope and ContentsIllinois Times article	Moon Men: A new lodestar will guide watchers of the Springfield sky	by Marissa MonsonScroggin, Karl to retire from WUISFolder 588018018 Feb 201258Scope and ContentsState Journal-Register article: Farewell to a classic: Karl Scroggin to retire from WUISSculpture on campusFolder 598018159Scope and Contents     Impermanent Column by Thomas Skomski, installed September 1993.     Window's Edge by SSU faculty Robert Dixon, installed July 1999.     Spaulding Memorial Fountain outside of Brookens Library, dedicated April 1977.     Dodger by John Henry, installed May 2012.     The Young Lawyer (Abraham Lincoln) by George Lundeen, installed May 2016.     Shakespeare's Garden by Gary Lee Price, dedicated September 29, 2016.Security on campusFolder 6080182198560Scope and ContentsNewspaper articlesSeptember 11 (2001) Attacks - Commemoration/ MemorialsFolder 6182061200161Scope and Contentsnewspaper clippingsSkloot, Rebecca - Henrietta LacksFolder 6280183201062Scope and ContentsArticle in State Journal Register 5 Nov 2011	Springfield native Rebecca Skloot chronicles woman's life in the book "The Immortal Life of Henrietta Lacks"	Skloot spoke and signed books at Sangamon Auditorium on 9 Nov 2011Soccer Joe Eck Retirement (SSU Team)Folder 6380184201063Scope and ContentsArticle in State Journal Register 17 Feb 2010	Fan Forum: UIS has forgotten its soccer rootsSoccer Statistics (SSU Team)Folder 6480185199364Scope and ContentsSee also K5/1/1 Box 1 F48 for list of opponents and scores 1977-96South AfricaFolder 658018665Scope and ContentsBrown Bag Lecture: A Couple of White Guys from South AfricaSpectrum-SSU's First NewspaperFolder 668018718 Sep 197066Scope and ContentsVol. 1, Number 1Spencer, Robert C. and Edith SpencerFolder 678018867Scope and ContentsSSU President from 1969 to 1978.	Newspaper articles about his tenure and his wife, includes his obituarySpringfield Inaugural Ceremony-Mayor and other City OfficialsFolder 688018929 Apr 201168Scope and ContentsMayor J. Michael Houston; Cecilia K. Tumulty, City Clerk; James O. Langfelder, City Treasurer; Ward 1 - 10 Aldermen	Includes CD with photos.Springfield Race RiotFolder 6980190Springfield Race Riot, 190869Scope and ContentsIncludes Resource List, newspaper articles from that time, excerpts from The Sociogenesis of a Race Riot by Roberta Senechal, and articles and pull-out section from State Journal-Register on 1 Jun 2008Springfield Symphony Orchestra BrochuresFolder 70801911985-8670Scope and ContentsBloomington/Normal and Springfield Symphony	Kenneth Keisler, Music Director and ConductorStreet NamesFolder 7180192199971Scope and ContentsCampus streets named for Illinois authorsStudent Center DedicationFolder 7280193October 198572Student Laureates - Lincoln Academy of IllinoisFolder 7380194October 200273Student LifeFolder 7480195April 198474Student ProtestsFolder 7580196198375Student Union - Groundbreaking and Ribbon Cutting Ceremony MaterialFolder 76812392016-201876Scope and ContentsProgram, Groundbreaking, 5 May 2016Program, Ribbon Cutting, 14 Jan 2018Podium Scripts:  Chancellor Susan Koch, President Timothy Killeen, Clarice Ford, Garrett NimmoNewspaper articlesPieces of cut ribbonStukel, James (U of I President) Retirement ReceptionFolder 7780197September 200477Scope and ContentsIncluded CD"Teaching Library: Organizing the Academic Library for Instruction" Howard W. Dillon, Journal of Academic Librarianship, 1 (Sept 1975): 4-7.  Article on instructional services librarians in the Sangamon State University Library.Folder 78801981985-8678Telephone Directories (SSU Employee)Folder 79801991981-8379TheaterFolder 80802001984-8580Scope and ContentsSangamon State University TheaterThibodeaux-Thompson, Eric and MissyFolder 818020112 Jun 200781Scope and ContentsIllinois Times article	Playmates: Eric and Missy Thibodeaux-Thompson drive UIS Theatre into the spotlight by Marissa MonsonTime CapsuleFolder 82802021971-200182Scope and ContentsSangamon State University Time Capsule list of contents, agreements, and articlesTRAC, September 2007Folder 838020383Scope and ContentsThe Recreational &amp; Athletic Center opening as reported in the UIS newspaper-The JournalTwenty-fifth AnniversaryFolder 848020484Scope and ContentsStar-Fest Celebration invitation, program and label pin (13 Sep 1995)	25th Anniversary Celebration Calendar of Events at UIS	Invitation to Campus Convocation (30 Sep 1995)	Also see Series 1 in this Reference Collection.UIS- News- Significant Events/ Historic MilestonesFolder 858020585UIS (&amp; SSU) Organizational ChartsFolder 86818811969-201286UIS Vision StatementFolder 8781885199687UIS Web Page - First OneFolder 8880207199688UIS Web Page, Quiz &amp; ScreensaverFolder 8980208200189Scope and ContentsWe Are Something Special	CD includedUniversity CodeFolder 90802091980-8190Scope and ContentsOffice of the Dean of Student Services	Sangamon State UniversityUniversity ForumFolder 91802101978?91Scope and ContentsHeld in the stair lounge of Brookens Library, speakers at lunchtimeUniversity Hall DedicationFolder 928021118 Aug 200492University of Illinois President Bulletins &amp; MemosFolder 93802121995-199793University of Illinois Statutes and RulesFolder 948021315 Feb 199594Scope and ContentsDocuments to review at information meeting RE U of I merger with Sangamon State University	Note: Find other merger documents under Sangamon State MergerUpdike, John (1932-2009)Folder 9580214199795Scope and ContentsRuth and Lester Friedman Lectureship; Updike read from his fictional works; includes photosVasconcelles, MarkFolder 9680215August 198596Scope and ContentsNewspaper articles about the shooting on campus and creation of a Scholarship in his name. See also: Security on Campus, 1985.Voter's Guide brochureFolder 97802167 Nov 200697Scope and ContentsKnow the issues and get out and Vote; provided by Pi Sigma AlphaWeiss Military Collectors' and Researchers Library (MCARL)Folder 988021798Scope and ContentsJulius L. and Dorothy U. WeissWhite, B. Joseph (U of I President) InaugurationFolder 998021822 Sep 200599White, VibertFolder 10080219100Scope and ContentsUIS Professor Moving On, Illinois Times Feature Article, March 2002Wilkins, Joe - Illinois Times articleFolder 1018161731 Mar 2005101Scope and ContentsPrecious Medals: Vietnam veteran Joe Wilkins claims he was twice wounded in combat and earned the nation's third-highest decoration, a silver Star.  The military says otherwise.Yang, Xuesong "Gary" -- rape caseFolder 102816562017102Yugoslavian ConflictFolder 103816211999103

