<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.34Archon Finding Aid Title MC.34UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:29:23 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC34. Charles Herbert Spaulding, Personal Papers, 1927-1972
    
      Spaulding, Charles Herbert
    
    MC.34
    736
    
      0.50 Cubic Feet
    
    1927-1972
    1 water module
    1
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Chemical engineer and water purification expert.  Came to Springfield in 1926 to start the operation of the water softening plant which he helped design for the Sangamon River Station. Designed the Springfield Water Purification Plant built in 1936. Noted internationally for his invention of the Spaulding Precipitator, used internationally in water treatment plants. During World War II, designed a mobile water filtration unit for use by troops. 

Technical article, manuscripts and reprints by Spaulding regarding operation of the water softening plant, preammoniation, manipulation of pH, and the water purification plant in Springfield; purification of water from the Sangamon River; and general issues of water purification, softening and odors.  Also comprises personal letters, photographs, clippings, obituaries and biographical statements regarding his career; a 1957 report by Spaulding to Springfield City, Water, Light and Power on operating the water purification plant; and reference materials. A news clipping and photographs regarding the dedication of the Spaulding Fountain at Brookens Library at SSU. A specimen of a Spaulding precipitator is included.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Mrs. C. H. Spaulding - Gifts of 1974 and 1976  
  
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 15835PublicationsSub-Series 15839"Operation of New Water Softening Plant at Springfield, Illinois"Item 158401927-071"Preammoniation at Springfield, Illinois"Item 258411929-082"Natural and Artificial Purification of the Sangamon River"Item 358421930-053"Water Softening at Bloomington, Illinois"Item 458431931-074"Manipulation of pH at Springfield, Illinois"Item 558441931-085"Quantitative Determination of Odor in Water"Item 658451931-096"Contamination of Mains by Jute Packing"Item 758461931-127"Some Quantitative Odor Determination"Item 858471932-088"Filter Problems and Water Softening"Item 958481932-099"The New Water Purification Plant for Springfield, Illinois"Item 1058491935-0310"Conditioning of Water Softening Precipitates"Item 1158501937-1111"Accuracy and Application of Threshold Odor Tests"Item 1258511942-0612"Diatomite Water Filtration Developed for Field Troops"Item 1358521944-1113"Operating Results at Lakeside Water Softening Plant, Springfield, Illinois"Item 1458531937-0914"Conditioning of Water Softening Precipitates"Item 1558541937-0615"Improved Water Quality at Springfield, Illinois"Item 1658551939-0416"Conclusions following discussions at State Water Survey"Item 1758561953-04-0917"Water Quality at Winnebago State Hospital"Item 1858571958-07-4018Scope and ContentsA report to the Bureau of Engineering, State of Wisconsin.Operation of Water Purification Plant, City of Springfield, IllinoisItem 195858195719"Mineral Analysis of the Public Water Supply"Item 2058591964-196520Lake Management ReportsSub-Series 25860Reports issued by the Natural History Survey, Urbana, ILItem 158611Scope and Contents#3, Lincoln Lakes, August 1939
#4, Fisheries Investigation, Fork Lake, August 1940PatentsSub-Series 35862U. S. Patents 1,752,789 and 1,893,451Item 158631Publications By Other AuthorsSub-Series 45864"Water Softening at Minneapolis," J. A. JensenItem 1586519381"A Fully Automatic Softening and Iron Removal Plant," R. F. MacDowell and H. L.Item 2586619372Data Book, Permutit CompanyItem 3586719423Scope and ContentsContains photograph of the Spaulding Precipitator in use at California power plant.Letter to Mrs. Hugh Morrow about history of Lake SpringfieldItem 158361947-03-241Letter to Urbana, IL Board of Education about selection of filter for pool at Urbana HighItem 258371961-05-082Citation for membership in Springfield High School Hall of Fame, w/brief biography of Mr. SpauldingItem 358383

