<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>O.F761.2Archon Finding Aid Title O.F761.2UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:29:40 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    F761.2 Foreign Born Physicians in Springfield, Illinois #2: Memoir
    
      Chaudhary, Subhash
    
    
      Fluckiger, Humphrey W. R.
    
    
      Kuehn, Luise Frieda Schaefer
    
    
      Eberle, Eugenia
    
    O.F761.2
    1172
    
      1.00 items
    
    1994-1995
    Folder
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Subhash Chaudhary (b. 1948), Humphrey W. R. ("Joe") Fluckiger b. 1922, Luise Frieda Schaefer Kuehn (b. 1916 ).Chaudhary, pediatrician, recalls his early years in Sonepat, India, his family, and Indian culture and customs; his education at the All India Institute of Medical Services in New Delhi; his internships in the U.S.; his employment at the Southern Illinois School of Medicine in Springfield; his wife, in-laws, and children. Fluckiger, in family practice, recalls his childhood in Dutch Indonesia, the Netherlands and New York City; attending medical school in the Netherlands and Jakarta in the 1930s; the capture of him and his family by the Japanese in WWII; his time in Japanese prison camps in Indonesia; the loss of his brothers and father in the sinking of the prison ship Junyo Maru; medical education after the war in Amsterdam; and his emigration to the U.S. in 1950 and practice in Springfield. Kuehn, psychiatrist, recalls her early years and education in Germany; her parents and siblings; her training in Germany during WWII; her arrival in the U.S. in 1950; Lutheranism and Easter and Christmas customs; life and practice in Chicago, Bluffs, and Springfield; her husband and children; and her retirement. 63 pp. 
Interviews by Eugenia Eberle, 1994-95 
Donated by Eugenia Eberle 
OPEN  
  
    Related Materials
Interview and Memoir in Illinois Digital Archives.http://www.idaillinois.org/u?/uis,4685  
  

