<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>O.F761.1Archon Finding Aid Title O.F761.1UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:29:42 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    F761.1 Foreign Born Physicians in Springfield, Illinois #1: Memoir
    
      Arjmand, Towfig
    
    
      Azeris, Harry Talivaldis
    
    
      Choi, Choon Bong
    
    
      Jackman, Jane Lloyd
    
    
      Rabinovich, Sergio
    
    
      Trautmann, Victor Franz Ferdinand Karl Maria
    
    
      Eberle, Eugenia
    
    O.F761.1
    1171
    
      1.00 items
    
    Dummy Date
    Folder
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Towfig Arjmand, Harry Talivaldis Azeris, Choon Bong Choi, Jane Lloyd Jackman, Sergio Rabinovich, Victor Franz Ferdinand Karl Maria Trautmann.
Narrators discuss their native homelands, family, religious faiths, holidays, university and medical education, childhood activities, brief history of their original country, and their reasons for coming to the U.S. Arjmand, an anesthesiologist from Iran, discusses the revolution of 1978, the Jewish religion, and the Iranian government. Azeris, a general surgeon from Latvia, discusses the family farm, WWII invasions by Germans and Russians, and Lutheranism. Choi, orthopedic surgeon from Korea, also discusses his family's escape from the Communist regime in 1948 in North Korea. Jackman, family practitioner from England, discusses growing up in the aftermath of WWII. Rabinovich, professor of infectious diseases from Peru, discusses Inca religion, health care, and infectious diseases. Trautmann, urologist from Czechoslovakia, discusses the after-effects of WWII in Eastern Europe. 112 pp. 
Interviews by Eugenia Eberle, 1994 
Donated by Eugenia Eberle 
OPEN  
  
    Related Materials
Memoir in Illinois Digital Archives.http://www.idaillinois.org/u?/uis,4678  
  

