<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>G.01/06/02Archon Finding Aid Title G.01/06/02UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:29:46 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    G1/6/2. "Skirting Convention: 12 Women Who Changed Springfield" Program
    
      Cardoza, Kavitha
    
    G.01/06/02
    740
    
      0.48 Cubic Feet
    
    2007
    Date acquired: 10/03/2007
    1
    Tapes
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Consists of material relating to the WUIS/WIPA FM radio program "Skirting Convention: Twelve Women Who Changed Springfield" which premiered on March 8, 2007 and ran on-air for several months; a CD of the program was released on September 27, 2007.  The program, authored by Kavitha Cardoza, profiled twelve women who influenced history and worked for social change in Springfield.  The file contains background research materials on each of the women as well as a press release and a program that contains the aforementioned audio CD of the radio broadcasts.  Also included are the audio tapes of the interviews conducted with several of the women as well as a video recording of Velma Carey.
WUIS (Radio Station: Springfield, IL; Rich Bradley/ Kavitha Cardoza); Radio interviews; Funded by grant from IL Humanities Council.  3 sound discs : digital ; 4 3/4 in.  Compact discs, inserted in back cover pocket of accompanying descriptive booklet ([24] p.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Note: Background material and CD located on compact shelving.  The audio cassette tapes are located in the Tape Collection cabinet.  
  
    Audio CDs
    Audio Tapes
    Correspondence
    Flyers/Brochures
    Newspaper Clippings
    Press Releases
    Videotapes
    Allen, Bettie
    Carey, Velma
    Carlino, Sister Anne
    Cummings, Theresa
    Dickerman, Barbara
    Gingold, Ethel
    Hasara, Karen
    Kaige, Alice
    Knoepfle, Peggy
    Leahy, Mary Lee
    Moy, Caryl
    Oxtaby, Carolyn
  
  Research MaterialsBox 123425Programs, Press ReleasesFolder 1234261Background Research MaterialsFolder 2234272Allen, Bettie: Research MaterialsFolder 3234283Carey, Velma: Research Materials (includes VHS video recording)Folder 4234294Carlino, Sister Anne: Research MaterialsFolder 5234305Cummings, Theresa: Research MaterialsFolder 6234316Dickerman, Barbara: Research MaterialsFolder 7234327Gingold, Ethel: Research MaterialsFolder 8234338Hasara, Karen: Research MaterialsFolder 9234349Kaige, Alice: Research MaterialsFolder 102343510Knoepfle, Peggy: Research MaterialsFolder 112343611Leahy, Mary Lee: Research MaterialsFolder 122343712Moy, Caryl: Research MaterialsFolder 132343813Scope and ContentsIncludes a copy of Sangamon County Medical Society: Cultivating the Science and Art of Medicine, 1899-2001Oxtaby, Carolyn: Research MaterialsFolder 142343914Tapes located in Oral History Tape CabinetBox 223440Bettie Allen (6 tapes)Item 1234411Scope and ContentsAudio cassette tape recordings of interviewJesse Mae Finley (5 tapes)Item 2234422Scope and ContentsAudio cassette tape recordings of interviewAlice Kaige (1 tape)Item 3234433Scope and ContentsAudio cassette tape recordings of interviewRuth Jackson (1 tape)Item 4234444Scope and ContentsAudio cassette tape recordings of interviewVelma Carey (2 tapes)Item 5234455Scope and ContentsAudio cassette tape recordings of interviewKaren Hasara's First City Council Meeting as Mayor (2 tapes)Item 6234466Scope and ContentsAudio cassette tape recordings of interview

