<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>P.PaludanArchon Finding Aid Title P.PaludanNicole L. LouisUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:29:52 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    P/Paludan. Phillip Shaw Paludan Papers, 1963-2006
    
      Paludan, Phillip Shaw
    
    P.Paludan
    742
    
      7.50 Cubic Feet
    
    1963-2006
    Date acquired: 10/25/2007
    1
    2
    3
    4
    5
    6
    7
    8
    9
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Member of the UIS history faculty, 2001-2007.  Dr. Paludan held the University's first distinguished chair, the Naomi B. Lynn Distinguished Chair in Lincoln Studies, established in 2001.  Before coming to UIS, Paludan taught at University of Kansas, Rutgers University, and University College, Dublin.  One of the nation's most preeminent American Civil War historians, Paludan wrote several books on the topic including The Presidency of Abraham Lincoln and Victims, a True Story of the Civil War, along with numerous other chapters and journal articles.

Notes, articles, drafts, transparencies, lecture notes, news clippings, correspondence and other items from Dr. Paludan's files, ranging from 1963 to 2006.  The majority of the collection contains research files maintained by Dr. Paludan on various topics pertaining to U.S. History, particularly the Civil War and U.S. Constitutional history.  The collection also contains his research for his 1981 book Victims, a True Story of the Civil War as well as files for classes he taught at UIS and the University of Kansas, 1987-2005.

Series I (Boxes 1-2) consists of general American Civil War research material.  Topics include political, social, and economic facets of the conflict.  Folders primarily contain information collected by Dr. Paludan with his personal notes.

Series II (Box 3, Folders 1-25; Box 7) consists of research material for Dr. Paludan's book Victims, a True Story of the Civil War, including several drafts of the text.  Also contains general Civil War research material.

Series III (Box 3, Folders 26-56 - Box 6, Folders 1-12) consists of general historical research on Colonial America, Constitutional history and other topics.  Some Civil War topics, research on the history profession, and other personal papers are also located here.

Series IV (Box 6, Folders 13-37) consists of lecture notes, syllabi, and exams from classes taught by Dr. Paludan at the University of Kansas and UIS, 1987-2005. Also includes videotape, news release, and text of speech from investiture ceremony of Paludan being awarded the first Naomi B. Lynn Distinguished Chair in Lincoln Studies (2005-11-07).

Series V (Box 8, RESTRICTED) contains graded student essays, tests, and assignments along with class rosters and grade books.  Also includes information pertaining to the hiring of an executive director for the Abraham Lincoln Presidential Center for Government Studies. 

Series VI (Oversize File) contains posters and and other oversized material from Dr. Paludan's office.  
  
    Arrangement Note
subject  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
Box 8 RESTRICTED  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Marty Paludan  
  
    Related Materials
Phillip Shaw Paludan Oral History Memoirhttp://library.uis.edu/archives/collections/oral/oralpq.html  
  
    Awards
    Class Schedules
    Correspondence
    Course Materials
    Flyers/Brochures
    Journal Articles
    Letters
    Microfilm
    Newspaper Clippings
    Newspapers
    Papers
    Photocopies
    Posters
    Programs
    Reports
    Speeches
    Statistics
  
  American Civil War Research NotesSeries 1143Box 1Box 1140Pictures by Winslow HomerFolder 11411Scope and ContentsTransparenciesCivil War Videos and FilmsFolder 21422000-20032Scope and ContentsNotes, correspondenceCivil War Song LyricsFolder 31443Scope and ContentsArticles, transparenciesModern Race RelationsFolder 41451991-19964Scope and ContentsNewspaper, magazine articlesLincoln HistoriographyFolder 514619795Scope and Contents"The Lincoln Theme Since Randall's Call: The Promise and Perils of Professionalism" by Mark E. Neely, Jr.Women AbolitionistsFolder 61471986-20036Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, lecture and essay notes"The Market Revolution"Folder 71487Scope and ContentsNotes, drafts of Paludan's chapter"Moby Dick: The Little Lower Layers" by Elizabeth SchultzFolder 81498CapitalismFolder 91509Scope and ContentsNewspaper articleAbolition and ReformFolder 10151196710Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesAmistad CaseFolder 1115211Scope and ContentsMagazine articleAntebellum Politics – Lincoln vs. DouglasFolder 121531972-200212Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, Paludan's "The American Civil War Considered as a Crisis in Law and Order"19th Century Law – Fugitive SlavesFolder 1315413Scope and ContentsLecture notes, articlesLincoln and Judicial ReviewFolder 141551983-198914Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articlesIrrepressible Conflict: "On the Irrepressible Conflict" by William Henry SewardFolder 15156200215Northern Response to SuccessionFolder 161571972-200416Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, John Brown Opera, Paludan's "Lincoln, the Rule of Law, and the American Revolution"Manifest Destiny (Pre-Civil War)Folder 1715817Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, maps, transparencies, lecture notesLincoln InformationFolder 181591961-200218Scope and ContentsNotes, book review, article, statistical dataSlavery DefendedFolder 1916019Scope and ContentsArticleConcept of Honor, dueling, etc. – Southern AntebellumFolder 201621999-200220Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, lecture notes, correspondence, Paludan's "Southern Honor – a Comment",RacismFolder 2116321Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper article, Paludan's "Racism"Race – 19th Century United StatesFolder 221641991-200222Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articlesLove, Death, God and Civil WarFolder 2316523Scope and ContentsNotes, lecture notesSoldiers and Sailors monument (Indiana)Folder 24166199824Scope and ContentsArticles, correspondence, brochureLincoln and RaceFolder 2516725Scope and ContentsNotesSlavery – Civil WarFolder 261681993-199926Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, correspondence, brochureNat TurnerFolder 2716927Scope and ContentsTransparencySlaveryFolder 28170200328Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, Paludan's "Sectionalism, Slavery and the Constitution",Antebellum south – Slave Ownership and Other SocietyFolder 291711969-198329Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesBattlefield Sites Visitor InformationFolder 3017230Scope and ContentsNational Park Service brochures for Gettysburg, Manassas, Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania, Antietam, and Harpers FerrySlavery – Population DemographicsFolder 311731981-199731Scope and ContentsNotes, magazine articleSlave SongsFolder 3217432Scope and ContentsArticles, transparenciesSlavery – WorkFolder 3317533Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, Paludan's "Work and Slavery"Slave LifeFolder 341761970-197334Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, lecture notes, newspaper articles"The Economics of Slavery" by Roger RansomFolder 35177198935Slave Trade/Comparative SlaveryFolder 3617836Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesFredrick DouglasFolder 37179199237Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, maps, Paludan's "Fredrick Douglas" and "Fredrick Douglas, Abraham Lincoln and the Gettysburg Metaphor"Uncle Tom's CabinFolder 38180198038Scope and ContentsArticlesReforms – Temperance, Bodily ReformFolder 39181199639Scope and ContentsArticle, notesCivil DisobedienceFolder 401821984-200340Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articles, lecture notesBackground for Reform and AbolitionFolder 411831972-199941Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, lecture notesThe Taney Court and the Civil War EraFolder 421841993-199442Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, speech notes, "Taney, Lincoln and the Constitutional Conversation," given by Paludan March 30, 1994 at the Supreme Court Historical SocietySlavery as Political Issue – Nullification to KansasFolder 43185199343Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, book reviewsStructure for Disorder – Constitutional Convention to MissouriFolder 4418644Scope and ContentsNotes, newspaper article, transparencies, map, lecture notesBackground for DisunionFolder 4518745Scope and ContentsNotes, transparenciesFugitive Slave Law JudgingFolder 4618846Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesDred ScottFolder 4718947Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, maps, postcards, brochure for Jefferson National Expansion Memorial, "Taney, Lincoln and the Constitutional Conversation," speech given by Paludan March 30, 1994 at the Supreme Court Historical Society"Communities Go To War"Folder 4819048Scope and ContentsTranscribed primary source, draft of Paludan's chapterAntislavery and the North – Civil LibertiesFolder 49191200149Scope and ContentsNotes, transparencies, mapsSouthern SecessionFolder 501921969-200150Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, book review written by PaludanDeclaration of IndependenceFolder 511931964-198651Scope and ContentsTransparenciesKansas CrisisFolder 5219452Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, maps, postersSecession – Summary South, North and LincolnFolder 531951989-200453Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, "Lincoln and the Rule of Law," speech given by Paludan March 23, 1989 at the Washburn University Harman Memorial Lincoln Lecture,Soldiers – Manhood and War, Gender and War:Folder 5419654Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, book review, CD-ROM of speakers from "Society Slavery and the Civil War, An Almost Silent Cry, Children of the Civil War: North and South," given June 25, 2004Wartime South and Mary ChestnutFolder 5519755Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transcribed primary sourcesWomen in WarFolder 561981999-200456Scope and ContentsNotes, articleForging Foreign and Domestic WeaponsFolder 57199199157Scope and ContentsArticle, draft of Paludan's chapter "Forging Foreign and Domestic Weapons"Sherman and Grant: Frankenstein and EverymanFolder 58200200058Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, maps"Scars of War": Personal Experience and Civil WarFolder 59201199059Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, transcribed primary documents, draft of Paludan's chapterMcClellan, Sherman GrantFolder 602021986-200260Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, maps, Civil War flashcards, draft of Paludan's chapter "Frankenstein and Everyman: Sherman, Grant and Modern War"McClellan and Early War, Grant to ShilohFolder 6120361Scope and ContentsTransparencies, maps, draft of Paludan's chapter "The Ways of Making War"GrantFolder 6220462Scope and ContentsNotes, articleWar and EconomicsFolder 6320563Scope and ContentsNotesBox 2Box 2206Economic Issues in Civil WarFolder 120719751Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesEconomic Impact of Civil War:Folder 22082Scope and ContentsArticles, Paludan's "What Did the Winners Win? The Social and Economic History of the North during the Civil War"Personal Costs of WarFolder 320919813Scope and ContentsNotes, transparencies, correspondence, copies of primary sourcesPolitics in War EraFolder 42101983-20044Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articles, drafts of Paludan's chapters "Congress Organizes, Lincoln Acts: April to December 1861" and "Civil War Politics"EmancipationFolder 52115Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, draft of Paludan's chapter "Leaving Old Moorings: McClellan and Emancipation: June to December 1862"Civil War and the Constitution – Civil LibertiesFolder 621219846Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, book review written by Paludan, draft of Paludan's chapter "The Dialogue of Politics: Loyalty and Unity, 1863-64"Lincoln – Rule of Law and RevolutionFolder 72131962-19777Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, Paludan's "The American Civil War Considered as a Crisis in Law and Order", draft of Paludan's "Lincoln, the Rule of Law and the American Revolution"Congress and Finance and Currency – Civil War 1861-5Folder 82148Scope and ContentsNotes, draft of Paludan's chapter "Congress and the Capitalists"Agriculture in the Civil War EraFolder 921519819Scope and ContentsDraft of Paludan's chapter "Agriculture in the Civil War Era" in A People's Contest: The Union and the Civil WarSecond American System – Civil WarFolder 1021610Scope and ContentsNotes, draft of Paludan's chapter "Congress and the Second 'American System'"Fredrick DouglasFolder 112171979-198711Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, draft of Paludan's "Fredrick Douglas"Robert E. LeeFolder 122181999-200112Scope and ContentsArticles, pamphlet, newspaper articleLincoln, F. Douglas, and Political CorrectnessFolder 13219200113Scope and ContentsArticles, newspaper article, National Park Service pamphlet for the Lincoln Home National Historic SiteCivil Liberties in ConfederacyFolder 142201992-200314Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, correspondence, drafts of "Lincoln and Liberty in the Civil War" by Mark E. NeelyBattle Maps – Antietam, Gettysburg and ChattanoogaFolder 15221200215Scope and ContentsNewspaper articles, transparenciesGuerrilla War- Civil WarFolder 16222197416Scope and ContentsArticle, issue of "Civil War Times Illustrated""The Civil War and the Constitution"Folder 17223198917Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, drafts for  Paludan's chapterGettysburg AddressFolder 1822418Scope and ContentsCopies, transparencies, newspaper articles, mapsIntellectual History of the Civil WarFolder 1922519Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesWinslow HomerFolder 20226199920Scope and ContentsArticles, transparenciesConfederate Soldiers in Virginia, 1861-1862 by Joseph T. GlatthaarFolder 21227199921Scope and ContentsCorrespondence"Religion in the Civil War Era"Folder 2222822Scope and ContentsDraft and final copy of Paludan's chapterImpeachmentFolder 23229200023Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, draft of Paludan's "The Impeachables,"Labor – Industrial Civil War EraFolder 24230199424Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, draft of Paludan's chapter "Industrial Workers and the War"Law, Race and the ConstitutionFolder 2523125Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, pamphlet, "Race, Law and the Constitution," speech given by Paludan to the Kansas City, Kansas Bar Foundation, October 29, 1984Emancipation Proclamation DraftsFolder 2623226Scope and ContentsNotes, transparenciesEmancipation and Free LaborFolder 27233198127Scope and ContentsNotes, book review written by Paludan, draft of Paludan's chapter "Emancipation and Free Labor Ideology"Jefferson Davis in PetticoatsFolder 282341999-200528Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparenciesGrant and the SouthFolder 29235198729Scope and Contents"Ulysses S. Grant and the South" by Brooks D. SimpsonReconstruction – ConstitutionFolder 302361977-198030Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articles, transparenciesWomen's Rights or Black Rights?Folder 3123731Scope and ContentsTranscribed primary sourceReconstruction – Documents from 1866-1875 and 1970sFolder 32238197632Scope and ContentsArticles, Paludan's "Reconstruction and the Problem of Legislating Social Change"Loss of Civil and Political rights, 1868-1900Folder 3323933Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, lecture notesReconstruction – OutlinesFolder 342401961-200634Scope and ContentsNotes, newspaper article, transparencies, book reviewReconstruction in South – Freedmen's ExperiencesFolder 352411986-200535Scope and ContentsNotes, article, transparencies, book review written by PaludanReconstruction and the South – PoliticalFolder 36242200536Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, lecture notesReconstruction – Northern Goals and PlansFolder 372431980-198137Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articlesReconstruction – Economics and the SouthFolder 382441979-198338Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articlesCivil Rights – Slaughterhouse Civil Rights CasesFolder 39245198939Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, lecture notes1876 ElectionFolder 40246200040Scope and ContentsNotes articles, transparencies, lecture notesFreeman's BureauFolder 41247Notes, article41Scope and Contents1979McClellan, Sherman and Grant: Images of Modernization in the Civil War EraFolder 4224842Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, draft of Paludan's "McClellan, Sherman and Grant: Images of Modernization in the Civil War Era"SharpshootersFolder 43249200343Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transcribed primary sources19th Century Republican BibliographyFolder 4425044Scope and ContentsArticleA. Lincoln – Lawyer, PrewarFolder 4525145Scope and ContentsArticle, postcards, brochure from The Lincoln MuseumOrganization of American Historians, 1990 "Lincoln, Intentions of Framers, Etc."Folder 4625246Scope and ContentsNotes, correspondence, "Lincoln, Slavery, and the Intentions of the Framers," speech given by Paludan at New York University Law School, May 27, 1989Lincoln Convention – His Own WordsFolder 47253196747Scope and ContentsArticle, pictureAbraham LincolnFolder 482541979-199648Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articles, correspondence, book reviews, pamphletsVictims: A True Story of the Civil War - Research NotesSeries 2161Box 3Box 3255War Crimes – My LaiFolder 12561970-19721Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesHeth Chapter – Heth and KeithFolder 225719762Scope and ContentsNotes, correspondenceMarshall Raid to MassacreFolder 32583Scope and ContentsNotes, copies of primary sourcesShelton LaurelFolder 425919764Scope and ContentsNotes, correspondenceHethFolder 526019745Scope and ContentsNotesVictims – Comments and CorrespondenceFolder 62611980-20036Scope and ContentsBook reviews, correspondenceArrest RecordsFolder 72627Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, correspondence, copies of primary sourcesMassacre AccountsFolder 82638Scope and ContentsCopies of primary sourcesMountain Way of LifeFolder 92641968-19779Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesVictims: A True Civil War StoryFolder 1026510Scope and ContentsDrafts of Paludan's book Victims: A True Civil War StorySociety in Mountain RegionFolder 112661974-197511Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, copies of primary sourcesHistoriography and New StuffFolder 1226712Scope and ContentsNotes, requests for recordsLaw of War – Guerrilla, Superior Orders, etc.Folder 1326813Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesPsychology of CombatFolder 142691974-197714Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, correspondenceEconomic Life in the MountainsFolder 15270198015Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesJames A. Keith and the 64th – PersonalitiesFolder 1627116Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, copies of primary sourcesAllen, Lawrence M.Folder 1727217Scope and ContentsNotes, copies of primary sourcesPost-Massacre – Chapter VFolder 1827318Scope and ContentsDraft of chapter five in VictimsSocial Environment – S. Laurel Census – SheltonFolder 19274197719Scope and ContentsNotes, newspaper articleAftermath – Court CasesFolder 2027520Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, copies of primary sourcesVictims – Recent MaterialsFolder 2127621Scope and ContentsNotes, requests for records, copies of primary sources, drafts of VictimsRoots of Mountain UnionismFolder 2227722Scope and ContentsNotes, articleReconstruction and Race in the MountainsFolder 23278198023Scope and ContentsNotes, requests for records, copies of primary sourcesReviews and Responses to VictimsFolder 242791982-198324Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, book reviews, newspaper articlesVictims – TransparenciesFolder 25280199325Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, transparencies, copies of primary sources, maps(Note Card Box)Box 8281Rowan County, North Carolina -  Minutes, Court of Pleas and Quarter Sessions, 1858-1868Folder 12821Scope and ContentsMicrofilm rollHawks, Joanne VarnerFolder 22832Scope and ContentsMicrofilm rollSmith, Cortland VFolder 32843Scope and ContentsMicrofilm rollRowan County, North Carolina - Minutes, Court of Pleas and Quarter Sessions, 1845-1858Folder 42854Scope and ContentsMicrofilm rollSocial StructureFolder 52865Scope and ContentsNotesGovernment and/or CommunityFolder 62876Scope and ContentsNotesWork – A. Smith and OrderFolder 72887Scope and ContentsNotesKnow NothingFolder 82898Scope and ContentsNotesBoozeFolder 92909Scope and ContentsNotesGeneral Disorder, Crime/LawFolder 1029110Scope and ContentsNotesSectional CrisisFolder 1129211Scope and ContentsNotesJohn BrownFolder 1229312Scope and ContentsNotesSecessionFolder 1329413Scope and ContentsNotesRailroad and BoosterFolder 1429514Scope and ContentsNotesHorriblesFolder 1529615Scope and ContentsNotesRace and SlaveryFolder 1629716Scope and ContentsNotesPolitics and MembershipFolder 1729817Scope and ContentsNotesReligionFolder 1829918Scope and ContentsNotesWarFolder 1930019Scope and ContentsNotesFood - Economic TroubleFolder 2030120Scope and ContentsNotesHabeas Corpus and MilitiaFolder 2130221Scope and ContentsNotesPrisonFolder 2230322Scope and ContentsNotesHanging Together - Local CommunityFolder 2330423Scope and ContentsNotesReconstructionFolder 2430524Scope and ContentsNotesKKK and ViolenceFolder 2530625Roster of Confederate Troops - Rowan Co, NCFolder 2630726Scope and ContentsNotes, copies of primary sourcesGeneral Historical ResearchSeries 3308Box 3Box 3309Constitutional Video SeriesFolder 2631026Scope and ContentsArticles, transparenciesColumbus and ExplorationFolder 273111992-200027Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesColonial EcologyFolder 28312199528Scope and ContentsNotesRevolution – Early, MusicFolder 2931329Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, copies of primary sourcesConstitutional – Political TheoryFolder 3031430Scope and ContentsNewspaper articlesIndian Culture – Seneca 1700Folder 31315198631Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesColonial Encounter – Indians in the New WorldFolder 3231632Scope and ContentsNotes, articles transparenciesColonial Virginia – Family, PoliticsFolder 3331733Scope and ContentsNotes, lecture notesPuritans – Decline and WitchesFolder 3431834Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, lecture notesMusic in U.S. HistoryFolder 3531935Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesCritics of PluralismFolder 3632036Scope and ContentsNotesConstitutional – Political theoryFolder 37321198037Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articles1776-1976Folder 38322197638Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articles, book reviewsWhite Servitude – ColonialFolder 3932339Scope and Contents"White Servitude" by Richard HofstadterFailure of British Constitution:Folder 40324199140Scope and ContentsNotesConstitutionFolder 4132541Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesBoston Massacre and Kent StateFolder 4232642Scope and ContentsNotes, article, transparencies, lecture notesTowards Independence, 1765-1774Folder 4332743Scope and ContentsNotesThe Coming of the American RevolutionFolder 4432844Scope and ContentsDraft of Paludan's chapter, "The Coming of the American Revolution"Declaration of Independence CopiesFolder 4532945Scope and ContentsCopiesDeclaration of IndependenceFolder 46330199546Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparenciesRevolution and ConstitutionFolder 47331198947Scope and Contents"The Ideological Fulfillment of the American Revolution: A Commentary on the Constitution" by Bernard BailynOriginal IntentFolder 48332198648Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesHistoriography of Founding of Constitution:Folder 49333198949Scope and Contents"Reflections on the Founding: Constitutional Historiography in Bicentennial Perspective" by Peter S. OnufReligion/Prayer 18th – 19th CenturyFolder 50334198550Scope and ContentsArticlesIntentions of FramersFolder 51335198651Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesSecond AmendmentFolder 52336199952Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articles, book reviews, pamphletsConstitution and Bill of RightsFolder 5333753Scope and ContentsCopies, transparenciesAntifederalistsFolder 5433854Scope and ContentsNotes, article, lecture notesThe Federalist EraFolder 5533955Scope and ContentsDraft of Paludan's chapter "The Federalist Era"First American RevolutionFolder 56340199556Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, lecture notes, transparenciesBox 4Box 4341Colonial America – Society and ConstitutionalismFolder 134219951Scope and ContentsNotes, article, lecture notesConstitution – Rights ConsciousFolder 23432Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesWashington AdministrationFolder 334419703Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparenciesHamiltonFolder 43454Scope and ContentsNotes, lecture notesJeffersonFolder 53461999-20065Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, lecture notes, transparenciesAlien and Sedition ActsFolder 634720066Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesMilitary Law – Revolution to Mexican WarFolder 734819777Scope and Contents"Legal, Egalitarian, and Humanitarian Influences on American Military Justice from the Revolutionary War to the Mexican War" by Edward F. ShermanJudicial ReviewFolder 834919808Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesJudicial Review – List of Federal Laws Overturned to 1937Folder 935019809Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesJudicial Review – MarburyFolder 10351199410Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies"Jeffersonian America"Folder 1135211Scope and ContentsArticle, draft of Paludan's chapterMarshall Court and NationalismFolder 123531981-200612Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, lecture notes, book reviewMarshall Court Ends, Taney's BeginsFolder 133541995-200613Scope and ContentsNotes, transparencies, lecture notesFletcher v. Peck – Yazoo SpeculationFolder 1435514Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies"The Myth of Class in Jacksonian America" by William E. GienappFolder 15356199415Cherokee Cases – U.S. Supreme CourtFolder 16357200016Scope and ContentsArticleHorwitz – Pro and ConFolder 173581973-198117Scope and ContentsArticlesAlexis De TocquevilleFolder 18359198918Scope and ContentsNotes, articles"The American Law of Slavery, 1810-1860 A Study in the Persistence of Legal Authority" by Mark TushentFolder 19360197519NullificationFolder 2036120Scope and ContentsNotes, article"Andrew Jackson and the Creation of the American Political Nation"Folder 21362199821Scope and ContentsChapter draft by PaludanLincoln and LawFolder 22363199822Scope and ContentsNewsletters from the Lincoln Legal PapersAmerican Indian Image – JacksonianFolder 23364198223Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articlesMobility – GeographicFolder 24365198024Scope and ContentsArticles, dataWealth DistributionFolder 25366197825Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, graphsEmersonFolder 2636726Scope and ContentsNewspaper article, book reviewConfederate ConstitutionFolder 27368198727Scope and ContentsArticles, pamphlet14th AmendmentFolder 283691984-199428Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesCivil Rights – 1866 Act, Modern DebateFolder 2937029Scope and ContentsArticlesFourteenth Amendment and FriendsFolder 303711987-199130Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, "Federalism in Civil War Era," speech given by Paludan in Reno, Nevada February 19, 1987Substantive Due Process and the Supreme Court, Late 19th CenturyFolder 313721972-198931Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, lecture notesMunn v. IllinoisFolder 32373200132Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, lecture notes, transparenciesModernization, 1870-1920Folder 33374198633Scope and ContentsArticlesProgressivism and LawFolder 34375200134Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesLegal Thought and Professionalism, 1900-1935Folder 35376198835Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesMuller v. OregonFolder 3637736Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, lecture notesOliver Wendell Holmes, Jr.Folder 3737837Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, lecture notesWelfare – Danish SystemFolder 3837938Scope and Contents"Rise and Fall of the Welfare State: The Case of Denmark" by Thorkild KjaergaardTaft and the Courts – 1920sFolder 3938039Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, lecture notesSupreme Court and New DealFolder 403812000-200140Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, lecture notes, transparenciesNew Deal and the LawFolder 4138241Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articlesCivil Liberties 1930s – 1940sFolder 42383198442Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparenciesJapanese-Americans, WWIIFolder 433841970-197243Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, lecture notes, transparenciesCold War and Internal SecurityFolder 4438544Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, lecture notesPress and National SecurityFolder 4538645Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesModernization, Pre-Civil WarFolder 4638746Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesAbolition DocumentsFolder 4738847Scope and ContentsArticlesWomen's HistoryFolder 483891973-198648Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articlesCivil War and ReconstructionFolder 49390197149Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, correspondence"Defining Goals of War"Folder 503911979-199250Scope and ContentsNotes, drafts of Paludan's chapterCivil War HistoriographyFolder 5139251Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, and Paludan's "Lincoln, the Rule of Law and the American Revolution"Morality of WarFolder 52393198652Scope and ContentsArticleWar Powers – PresidentialFolder 533941984-198753Scope and ContentsArticles, newspaper articlesBox 5Box 5395Biography as GenreFolder 13961997-19981Scope and ContentsNotes, articleNarrative HistoryFolder 23971986-19902Scope and ContentsNotes, articleThe Nature of Historical NarrativeFolder 33981969-19893Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articleNarrative Quality of ExperienceFolder 43994Scope and ContentsArticle, newspaper article, draft of Paludan's VictimsMethod – Narrative – ParadigmFolder 54001985-19945Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articles, "Writing History: Experiments in Narrative" speech given by Paludan to the American Historical Association, December 29, 1990; "Victims: A True Story of the Civil War Revisited" speech given by Paludan to Western Carolina University, October 3, 1994Faber and NarrativeFolder 640119886Scope and ContentsArticles, lecture notes, correspondenceWhat is History?Folder 74021971-19867Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, lecture notesSynthesis in American HistoryFolder 840319868Scope and ContentsArticlesPaludan vs. RosenbergFolder 940419869Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, correspondence,Republican Party Social Vision, 1850sFolder 1040510Scope and ContentsNotesLincoln Conference September 14-16, 1984Folder 114061984-198811Scope and ContentsNotes, correspondence, brochureSlavery and the 13th AmendmentFolder 12407198512Scope and ContentsNotesWhy Did the South Loose?Folder 1340813Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesLincoln and EconomicsFolder 1440914Scope and ContentsNotes, articleBackground, 14th AmendmentFolder 15410198515Scope and ContentsNotes, articleImpact of Civil War – Benefits, Consequences, and LessonsFolder 1641116Scope and ContentsNotesMary B. Chestnut's DiaryFolder 1741217Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, pamphlets, transparencies, newspaper articles, transcribed primary sourcesReligion, Censorship SchoolsFolder 18413198718Scope and ContentsArticles, newspaper articlesReapportionmentFolder 1941419Scope and ContentsNotes, lecture notesWarren Court – General ViewsFolder 204151969-198820Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articlesAccused Rights – Warren courtFolder 21416197321Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articlesBrown v. Board of EducationFolder 224171988-200022Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articles, transparencies, book reviewsSpeech and Advertising – ConstitutionFolder 23418198723Scope and ContentsPamphlet, correspondenceAffirmative Action – General IssueFolder 244191977-200124Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, Paludan's "Seeing the Constitution Differently as an Appeal for Affirmative Action"Affirmative ActionFolder 254201976-200125Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articles, correspondenceFreedom of PressFolder 26421198726Scope and ContentsArticleRaceFolder 27422199127Scope and ContentsArticleBurger Court, 1980sFolder 28423198428Scope and ContentsArticle, newspaper articleWebster Arguments 1989Folder 29424198929Scope and ContentsNewspaper articlesPrayer in SchoolFolder 304251983-198730Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesWomen and Constitution – General Notes/LectureFolder 31426197231Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, lecture notesWomen and ConstitutionFolder 32427198432Scope and ContentsNotes, articleRoe v. WadeFolder 33428198933Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articlesWomen and the Constitution – Lecture MaterialsFolder 344291984-198834Scope and ContentsArticles, newspaper articles, lecture notesWomen's ConstitutionFolder 35430198435Scope and ContentsNotes, articleJustice GinsburgFolder 36431199736Scope and ContentsArticleConstitutional InterpretationFolder 374321987-199137Scope and ContentsArticlesEducation and Supreme CourtFolder 3843338Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesFlag Burning Cases and AmendmentFolder 39434198939Scope and ContentsNotes, article, newspaper articlesRobert Bork Nomination to U.S. Supreme CourtFolder 40435198740Scope and ContentsArticlesDeath PenaltyFolder 414361983-200141Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesPornographyFolder 4243742Scope and ContentsArticleAbortion and ConstitutionFolder 434381973-198843Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articlesGriswold v. ConnecticutFolder 44439197644Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesRehnquist CourtFolder 454401986-198945Scope and ContentsArticles, newspaper articlesDeath Penalty to 1995Folder 4644146Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, mapsBush v. GoreFolder 474422000-200147Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesBox 6Box 6443ServiceFolder 14441998-20021Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, brochureLincoln and SlaveryFolder 244519992Scope and ContentsLecture notesA People's Contest RevisitedFolder 34461984-20013Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articles, lecture notes, brochures"Religion and the American Civil War"Folder 44474Scope and ContentsSpeech by Paludan in Louisville, Kentucky, October 13, 1994"Lincoln and Democracy"Folder 54485Scope and ContentsNotes, brochure, speech by Paludan at the University of Chicago on May 11, 2003Second Annual MessageFolder 64496Scope and ContentsNotes, "Lincoln's Second Annual Message – Policy or Propaganda?" speech by Paludan at the 17th Annual Lincoln Colloquium, September 28, 2002The Quintessential Antebellum Supreme Court of Illinois by Dan BannisterFolder 745020037Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, draftCorrespondenceFolder 84511992-20048Reviews of Paludan's WorkFolder 94521972-19809Scope and ContentsCorrespondenceCopies of Book ReviewsFolder 104531965-200410Scope and ContentsBook reviews written by PaludanPublished WorksFolder 114541972-197711Scope and ContentsCopies of articles by PaludanPlatoFolder 1245512Scope and ContentsNotes, transparencies, lecture notesBox 7Box 71541Slavery – Law and Treatment, SalesFolder 115421Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparenciesSlavery - HistoriographyFolder 215432Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, book reviewsSlavery – Family, Religion, ChildrenFolder 3154420003Scope and ContentsNotesAbraham LincolnFolder 415451991-20024Scope and ContentsNotes, book reviewsLincoln and SlaveryFolder 5154620035Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesLincoln on SlaveryFolder 615476Scope and ContentsNotesHallowed GroundFolder 7154820037Scope and ContentsPamphlets, correspondenceColonial - Northern Colonies, PuritansFolder 815498Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparenciesEarly Settlement Colonies - Jamestown, New EnglandFolder 915509Scope and ContentsArticles, notesGordon Wood - RepublicanismFolder 10155110Scope and ContentsNotesConstitutional ConventionFolder 1115521988-200311Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, pamphletsAn Empire of ReasonFolder 121553200012Scope and ContentsArticlesLaw and Economic Growth - 19th CenturyFolder 13155413Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparenciesAndrew Jackson - SymbolFolder 1415551996-200614Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, book reviewsTaney - Jacksonian LiberalFolder 1515561981-198715Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, correspondenceAbraham Lincoln AssociationFolder 161557200416Scope and ContentsNotes, lecture notesAbraham Lincoln AssociationFolder 171558200217Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, pamphletsHistory 412 - Civil War in AmericaFolder 181559200118Scope and ContentsNotesHistory 510 - War and SocietyFolder 191560200719Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesMeFolder 201561200520Scope and ContentsNotes, correspondence, articles, pamphletsLincoln LegacyFolder 211562200521Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, draftsFoundations of FederalismFolder 22156322Scope and ContentsNotesHistory 440 – Constitutional HistoryFolder 231564200623Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, pamphlets, photographsVita and MiscellaneousFolder 2415652001-200224Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, book reviewsServiceFolder 251566200225Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, correspondence, pamphletsResearchFolder 2615671987-200226Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, pamphletsHistory 441 – Civil WarFolder 271568200527Scope and ContentsSyllabus, notes, testsLincoln LegacyFolder 2815692002-200328Scope and ContentsNotes, correspondenceMeFolder 291570200329Scope and ContentsPamphlets, correspondence, newspaper articlesCivil War CoursesFolder 3015712001-200530Scope and ContentsClass notes, syllabus, tests, assignmentsHistory 441Folder 31157231Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, correspondenceFaculty and Course EvaluationsFolder 3215732001-200632Electronic FilesFolder 3315742003-200533Scope and Contents"Society, Slavery, and the Civil War: With Hearts on Fire – Women in the Civil War" (CD-ROM)
"Society, Slavery, and the Civil War: An Almost Silent Cry – Children of the Civil War, North War" (CD-ROM) 
"Marty Birthday – 2003" (Zip Disk)Abraham Lincoln Presidential Center for Government StudiesFolder 34537721/31/2003-2/1/200334Scope and ContentsRESTRICTED - FILE RESTRICTED - RESTRICTED
Executive Director Search documentsClass FilesSeries 4456Box 6Box 6457Rome – Western Civilizations, Fall 1987Folder 1345813Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, correspondenceJohn Locke – Western Civilizations, Fall 1987Folder 1445914Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparencies, correspondencePico, Machiavelli, and Renaissance – Western Civilizations, Fall 1987Folder 1546015Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparenciesNietzsche – Western Civilization, 1988Folder 1646116Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparenciesBurke and Paine – Western Civilizations, Spring 1988Folder 1746217Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparenciesJohn Stuart Mill – Western Civilizations, Spring 1988Folder 1846318Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, transparenciesHuman Nature and Brave New World – Western Civilizations, Fall 1988Folder 1946419Scope and ContentsNotes, articlesHistory 440 – Topics in 19th Century U.S., Fall 2003Folder 2046520Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, syllabus, examsHistory 510 – Graduate Readings on Abraham Lincoln and His Times, Spring 2002Folder 2146621Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, exams, assignmentsHistory 491 – Civil War Era, Fall 2002Folder 2246722Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, exams, assignmentsHistory 493 – History of the American Constitution – The First Century, Spring 2003Folder 2346823Scope and ContentsArticles, syllabus, examsHistory 441 – The Civil War Era, Fall 2004Folder 2446924Scope and ContentsNotes, syllabusHistory 441 – The Civil War Era, Fall 2003Folder 2547025Scope and ContentsNotes, syllabus, examsHistory 495 – The Civil War Era, Fall 2001Folder 2647126Scope and ContentsNotes, syllabus, examsHistory 440 – Lincoln, Race, and Slavery in the United States, Spring 2005Folder 2747227Scope and ContentsNotes, syllabus, examsCivil War in American IntroductionFolder 284731999-200128Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, syllabus, exams, newspaper articles, transparenciesHistory 320 – Civil War and Reconstruction, Spring 1997Folder 2947429Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, syllabus, exams, transparenciesHistory 510 – Abraham Lincoln and His World, Spring 2002Folder 3047530Scope and ContentsNotes, book listHistory 412 – Civil War in America, Summer 2000Folder 3147631Scope and ContentsArticles, syllabus, examsHistory 891 – U.S. 1800-1900 Colloquium, Spring 2000Folder 3247732Scope and ContentsSyllabus, book listConstitutional – Introduction to CourseFolder 334781974-198933Scope and ContentsNotes, articles, newspaper articles, magazine articlesColloquium in US Political History 1790-1880, Spring 1996Folder 3447934Scope and ContentsSyllabus, articlesNot FiledFolder 354801963-200235Scope and ContentsArticles, newspapers, drawingsAbraham Lincoln Presidental Library and Museum PlaqueFolder 36481April 19, 200536Scope and ContentsCommemorative plaque for the dedication of the Abraham Lincoln Presidential Museum  [from Timothy J. Davlin, Mayor of Springfield]
Clear Glass, 6" round diameter, 1" thickInvestiture-First Naomi B. Lynn Distinguished Chair in Lincoln StudiesFolder 37268582001-11-0737Scope and ContentsAwarded to Phillip Paludan, file includes remarks he made at the ceremony and a videotape of the ceremony.  Dr. Richard E. Vaden and his family contributed $1.25 million to UIS to establish its first endowed chair.Faculty Personnel PolicyFolder 3853770200138Scope and Contents(2 copies)
Plus UIS brochures for Disability ServicesFaculty Orientation Session "Teaching &amp; Learning"Folder 3953771200139Scope and ContentsPlus UIS brochures for Disability Services, Campus Health Service, Student Technology Guide, Brookens Library Guide, Capital Scholars, and Adult &amp; Part-time StudentsRESTRICTED FILESSeries 5482Box 9Box 9487Restricted Files – Class Rosters/GradesFolder 14881997-20061Restricted Files – Student Essays 1 of 2Folder 24891983-20032Restricted Files – Student Essays 2 of 2Folder 34901978-20033Oversize FileSeries 6483OVERSIZE cabinet 1OVERSIZE cabinet 150708"American Memory: Lincoln" posterItem 14841Scope and ContentsPhotomosaic by Robert Silvers, (27"x39")
Located in Oversize Cabinet, drawer 3"Abraham Lincoln's Cabinet" posterItem 24852Scope and ContentsFrom the Papers of Abraham Lincoln, (24"x36")
Located in Oversize Cabinet, drawer 3Abraham Lincoln cardboard cutoutItem 34863Scope and Contents(life size - approx. 21"x 74")
Located in Room 144, back wall

