<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>Q.07Archon Finding Aid Title Q.07UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:30:14 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    Q7. Institute for Public Affairs/Center for State Policy &amp; Leadership
    
      Center for State Policy and Leadership
    
    
      Institute for Public Affairs
    
    
      Abraham Lincoln Presidential Center for Governmental Studies
    
    Q.07
    745
    
      0.66 Cubic Feet
    
    1991-2009
    1
    2
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The Institute for Public Affairs/Center for State Policy &amp; Leadership file contains newsletters, publications, flyers, brochures, and other materials.  

Material includes annual reports from 1994 to 2006.  The Institute for Public Affairs published newsletters entitled "Synergy," later became "Politically Noted", 1990-1998, and later became "State Policy  and Leadership News."  
The file also contains a workshop brochure entitled "Enhancing Career Development Opportunities for State Employees: Building a High Performance Workforce."  Also included are two studies, "Enterprise Zones in Illinois, Study for Illinois Tax Foundation" and "A Public Service and Research Unit Review (FY98-FY06)."  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Flyers/Brochures
    Reports
    Newsletters
    Surveys
    Posters
  
  Box 1Box 11903Institute for Public Affairs Newsletters, flyers, brochures, etc.Folder 119041990-20051Study: Enterprise Zones in IllinoisFolder 219052Scope and ContentsStudy Conducted for the Illinois Tax FoundationConference: Enhancing Career Development Opportunities for State EmployeesFolder 319063Scope and ContentsBuilding a High Performance WorkforceInstitute for Public Affairs Annual ReportFolder 419071994-954Institute for Public Affairs Annual ReportFolder 519081996-975Institute for Public Affairs Annual ReportFolder 619091998-996Institute for Public Affairs Annual ReportFolder 719102000-20017Abraham Lincoln Presidential Center for Governmental Studies Annual ReportFolder 8191120028Center for State Policy and Leadership Annual ReportFolder 919122003-20049Center for State Policy and Leadership Annual ReportFolder 1019132005-200610Box 2Box 275549Public Service and Research Unit Review, FY98-FY06Folder 1191412/14/20071Scope and ContentsCenter for State Policy and LeadershipCenter for State Policy and Leadership Annual ReportFolder 2755502007-20082Center for State Policy and Leadership Annual ReportFolder 35174220093Scope and ContentsAlso Center for State Policy and Leadership Annual Report for 2009-2010 booklet identifying Unit Directors and how the Center is "Making a Difference in our World"Center for State Policy and Leadership Annual ReportFolder 47555120114

