<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.95Archon Finding Aid Title MC.95Matthew EtzelUIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:30:47 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC95. Donner Family Collection, 1835-2010
    
      Springer, Don
    
    
      Springer, William
    
    
      Donner Family
    
    MC.95
    751
    
      9.00 Cubic Feet
    
    
      7 cubic feet, 62 books, artifacts, and 7 oversize items. other_unmapped
    
    1835-2010
    Date acquired: 09/03/2008
    1
    2
    3
    4
    5
    6
    7
    8
    Folder16
    Series 5
    Item 3
    Series 5
    Item 4
    Series 5
    Item 5
    Series 5
    Item 6
    Series 5
    Item 7
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The Donner Family Collection consists of newspaper articles, artifacts, books, correspondence, photographs, articles, journals, newsletters, brochures, notes, photocopies, posters, land grants and deeds, videocassettes, cassette tapes and CD-ROMs. The material pertains to the family of George Donner, who left Sangamon County, Illinois in 1846 to emigrate to California. After a series of mishaps and delays, they and their emigrant party were trapped by heavy snow and faced starvation in the Sierra Nevada Mountains in the winter of 1846-47. The collection also documents the Oregon Trail and western migration in general. 

The material was collected by William Springer and his brother Don, direct descendants of George Donner. 

Series 1, the Donner Party (Boxes 1-2, and 3, folders 1-17), concentrates on the history of the Donner Party as well as newspaper articles on the Donner Family. There is a large section on Donner Family genealogy, specifically focusing on the Donner Family Reunion in 1996. The series also has photographs of the Donner Museum and various Donner memorials, taken by Don and William Springer.

Series 2, Donner Culture (Box 3, folders 18-19 and box 4, folders 1-9), concentrates on the Donner Party as represented in various media. It contains notes, newspaper articles, correspondence, pamphlets, and audio and videotapes of songs, plays, movies, documentaries, and an opera relating to the Donner Party. 

Series 3, Oregon Trail, 1842-1860 (Box 4, folders 10-17, and boxes 5-7), concentrates on the history of the Oregon Trail and westward expansion. Much of the material relates to the Oregon-California Trail Association (OCTA), its journal, membership information and newsletters, and photocopies of books on the Oregon Trail. Also contains photographs from trips by the Springer brothers along the Oregon Trail. 

Series 4 contains books shelved in Special Collections. These are mostly books on the Donner Party, including histories, children's literature, fiction, a graphic novel, and poetry. Also contains books on the history of the Oregon Trail. Some of the books have notes and annotations by the Springer brothers.
September, 2009 - additional books for Special Collection.

Series 5 consists of artifacts, posters and documents donated by the Springer family that are related to the Donner family: original land patents dating from 1835 and 1841, commemorative plate, covered wagon replica, a large reprint of  a western region map dating from 1846, and various framed posters. Part of the collection is located in the Oversize cabinet.

The collection is arranged topically. The earliest original material dates from 1835 and photocopied and reprinted material dates back to 1840.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Topical  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Don Springer, William Springer  
  
    Accruals and Additions
September 24, 2009
Eleven additional books donated by Don Springer.  
  
    Processing Information
All folder titles are original unless in brackets.  
  
    Book
    Correspondence
    Videotapes
    Newspaper Clippings
    Journal Articles
    Photocopies
    Photographs
    Newsletters
    Newspapers
  
  Donner PartySeries 132087Box 1Box 132090Donner Party BooksFolder 1345691977-19831Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, newspapers articles, and receipts regarding the search for and purchase of books relating to the Donner Party. Also contains bibliographies of Donner Party books, articles, newspapers, museums, libraries, historical societies and visual productions.Donner "Print": Nevada County Historical SocietyFolder 2345701954-19602Scope and ContentsNevada County Historical Society pamphlets volume 8, number 3, and volume 14, number 3.Donner "Print": Donner Articles and CartoonsFolder 3345711980-19923Scope and ContentsAn undated newspaper article on Tamsen Donner by David Galloway with a handwritten note on top (photocopy); a photocopy of the entry on George Donner in Who Was Who in America, 1967 edition; a Popular Mechanics magazine article, December 1988; obituary of Mrs. Elizabeth Donner, from the Illinois State Journal, 11/30/1905 (photocopy); a letter to the editor in American History magazine, January 1987; two "The Far Side" comics, dated 1980 and 12/25/1992; an article with enlarged pictures of George Donner; and a newspaper article on the Donner Party rescue, 10/25/1987 (photocopy).Donner "Print": Truckee (CA) BooksFolder 43457219794Scope and ContentsU.S. Post Office shipment notice, and correspondence regarding the purchase of History of Truckee by Joanne Meschery, Give Me a Mountain Meadow by Nona McGlashan, and Camp of Death by J. Quinn Thornton, and a newspaper article on Joanne Meschery.Donner "Print": Sierra Sun Newspaper (Folder 1 of 4)Folder 5345731977-19825Scope and ContentsPhotocopies of newspaper articles, photos and advertisements in chronological order, 5/20/1977 through 12/16/1982.Donner "Print": Sierra Sun Newspaper (Folder 2 of 4)Folder 6345741977-19826Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, notes, and receipts regarding subscription. Undated photocopies of newspaper articles, photos and advertisements.Donner "Print": Sierra Sun Newspaper (Folder 3 of 4)Folder 7345751977-19827Scope and ContentsOriginal newspaper articles, 5/20/1977 through 10/21/1982 in chronological order.Donner "Print": Sierra Sun Newspaper (Folder 4 of 4)Folder 8345761977-19828Scope and ContentsOriginal newspaper articles, undated.Donner "Print": Tahoe World Newspaper (Folder 1 of 2)Folder 9345771977-19799Scope and ContentsOriginal and photocopies of newspaper articles and correspondence, 5/26/1977 through 6/29/1979, in chronological order.Donner "Print": Tahoe World Newspaper (Folder 2 of 2)Folder 10345781977-197810Scope and ContentsOriginal newspapers, 5/26/1977 through 4/20/1978, in chronological order. There are gaps in the date span.Donner Park, Museum and Lake: Donner Museum - Grantville, UtahFolder 113457911Scope and ContentsA brochure on the Donner-Reed Pioneer Museum, undated.Donner Park, Museum and Lake: Donner Historical Society (Folder 1 of 2)Folder 12345801978-198212Scope and ContentsCorrespondence and photocopies of newspaper articles regarding the Truckee-Donner Historical Society.Donner Park, Museum and Lake: Donner Historical Society (Folder 2 of 2)Folder 13345811978-198113Scope and ContentsOriginal newspaper articles regarding the Truckee-Donner Historical Society, 7/5/1978 through 9/23/1982, in chronological order. There are large gaps in the date span. Most of the articles are undated.Donner Park, Museum and Lake: Donner Museum (Folder 1 of 2)Folder 14345831978-198214Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, newspaper articles (photocopies), photographs (4X6), negatives, brochures, notes, and postcards regarding the Donner Memorial State Park in California, including the museum located there. Includes the May 1978 correspondence relating to a gift to the museum - a photographic reproduction of a land deed by George Donner to William Donner, 3/13/1841. Copies of the land deed can be found in Box 1, Folder 23.Donner Park, Museum and Lake: Donner Museum (Folder 2 of 2)Folder 15345841978-198015Scope and ContentsOriginal newspaper articles regarding the Donner Museum or Donner Memorial State Park, 6/1/1978 through 4/24/1980, in chronological order. Most of the articles are undated.Donner Park, Museum, and Lake: Donner CampFolder 1634585198016Scope and ContentsColor and black and white photographs (4X6) showing a trip to the Donner campsite near Alder Creek in the Tahoe National Forest, undated. Also contains two newspaper articles, one dated 11/6/1980, the other undated.Donner Park, Museum and Lake: Sutter's FortFolder 1734586197617Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6), brochures, maps, notes, and postcards regarding the Sutter's Fort State Historic Park, in California. Some of the photographs are dated 1976.Donner at 100 years (1946) Reunion, Springfield (Folder 1 of 2)Folder 18345871945-197918Scope and ContentsPhotocopies of newspaper articles, color and black and white photographs (4X6), negatives, and correspondence regarding the Donner party during the year 1946.Donner at 100 years (1946) Reunion, Springfield (Folder 2 of 2)Folder 19345881945-197919Scope and ContentsOriginal newspaper articles, 1945 through 4/16/1979, in chronological order. One undated article.Donner at 50 yearsFolder 20345901935-197120Scope and ContentsA photocopy of an Illinois State Journal article written in 1946; a photocopy of the Illinois House of Representatives resolution 176, 4/15/1971; an article relating a brief history of the Donner Party, undated; newspaper article on the death of last Donner party member, 3/26/1935; photocopies of a Reno evening Gazette article on Donner Party, 3/30/1930; photocopies of a newspaper article commemorating the Donner Party, 5/21/1896.Donner Paper: DonneranaFolder 2134591197921Scope and ContentsNewspaper article with a poll on Donner Party, 12/10/1979; notes on Donner books and Donner Memorial State Park contact information, undated; newspaper article on modern wagon train rides, undated; list of future Donnerana objectives, undated.Donner MedallionsFolder 2234592198522Scope and ContentsCorrespondence and photocopies regarding the Donner Party commemorative medallions minted by the Nevada City Mint, 1/1/1985. Also contains a receipt for 10 of the medallions, 6/17/1985.Donner Land DeedsFolder 23345931835-184123Scope and ContentsPhotographs and photocopies of a land deed from George Donner to William Donner, 3/13/1841, and from the U.S. Government to William Donner, 9/8/1835.Tamsen's LettersFolder 24345941840-184624Scope and ContentsPhotocopies of two letters written by Tamsen Donner, one dated 1/12/1840 while she was in Springfield, Illinois; the other dated 5/11/1846, while in Independence, Missouri.George Donner's AnvilFolder 2534595199625Scope and ContentsA photocopy and color photograph (4X6) of an anvil said to have been owned by George Donner. Photograph dated 5/14/1996.George Donner Stud PosterFolder 2634596183126Scope and ContentsPhotocopies, Black and white photographs (4X6) and negatives of a poster advertising a stallion available for stud, 3/26/1831.Donner at 150 Years: Donner Reunion 7-20-1996 (Folder 1 of 4)Folder 2734597199627Scope and ContentsBrochures, notes, schedules receipts and plane tickets for the 150th anniversary of the Donner party, a reunion of Donner Party descendants held at Donner Lake, Truckee, California. Also contains two micro cassettes.Donner at 150 Years: Donner Reunion 7-20-1996 (Folder 2 of 4)Folder 2834599199628Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) from the reunion. Note says: "From Don."Donner at 150 Years: Donner Reunion 7-20-1996 (Folder 3 of 4)Folder 2934600199629Scope and ContentsBrochures, correspondence, color photographs (4X6), newspaper articles and notes regarding the reunion. Also contains a receipt to Phillippa Ball in payment for instructing a school, dated 8/5/1806.Donner at 150 Years: Donner Reunion 7-20-1996 (Folder 4 of 4)Folder 3034601199630Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, schedules, notes and newspaper articles regarding the reunion.[Donner Family Reunion]: California (Folder 1 of 4)Folder 3134602199631Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) and negatives of the reunion.[Donner Family Reunion]: Donner Party at Salt Lake (Folder 2 of 4)Folder 3234603199632Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) and negatives of the reunion.[Donner Family Reunion]: "Donner Trail Days" California (Folder 3 of 4)Folder 3334604199633Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) and negatives of the reunion.[Donner Family Reunion]: Donner Trail - Hastings Cutoff (Folder 4 of 4)Folder 3434605199634Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) and negatives of the reunion.[Donner Magazine Articles and Commemorative Coin]Folder 35346061992-199635Scope and Contents"Wild West" magazine article, dated April 1992; a Donner Party commemorative coin, undated; "Old News advertisement," undated; postcards, undated; notes, dated 8/27/1996; excerpts from magazines, undated.Box 2Box 232091[Donner TV Movie Listing, and Pamphlet]Folder 13460919921Scope and ContentsDonner book order form, undated; TV guide listing, dated 10/25/1992; Shoe ad, undated; pamphlet on the Donner Party, undated.[Donner Family Reunion 2006]Folder 23461020042Scope and ContentsCorrespondence regarding a possible Donner Family Reunion in 2006. One letter undated, the other dated 7/23/2004.Ordeal By Hunger and "The Smart Ones Got Through," by George R. StewartFolder 3346111955-19643Scope and ContentsPhotocopies of pages from: George R. Stewart. Ordeal By Hunger, 1964 edition, Massachusetts: Riverside Press, 1936, and George R. Stewart. "The Smart Ones Got Through." American Heritage. 6, No.4 (June 1955): 61-108.Palace Wagon Family by Margaret SuttonFolder 43461219574Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: Margaret Sutton. Palace Wagon Family. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1957.Names on the Land and Donner Pass by George R. StewartFolder 5346131945-19645Scope and ContentsPhotocopies of: George R. Stewart. Names on the Land. New York: Random House, 1945 and George R. Stewart. Donner Pass. California: Lane Book Company, 1964.For Fear We Shall Perish, by Joseph Pigney, and "The Donner Party" by Encyclopedia BritannicaFolder 63461419616Scope and ContentsPhotocopies of: Joseph Pigney. For Fear We Shall Perish. New York: E.P. Dutton and Co., Inc, 1961, and an article on the Donner Party from the Encyclopedia Britannica Library Research Team, undated.[Donner Party Articles]Folder 7346151870-19567Scope and ContentsPhotocopies of seven magazine, journal, and newspaper articles relating to the Donner Party, spanning the dates July 1870, September 1887, 5/21/1896, 3/30/1930, 1938, 9/8/1940, and 2/8/1956.[Unsorted Donner Party Materials: Articles] (Folder 1 of 4)Folder 8346161976-20058Scope and ContentsThis group of documents was unsorted. During processing, they were separated into four categories: articles, correspondence, genealogy and collected Donnerana. This folder contains newspaper and journal articles, original and photocopies, from 4/5/1976- Spring 2005.[Unsorted Donner Party Materials: Correspondence] (Folder 2 of 4)Folder 9346171976-20049Scope and ContentsThis group of documents was unsorted. During processing, they were separated into four categories: articles, correspondence, genealogy, and collected Donnerana. This folder contains correspondence, mostly related to genealogy, from 11/26/1976- December 2004. There is a gap between the years 1986-2004.[Unsorted Donner Party Materials: Genealogy] (Folder 3 of 4)Folder 10346181953-199610Scope and ContentsThis group of documents was unsorted. During processing, they were separated into four categories: articles, correspondence, genealogy and collected Donnerana. This folder contains notes, family trees, pictures, obituaries and book excerpts relating to Donner family genealogy, 6/10/1953 through 7/1/1996. Also contains photocopies of the marriage license between George Donner and Tamsen Dosier on 5/18/1839.Unsorted Donner Party Materials: Collected Donnerana] (Folder 4 of 4)Folder 11346191966-199611Scope and ContentsThis group of documents was unsorted. During processing, they were separated into four categories: articles, correspondence, genealogy and collected Donnerana. This folder contains "Donner Pass" song lyrics, 1974; "Donner Pass" paint color, 1996, Donner Party play, list of the Donner Party members; Sangamon County Historical Society Press Release dated 3/30/1996, including a written copy of a speech given by Donald Donner Springer, dated 4/16/1966; a log cabin floor plan, undated.Seminars: California Trail DaysFolder 1234620199612Scope and ContentsBrochures, schedules, and correspondence regarding the Donner Party Sesquicentennial at Truckee California during August 15-18, 1996.Grim Journey by Hoffman BirneyFolder 1334621193413Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: Hoffman Birney. Grim Journey. New York: A.L. Burt and Co., 1934.Donner Miscellany: 41 Diaries and Documents, Edited by Carroll D. HallFolder 1434622194714Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: Carroll D. Hall, ed. Donner Miscellany: 41 Diaries and Documents. San Francisco: L.D. Allen Press, 1947.History of the Donner Party by C.F. McGlashan and The Ungodly by Richard RhodesFolder 15346231940, 197315Scope and ContentsPhotocopies of excerpts from C. F. McGlashan. History of the Donner Party. Revised Edition. California, Stanford University Press, 1940 and Richard Rhodes. The Ungodly. New York: Charterhouse, 1973.Donner Pooperana (Folder 1 of 3)Folder 16346241995-199716Scope and ContentsBrochures, correspondence, articles and notes regarding the Donner Party, mostly concerned with Donner Party Sesquicentennial and Donner Reunion, 1996.Donner Pooperana (Folder 2 of 3)Folder 17346251995-199717Scope and ContentsBrochures, correspondence, articles, photographs (4X6) and notes regarding the Donner Party, mostly concerned with genealogy and the Donner Reunion, 1996.Donner Pooperana (Folder 3 of 3)Folder 1834626199618Scope and ContentsOriginal newspaper articles, dated 4/27/1996 through 7/22/1996. Several are undated.[Donner Articles and Genealogy] (Folder 1 of 2)Folder 19346271980-199719Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, notes, magazine, journal, pamphlet, and photocopies of newspaper articles, mostly relating to genealogy.[Donner Articles and Genealogy] (Folder 2 of 2)Folder 2034628199620Scope and ContentsOriginal newspaper articles, dating from 1/25/1996 through 11/3/1996.[Donner Pass Video]Folder 2134629197821Scope and ContentsDonner Pass: The Road to Survival. Dir. James L. Conway. Perfs. Robert Fuller, Diane McBain, and Andrew Prine. A Schick Sunn Classic Production. USA: Starmaker Entertainment, 1978. 1 videocassette.[U.S.D.A. Forest Service, On the Trail of Tragedy: The Excavation of the Donner Party Site]Folder 223463022Scope and ContentsOn the Trail of Tragedy: The Excavation of the Donner Party Site. U.S.D.A. Forest Service. Undated.  1 videocassette.[Donner Trail Trip] (Folder 1 of 4)Folder 233463123Scope and ContentsPictures, brochures, and notes from a trip following in the Donner Party's footsteps, mostly of the Donner Memorial State Park and Donner Museum. The materials are undated.[Donner Trail Trip] (Folder 2 of 4)Folder 243463224Scope and ContentsPictures, brochures, and notes from a trip following in the Donner Party's footsteps, mostly of the Donner Memorial State Park and Donner Museum. The materials are undated.[Donner Trail Trip] (Folder 3 of 4)Folder 253463325Scope and ContentsPictures from a trip following in the Donner Party's footsteps, mostly the Donner camp site. Some of the pictures are dated 1977, most are undated.[Donner Trail Trip] (Folder 4 of 4)Folder 263463426Scope and ContentsNegatives from a trip following in the Donner Party's footsteps. Separated into six categories: Miscellaneous; Virginia City, Tahoe City, Squaw Valley; Lake Scenes; Settlers Post; Donner Museum and Park; Donner Camp. They are undated.Donner BibliographyFolder 27346351979-198127Scope and ContentsA listing of books on the Donner Party, separated into eleven categories: Books - Complete; Books - Partial; Newspapers; Periodicals; Museums and Libraries; Historical Societies; Miscellaneous; Visual Productions; Music; Documents, Other Books of Interest; and Genealogy. Also contains newspaper articles, notes and correspondence on Donner materials such as plays and operas, 11/20/1979 through 3/12/1981.The Cypress by Hermann SeeleFolder 2834636197928Scope and ContentsPhotocopies of excerpts from: Hermann Seele. The Cypress and Other Writings of a German Pioneer in Texas. Translated by Edward C. Breitenkamp. Texas: University of Texas Press, 1979.Donner PartyFolder 29346372001-200429Scope and ContentsNotes, correspondence, and computer printouts on acquiring Donnerana. Mostly through Ebay, 12/3/2003 through 2/26/2004. Also contains a photocopy of a letter to the editor in Overland Journal.Trailing the Donners by Frank Mullen Jr.Folder 3078505199930Scope and ContentsTour guide booklet and brief history of the California trail.  Personal note written to Don Springer from Frank Mullen Jr. on July 29th, 1999
Added to collection 08-14-14The Hastings Cutoff by Roy D. TeaFolder 3178536199631Scope and ContentsShort guide booklet detailing the geography and history of the area between Grantsville and Donner Springs, Utah.
Includes a printed email regarding Donner Party event.
Added to collection on 09/11/2014Box 3Box 332092[Unfiled Donner Party Material: Articles] (Folder 1 of 8)Folder 1346381986-19981Scope and ContentsBox 3, Folders 1-8 contain material that was unsorted and unorganized when received by the UIS Archives. During processing it was separated into five categories: Articles; Newspaper Articles; Books and Book Excerpts; Brochures, Pictures and Notes; and Genealogy. This folder contains magazine, newsletter and journal articles and photocopies of articles relating to the Donner Party.[Unfiled Donner Party Material: Articles] (Folder 2 of 8)Folder 2346391986-19982Scope and ContentsThis folder contains magazine, journal and newsletter articles relating to the Donner Party.[Unfiled Donner Party Material: Newspaper Articles] (Folder 3 of 8)Folder 3346401946-19963Scope and ContentsThis folder contains photocopies of newspaper articles relating to the Donner Party.[Unfiled Donner Party Material: Newspaper Articles] (Folder 4 of 8)Folder 4346411982-19964Scope and ContentsThis folder contains original newspaper articles and clippings[Unfiled Donner Party Material: Books and Book Excerpts] (Folder 5 of 8)Folder 5346421980-19835Scope and ContentsThis folder contains photocopies of books and photocopies of excerpts from books on the Donner Party. Mostly undated. Contains a copy of the Donner bibliography, and receipts for books, dated 1980-1983.[Unfiled Donner Party Material: Books and Book Excerpts] (Folder 6 of 8)Folder 6346431910-19646Scope and ContentsThis folder contains photocopies of books and photocopies of excerpts from books on the Donner Party. Mostly undated. Contains Patrick Breen's diary, published 1910.[Unfiled Donner Party Material: Brochures, Pictures and Notes] (Folder 7 of 8)Folder 73464419977Scope and ContentsThis folder contains brochures, color photographs (4X6) and notes regarding the Donner Party, specifically the Emigrant Trail. Pictures are dated 1997.[Unfiled Donner Party Material: Genealogy] (Folder 8 of 8)Folder 83464519558Scope and ContentsThis folder contains notes and correspondence on members of the Donner Party and their descendants. Mostly undated, one letter dated 11/10/1955.[The Donner Party, A film by Ric Burns]Folder 93464620009Scope and ContentsThe Donner Party. Dir. Ric Burns. Narr. David McCullough. American Experience. PBS Home Video, 2000. 1 videocassette.[Oregon Trail Park, Donner Party Trail]Folder 103464710Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) of a trip to the Oregon Trail Park, following the Donner Party Trail. Undated.[Unfiled Donner Party Material: Books] (Folder 1 of 3)Folder 11346481977-200211Scope and ContentsThis folder contains published reprints Virginia Reed's narrative of the Donner Party, published 1977, ordering information on Donner Books, some dated August 2002, and notes.[Unfiled Donner Party Material: Articles] (Folder 2 of 3)Folder 12346492001-200512Scope and ContentsThis folder contains journal, newspaper and other articles on the Donner Party or Donner Family genealogy. The newspaper articles are mostly undated.[Unfiled Donner Party Material: Brochures and Photographs] (Folder 3 of 3)Folder 133465013Scope and ContentsThis folder contains brochures, flyers, and postcards of various Donner sites, mostly the Memorial State Park. Also contains color and black and white photographs (various sizes) of the Donner Memorial and Georgia, Eliza and Francis Donner. Undated.Patty Reed's DollFolder 14346511995-199814Scope and ContentsA copy of song lyrics by Keith Clark, dated 1995; a cassette tape, dated 1998; and a book about Patty Reed, a member of the Donner Party.  The book, Patty Reed's Doll: The Story of the Donner Party, by Rachel K. Laurgaard (California: Tomato Enterprises, 1989), was moved to Special Collections (See Series 4).[Donner Reunion, 2006]Folder 153465215Scope and ContentsBrochures, correspondence, articles and notes regarding a Donner Family Reunion in 2006. Also contains information on the U.S.S. Donner and other Donnerana. Undated.[Donner Bulletin]Folder 1634653200416Scope and ContentsComputer printouts of the Donner Party Bulletin, a website by Kristin Johnson that compiles information on the Donner Party. Printed 7/26/2004.The Donners: Their Courage is Our LegacyFolder 173465417Scope and ContentsA compilation of various Donner Party history material and genealogy. Edited by Barbara Wilder Politano, probably for the Reunion in 1996. Undated.Donner CultureSeries 232088Box 3Box 334607[Donner Party]Folder 1834655199218Scope and ContentsA recordable videocassette, labeled: "Donner Party, 10/28/92."[Donner Special]Folder 193465619Scope and ContentsA recordable videocassette, labeled: "Donner Special." Undated.Box 4Box 432094[One More Mountain and The Donner Party by Ric Burns]Folder 13465719941Scope and ContentsTwo recordable videocassettes, labeled "One More Mountain TV Movie, 3/6/94, Donner Party Story, and "The Donner Party, American Experience Documentary by Ric Burns." Undated.

"The Donner Party, American Experience Documentary by Ric Burns" DVD added, 2014[The Donner Party and The Donner Party: A Documentary Film by Ric Burns]Folder 23465819912Scope and ContentsTwo copies of: The Donner Party. Dir. Ric Burns. Narr. David McCullough. American Experience. Unknown Place: PBS Home Video, 2000.; one recordable videocassette labeled "The Donner Party," undated. Also contains notes, articles and correspondence regarding the Ric Burns film, mostly undated, but the letters are dated 8/20/1991 and 11/20/1991.["The Donner Party, Squaw Valley" and "Donner Pass, the Road to Survival"]Folder 33465919823Scope and ContentsTwo Recordable videocassettes, labeled "The Donner Party, Squaw Valley, 8/1/82" and "Donner Pass: The Road to Survival, TV Movie," undated.
"The Longest Winter" videotape, undated. added to file, 8/14/2014Donner Culture and Arts: Donner Opera (Folder 1 of 2)Folder 43466019824Scope and ContentsA recordable videocassette and cassette tape of the Donner Opera, presented in Squaw Valley, 8/1/1982.Donner Culture and Arts: Donner Opera (Folder 2 of 2)Folder 53466119825Scope and ContentsNewspaper articles, correspondence and notes about the Donner Opera, presented in Squaw Valley, 8/1/1982. Also contains copies of the program for the opera.Donner Culture and Arts: Donner MusicFolder 6346621974-19796Scope and ContentsCopies of the "Donner Pass" song by Frank Fara, dated 1974 and "Patty Reed's Doll" song by Keith Clark, 1979.Donner Culture and Arts: Donner TheatreFolder 7346631979-19827Scope and ContentsNewspaper articles regarding the play on the Donner Party, dated 11/20/1979 through 5/27/1982. Also contains a script of the play, "The Donners: A Chronicle in Twelve Scenes," by Robert Pinger, undated.Donner Culture and Arts: Donner-Play by Robert MurrayFolder 7.10690071975-767.10Scope and ContentsScript of, "Donner" a Play by Robert Murray presented by Tulane University.
Includes Theatre program from 1975-76 production of the play.Donner Culture and Arts: Donner Camp Dig DVDFolder 7.2069008n.d.7.20Scope and ContentsDonner Camp Dig with DVD titled, " "Trail of Tragedy," undatedDonner Culture and Arts: Donner Pass Movie (Folder 1 of 2)Folder 83466419788Scope and ContentsCorrespondence, dated 6/8/1978 and photocopies of newspaper articles on the Donner Pass TV movie by Schick Sunns Classic Productions, 6/6/1978 through 10/24/1978. Also contains two cassette tapes with the audio of the film.Donner Culture and Arts: Donner Pass Movie (Folder 2 of 2)Folder 93466519789Scope and ContentsOriginal newspaper articles regarding the Donner Pass TV movie, 6/6/1978 through 10/24/1978. Two of these are TV listings showing when the movie will play.Oregon Trail, 1842-1860Series 332089Box 4Box 434608Oregon Trail Information (Folder 1 of 2)Folder 103466610Scope and ContentsMaps, brochures, articles and postcards of the Western Emigrant Trails, undated.Oregon Trail Information (Folder 2 of 2)Folder 113466711Scope and ContentsMaps, brochures, articles and postcards of the Western Emigrant Trails, undated."Trail" Lead ActionsFolder 12346681984-199812Scope and ContentsNotes, correspondence, and articles on Donner family genealogy, Donner books, Oregon-California Trails Association and Friends of Alcove Spring Society. Also contained a book: Phillip W. Steele and Steve Cottrell, Civil War in the Ozarks (Gretna: Pelican Publishing Company, 1993), moved to Special Collections (See Series 4).[Oregon-California Trails Association: Catalogs and Correspondence]Folder 13346691996-200413Scope and ContentsCatalogs, correspondence, rosters, notes and brochures regarding membership to the OCTA and Kanza, a chapter of the OCTA. Correspondence dated 10/30/1996 through 6/14/2004. Catalogs are dated 1996 through 2002.[Oregon-California Trails Association: Conventions]Folder 14346701996-2005.14Scope and ContentsPrograms, schedules and registration forms for the OCTA annual conventions, 1996 through 2005.[Oregon-California Trails Association: Membership Rosters]Folder 15346711995-200315Scope and ContentsOCTA membership rosters from the years 1995, 1996, 1997, 1998, 2000, and 2003.[Oregon-California Trails Association: Lincoln Highway Association]Folder 1634672199816Scope and ContentsBrochures, pamphlets, book lists and correspondence regarding the Lincoln Highway Association, 1998.[Oregon-California Trails Association: Folio Newsletters]Folder 17346731995-200017Scope and ContentsNewsletters and catalogs from Folio, the newsletter of the Patrice Press, which lists books on the Oregon Trial. Issues run from November 1995 through May 2000.Box 5Box 532096[OCTA: "News From the Plains"] (Folder 1 of 3)Folder 1347271996-19991Scope and ContentsNewsletters of the Oregon-California Trails Association, dating from July 1996 through October 1999.[OCTA: "News from the Plains"] (Folder 2 of 3)Folder 2347282000-20032Scope and ContentsNewsletters of the Oregon-California Trails Association, dating from January 2000 through October 2003.[OCTA: "News from the Plains"] (Folder 3 of 3)Folder 3347292004-20053Scope and ContentsNewsletters of the Oregon-California Trails Association, dating from January 2004 through Winter 2005.[OCTA: Kanza Chapter] (Folder 1 of 2)Folder 4347301998-20034Scope and ContentsNewsletters and correspondence from the Kanza chapter of the Oregon-California Trails Association, dating from 2/2/1998 through November 2003.[OCTA: Kanza Chapter] Folder (2 of 2)Folder 5347312004-20075Scope and ContentsNewsletters and correspondence from the Kanza chapter of the Oregon-California Trails Association, dating from January 2004 through November 2007.[OCTA: "Overland Journal"] (Folder 1 of 8)Folder 6347321986-19906Scope and ContentsJournal of the Oregon-California Trails Association, dating from Spring 1986 through 1990.[OCTA: "Overland Journal"] (Folder 2 of 8)Folder 7347331991-19977Scope and ContentsJournal of the Oregon-California Trails Association, dating from Fall 1991 through Winter 1996-1997.[OCTA: "Overland Journal"] (Folder 3 of 8)Folder 8347341997-19988Scope and ContentsJournal of the Oregon-California Trails Association, dating from Spring 1997 through Fall 1998.[OCTA: "Overland Journal"] (Folder 4 of 8)Folder 9347351998-20009Scope and ContentsJournal of the Oregon-California Trails Association, dating from Winter 1998-1999 through Winter 1999-2000.[OCTA: "Overland Journal"] (Folder 5 of 8)Folder 10347362000-200210Scope and ContentsJournal of the Oregon-California Trails Association, dating from Spring 2000 through Winter 2001-2002.[OCTA: "Overland Journal"] (Folder 6 of 8)Folder 1134737200211Scope and ContentsJournal of the Oregon-California Trails Association, dating from Summer 2002 through Winter 2002.[OCTA: "Overland Journal"] (Folder 7 of 8)Folder 1234738200312Scope and ContentsJournal of the Oregon-California Trails Association, dating from Spring 2003 through Winter 2003.[OCTA: "Overland Journal"] (Folder 8 of 8)Folder 13347392004-200513Scope and ContentsJournal of the Oregon-California Trails Association, dating from Spring 2004 through Summer 2005.Oregon-California Trails Association (Folder 1 of 2)Folder 14347401963-199814Scope and ContentsMagazine articles, brochures, postcards, color photographs (4X6), negatives, notes and correspondence on the history of the Oregon Trail and relating to the OCTA. Most of the material is undated.Oregon-California Trails Association (Folder 2 of 2)Folder 15347411963-199815Scope and ContentsMagazine articles, brochures, postcards, color photographs (4X6), negatives, notes and correspondence on the history of the Oregon Trail and relating to the OCTA. Three issues of Crossroads newsletter, 1995-1997.Oregon-California Trail Association: "Historic Stamps along the Old Oregon Trail."Folder 16347421804-186216Scope and ContentsA poster of stamps showing various events that took place along the Oregon Trail, from 1804 through 1862. 
Located in Oversize Cabinet, Drawer #9Oregon and California in 1848, by J. Quinn Thornton Folder 1 of 3Folder 1734743197317Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: J. Quinn Thornton. Oregon and California in 1848. New York: Arno Press, 1973. Pages 1 through 343 of volume I.Oregon and California in 1848, by J. Quinn Thornton Folder 2 of 3Folder 1834744197318Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: J. Quinn, Thornton. Oregon and California in 1848. New York: Arno Press, 1973. Pages 344 through the end of volume I. Pages 1 through 225 of volume II.Oregon and California in 1848, by J. Quinn Thornton Folder 3 of 3Folder 1934745197319Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: J. Quinn Thornton. Oregon and California in 1848. New York: Arno Press, 1973. Pages 226 through the end of volume II.Box 6Box 632097Women and Men on the Overland Trail by John Mack FaragherFolder 13474619791Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: John Mack Faragher. Women and Men on the Overland Trail. New Haven: Yale University Press, 1979.Lake of the Sky by George Wharton JamesFolder 23474819782Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: George Wharton James. Lake of the Sky. Abridgement of 1915 Edition. California: Outbooks, 1978.California In-Doors and Out by Eliza W. FarnhamFolder 33474919723Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: Eliza W. Farnham. California In-Doors and Out. Nieuwkoop: B. De Graaf, 1972.Beyond the Mississippi by Albert D. RichardsonFolder 43475019684Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: Albert D. Richardson. Beyond the Mississippi. Reprint of 1867 Edition. Connecticut: American Publishing Company, 1968.The Emigrants Guide to Oregon and California by Lansford W. HastingsFolder 53475119695Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: Lansford W. Hastings. The Emigrants Guide to Oregon and California. Reprint of 1845 Edition. New York: Da Capo Press, 1969.Eyewitness to Wagon Trains West Ed. by James Hewitt and The Last West by Russell McKeeFolder 6347521973-1974.6Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: James Hewitt, Ed. Eyewitness to Wagon Trains West. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1973; and Russell McKee. The Last West. New York: Thomas Y. Crowell Company, 1974.The Old Trails West by Ralph Moody and Love Song to the Plains by Mari SandozFolder 7347531961-19637Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: Ralph Moody. The Old Trails West. New York: Thomas Y. Crowell Company, 1963; and Mari Sandoz. Love Song to the Plains. Lincoln: University of Nebraska Press, 1961.Overland in 1846 Volume I, Ed. by Dale Morgan (Folder 1 of 2)Folder 83475419638Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: Dale Morgan, ed. Overland in 1846. Vol. I. California: Talisman Press, 1963. Pages 1 through 239.Overland in 1846 Volume I, Ed. by Dale Morgan (Folder 2 of 2)Folder 93475519639Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: Dale Morgan, ed. Overland in 1846. Vol. I. California: Talisman Press, 1963. Pages 240 through the end.Overland in 1846 Volume II, Ed. by Dale Morgan (Folder 1 of 2)Folder 1034756196310Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: Dale Morgan, ed. Overland in 1846. Vol. II. California: Talisman Press, 1963. Pages 458 through 633.Overland in 1846 Volume II, Ed. by Dale Morgan (Folder 2 of 2)Folder 1134757196311Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: Dale Morgan, ed. Overland in 1846. Vol. II. California: Talisman Press, 1963. Pages 634 through the end.Trail to California ed. by David Morris PotterFolder 1234758194512Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: David Morris Potter, ed. Trail to California. New Haven: Yale University Press, 1945.From St. Louis to Sutter's Fort, 1846 by Heinrich Lienhard and Sutter's Fort by Oscar LewisFolder 13347591961-196613Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: Heinrich Lienhard. From St. Louis to Sutter's Fort, 1846. Norman: University of Oklahoma Press, 1961; and Oscar Lewis. Sutter's Fort. New Jersey: Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1966. Also contains a photocopy of a pamphlet on Sutter's Fort State Historical Monument produced by the California Department of Parks and Recreation.Ghost Trails to California by Thomas H. HuntFolder 1434760197414Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: Thomas H. Hunt. Ghost Trails to California. United States: American West Publishing Company, 1974.Donners, Tuckers, Kelloggs, and Culvers GenealogyFolder 153476115Scope and ContentsPhotocopies of articles, pictures and correspondence on the genealogy of various families, including Donners, Tuckers, Kellogs and Culvers.Life on the Plains by A. Delano (Folder 1 of 2)Folder 1634762197316Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: Alonzo Delano. Life on the Plains. New York: Arno Press, 1973. Pages 1 through 213.Life on the Plains by A. Delano (Folder 2 of 2)Folder 1734763197317Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: Alonzo Delano. Life on the Plains. New York: Arno Press, 1973. Pages 214 through the end.The Overland Trail by Jay MonaghanFolder 1834764194718Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: Jay Monaghan. The Overland Trail. Indianapolis: Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1947.Conquering the Wilderness by Frank Triplett (Folder 1 of 3)Folder 1934765188319Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: Frank Triplett. Conquering the Wilderness. New York: N.D. Thompson and Company, 1883. Pages 1 through 275.Conquering the Wilderness by Frank Triplett (Folder 2 of 3)Folder 2034766188320Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: Frank Triplett. Conquering the Wilderness. New York: N.D. Thompson and Company, 1883. Pages 276 through 501.Conquering the Wilderness by Frank Triplett (Folder 3 of 3)Folder 2134767188321Scope and ContentsPhotocopy of: Frank Triplett. Conquering the Wilderness. New York: N.D. Thompson and Company, 1883. Pages 502 through 716.Oregon Trail IIFolder 2234768199622Scope and ContentsCD-Rom computer game: Oregon Trail II. 25 year anniversary edition. [Cambridge Massachusetts] Softkey Multimedia Inc., 1996.Oregon Trail and Oregon Trail: A Complete HistoryFolder 23347691996-200223Scope and ContentsTwo editions of the CD-Rom computer game: Oregon Trail. Classic Edition. [Cambridge, Massachusetts] Softkey Multimedia, Inc., 1996; and Oregon Trail. 4th Edition. [Novato, California] TLC Education Properties, LLC., 1999. Also contains CD-Rom: Oregon Trail: A Complete History. [Unknown Place] Boettcher/Trinklein, 2002.Box 7Box 732098Fort Laramie to Nebraska, Oregon Trail (Folder 1 of 9)Folder 1347701Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) and negatives of a trip following the Oregon Trail. Undated.Oregon Trail, Wyoming (Folder 2 of 9)Folder 2347712Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) and negatives of a trip following the Oregon Trail. Undated.Casper to Ft. Laramie, Wyoming (Folder 3 of 9)Folder 3347723Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) and negatives of a trip following the Oregon Trail. Undated.Fort Casper, Wyoming (Folder 4 of 9)Folder 4347734Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) and negatives of a trip following the Oregon Trail. Undated.Independence Rock and Devil's Gate, Wyoming (Folder 5 of 9)Folder 5347745Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) and negatives of a trip following the Oregon Trail. Undated.Oregon Trail, Casper Wyoming to South Pass (Folder 6 of 9)Folder 6347756Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) and negatives of a trip following the Oregon Trail. Undated.South Pass to Fort Bridger (Folder 7 of 9)Folder 7347767Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) and negatives of a trip following the Oregon Trail. Undated.Fort Bridger, Wyoming to Salt Lake (Folder 8 of 9)Folder 8347778Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) and negatives of a trip following the Oregon Trail. Undated. Also contains notes.Donner Museum, Utah and Skull Valley (Folder 9 of 9)Folder 9347789Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) and negatives of a trip following the Oregon Trail. Undated. Also contains notes and brochures.[Oregon Trail Photographs] (Folder 1 of 6)Folder 10347791996-199810Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) of a trip along the Oregon Trail. Dated 7/22/1996. Also contains a magazine article: Richard A. Lovett. "The Trail to Liberty." Nevada Magazine. September/October (1998): 73-76.[Oregon Trail Photographs] (Folder 2 of 6)Folder 1134780199711Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) of a trip along the Oregon Trail. Dated 11/10/1997.[Oregon Trail Photographs] (Folder 3 of 6)Folder 1234781199712Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) of a trip along the Oregon Trail. Dated 11/9/1997.[Oregon Trail Photographs] (Folder 4 of 6)Folder 1334782199713Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) of a trip along the Oregon Trail. Dated 11/9/1997 through11/10/1997.[Oregon Trail Photographs] (Folder 5 of 6)Folder 1434783199714Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) of a trip along the Oregon Trail. Dated 11/10/1997.[Oregon Trail Photographs] (Folder 6 of 6)Folder 153478415Scope and ContentsColor photographs (4X6) of a boat. Undated.[Oregon Trail Exhibit and Monument Photographs] (Folder 1 of 5)Folder 163478516Scope and ContentsColor Photographs (4X6) and negatives of a museum exhibit. Undated.[Oregon Trail Exhibit and Monument Photographs] (Folder 2 of 5)Folder 173478617Scope and ContentsColor Photographs (4X6) and negatives of a museum exhibit. Undated.[Oregon Trail Exhibit and Monument Photographs] (Folder 3 of 5)Folder 183478718Scope and ContentsColor Photographs (4X6) and negatives of a museum exhibit. Undated.[Oregon Trail Exhibit and Monument Photographs] (Folder 4 of 5)Folder 193478819Scope and ContentsColor Photographs (4X6) and negatives of monuments along the Oregon Trail. Undated.[Oregon Trail Exhibit and Monument Photographs] (Folder 5 of 5)Folder 203478920Scope and ContentsColor Photographs (4X6) and negatives of a museum exhibit and monuments along the Oregon Trail. Undated.[Assorted Oregon Trail Videos]Folder 21347991923-199621Scope and ContentsFiles consists of an assortment of tapes regarding the Oregon Trail.
"The Oregon Trail, narrated by Red Steagall" and "America's Historic Trails with Tom Bodett" added 8/14/2014The Oregon Trail by Francis ParkmanAudiotape 10348091996Scope and ContentsFrancis Parkman. The Oregon Trail. Abridged. Read by Frank Muller. California: The Audio Partners, 1996. This last is an audio book. 4 cassettes.The Oregon TrailVideotape 1348001992Scope and ContentsThe Oregon Trail. Vols. 1-4. Dir. Mike Trinklein and Steve Boettcher. [Films for the Humanities, 1992]. 4 videocassettes.The Covered WagonVideotape 2348011923Scope and ContentsThe Covered Wagon. Dir. James Cruze. [Famous Players. Hollywood, California: Paramount Pictures Corporation, 1923]. 1 videocassette.West to Oregon: Along the Oregon TrailVideotape 3348021993Scope and ContentsWest to Oregon: Along the Oregon Trail. Dir. Ed Mellnik. [MECC. Portland, Oregon: EMA Video, 1993]. 1 videocassette.Westward the WomenVideotape 4348031994Scope and ContentsWestward the Women. Dir. William A. Wellman. [UA Home Video. Unknown Place: MGM, 1994]. 1 videocassette.Oregon Trail: BeginningsVideotape 5348041992Scope and ContentsOregon Trail: Beginnings. Vol. 1. Dir. Mike Trinklein and Steve Boettcher. [Films for the Humanities, 1992]. 1 videocassette.The Story of the Oregon TrailVideotape 6348051996Scope and ContentsThe Story of the Oregon Trail. Dir. Steve Boettcher and Mike Trinklein. [Unknown producer, 1996]. 1 videocassette. Also contains a booklet: "Oregon Trail Traveler's Guide."The Nebraska Heritage Collection: Platte River RoadVideotape 7348061992Scope and ContentsThe Nebraska Heritage Collection: Platte River Road. [KUON-TV. Lincoln, Nebraska: Great Plains National, 1992]. 1 videocassette.In Search of the Oregon TrailVideotape 8348071995Scope and ContentsIn Search of the Oregon Trail. Parts 1 and 2. Narr. Stacy Keach. [Nebraska Educational Television. Lincoln, Nebraska: Great Plains National, 1995]. 2 videocassettes.The Trail to OregonVideotape 934808Scope and ContentsThe Trail to Oregon. Gene and Betty Comfort. [Vistas Unlimited, unknown date]. 1 videocassette.The Oregon Trail narrated by Red SteagallVideotape 1178506America's Historic Trails with Tom BodettVideotape 1278507California Trail Magazines/ ArticlesFolder 22785041992-200022Scope and ContentsIncludes magazine with articles pertinent to the California Trail and Donner Party.  National Geographic "California Trails," The Californians "Donner Party Ordeal," and a magazine titled "California Trail: The Story Behind the Scenery.:Donner Family books shelved in Special CollectionsSeries 432099Altrocchi, Julia Cooley. Snow Covered Wagons. New York: Macmillan, 1936.Item 1348101Scope and ContentsHardcover. Poetry. PS3501.L795 S6 1936Calabro, Marian. The Perilous Journey of the Donner Party. New York: Clarion Books, 1999.Item 2348112Scope and ContentsHardcover. Juvenile literature. Two copies. 	 F868.N5 C33 1999The California Star: Yerba Buena and San Francisco. Volume I, 1847-1848. A Reproduction in Facsimile. Berkeley, CA: Howell-North Books, 1965Item 3501333Scope and ContentsOversized Hardbound. PN4899.C3.C3 1965Chapman, Mabel. At Great Price: The Story of Tamsen Donner. California: Mabel Chapman, 1992.Item 4348124Scope and ContentsPaperback. PS3553.H2875 .A8 1992Craig, Frankye. The Fateful Journey of Tamsen Donner. Henderson, NV: 21st-Century Publishing 2006Item 5501285Scope and ContentsSoftcover. PS3553.R24.F25 2006
Note: Signed by authorCroy, Homer. Wheels West: The Story of the Donner Party. New York: Hastings House, 1955.Item 6348136Scope and ContentsHardcover. F868.N5.C7 1955Curran, Harold. Fearful Crossing. Las Vegas, NV: Nevada Publications c1987Item 7501307Scope and ContentsSoftcover. F841.C87 1987DeVoto, Bernard. The Year of Decision, 1846. Boston: Little, Brown and Company, 1943.Item 8348148Scope and ContentsHardcover. F592 .D381 1943Dodd, Charles H. Ed. Not Half the Trubles: A Letter From Virginia Reed, May 16, 1847. California: 19th Century Publications, 1996.Item 9348159Scope and ContentsPaperback. F868.N5 M87 1996Fisher, Vardis. The Mothers. New York: Vanguard Press, 1943.Item 103481610Scope and ContentsHardcover. Fiction. PS3511.I744.M6 1943Franzwa, Gregory M. The Oregon Trail Revisted. Tucson, AZ: The Patrice Press 1988Item 115012711Scope and ContentsPaperback. F597.F73 1988Galloway, David. Tamsen. San Diego, CA: Harcourt Brace Jovanovich Publishers, 1983.Item 123481712Scope and ContentsHardcover. Fiction. Contains a newspaper clipping under the back cover, with a copy under the front cover. 	 PS3557.A4155 T3 1983 c. 1Guthrie Jr., A.B. The Way West. New York: William Sloane Associates, 1949.Item 133481813Scope and ContentsHardcover. Fiction. PS3513.U855.W31 c. 2Hawkins, Bruce R. and David B. Madsen. Excavation of the Donner-Reed Wagons. Salt Lake City: University of Utah Press, 1990.Item 143481914Scope and ContentsHardcover. Contains copies of pages 3, 6, and 128 from the book and two copies of a newspaper clipping about the books under the front cover. F832.G7 H38 1990Hardesty, Donald L. The Archaeology of the Donner Party. Reno: University of Nevada Press, 1997.Item 153482015Scope and ContentsHardcover. Contains a personal note from the author on front pages. F868.T2 H27 1997Hastings, Lansford W. The Emigrants Guide to Oregon and California. Massachusetts: Applewood Books. Originally Published 1845.Item 163482116Scope and ContentsPaperback. F864.H345 1994Hough, Emerson. The Covered Wagon. 2nd Ed. New York: Pocket Books, 1960.Item 173482217Scope and ContentsHardcover. Fiction. PS3515.O7593.C68 1946Houghton, Eliza P. Donner. The Expedition of the Donner Party and its Tragic Fate. Los Angeles: Grafton Publishing Company, 1920.Item 183482318Scope and ContentsHardcover. Contains a note from author on the title page. F868.N5.H8 1920Jackson, David W. ed. Direct Your Letters to San Jose. Missouri: Orderly Pack Rat, 2000.Item 193482419Scope and ContentsHardcover. Contains a note from the author on the title page. F593 .C26 2000Johnson, Kristin, ed. Unfortunate Emigrants: Narratives of the Donner Party. Logan: Utah State University Press, 1996.Item 203482520Scope and ContentsPaperback. Contains a copy of the October 2008 edition of the Sangamon Historical Society's: "Historico," between pages six and seven, which contains a review of the book. F868.N5 U54 1996
Note: Signed by the authorKeithly, George. The Donner Party. New York: George Braziller, 1972.Item 213482621Scope and ContentsHardcover. Poetry. Contains copies of pages 65-81 under the back cover. PS3561.E378.D6  c. 2King, Joseph A. Winter of Entrapment: A New Look at the Donner Party. Toronto: P.D. Meany Publishers, 1992.Item 223482722Scope and ContentsHardcover. Contains ordering information for the book under the front cover. F868.N5 K56 1992King, Joseph A. Winter of Entrapment: A New Look at the Donner Party. Revised Ed. California: K&amp;K Publications, 1994.Item 233482823Scope and ContentsHardcover. Contains ordering information for the book under the front cover. F868.N5 K56 1994Laurgaard, Rachel K. Patty Reed's Doll. California: Tomato Enterprises, 1989.Item 243482924Scope and ContentsPaperback. Juvenile literature. Found in Box 3, Folder 14. PZ7.L37279 Pat 1989Lavender, David. Snowbound: The Tragic Story of the Donner Party. New York: Holiday House, 1996.Item 253483025Scope and ContentsHardcover. Juvenile literature. F868.N5 L38 1996Limburg, Peter R. Deceived: The Story of the Donner Party. California: IPS, 1998.Item 263483126Scope and ContentsHardcover. Contains the receipt for the book under the back cover. F868.N5 L55 1998Lofts, Norah. Winter Harvest. New York: Fawcett Crest, 1955.Item 273483227Scope and ContentsPaperback. Fiction. PR6023.O35 1973Lopez, Enrique Hank. They Lived on Human Flesh. New York: Pocket Books, 1973.Item 283483328Scope and ContentsPaperback. TL553.9.L6635 1973Mabie, Mary Louise. The Long Knives Walked. Indianapolis: Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1932.Item 293483429Scope and ContentsHardcover. Fiction. PS3525.A11293 L6 1932Marcy, Randolph. The Prairie Traveler. 1965 Reprint. New York: Harper and Brothers, 1859.Item 303483530Scope and ContentsHardcover. Contains a label on the front cover that has William Springer's address written on it. F593.M32 1859aMattes, Merrill J. The Great Platte River Road.  Lincoln: University of Nebraska Press. 1987Item 315013131Scope and ContentsSoft Cover. F672.P6.M38 1987McGlashan, C.F. History of the Donner Party. 11th Ed. San Francisco: A. Carlisle and Co., Printers, 1918.Item 323483632Scope and ContentsPaperback. F868.N5.M33 1918McGlashan, C.F. History of the Donner Party. Revised Ed. California: Stanford University Press, 1947.Item 333483733Scope and ContentsPaperback. Contains the Springer-Donner family tree taped under the front cover. F868.N5 M33 1947McGlashan, M. Nona. Give Me a Mountain Meadow. Fresno: Valley Publishers, 1977.Item 343483834Scope and ContentsHardcover. Contains a letter from the author under the front cover and a personal note from the author on the title page. F869.T8 M32 1977McGlashan, M. Nona and Betty H. McGlashan, eds. From the Desk of Truckee's C.F. McGlashan. 2nd Ed. California: The Sierra State Parks Foundation, 1986.Item 353483935Scope and ContentsPaperback. F868.N5 M26 1986Morgan, Dale. Overland in 1846: Diaries and Letters of the California-Oregon TrailItem 365012936Scope and ContentsSoftcover. F592.O94 1993Mullen, Jr., Frank. The Donner Party Chronicles. Reno: Nevada Humanities Committee, 1997.Item 373484037Link to catalog record: The Donner Party chronicles : a day-by-day account of a doomed wagon train, 1846-1847 / by Frank Mullen Jr.Scope and ContentsHardcover. Contains a personal note from the author on the title page. F868.N5 M75 1997Murphy, Virginia Reed. Across the Plains in the Donner Party: A Personal Narrative of the Overland Trip to California, 1846-47. Colorado: Vista Books, 1995.Item 383484138Scope and ContentsPaperback. F868.N5 M8 1995Parkman, Francis. The Discovery of the Great West: La Salle. Edited by William Taylor. New York: Holt, Rinehart and Winston, 1956.Item 393484239Scope and ContentsPaperback. F1030.5.P225 c. 2Parkman, Francis. The Oregon Trail. Adapted by Norman Weiser. New York: Moby Books, 1979.Item 403484340Scope and ContentsPaperback. Juvenile literature. F592.P284 1979Parkman, Francis. The Oregon Trail. New York: Modern Library, 1949.Item 413484441Scope and ContentsPaperback. F592.P284 1949Philbrick, Rodman. The Journal of Douglas Allen Deeds: The Donner Party Expedition. New York: Scholastic Inc, 2001.Item 423484542Scope and ContentsHardcover. Fiction. Juvenile literature. PZ7.P52112 Jo 2001Rarick, Ethan. Desperate Passage: The Donner Party's Perilous Journey West. Oxford: Oxford University Press, 2008.Item 433484643Scope and ContentsHardcover. F868.N5 R37 2008Read, Piers Paul. Alive: The Story of the Andes Survivors. New York: Avon Books, 1974.Item 443484744Scope and ContentsPaperback. TL 553.9.R4 1975Readex Microprint. A Visit to Texas. Michigan: University Microfilms, 1966.Item 453484845Scope and ContentsHardcover. Contains a newspaper clipping between pages 242-243. F389.V84 1834BRhodes, Richard. The Ungodly: A Novel of the Donner Party. New York: Charterhouse, 1973.Item 463484946Scope and ContentsHardcover. Fiction. Contains an article written by the author under the back cover. PS3568.H64 U5X c.2Steed, Jack. The Donner Party Rescue Site. 3rd Ed. California: Graphic Publishers, 1993.Item 473485047Scope and ContentsPaperback. Contains an article by the author under the front cover and the author's signature on the front pages. F869.J64 S74 1999Steele, Phillip W. and Steve Cottrell. Civil War in the Ozarks. Gretna: Pelican Publishing Company, 1993.Item 483485148Scope and ContentsPaperback. Found in Box 4, Folder 12.Stewart, George. Ordeal by Hunger. New Ed. "With a Supplement and Three Accounts by Survivors." Boston: Houghton Mifflin, 1960.Item 493485249Scope and ContentsHardcover. Paperback. Hardcover copy contains the author's biography under the front cover. F868.N5 S7 1960 c.2Stewart, George. Ordeal By Hunger. New York: Pocket Books, 1971.Item 503485350Scope and ContentsPaperback. F868.N5.S7 1971Stookey, Dr. Walter M. Fatal Decision: The Tragic Story of the Donner Party. Utah: Deseret Book Company, 1950.Item 513485451Scope and ContentsHardcover. F868.N5 S77 1950Tannahill, Reay. Flesh and Blood: A History of the Cannibal Complex. New York: Stein and Day, 1975.Item 523485552Scope and ContentsHardcover. GN409 .T36 1975Tea, Roy. Hastings Cutoff: The "Long Drive" Across the Great Salt Lake Desert. Salt Lake City, Utah: Utah Crossroads Chapter, The Oregon-California Trails AssociationItem 535013253Scope and ContentsSpiral bound softcover. C40.T22Thornton, J. Quinn. The California Tragedy. California: Biobooks, 1945.Item 543485654Scope and ContentsHardcover. F868.N5 T5 1945Thornton, J. Quinn. Camp of Death: The Donner Party Mountain Camp, 1846-1847. California: Outbooks, 1978.Item 553485755Scope and ContentsPaperback. F868.N5.T525 1978Thornton, J. Quinn. Camp of Death: The Donner Party Mountain Camp, 1846-1847. 2nd Ed. California: Vista Books, 1996.Item 563485856Scope and ContentsPaperback. F868.N5 T525 1996Wachtel, Roger. The Donner Party. New York: Children's Press, 2003.Item 573485957Scope and ContentsHardcover. Juvenile literature. F868.N5 W33 2003Welvaert, Scott R. The Donner Party. Minnesota: Capstone Press, 2006.Item 583486058Link to catalog record: The Donner Party / by Scott WelvaertScope and ContentsHardcover. Graphic novel. F868.N5 W415 2006Werther, Scott P. The Donner Party. New York: Children's Press, 2002.Item 593486159Scope and ContentsHardcover. Juvenile literature. F868.N5 W47 2002West, Naida. River of Red Gold. California: Bridgehouse Books, 1996.Item 603486260Scope and ContentsPaperback. Fiction. Contains a note from the author on the title page, and the author's business card between pages 264-265. PS3573.E8245 R43 1996Willoughby, Lee Davis. The Donner People. New York: Dell Publishing Company, 1982.Item 613486361Scope and ContentsPaperback. Fiction. Some pages are marked in red pen. PS3573.I 45657.D66 1982Woestemeyer, Ina Faye. The Westward Movement. New York: D. Appleton-Century Company, 1939.Item 623486462Scope and ContentsHardcover. F591 .V24 1939Artifacts, oversize items, and original documentsSeries 550184Box 8Box 850427Covered Wagon model replica (16 x 8.5 x 6.5 in.)Item 1501851Scope and ContentsModel consists of wood frame and bed with metal nails and movable wheels, red cloth wagon cover pitched on wire bows, hinged front tongue.Commemorative Plate (13 x 8.5 in., oval) with metal plate standItem 250186n.d.2Scope and ContentsCommemorative plate of Donner party depicts a wagon train being led through the woods. Text says, "Donner Party 1846."  Band around the plate shows pictures representing early aspects of California such as a stagecoach and wagon train.  "Early California" is printed at the top of the plate with a brand encircled with rope is at the bottom.  Back of the plate imprinted "Tepco USA China."OVERSIZE cabinet 1OVERSIZE cabinet 150369An enlarged copy of an 1846 map of western regions (35 x 38 in.)Item 3503703Scope and ContentsFolded poster board with red pins marking California Overland Trail, green pins marking the Oregon Trail, and yellow pins marking the Donner Party's California destination.  Title of original map:  A new map of Texas, Oregon and California with the regions adjoining.  Compiled from the most recent authorities.  Philadelphia, published by S. Augustus Mitchell, N.E. corner of Market &amp; Seventh Streets, 1846.
Located in Oversize Cabinet, Drawer 10.Framed poster, (24 x 38 in.) ca. 1994Item 4504284Scope and ContentsTitled: "1844-1848 Sesquicentennial 150 years of the California Overland Emigrant Trail, Truckee River  Donner Pass, Donner Memorial State Park  Emigrant Trail Museum, Truckee, California." Artwork is a replica of a painting by Harold Von Schmidt titled "Rough Going over the Sierra," showing pioneers and their oxen hosting a dismantled wagon up a cliff.
Located in Oversize area.Framed poster, (18 x 24 in.)Item 5504295Scope and ContentsReading: "Tulane University Theatre Presents - Donner - Arena April 1-11 PM." Stage presentation funded by the New Orleans Bicentennial Commission, 1976. Poster shows a replica of a 19th century engraving of a wagon train.
Located in Oversize Cabinet, Drawer 9.Framed original land patent, 1835, (24 x 38 in.)Item 6504306Scope and ContentsPatent for land in Sangamon County, Illinois issued to William Donnar [sic] on September 8, 1835. Certificate No. 8250. Includes signature of President Andrew Jackson, likely made by a clerk. Document is encased in a wooden frame with a gold felt mat.
Located in Oversize Cabinet, Drawer 9.Original deed indenture, dated March 13, 1841 (7.5 x 11 in.)Item 7504317Scope and ContentsShowing sale of land in Sangamon County, Illinois by George and Tamzene Donner  to William Donner for the sum of one dollar "&amp; natural love &amp; affection."
Located in Oversize Cabinet, Drawer 9.Oregon-California Trail Association: "Historic Stamps along the Old Oregon Trail."Item 8507071804-18628Scope and ContentsA poster of stamps showing various events that took place along the Oregon Trail, from 1804 through 1862. 
Located in Oversize Cabinet, Drawer #9
[See also Series III, Box 5, Folder 16]

