<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>O.EA77Archon Finding Aid Title O.EA77UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:31:52 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    EA77 East Park Baptist Academy Project: Interview and memoir
    
      Anderson, Marjorie Ellen
    
    
      Henderson, Robert L.
    
    
      Moore, Jack
    
    
      Warren, Betty
    
    
      Wood, William Gregory
    
    
      Moore, Linda
    
    O.EA77
    777
    
      7.00 items
    
    Dummy Date
    Tapes et al
  
  
    Scope and Contents
EAST PARK BAPTIST ACADEMY PROJECT 
This memoir consists of five interviews with administrators and teachers of the East Park Baptist Academy in Decatur, Illinois. They discuss the creation and operation of the school: its governing board, curriculum, school activities, faculty, superintendent and administrators, buildings, enrollment growth, and its closing in 1989. They also discuss education in Christian schools, development of the history curriculum from a Christian perspective, and different philosophical approaches to education found in Christian and public schools. Included in the memoir are photocopied pictures of the school building, a newspaper article regarding the closing of the school, a list of graduates, and a paper entitled "Why We Need Christian Schools." 5 tapes, 344 mins., 122 pp., 2 vols. 
Interview by Linda Moore, 1989 
OPEN 
See collateral file: interviewer's notes, copy of the student handbook, copy of the letter informing parents of the school's closing, graph showing enrollment 1975-1989, and a copy of entrance requirements and tuition. 
See individual collateral files For tapes see individual names 
Anderson, Marjorie Ellen 
Henderson, Robert L. 
Moore, Jack 
Warren, Betty 
Wood, William Gregory  
  
    Related Materials
Interview and Memoir in Illinois Digital Archives.http://www.idaillinois.org/u?/uis,4690  
  Series 1Series 134879Anderson, Marjorie EllenItem 1348801Henderson, Robert L.Item 2348812Moore, JackItem 3348823Warren, BettyItem 4348834Wood, William GregoryItem 5348845

