<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>E.04.02/01Archon Finding Aid Title E.04.02/01UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:32:03 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    E4/2/1. University Legal Counsel Illinois Educational Labor Relations Board Case Files, 1986-1992
    
      University Legal Counsel
    
    
      Illinois Educational Labor Relations Board
    
    E.04.02/01
    302
    
      2.50 Cubic Feet
    
    1986-1992
    Date acquired: 12/21/1995
  
  
    Scope and Contents
(RESTRICTED)
Combined control card for E4/2/1-E4/2/16; Legal Counsel files are case files that pertain to grievance charges, dismissal cases, contractual agreements, and other court case files brought against the University.  They are retained by the University and housed in the Archives.This collection contains all of the Legal Counsel files in the E4/2 series.  This collection consists of the following files:  Illinois Educational Labor Relations Board Case Files, 1986-1992, Grievance Files, 1984-1992, Grants and Contracts, 1983-1991, Veterans Administration, 1986-1987, National League of Nursing Review, Inactive Files, 1984-1989, Accession of 8/27/1997 (Inactive files, Litigation BOR/SSU, Legal Counsel, Miscellaneous Documents, and Martin v. SSU), Grievance Files, 1975-1992, Huck Investigation, 1991-1993, Accession Dates 1999-2000 (Brewer Grievance and Individual Files), Miscellaneous Files, 1979-1992, Closed Cases, 1990-2000, Accession Date 8/21/2003, Accession Date 1/07/2002, Accession Date 3/30/2004, and Accession Date 1/24/1996.  This collection is RESTRICTED and is continuously added to when files are received.  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
RESTRICTED  
  
    Related Materials
Index of Files:
E4/02/01	Illinois Educational Labor Relations Board Case Files, 1986-1992
E4/02/02	Grievance Files, 1984-1992
E4/02/03	Grants and Contracts, 1983-1991
E4/02/04	Veterans Administration, 1986-1987
E4/02/05	National League of Nursing Review
E4/02/06	Inactive Files, 1984-1989
E4/02/07	Accession of 8/27/1997
E4/02/08	Grievance Files, 1975-1992
E4/02/09	Huck Investigation, 1991-1993
E4/02/10	Accession Dates 1999-2000
E4/02/11	Miscellaneous Files, 1979-1992
E4/02/12	Closed Cases, 1990-2000
E4/02/13	Accession Date 8/21/2003
E4/02/14	Accession Date 1/07/2002
E4/02/15	Accession Date 3/30/2004
E4/02/16	Accession Date 1/24/1996  
  IELRB Cases – InactiveBox 161019AFT v. Board of Trustees – IELRB No:  96-CA-0014-AFolder 1610201Unfair Labor Practice Charge – (IELRB No:  86-CA-0047-S)   AFSCMEFolder 2610212Urbanek v. AFSCME – (IELRB No:  87-RD-0003-S)Folder 36102219873UPI v. SSU  (ULP No: 1)Folder 4610234UPI v. SSU  (ULP No: 1)Folder 5610245UPI v. SSU  (ULP No: 2)Folder 6610256UPI v. BOR/SSU (Charge No: 3)  IELRB No:  88-CA-0039-SFolder 7610267BOR v. IELRB No:  89-CA-0030-S and 89-CA-0035-SFolder 8610278Scope and Contents(Release Time/Equity)IELRB Case No:  89-UC-0014-SFolder 9610289BOR v. UPI – Department Chairs (1990)  90-CA-0030-SFolder 106102910IELRB Cases – InactiveBox 261030IELRB 90-CA-0032-S  (Theresa Rosen)Folder 1610311IELRB 90-CA-0039-S / 90-CA-0040-S / 90-CA-0049-SFolder 2610322Sakolsky Promotion Denial 90-CA-0002-S   90-CB-0001-SFolder 3610333IELRB No:  90-RC-0026-S  1990Folder 4610344IELRB No:  90-RC-0026-S  1990Folder 5610355IELRB No:  90-RC-0026-S  1990Folder 6610366IELRB No:  90-RC-0026-S  1990Folder 7610377IELRB Cases – InactiveBox 361038UPI, Local 4100, IFT-AFL-CIO and BRO / SSUFolder 1610391Scope and Contents(IERLB Case No:  91-CA-0007-S  1990)IELRB Case No:  91-CA-0020-S  (1990 UPI v. BOR/SSU)Folder 2610402IELRB Case No:  91-CA-0063-S (1992)Folder 3610413ULP 92-CA-0018-S  (Health Benefits)Folder 4610424UPI v. BOR/SSU – IELRB Case No:  92-CA-0038-SFolder 5610435Board of Regents v. Illinois Educational Labor Relations BoardBox 46104486-CA-0087-C - Court DocumentsFolder 161045186-CA-0087 - Joint Stipulated ExhibitsFolder 261046286-CA-0087 - BriefsFolder 361047386-CA-0087 - OrdersFolder 461048486-CA-0087 - Notice of FilingFolder 561049586-CA-0087 - MotionsFolder 661050686-CA-0087 - CorrespondenceFolder 761051786-CA-0087 - AnswersFolder 861052886-CA-0087 - PetitionsFolder 9610539IELRB - Charge Against EmployerFolder 106105410Box 5Box 561055State of Illinois - University Civil Service Merit Board - Public HearingFolder 1610561Petition for Leave to Appeal of the American Federation of State, Community and Municipal Employees, AFL-CIOFolder 2610572Answer to Petition for Leave to AppealFolder 3610583Brief in Support of respondents Board of Governors of State Colleges and Universities and SIUFolder 4610594Brief of the Board of Trustees of the University of IllinoisFolder 5610605Answer to the Board of Trustees of the University of IllinoisFolder 6610616Answer to the Petition for leave to appealFolder 7610627Box 6Box 661063Brief and Appendix of PetitionerFolder 1610641Brief of the Board of Regents of the regency universities systemFolder 2610652Petitioner's Reply Brief to Brief of Respondents University Civil Service Merit BoardFolder 3610663Brief of University Civil Service Merit BoardFolder 4610674Brief of Respondent - Illinois Educational Labor Relations BoardFolder 5610685Brief of Respondent - Illinois Educational Labor Relations BoardFolder 6610696Petitioner's Reply Brief to Responsive Briefs of Some RespondentsFolder 7610707Petitioner for Leave to AppealFolder 8610718Brief of Respondent American Federation of State County and Municipal Employees, AFL-CIOFolder 9610729Petitioner for RehearingFolder 106107310Petitioner's Reply Reply to Brief of Respondent IELRBFolder 116107411University of Illinois - Policy and Rules NonacademicFolder 126107512Illinois Register - State Universities Civil Service SystemFolder 136107613Contracts between Board of Trustees of SIU, and U of I and American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees, AFL-CIOFolder 146107714Collective Barging AgreementsFolder 156107815Scope and ContentsBetween Board of Regents of Regency Universities, Board of Governors of State Colleges and Universities and NIU, NEIU, EIU, SSU, and the American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees, AFL-CIOPolicies Affecting Civil Service Employees at SIUEFolder 166107916Board of Regents - Civil Service EmployeesFolder 176108017	ExhibitsFolder 186108118University of Illinois at Champaign-Urbana Campus Administrative Manual Personnel PoliciesFolder 196108219Policies, Procedures, and Regulations, SIUCFolder 206108320Personnel Policies Applicable to all employees of SIUE - Sections I and IIFolder 216108421

