<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.01.04/01Archon Finding Aid Title J.01.04/01UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:35:06 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J1/4/1. Vice President Academic Affairs University Grants &amp; Contracts Comm Records, 1973-1979
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    J.01.04/01
    354
    
      1.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1973-1979
    Date acquired: 01/17/1979
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Series contains grant proposals, committee memos, agenda minutes, reports, position papers and legal opinions. File also includes brochures, papers, publications, and draft policies. Working papers, including grants and contracts proposals, FY 1978.  Legal options, policy statements on patents and copyrighting.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Dick Sames and Mary McDonald  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Revised on 7/31/1990 and 8/8/1997  
  Box 1Box 149124Agendas, Minutes, Reports, MemosFolder 149125January-April 19731Agendas, Minutes, Reports, MemosFolder 249126May-June 19732Agendas, Minutes, Reports, MemosFolder 349127July-September 19733Agendas, Minutes, Reports, MemosFolder 449128October-December 19734Agendas, Minutes, Reports, MemosFolder 549129January-May 19745Agendas, Minutes, Reports, MemosFolder 649130June-December 19746Box 2Box 249131Agendas, Minutes, Reports, MemosFolder 1491321975-1Grant ProposalsFolder 2491332Governor's Office of Manpower and Human DevelopmentFolder 34913419753Scope and ContentsLabor Market Survey, L. W. MurrayIllinois Division of Vocational and Technical EducationFolder 44913519754Scope and ContentsOccupational Education Curriculum Workshops, Redge RanyardTitle IV, Adult Interracial InstitutesFolder 5491361975 and 19765National Endowment for HumanitiesFolder 64913719766Scope and ContentsLincoln Sites Project, Charles B. StrozierNational Endowment for HumanitiesFolder 74913819757Scope and ContentsLincoln's Thought and the Present: A Program for Historic Site Interpretation, Charles B. StrozierGrant Proposals, Nos. 1-6Folder 849139FY 19778Box 3Box 349140Grant Proposals, Nos. 7-9Folder 149142FY 19771Grant Proposals, Nos. 10-16Folder 249143FY 19772Grant Proposals, Nos. 17-22Folder 349144FY 19773Grant Proposals, Nos. 23-27Folder 449145FY 19784Grant Proposals, Nos. 28-37Folder 549146FY 19785Grant Proposals, Nos. 38-41Folder 649147FY 19786Box 4Box 449141Grant ProposalsFolder 149148FY 19781Stuart, Charles--Office of Human DevelopmentFolder 2491492Scope and ContentsGraduate Program in Rehabilitation CounselingBruzan, Raymond M.--National Science FoundationFolder 3491503Scope and ContentsTopics in Science ProgramSmith, Anna M.--Illinois Dept of PersonnelFolder 4491514Scope and ContentsEmerging Women in Management (2 folders)Katz, J.--Illinois Dept on AgingFolder 5491525Scope and ContentsCommunications, the Arts and Aging Training Workshops for the Professions (2 folders)Bunnell, R.--Illinois Office of EducationFolder 6491536Scope and ContentsEducation Policy Fellows ProgramMilner, S. B.--Illinois State PoliceFolder 7491547Scope and ContentsAnti-Terrorism ProgramJohnson--Science for CitizensFolder 8491558Scope and ContentsNational Science Foundation, Special PACsCohen, L.--Illinois House of Representatives, Additional InternFolder 9491569Cohen, L.--Illinois Energy Resources CommissionFolder 104915710Scope and ContentsEnergy Legislation ConferenceCohen, L.--Five Private Sector AssociatesFolder 114915811Scope and ContentsIllinois Private Sector Legislative Intern ProgramJohnson, D.--Illinois Law Enforcement CommissionFolder 124915912Scope and ContentsCriminal Justice AwarenessJohnson, D.--National Science FoundationFolder 134916013Scope and ContentsUndergraduate Participation in Social Indicator/Quality of Life Research (2 folders)Cohen, L.--National Science FoundationFolder 144916114Scope and ContentsIn-Service Teacher Education in Political ScienceRomans, G.--Illinois State TheaterFolder 154916215Scope and ContentsIST Summer FestivalStrozier, C.--National Endowment for HumanitiesFolder 164916316Scope and ContentsLincoln's Thought and Present Historic Site InterpretationFolder 1749164Shin, D.--National Science Foundation17Scope and ContentsScientists and Engineers in Economic Development (Korea)Moskoff, William--Illinois Insurance Laws Study CommissionFolder 184916518Scope and ContentsSex Discrimination in InsuranceRomans, G. &amp; Sangamon-Cass Consortium--Comprehensive Employment Training ActFolder 194916619Scope and ContentsSSU Young People's TheaterMilner, S. B.--Law Enforcement CommissionFolder 204916720Scope and ContentsEvaluation of the Process and Impact of Crime Analysis Units

