<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.04Archon Finding Aid Title MC.04UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:35:25 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC04. Abrams Collection of Historic Newspapers, 1917-1973
    
      Abrams, James
    
    
      Abrams, Edith
    
    MC.04
    10
    
      3.50 Cubic Feet
    
    1917-1973
    Date acquired: 03/00/1979
    1
    2
    3
    4
    5
    6
    7
    8
    9
    10
    11
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Optometrist James Abrams and his wife, Edith, collected newspapers after moving to Arthur, Illinois in 1916.

The collection includes copies of the Chicago Daily Tribune and other Illinois and Midwestern newspapers featuring historical headlines, particularly World War II, D-Day, and the Korean War.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
James &amp; Edith Abrams  
  
    Newspapers
  
  Box 1Box 1630President Wilson's Great MessageFolder 1631ca. 19171Scope and ContentsCopy of Woodrow Wilson's address to a joint session of Congress, asking for a declaration of war, April 2, 1917.  Contains a depiction of Wilson; published as a keepsake for readers.(Chicago Tribune)Folder 26321919-01-012"Roosevelt Dead" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 36331919-01-063Scope and ContentsArticles about the death of Theodore Roosevelt."U. S. Mourns Roosevelt" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 46341919-01-074Scope and ContentsArticles about the death of Theodore Roosevelt."Theodore Roosevelt's Last Resting Place" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 56351919-01-095Scope and ContentsArticles about the death of Theodore Roosevelt.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 66361919-02-026Scope and ContentsPresident Wilson and his War Cabinet"Death Calls Wilson" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 76371924-02-047Scope and ContentsArticles about the death of Woodrow Wilson."Wilson is Dead; World Mourns" (Decatur [IL] Review)Folder 86381924-02-048Scope and ContentsArticles about the death of Woodrow Wilson.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 96391925-03-159Scope and ContentsImages from Calvin Coolidge's inauguration, various political leaders, workers at Stone Mountain in Georgia, spider webs, and military boats and airplanes."Shenandoah Falls: 14 Die" (Chicago Herald and Examiner)Folder 106401925-09-0410Scope and ContentsArticles about the crash of a giant dirigible in a storm in New Jersey."Flyers Pass Newfoundland" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 116411927-06-0511Scope and ContentsArticles about pilot Clarence Chamberlain's flight to Europe."U.S. Flyers Over Rhine" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 126421927-06-0612Scope and ContentsArticles about pilot Clarence Chamberlain's flight to Europe."Germans Hail U.S. Flyers" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 136431927-06-0713Scope and ContentsArticles about pilot Clarence Chamberlain's flight to Europe."Berlin Wild Over Flyers" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 146441927-06-0814Scope and ContentsArticles about pilot Clarence Chamberlain's flight to Europe.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 156451928-02-1915Scope and ContentsColor reproductions of paintings depicting George WashingtonPicture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 166461928-03-1116Scope and ContentsColor images of Grand Canyon wildlife; images of World War I battlefields, famous composers, historical sites, and celebrities.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 176471928-09-3017Scope and ContentsColor map of Europe after World War I; images of World War I battlefields, political leaders, and celebrities.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 186481928-11-0418Scope and ContentsImages of Alfred E. Smith and Joseph T. Robinson, the Democratic candidates for president and vice president, Herbert C. Hoover and Charles Curtis, the Republican candidates for president and vice president; portraits of political candidates from Illinois and other Midwestern states, other political leaders, and World War I battlefields."Hoover Sweeps Into Lead" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 196491928-11-0719Scope and ContentsArticles about the 1928 presidential election."Hoover Wins in 40 States" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 206501928-11-0820Scope and ContentsArticles about the 1928 presidential election."Hoover 444; Smith 87" (Decatur [IL] Herald)Folder 216511928-11-0821Scope and ContentsArticles about the 1928 presidential election.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 226521930-07-0622Scope and ContentsColor reproduction of a painting of George Washington; images of urban scenes, the new John G. Shedd Aquarium, military boats and planes, and ladies' fashions.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 236531930-08-1023Scope and ContentsColor images depicting various types of ivy; images of the Communist movement in the United States, foreign dignitaries, Chicago skylines.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 246541930-09-0724Scope and ContentsImages of Italy and American urban scenesPicture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 256551930-09-2125Scope and ContentsColor images of Chicago's Garfield park; images of airplanes, Chicago skylines, military training, and men's fashions.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 266561930-09-2726Scope and ContentsColor images of international movie stars; images of sporting events (baseball, horse racing, football, fishing), military, agriculture, and industry pictures.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 276571930-11-2327Scope and ContentsColor images of the Chicago skyline, industry and turkeys; images of aviation advancements, foreign armies (including pictures of Hitler and Mussolini).Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 286581930-11-3028Scope and ContentsColor reproductions of impressionist images of Chicago; foreign ceremonies, military exercises, aviation, and sports.Citizens Building Edition (Decatur [IL] Review)Folder 296591930-12-0729Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 306601930-12-2830Scope and ContentsColor image of a winter urban scene (with calendar for 1931); images of the Brazilian revolution, bibles, sports, New Year's parties and new technologies.Box 2Box 2661Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 316621931-01-0431Scope and ContentsColor images of actresses; images of the Brazilian revolution, military exercises, and duck hunting.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 326631931-01-1132Scope and ContentsColor images of Chicago children; images of aviation advances, foreign military engagements, animals, and sports.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 336641931-01-2533Scope and ContentsColor images of naval battles and Chicago scenes; images of aviation advancements, sports, and Chicago buildings.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 346651931-02-0134Scope and ContentsColor images of Chicago industry; images of aviation advancements, military exercises, and sports.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 356661931-01-1535Scope and ContentsColor images of Chicago children; images of aviation, celebrities, sports, and foreign locals.(Decatur [IL] Review)Folder 366671931-02-1536Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 376681931-03-0137Scope and ContentsImages of sports, aviation, and urban scenes.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 386691931-03-0838Scope and ContentsColor images of movie stars; images of Chicago urban scenes, sports, military exercises, and foreign locals.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 396701931-03-1539Scope and ContentsColor images of nautical scenes; images of aviation, automobiles, sports, celebrities, and dogs.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 406711931-03-2240Scope and ContentsColor impressionist images of Chicago industry; images of the Pacific fleet, veterans, politicians, sports, and Chicago parks.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 416721931-03-2941Scope and ContentsImages of the Stateville Prison riot, sports, aviation, automobiles, and celebrities.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 426731931-04-0542Scope and ContentsImages of Soviet propaganda posters, sports, outdoor scenes, aviation, and celebrities.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 436741931-05-0343Scope and ContentsImages of the Soviet Union, celebrities.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 446991931-05-1044Scope and ContentsColor images of spring flowers; images of famous mothers, the Chicago Jubilee, and the new Rosenwald Industrial Museum (later renamed the Museum of Science and Industry).Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 456751931-05-2445Scope and ContentsColor images of fox hunting; images of sports, bridges, the Chicago Jubilee, aviation, military parades, and horses.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 466761931-05-3146Scope and ContentsColor images of Chicago and military leaders; images of aviation, celebrities, springtime in Chicago, and the construction of a series of canals, locks, and dams to connect the Great Lakes to the Gulf of Mexico.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 477051931-06-0747Scope and ContentsColor images of Chicago gardens; images of aviation and sports.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 486771931-06-1448Scope and ContentsColor images of Chicago children; images of Nicaragua, and military aviation and ships.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 497061931-06-2149Scope and ContentsColor images of animals; images of sports and military exercises.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 506781931-06-2850Scope and ContentsColor images of Revolutionary War battles and Chicago parks.(Decatur [IL] Review)Folder 516791931-06-2851Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 527071931-07-0552Scope and ContentsColor images of naval battles; images of urban scenes, animals, sports, and aviation.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 536801931-07-2653Scope and ContentsColor impressionist images of children at the ocean; images of sports, and celebrities.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 546811931-08-0954Scope and ContentsColor impressionist images of children at the ocean.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 556821931-08-2355Scope and ContentsImages of sports, military reviews, and Northwestern University.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 566831931-09-2056Scope and ContentsImages of sports, zoos, and aviation.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 576841931-10-0457Scope and ContentsColor images of ladies' fashions; images of sports, industry, and aviation.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 586851931-10-1158Scope and ContentsColor reproductions of paintings of Christopher Columbus; images of sports, aviation, foreign locals, and nature.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 596861931-10-1859Scope and ContentsColor reproduction of Revolutionary War battle; images of sports, aviation, animals, military exercises, ladies' fashions, and celebrities."World Mourns Death of Thomas A. Edison" (Decatur [IL] Review)Folder 606871931-10-1960(Decatur [IL] Review)Folder 616881931-10-2161Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 626891931-10-2562Scope and ContentsColor images of frontier Americans, images military exercises, foreign locals, and ladies' fashions.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 636901931-11-0163Scope and ContentsColor images of fall foliage; images of foreign military exercises, animals, entertainment, aviation, and sports.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 646911931-11-0864Scope and ContentsColor images of forest animals; images of aviation, military exercises, ladies' fashions, and famous American sites (Statue of Liberty, Grand Canyon).Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 656921931-11-1565Scope and ContentsColor images of animals; images of military exercises, sports, and ladies' fashions.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 666931931-11-2966Scope and ContentsColor reproduction of a painting of George Washington; images of foreign locals, aviation, sports, and military exercises.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 676941931-12-0667Scope and ContentsColor images of steamboats and winter scenes; images of Monticello, sports, military exercises, aviation, and industry.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 686951931-12-2768Scope and ContentsColor reproduction of a 16th century Flemish calendar; images of sports, rock climbing, aviation, and theater.The Graphic Weekly (Chicago Tribune)Folder 696961932-02-0769Scope and ContentsColor images of the Lincoln Memorial, the Middle East; images of tobacco farming, and subways.The American Weekly (Chicago Tribune)Folder 706971932-02-2170Scope and ContentsColor reproduction of one of Gilbert Stuart's George Washington portraits.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 716981932-03-1071Scope and ContentsColor reproductions of paintings depicting the French countryside and portraits of noblewomen and military officers; images of foreign dignitaries, ladies fashions, automobiles and entertainment.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 727081932-07-3172Scope and ContentsColor reproductions of impressionist landscapes; images of celebrities and animals.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 737091932-08-0773Scope and ContentsColor images of beach scenes; images of urban scenes, sports, celebrities, animals, aviation, military exercises, and an early example of high speed photography.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 747101932-08-1474Scope and ContentsColor image of Yo-Hamite Falls in California; images of celebrities, aviation, military exercises, and animals."Vote Republican!" (The Prosperity Bulletin, Kankakee IL)Folder 757131932-1075Scope and ContentsPublished by the Kankakee Daily Republican-News Plant in Illinois, this newspaper features articles about and endorsements for Republican candidates for the 1932 election.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 767111932-10-1676Scope and ContentsColor portrait of the Republican candidate for president, Herbert Hoover.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 777121932-10-3077Scope and ContentsColor reproductions of paintings of American rural political life; images of celebrities, sports, animals, and automobiles."40 Million Vote Today" (Chicago Herald and Examiner)Folder 787141932-11-0878Scope and ContentsArticles on the 1932 presidential election contest."Landslide for Roosevelt Sweeps Republicans Out of Office in National Ballot" (Decatur [IL] Daily News)Folder 797151932-11-0979Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 807161932-11-1380Scope and ContentsColor reproductions of paintings of noblewomen and nautical scenes; images of celebrities, animals, and naval ships.(Chicago Herald and Examiner)Folder 817171932-11-1481Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 827181932-11-2082Scope and ContentsColor images of impressionist landscapes; images of celebrities, sports, animals, and riots in London.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 837191932-12-1183Scope and ContentsColor images of naval battles and a portrait of John Paul Jones.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 847201932-12-2584Scope and ContentsImages of aviation, sports, celebrities, and animals.Box 3Box 3721The Graphic Weekly (Chicago Tribune)Folder 857221933-01-0185Scope and ContentsImages of the Chinese New Year, wine, celebrities, and royal weddings."Coolidge Dead; Heart Fails" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 867231933-01-0686Scope and ContentsArticles about the death of former president Calvin Coolidge."Brief Rites at Coolidge Bier" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 877241933-07-0787Scope and ContentsArticles about the death of former president Calvin Coolidge.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 887251933-03-0588Scope and ContentsImages of beauty pageant contestants, reproduction of the front page of the Chicago Tribune from July 19, 1861, featuring articles on the American Civil War Battle of Bull Run."So. California Quakes Kill Many" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 897261933-03-1189Scope and ContentsArticles about earthquakes in southern California."New Quakes; Death Toll 140" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 907271933-03-1290Scope and ContentsArticles about earthquakes in southern California."143 Quake Dead: New Shocks" (Chicago Herald and Examiner)Folder 917281933-03-1291Scope and ContentsArticles about earthquakes in southern California.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 927291933-03-1992Scope and ContentsColor images of Revolutionary War leaders; images of foreign monarchy and beauty pageant contestants.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 937301933-05-2893Scope and ContentsColor images of the 1933 World's Fair; images of military exercises, aviation, celebrities, and beauty pageant winners."City Roars Welcome to World as Fair Opens; Roosevelt Sends Praise for Century's Progress; Michigan Avenue Cheers Parade of Nations" (Chicago Herald &amp; Examiner)Folder 947311933-05-2894Scope and ContentsArticles about the opening of the World's Fair in Chicago.Century of Progress Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 957321933-06-0495Scope and ContentsSpecial section highlighting the activities taking place at the World's Fair in Chicago; includes images of Chicago and the Fair itself.The Graphic Weekly (Chicago Tribune)Folder 967331933-04-0496Scope and ContentsImages of trapeze artists, bicycles, and ocean scenes.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 977341933-04-0497Scope and ContentsImages of the Queen of the Century of Progress Exposition Inaugural, ladies' fashions, trains, Hawaii scenes, and aviation.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 987351933-07-1698Scope and ContentsColor reproduction of Titian's "Venus and the Lute Player;" images of ladies' fashions, nature scenes, and animals.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 997361933-08-0699Scope and ContentsColor images of firefighters; images of foreign scenes, aviation, celebrities, ladies' fashions, and military exercises.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1007371933-08-20100Scope and ContentsColor reproductions of impressionist church and beach paintings; images of aviation, ladies' fashions, celebrities, foreign scenes, and military exercises.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1017381933-08-27101Scope and ContentsColor images of hunting; images of sports, ladies' fashions, celebrities, animals, and naval ships.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1027391933-09-03102Scope and ContentsColor image of Queen Elizabeth; images of sports, aviation, celebrities, and foreign scenes.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1037401933-09-10103Scope and ContentsColor reproductions of paintings of Pocahontas; images of military exercises, foreign scenes, celebrities, ladies' fashions, boating, and animals.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1047411933-09-17104Scope and ContentsColor reproductions of painting of Dolly Madison and the Capture of the City of Washington during the War of 1812.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1057421933-09-24105Scope and ContentsColor reproductions of Revolutionary War-era events.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1067431933-10-08106Scope and ContentsColor reproductions of paintings of Queen Isabella of Spain and Christopher Columbus; images of sports, ladies' fashions, and animals.The Graphic Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1077441933-10-15107Scope and ContentsColor images of "Injun Summer" and new anthropology information."Roosevelt Pardons to 1,000" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1087451933-12-25108Scope and ContentsArticles on President Franklin Roosevelt's presidential pardons.People Furniture Co.'s Fashion Festival (Unknown Publisher)Folder 1097461933109Scope and ContentsAdvertising supplement for home furnishings."New Era Dawns - Roosevelt" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1107471934-01-04110Scope and ContentsArticles about President Franklin Roosevelt's State of the Union address.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1117481934-01-07111Scope and ContentsColor image of the Battle of Princeton; images of foreign scenes, trains, and ladies' fashions.The Graphic Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1127491934-02-18112Scope and ContentsColor drawings of permanent buildings from the World's Fair (The Art Institute, The Field Museum, etc).Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1137501934-02-18113Scope and ContentsColor reproduction of a portrait of George Washington.Album of World Events (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1147511934-02-25114Scope and ContentsSpecial section of memorable events of the twentieth century, including images of President Franklin Roosevelt addressing congress, the Eastland Disaster (capsizing of a boat in the Chicago River), Japan invading China, and Pancho Villa and other Mexican revolutionaries.Album of World Events (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1157521934-03-04115Scope and ContentsSpecial section of memorable events of the twentieth century, including images of Mussolini, Theodore Roosevelt on safari in Africa, Amelia Earhart after her solo flight across the Atlantic, and American soldiers fighting in World War I.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1167531934-03-04116Scope and ContentsColor portrait of President Franklin Roosevelt; images of Roosevelt and his family, sports, ladies' fashions, celebrities, and animals.Album of World Events (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1177541934-03-11117Scope and ContentsSpecial section of memorable events of the twentieth century, including images of the Balkan-Turkish War, an Italian earthquake, the assassination of Japanese premier Yuko Hamaguchi, and Charles Lindbergh.Album of World Events (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1187551934-03-18118Scope and ContentsSpecial section of memorable events of the twentieth century, including images of Jeff Jeffries (heavyweight champion), Spanish and French military campaigns in Africa, President Calvin Coolidge, and the funeral of King Edward VII of England.Album of World Events (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1197561934-03-25119Scope and ContentsSpecial section of memorable events of the twentieth century, including images of the assassination of French President Paul Doumer,  train wreck in Hungary,  rescue workers saving patients from a Cleveland hospital after an explosion filled the clinic with gas, and the steamer Munleon running aground near Point Reyes, California.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1207571934-04-01120Scope and ContentsColor reproduction of an impressionist painting of a sailboat; images of celebrities, animals, industrial projects.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1217581934-05-13121Scope and ContentsColor reproductions of portraits of colonial-era children.(Decatur [IL] Herald)Folder 1227591934-05-13122Scope and ContentsSupplemental issue featuring pictures of Chicago."$8,000,000 South Side Fire" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1237601934-05-20123Scope and ContentsArticles about blaze that stuck the south side of Chicago.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1247611934-05-20124Scope and ContentsColor reproduction of boxing painting; images of animals, ladies' fashions, celebrities, and foreign scenes.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1257621934-08-05125Scope and ContentsColor images of nautical scenes; images of military exercises, foreign scenes, animals, and ladies' fashions.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1267631934-08-12126Scope and ContentsColor reproductions of paintings of harvest time; images of animals, foreign scenes, military exercises.(Chicago Tribune)Folder 1277641934-08-12127Scope and ContentsImages of modern interior decor.Illinois Magazine (Decatur [IL] Herald and Review)Folder 1287651934-08-12128Scope and ContentsContains map of Decatur, advertisement for postage stamps depicting natural scenes.(Decatur [IL] Herald and Review)Folder 1297671934-08-19129Scope and ContentsMap of the city of Decatur.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1307681934-08-26130Scope and ContentsColor images of the Fine Arts Building (later the Museum of Science and Industry) from the World's Fair.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1317691934-09-02131Scope and ContentsColor images of impressionist scenes.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1327701934-09-09132Scope and ContentsColor reproductions of paintings of battle scenes; images of foreign scenes, animals, and celebrities.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1337711934-09-16133Scope and ContentsColor reproduction of the Constitution.Box 4Box 4772"Lowden Sees Nation in Peril" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1347741934-06-11134Scope and ContentsArticles about former Illinois governor Frank O. Lowden decrying President Franklin Roosevelt's policies."WAR! Italian Bombers Attack Ethiopia; Troops Advance" (Decatur [IL] Review)Folder 1357751935-10-08135Scope and ContentsArticles about the Italian invasion of Ethiopia.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1367761935-12-22136Scope and ContentsImages of foreign scenes, military exercises, reproductions of paintings depicting Jesus."Mikado's Edict Ends Revolt" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1377771936-03-01137Scope and ContentsArticles about a revolt in Japan.The Graphic Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1387781936-03-01138Scope and ContentsImages depicting trans-Atlantic airplane service and European destinations.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1397791936-03-01139Scope and ContentsColor reproduction of a painting of a field worker; images of sports, celebrities, foreign scenes, and labor unrest during the turn of the century.Society; Travel (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1407801936-03-01140Scope and ContentsArticles and images concerning upper class society and travel.Fashion; Clubs (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1417811936-03-01141Scope and ContentsArticles and images concerning fashion and clubs and organizations."Hitler Act Hostile: France" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1427821936-03-08142Scope and ContentsArticles concerning Hitler's occupation of the Rhineland.Fashion; Clubs (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1437831936-03-08143Scope and ContentsArticles and images concerning fashion and clubs and organizations.(Evening Courier, Urbana IL)Folder 1447841936-03-12144(Decatur [IL] Review)Folder 1457851936-05-08145"Keynoter Asks 'U.S. Deal'" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1467861936-06-10146Scope and ContentsArticles about Senator Frederick Steiwer of Oregon's keynote address at the Republican National Convention in Cleveland."'Fight for Liberty': Hoover" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1477871936-06-11147Scope and ContentsArticle about former President Hoover's address to the Republican National Convention in Cleveland."G.O.P. United with Landon" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1487881936-06-12148Scope and ContentsArticles about the Republican nomination of Governor Alf Landon (Kansas) for President."G.O.P. Led by Landon, Knox" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1497891936-06-13149Scope and ContentsArticles about the nomination of Governor Alf Landon and Frank Knox as the Republican nominees for president and vice president.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1507901936-06-21150Scope and ContentsColor portrait of Governor Landon, the Republican nominee for President; images of animals and children.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1517911936-07-12151Scope and ContentsImages of Republican presidential nominee Landon and family, foreign scenes, celebrities, and animals.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1527921936-10-04152Scope and ContentsColor portrait of Republican nominee for president, Governor Alfred Landon.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1537931936-10-11153Scope and ContentsColor portrait of Franklin D. Roosevelt."Agree King Will Abdicate" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1547941936-12-10154Scope and ContentsArticles about England's King Edward VIII's decision to abdicate the throne."Edward Forsakes His Titles" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1557951936-12-11155Scope and ContentsArticles about England's King Edward VIII's decision to abdicate the throne.(Cincinnati Times-Star)Folder 1567961937-01-25156(Cincinnati Enquirer)Folder 1577971937-01-26157(Chicago Tribune)Folder 1587981937-01-26158"River Falling; Crest Reached, Belief List of Dead Stands at 132 in 11 States of Flood Zone" (Cincinnati Times-Star)Folder 1597991937-01-26159Scope and ContentsArticles concerning the Southern flood of 1937."133 Dead; 594,000 Homeless" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1608001937-01-27160Scope and ContentsArticles concerning the Southern flood of 1937."Flood Halts; Hope in South" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1618011937-01-28161Scope and ContentsArticles concerning the Southern flood of 1937."Whip C.I.O. at Ford Gates" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1628021937-05-27162Scope and ContentsArticles about the conflict between union workers and Ford Motor Company officials.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1638031938-07-03163Scope and ContentsColor images of Native Americans; images of foreign scenes and ladies' fashions."Lone Aviator Crosses Atlantic in Old Plane" (Decatur [IL] Review)Folder 1648041938-07-18164Scope and ContentsArticles about pilot Douglas Corrigan's unscheduled flight across the Atlantic."N.Y. to Ireland: Corrigan!" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1658051938-07-19165Scope and ContentsArticles about pilot Douglas Corrigan's unscheduled flight across the Atlantic."Hitler Issues Ultimatum" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1668061938-09-28166Scope and ContentsArticles concerning Hitler's invasion of Czechoslovakia."War? Peace? Parley Today" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1678071938-09-29167Scope and ContentsArticles concerning the meeting between British, French, Italian, and German heads of state."Hitler Wins! Moves in Oct. 1" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1688081938-09-30168Scope and ContentsArticles concerning the decision to give into Hitler's demands in an effort to avoid war in Europe."Staley Hearing Nears Close, With Rissman Amending Complaint" (Decatur [IL] Review)Folder 1698091938-12-05169Scope and ContentsArticles about labor board complaints against A. E. Staley Manufacturing Company.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1708101938170Scope and ContentsColor reproduction of painting depicting George Washington crossing the Delaware River.Box 5Box 5873"Death Take Senator Borah" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1718151940-01-20171Scope and ContentsArticles about the death of Senator Edgar Borah from Idaho."Register for Draft Today!" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1728161940-10-16172Scope and ContentsArticles about the formation of draft boards.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1738171940-10-27173Scope and ContentsColor portrait of Wendell L. Willkie, the Republican nominee for president; images of the war in Europe, the presidential campaigns, and ladies' fashions."Songs of the 1940 Campaign!" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1748181940-10-27174Scope and ContentsSheet music for the Republican campaign song, "We Are With You Wendell Willkie."Graphic Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1758191941-04-06175Scope and ContentsColored maps of Europe, Africa, and the Middle East."Report Japs in Philippines Capture of Guam Claimed" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1768201941-12-09176Scope and ContentsArticles on Japanese conquests in the Pacific theater of World War II."U.S. Admiral Killed in Oahu; Big Battle in Philippines!" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1778211941-12-11177Scope and ContentsArticles about the death of Admiral Isaac Campbell Kidd following the bombing of Pearl Harbor and Japanese advancements in the Pacific."U.S. at War With Germany, Italy After Axis Declaration; First Jap Battleship Sunk by U.S. Bomber" (Decatur [IL] Review)Folder 1788221941-12-11178"U.S. Planes Blast Another Jap Battleship off Luzon" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1798231941-12-12179Scope and ContentsArticles about the war in the Pacific theater."Japs Close in on Australia" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1808241942-12-24180"Story of a Fleet's 'Suicide'" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1818251942-11-28181Scope and ContentsArticles about French officers who ordered the dynamiting and sinking of their own ships so that the Germans could not use themMap Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1828261942182Scope and ContentsColored maps of different regions of the world, many outlining World War II military campaigns and territory acquisitions."Kill Tokio Bombers" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1838271943-04-22183Scope and ContentsArticles concerning the Japanese military executing American prisoners of war.(Chicago Tribune)Folder 1848281943-07-07184Map Sections (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1858291943185Scope and ContentsColored maps of different regions of the world, many outlining World War II military campaigns and territory acquisitions."Anger at Japs Sweeps U.S." (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1868301944-01-29186Scope and ContentsArticles about anti-Japanese sentiment in the United States over reports of the treatment of Allied prisoners of war by the Japanese military."Bataan Death March" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1878311944-01-30187"Turn River on U.S. Troops" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1888321944-01-31188Scope and ContentsArticles about the Germans plan to dam the Rapido River in Italy and flood the area controlled by the Allies."Navy Bombs Wake Island" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1898331944-02-01189"Marshalls Invaded" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1908341944-02-02190Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allied invasion of the Japanese-controlled Marshall Islands."Capture 11 Marshall Isles" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1918351944-02-03191Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allied capturing of several islands previously controlled by the Japanese."5 New Marshall Isles Won" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1928361944-02-04192Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allied capturing of several islands previously controlled by the Japanese."Balk Air Rescue of Nazis" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1938371944-02-05193Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allies successful military maneuvers in the Ukraine."3 Marshall Isles Seized" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1948381944-02-06194Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allied capturing of several islands previously controlled by the Japanese."Nazis Attack Italy Beach" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1958391944-02-07195Scope and ContentsArticles about Nazis attack on the Italian coast south of Rome."Slay 8,122 Kwajalein Japs" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1968401944-02-08196Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allied bombing of Japanese base Paramushiro.Box 6Box 6909"Calls Drake Case Accident" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1978411944-02-09197Scope and ContentsArticle about a murder investigation at the Drake Hotel."New Marshalls Attacks!" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1988421944-02-10198Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allied capturing of several islands previously controlled by the Japanese."Chaplin Indicted by U.S." (Chicago Tribune)Folder 1998431944-02-11199Scope and ContentsArticle about the charges brought against actor Charles Chaplain."Senate Bans Food Subsidy" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2008441944-02-22200"Repel Nazi Attack on Beach" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2018451944-02-14201Scope and ContentsArticles about the fighting taking place on the coast of Italy."Finn-Red Truce Seen Near" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2028461944-02-16202"Japs' 'Gibraltar' Bombed" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2038471944-02-17203Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allied bombing of Japanese-controlled Caroline Islands."Sink Ship, Kill 1,000 Yanks U.S. Attack on Truk Begins" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2048481944-02-18204Scope and ContentsArticles about the sinking of an American ship in European waters and the attack on Truk, a Japanese air and naval base."New Marshalls Invasion" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2058491944-02-19205Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allied capturing of several islands previously controlled by the Japanese."U.S. Ships Bombard Rabaul" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2068501944-02-20206"19 Jap Ships Sunk at Truk" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2078511944-02-21207Scope and ContentsArticles about the attack on Truk, a Japanese air and naval base."Love Feud! Physician Slain" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2088521944-02-22208Scope and ContentsArticles about a murder case in Washington D.C."5th Army Wins Rome" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2098531944-06-05209"Allies Pursue Fleeing Nazis" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2108541944-06-06210Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allies progress in Italy."Rush More Invaders" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2118551944-06-07211Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allies' advancements after the invasion of Normandy (D-Day)."Seize French Town" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2128561944-06-08212Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allies' advancements after the invasion of Normandy (D-Day)."Widen French Front" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2138571944-06-09213Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allies' advancements after the invasion of Normandy (D-Day)."Cherbourg Road Cut" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2148581944-06-10214Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allies' advancements after the invasion of Normandy (D-Day)."Gain in Cherbourg Drive; Americans 15 Miles Away" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2158591944-06-11215Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allies' advancements after the invasion of Normandy (D-Day)."Street Battle in Normandy Village" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2168601944-06-12216Scope and ContentsImages from French battlefields."60 Mile Front Firmly Held; Yanks Push Deeper Inland" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2178611944-06-13217Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allies' advancements after the invasion of Normandy (D-Day).Map Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2188621944218Scope and ContentsColored maps of different regions of the world, many outlining World War II military campaigns and territory acquisitions."Reds Widen Push on Berlin" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2198631945-02-01219"New Invasion Near Manila Yank Prison Rescue Told" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2208641945-02-02220Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allied invasion of Manila and the rescue of prisoners of war from a Japanese prison."2 Forces Race For Manila" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2218651945-02-03221"Manila Hears Yanks' Guns" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2228661945-02-04222"U.S. Flag Over Manila" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2238671945-02-05223"Manila Conquest Finished Jap Prison Brutality Told" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2248681945-02-06224Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allies gaining control of Manila and the conditions in Japanese prisoner of war camps."Manila Afire; Fight in City" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2258691945-02-07225Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allies fighting Japanese who became trapped on Manila."'Big 3' Fix Hitler's Doom! Meet in Black Sea Region" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2268701945-02-08226Scope and ContentsArticles about the meeting between President Roosevelt, Prime Minister Churchill, and Premier Stalin, during which the leaders discussed post-war plans."Canadian-British Push On!" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2278711945-02-09227Scope and ContentsArticles about the continued fighting on the Western Front."Big Battle in South Manila" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2288721945-02-10228"Germans Blast Roer Dam" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2298741945-02-11229Scope and ContentsArticles about the Germans detonating dams along the Roer river in hopes of stopping the advancing Allied forces."2 Spies Sentenced to Hang" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2308751945-02-15230Scope and ContentsArticles about the sentencing of two German spies who were caught after they came into the United States via German submarine.Box 7Box 7910"Carriers Raid Tokyo" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2318761945-02-16231"Bataan Recaptured" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2328771945-02-17232"7,000 Set Free in Manila" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2338781945-02-19233Scope and ContentsArticles about the release of Allied prisoners following the capture of Manila by Allied forces."Fight Japs on Iwo Volcano" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2348791945-02-20234Scope and ContentsArticles about Allied-Japanese fighting on Iwo Island."Battle on Iwo 'Toughest'" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2358801945-02-21235Scope and ContentsArticles about Allied-Japanese fighting on Iwo Island."Fists Fly on House Floor!" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2368811945-02-23236Scope and ContentsArticles concerning a fight that broke out between Democratic Representative John Rankin (Mississippi) and Democratic Representative Frank E. Hook (Michigan) after Rankin alleged that Hook was a member of the Communist Party."Storm Across Roer!" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2378821945-02-24237Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allied advancing across the Roer River along the Western front."2 U.S. Armies Ringing Saar" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2388831945-03-19238Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allied advancements on the Western front, including the closing in on Saar, located in south-western Germany."Invade Panay in Philippines" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2398841945-03-20239Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allied invasion of the Philippines, including the strategic island of Panay."U.S. Rips Jap Fleet!" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2408851945-03-21240Scope and ContentsArticles about Allied advancements in the Pacific theater."Fight Thru Ludwigshafen" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2418861945-03-22241Scope and ContentsArticles concerning Allied advancements on the Western front."Fan Out Over Rhine" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2428871945-03-25242Scope and ContentsArticles about Allied advancements on the Western front."Allies Gain in the Ruhr" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 2438881945-03-25243Scope and ContentsArticles about Allied advancements on the Western front."3rd Army Gains 27 Miles" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2448891945-03-26244Scope and ContentsArticles about Allied advancements along the Western front."Koenigsberg Won by Reds" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2458901945-04-10245Scope and ContentsArticles about Allied advancements on the Eastern front."Trap 285 Nazi Diplomats; U.S. Seized Closed Mines" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2468911945-04-11246Scope and ContentsArticles about Allied advancements along the Western front."Three Armies Drive for Berlin" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 2478921945-04-11247Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allied advancements on the Western front."Nazis Fail to Smash Bridgehead on Elbe" (Decatur [IL] Review)Folder 2488931945-04-17248Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allied advancements on the Western front."Yanks in Czechoslovakia, Set for Drive to Join Reds" (Decatur [IL] Review)Folder 2498941945-04-18249"Reds Gain in Berlin Drive" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2508951945-04-19250"Molotov Demand Rejected / Tell How Yanks Met Reds!" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2518961945-04-28251Scope and ContentsArticles about Russian Foreign Commissar Vyacheslav Molotov meeting with other Allied leaders and the meeting between American and Russian troops."4 Ships Sunk Off Okinawa" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2528971945-06-12252Scope and ContentsArticles about the Allied sinking of Japanese ships in the Pacific."Truman Shifts Stettinius" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2538981945-06-28253Scope and ContentsArticles about President Truman appointing Secretary of State Edward Stettinius, Jr. as the United States Ambassador to the United Nations."Planes Blast 23 Jap Ships" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2548991945-06-29254"3 Mile Borneo Beach Won" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2559001945-07-03255Scope and ContentsArticles about Allied advancements in the Pacific theater."Assail Charter as Fraud" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2569011945-07-12256Scope and ContentsArticles about the debate by Washington lawmakers over the formation of the United Nations."Typhoon Lashes Halsey's Fleet" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 2579021945-07-13257Scope and ContentsArticle about the destruction of twenty vessels of Admiral William F. Halsey's third fleet in the Pacific due to a typhoon."Old Glory Raised Over Berlin" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 2589031945-07-30258(Chicago Tribune)Folder 2599041945-07-30259Scope and ContentsSports Section"U.S. to Keep Bases: Truman Reds Push on in Manchuria" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2609051945-08-10260Scope and ContentsArticles about President Truman's intention to keep U.S. military bases abroad and the developments in the Soviet Union's land war against the Japanese."Eyewitness Tokyo Story!" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2619061945-08-31261Scope and ContentsArticle detailing a Tribune reporter's observations while traveling around the Japanese capitol."Surrender Signed!" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2629071945-09-02262Scope and ContentsArticles about the surrender of the Japanese military, effectively ending World War II.Box 8Box 8911(Chicago Tribune)Folder 2639081946-01-01263Scope and ContentsFacsimiles of twelve front pages from the Chicago Tribune that highlight important events during World War II:"War! Bomb Warsaw!" (1939-09-01)
"U.S. and Japs at War" (1941-12-08)
"Corregidor Falls" (1942-05-06)
"Repulse Jap Fleet!" (1942-05-09)
"Japs Repulsed at Midway!" (1942-06-06)
"AEF Invades Africa" (1942-11-08)
"Allies Invade Italy" (1943-09-03)
"Allies Invade France" (1944-06-06)
"Roosevelt is Dead!" (1945-04-13)
"V-E Day - Truman" (1945-05-08)
"Atomic Bomb Story!" (1945-08-07)
"Great War Ends!"(1945-08-15)"Two Killed at Truman Fete" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2649121947-03-05264Scope and ContentsArticles about the deaths of two people as a result of the massive crowds that showed up to hear President Truman speak at an event in Mexico City.'Coal Board Subpoenas Lewis" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 2659131948-03-29265Scope and ContentsArticles about the summoning of union leader John L. Lewis to appear before a presidential fact-finding board with regards to the soft coal strike."Airport Flooded" ([Portland] Oregon Daily Journal)Folder 2669141948-06-11266Scope and ContentsArticles about the flooding of the Portland airport due to heavy rains."Charge 4 Indicted Troopers 'Wronged'" (Indianapolis Times)Folder 2679151948-12-19267Scope and ContentsArticles about an ongoing trial involving four Indiana state troopers."Evarts' Chief No. 5 Charged in Murder" (Herald-Advertiser, Huntington WV)Folder 2689161948-12-19268Scope and ContentsArticles about a murder investigation involving the fifth police chief that the town of Evarts, Kentucky has had in the space of five months."Israeli, Egypt OK Armistice Talks" (Dayton Journal)Folder 2699171949-01-07269Scope and ContentsArticles about Egypt and Israel agreeing to talks to achieve an armistice in Palestine.(Dayton Press)Folder 2709181949-01-07270"Israel Protests to UN as Britain 'Alerts' Fleet, Land Forces" (Journal Herald, Dayton OH)Folder 2719191949-01-10271Scope and ContentsArticles about Israel's dissatisfaction with the presence of British troops in the Red Sea area."Chiang Forces Concede 'Tientsin Is Lost'" (Dayton Daily News)Folder 2729201949-01-11272Scope and ContentsArticles about ongoing fighting in China.(Hammond [IL] Courier)Folder 2739211949-02-24273(Lovington [IL] Reporter)Folder 2749221949-02-25274"More Than $1,000 in Prizes at Feldman's Anniversary Party" (Feldman Farm and Home Journal, Milford OH)Folder 2759231949-03275Scope and ContentsArticle about the events taking place at the Farm and Home Center's second anniversary celebration in Milford, Ohio.(Milford [OH] Record)Folder 2769241949-03-03276"Red Envoy Asks Spy Suspect's Release" (Cincinnati Enquirer)Folder 2779251949-03-06277Scope and ContentsArticles about the detaining of two Russian workers by the United States government on suspicion of being spies.(Indianapolis Star)Folder 2789261949-05-07278(St. Louis Globe-Democrat)Folder 2799271949-05-09279(Bement [IL] Register)Folder 2809281949-07-28280(DeKalb [AL] Times)Folder 2819291949-10-05281(Fort Payne [AL] Journal)Folder 2829301949-10-05282"Agree to End Long Hawaii Dock Strike; Mine Talks Set Today in Washington" (Terre Haute [IN] Star)Folder 2839311949-10-07283Scope and ContentsArticle about the end of a 159-day dockworkers strike in Hawaii.(Chattanooga News-Free Press)Folder 2849321949-10-08284(Chattanooga News-Free Press)Folder 2859331949-10-10285(Atlanta Journal)Folder 2869341949-10-14286"Convictions Deal Blows to Reds in U.S." (Evansville [IN] Courier)Folder 2879351949-10-15287Scope and ContentsArticle about the conviction of eleven leaders of the communist party in the United States for advocating violent revolution against the government.(Olney [IL] Daily Mail)Folder 2889361949-10-15288"U.S. Reds Get Knockout Blows" (St. Louis Globe-Democrat)Folder 2899371949-10-15289Scope and ContentsArticle about the conviction of eleven leaders of the communist party in the United States for advocating violent revolution against the government."NAACP Doubles Award in Dallas Bombing" (Texas Edition of the Call)Folder 2909381950-05-26290Scope and ContentsArticles about the NAACP offering a $1,000 reward for information regarding the bombing of several African-American homes in Dallas."Order Use of Draft; U.S. Tanks in Korea" (Decatur [IL] Review)Folder 2919391950-07-07291Scope and ContentsArticles about the build-up to the beginning of the Korean War."Revive Draft!  Call Boards U.S. Tanks Arrive in Korea" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 2929401950-07-08292Scope and ContentsArticles about the build-up to the beginning of the Korean War."Hoods, Officials Throng 1st Crime Session" (Chicago Herald American)Folder 2939411950-10-05293Scope and ContentsArticles about a government commission set up to expose links between syndicate crime and official corruption in Chicago."Planes Rip Frantic Reds Digging in North of 38th Record ROK Drive Slows" (Nashville Tennessean)Folder 2949421950-10-06294Scope and ContentsArticles about advancements made during the Korean War."New South Korea Division Invades Enemy Territory; U.N. Forces Await Orders" (Chattanooga Daily Times)Folder 2959431950-10-07295Scope and ContentsArticles about advancements made during the Korean War."U.S. Troops Take Key Border City" (Chattanooga News-Free Press)Folder 2969441950-10-07296Scope and ContentsArticles about advancements made during the Korean War, including the capture of Kaesong, only two miles south of the 38th parallel."Notre Dame Falls, Tide, Too" (Birmingham News)Folder 2979451950-10-08297Scope and ContentsArticles about college football.(Atlanta Constitution)Folder 2989461950-10-12298"U.N. Troops Closing in on Kumchon" (Chattanooga News-Press)Folder 2999471950-10-12299Scope and ContentsArticles about advancements made during the Korean War."Launch Broadway Widening Project" (Daily Journal-Gazette, Mattoon IL)Folder 3009481950-10-13300Scope and ContentsArticle about the widening of a major street in the Mattoon, Illinois business district."Shelling Hints New Landing" (Chicago Herald American)Folder 3019491950-10-13301Scope and ContentsArticles about advancements made during the Korean War."Bradley Raps Arms Lack" (Indianapolis Star)Folder 3029501950-10-13302Scope and ContentsArticles about General Omar N. Bradley's concerns over the rate of rearmament and the need for a stepped-up mobilization plan.(Olney [IL] Daily Mail)Folder 3039511950-10-13303(Arthur [IL] Graphic-Clarion)Folder 3049521950-11-02304(Chicago Sun Times)Folder 3059531950-11-09305(Cerro Gordo [IL] News)Folder 3069541950-12-28306"Spectacular Rose Parade Thrills Vast Throng" (Los Angeles Times)Folder 3079551951-01-02307(Duncan [OK] Daily Banner)Folder 3089561951-01-07308"New Lackland Probes Slated" (San Antonio Light)Folder 3099571951-01-28309Scope and ContentsArticles about the overcrowded conditions at Lackland Air Force Base in San Antonio, Texas."Lackland to Get New Super-Probe" (San Antonio Light)Folder 3109581951-01-29310Scope and ContentsArticles about the overcrowded conditions at Lackland Air Force Base in San Antonio, Texas."Ice Hits South Texas" (San Antonio Express)Folder 3119591951-01-30311Scope and ContentsArticles about a winter storm that struck in southern Texas, a rarity for the region."5 Degrees Friday Morn" (San Antonio Evening News)Folder 3129601951-02-01312Scope and ContentsArticles about a winter storm that struck in southern Texas, a rarity for the region"Low of 6 Degrees Here" (San Antonio Evening News)Folder 3139611951-02-02313Scope and ContentsArticles about a winter storm that struck in southern Texas, a rarity for the region"Allies May Not Cross Parallel" (San Antonio Express)Folder 3149621951-02-02314Scope and ContentsArticles about the proposed plan to have U.N. forces stop their northward advance at the 38th parallel if the Communists would accept cease-fire terms.(North DeKalb [AL] Record)Folder 3159631951-04-19315"Senate Passes Tax Hike Bill" (Illinois State Journal)Folder 3169641951-09-29316Scope and ContentsArticles about the U.S. Senate passing a bill to raise personal and corporate income taxes.(Alabama Rural Electric News)Folder 3179651951-10317(Times-New Era, Fort Payne AL)Folder 3189661951-10-03318(North DeKalb [AL] Record)Folder 3199671951-10-04319(Chattanooga News-Free Press)Folder 3209681951-10-04320(The Birmingham News)Folder 3219691951-10-07321"China Shifts Armies, Trying to Check U.N." (Birmingham Post-Herald)Folder 3229701951-10-09322Scope and ContentsArticles about developments in the Korean War."Reds to Answer U.N. Note Tonight" (Chattanooga News-Free Press)Folder 3239711951-10-09323Scope and ContentsArticles about the possible reopening of peace talks to end the Korean War."Reds Ask Immediate Truce Talks" (St. Louis Globe-Democrat)Folder 3249721951-10-10324Scope and ContentsArticles about the possible reopening of peace talks to end the Korean War."Germ War Threat Looms" (San Antonio Evening News)Folder 3259731951-11-12325Scope and ContentsArticles about the possibility of Cold War enemies targeting American farms and ranches through biological sabotage.(Evening Tribune, San Diego CA)Folder 3269741951-12-31326"Big Storm Hits So. Calif." (Los Angeles Evening Herald Express)Folder 3279751951-12-31327Scope and ContentsArticles about rainstorms that caused flooding in many parts of southern California, including Los Angeles.(Los Angeles Times)Folder 3289761952-01-02328(Los Angeles Times)Folder 3299771952-01-17329(Hermann Sons News, San Antonio TX)Folder 3309781952-02330"King's Neighbors in Tribute" (New York Journal American)Folder 3319791952-02-09331Scope and ContentsArticles about the death of King George VI of England.(San Antonio Express)Folder 3329801952-04-26332(San Antonio Light)Folder 3339811952-04-26333"Red POWs Face Crackdown" (San Antonio Light)Folder 3349821952-05-15334Scope and ContentsArticles about the prison conditions at the U.N. POW camp on Koje Island, South Korea.(Sumner [IL] Press)Folder 3359831952-06-12335"'Human Sea' of Chinese Breaches Allied Lines" (Charlotte Observer)Folder 3369841952-10-08336Scope and ContentsArticles about the continuing conflicts of the Korean War."U.N. Fights to Plug Breaks in Lines" (Knoxville News-Sentinel)Folder 3379851952-10-08337Scope and ContentsArticles about the continuing conflicts of the Korean War."Knoxville Colored GOP Leaders Attend Rally Here" (Chattanooga Observer)Folder 3389861952-10-10338"Reds Capture 'Gateway' to Seoul" (Chattanooga News-Free Press)Folder 3399871952-10-10339Scope and ContentsArticles about the continuing conflicts of the Korean War.(Times-Picayune, New Orleans LA)Folder 3409881952-10-10340"U.N. Gunfire Strips Embattled Hilltop" (Atlanta Journal and Atlanta Constitution)Folder 3419891952-10-12341Scope and ContentsArticles about the continuing conflicts of the Korean War."U.N. Forces Deliver Mightiest Blow of Year at Korea Reds" (Tampa Morning Tribute)Folder 3429901952-10-14342Scope and ContentsArticles about the continuing conflicts of the Korean War.Box 9Box 9991"Reds to Reward Plane Captors" (Cincinnati Post)Folder 3439921953-03-19343Scope and ContentsArticles about the Soviet government offering rewards for any solider who forces down any western Allied aircraft that are caught flying in Communist territory.(San Antonio Express)Folder 3449931953-04-25344(San Antonio Light)Folder 3459941953-04-29345(Tuscola [IL] Journal)Folder 3469951953-04-30346(Tuscola [IL] Review)Folder 3479961953-04-30347(Evansville [IN] Press)Folder 3489971953-10-01348(Chattanooga News-Free Press)Folder 3499981953-10-02349(Chattanooga Daily Times)Folder 3509991953-10-02350(Chattanooga News-Free Press)Folder 35110001953-10-06351(Corpus Christi Caller)Folder 35210011954-06-30352"Nixon Assails Democrats For Record of 'Cover Up' for Reds and Leftists" (Terre Haute [IN] Star)Folder 35310021954-10-20353Scope and ContentsArticles about Vice President Richard Nixon's contention that Democrats have "covered up" for Communists and other security risks.(Wall Street Journal)Folder 35410031954-10-20354(Chattanooga News-Free Press)Folder 35510041954-10-21355(New Mexican, Sante Fe NM)Folder 35610051954-10-24356"Russia Glowers at European Pact" (Roswell [NM] Daily Record)Folder 35710061954-10-24357Scope and ContentsArticles about the Soviet reaction to the possible rearming of West Germany."Adenauer Faces Treaty Revolt" (Birmingham Post-Herald)Folder 35810071954-10-25358Scope and ContentsArticles about West Germany chancellor Konrad Adenauer's reaction to the revolt in West German over the Paris agreement on sovereignty and rearmament."Soviet Talks Possible--Dulles" (Atlanta Constitution)Folder 35910081954-10-26359Scope and ContentsArticles about Secretary of State John Foster Dulles hinting at the possibility of talks with the Soviets over the issue of West Germany.(Sports Roundup, Chattanooga TN)Folder 36010091954-10-30360"Red China Sentences Tanks as Spies" (Daily Journal-Gazette, Mattoon IL)Folder 36110101954-11-23361Scope and ContentsArticles about the sentencing of thirteen U.S. airmen on charges of espionage by a Chinese military tribunal after the men were captured during the Korean War.(Motor News, Chicago IL)Folder 36210111954-12362"Heavy Quake Felt in 5 Western States" (The Sun, San Bernardino CA)Folder 36310121954-12-17363Scope and ContentsArticles about an earthquake centered in Reno, Nevada but felt in California, Idaho, Oregon and Utah.(Miami Valley News, Milford OH)Folder 36410131954-12-30364(Tuscola [IL] Review)Folder 36510141955-01-13365(Tuscola [IL] Review)Folder 36610151955-01-20366(Loveland [IL] Herald)Folder 36710161955-01-27367(News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 36810171955-02-20368"McCormick Rites Monday" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 36910181955-04-02369Scope and ContentsArticles about the death of Robert R. McCormick, editor and publisher of the Chicago Tribune."Global Arms Survey Plan of U.S." (Cincinnati Enquirer)Folder 37010191955-08-19370Scope and ContentsArticles about President Eisenhower's plan that the United States and the USSR exchange military blueprints and aerial arms inspection in an effort to thaw the tensions of the Cold War."Cairo Asks Suez Meet Modeled on Russ Plan" (Evening World Herald, Omaha NE)Folder 37110201955-09-10371Scope and ContentsArticles concerning the fight over control of the Suez Canal.(Nashville Banner)Folder 37210211955-11-14372(Atlanta Constitution)Folder 37310221955-11-18373(Knoxville News-Sentinel)Folder 37410231955-11-18374(The Messenger, Mariemont OH)Folder 37510241956-10-05375(South Omaha Sun)Folder 37610251957-08-29376"Earth Satellite Sighted by Observer in Alaska" (Topeka Daily Capital)Folder 37710261957-10-07377Scope and ContentsArticles about the launch of the Soviet satellite Sputnik."Wilson Denies Reds Possess Global Missile" (Evening Eagle, Wichita KA)Folder 37810271957-10-08378Scope and ContentsArticles about Defense Sectary Charles E. Wilson's assurances that the Soviets did not possess intercontinental ballistic missiles."Dulles Says U.S. Prepared to Discuss Space Missile Curbs as Separate Topic" (Tulsa Daily World)Folder 37910281957-10-09379Scope and ContentsArticles about the Secretary of State John Foster Dulles wish to engage in talks with the Soviets over the issue of militarizing space."U.S. Reverses Stand on Control of Space" (Wichita Eagle)Folder 38010291957-10-09380Scope and ContentsArticles about the Secretary of State John Foster Dulles wish to engage in talks with the Soviets over the issue of militarizing space."What's Sputnik Doing?" (Springfield [MO] Leader &amp; Press)Folder 38110301957-10-10381Scope and ContentsArticles updating the progress of the Soviet satellite Sputnik."U.S. Will Defend Turkey, Reds Told" (Springfield [MO] Daily News)Folder 38210311957-10-11382(Terre Haute [IN] Star)Folder 38310321957-10-12383(Big Sandy News, Louisa KY)Folder 38410331957-10-17384(Honolulu Star-Bulletin)Folder 38510341958-01-01385(Tuscola [IL] Journal)Folder 38610351958-01-23386"America Joins Satellite Age" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 38710361958-02-01387Scope and ContentsArticles concerning the launch of Explorer, the first U.S. satellite."DeGaulle Offers His Services" (Manchester [England] Guardian)Folder 38810371958-05-16388Scope and ContentsArticles concerning Charles De Gaulle offering to return to French politics.(Detroit Free Press)Folder 38910381958-05-31389"Alaska Voted Statehood" (Chicago Daily Tribune)Folder 39010391958-07-01390"Flag Gets Another Star--49th" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 39110401958-07-01391Scope and ContentsArticles about Alaska becoming the 49th state to join the United States.(Loveland [OH] Herald)Folder 39210411958-07-10392(Miami Valley News, Milford OH)Folder 39310421958-07-10393"U.S. Marines Land in Lebanon" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 39410431958-07-15394Scope and ContentsArticles about the sending of troops to Lebanon in response to the overthrow of the Iraqi government."U.N. Assembly Will Meet on Mideast Crisis Today; Council Adopts U.S. Plan" (New York Times)Folder 39510441958-08-08395Scope and ContentsArticles about the U.N.'s response to the overthrow of the Iraqi government.(St. Louis Globe Democrat)Folder 39610451958-08-08396"Reds Again Fire on Island Groups" (Rapid City Daily Journal)Folder 39710461958-08-25397Scope and ContentsArticles about the Chinese shelling of the Quemoy Islands located just off-shore of mainland China.  The United States had previously pledged support for the nearby islands of Formosa and Pescadore.(Cedar Rapids Gazette)Folder 39810471958-10-10398"Moon Rocket on Way; Trip to Take 60 Hours" (Evening World Herald, Omaha NE)Folder 39910481958-10-11399Scope and ContentsArticles concerning the launch of a U.S. rocket.(Denver Post)Folder 40010491958-10-13400"Happy Birthday, Ike!" (Rapid City Daily Journal)Folder 40110501958-10-14401Scope and ContentsArticles about the birthday of President Eisenhower."British Charge Atom Ultimatum Is Used by Russians in U.N." (Billings Gazette)Folder 40210511958-10-15402Scope and ContentsArticles about a alleged ultimatum issued by the Soviets in which they threatened to go ahead with nuclear weapons tests unless Western powers agreed to Soviet demands.(Minot [ND] Daily News)Folder 40310521958-10-16403(Fargo Forum)Folder 40410531958-10-17404(Winnipeg [Canada] Free Press)Folder 40510541958-10-18405"Red China Calls Off Cease-Fire" (Mesabi Daily News)Folder 40610551958-10-20406Scope and ContentsArticles about the Chinese government ignoring a previous cease-fire agreement and bombarding the island of Quemoy off the coast of mainland China."Ike Calls for G.O.P. Victory, Blasts 'Radical' Democrats" (Minneapolis Morning Tribune)Folder 40710561958-10-21407(Juneau County Chronicle, Mauston WI)Folder 40810571958-10-21408"Ike Calls for 'Fumigation' of Corrupt Unions" (Milwaukee Journal)Folder 40910581958-10-22409"'Fumigate' Corrupt Unions, Ike Urges" (Wisconsin State Journal)Folder 41010591958-10-22410"End Balloon Satellite Sky Hunt" (Dixon [IL] Evening Telegraph)Folder 41110601958-10-23411Scope and ContentsArticles concerning a missing U.S. military balloon satellite at Cape Canaveral, Florida.(Hard Hat)Folder 41210611958-11-07412"New Base Fires Missile!" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 41310621958-12-17413Scope and ContentsArticle about the firing of the first ballistic missile at Vandenberg Air Force Base in California."U.S. Launches Space Surprise" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 41410631958-12-19414Scope and ContentsArticles about the launch of the Atlas Satellite from Cape Canaveral, Florida."Atlas Answers Earth's Call" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 41510641958-12-21415Scope and ContentsArticles about the launch of the Atlas Satellite from Cape Canaveral, Florida.Box 10Box 101065(News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 41610661959-01-22416(Wall Street Journal)Folder 41710671959-03-06417(Shelbyville [IN] News)Folder 41810681959-05-07418"John Foster Dulles Dies" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 41910691959-05-25419(Waukegan [IL] News-Sun)Folder 42010701959-10-02420"Air Force Cancels Bong Base; Flynn Will Ask for Investigation" (Milwaukee Journal)Folder 42110711959-10-03421Scope and ContentsArticles about the halting of construction on the Richard I. Bong air force base located in Racine and Kenosha counties, Wisconsin."Recall Chrysler Workers" (Detroit Times)Folder 42210721959-10-05422Scope and ContentsArticles about the resolving of a workers' strike at the Chrysler Corporation stamping plant in Twinsburg, Ohio."May Allow Commons Death Penalty Vote" (Chatham [Ontario, Canada] News)Folder 42310731959-10-06423Scope and ContentsArticles about the possibility of abolishing the death penalty in Canada.(Toledo Blade)Folder 42410741959-10-07424"Hundreds Routed by Gas Fumes in Texas" (Indianapolis News)Folder 42510751959-10-08425Scope and ContentsArticles about a propane gas line explosion near Austin, Texas."USW Will 'Go to Court' If U.S. Uses T-H in Steel Strike" (Journal-Gazette, Fort Wayne IN)Folder 42610761959-10-08426Scope and ContentsArticles about the United Steel Workers' contention to pursue legal action if the U.S. government attempted to end an 85-day steel strike through the use of the Taft-Hartley Act.(Kissimmee Gazette)Folder 42710771959-10-15427(Maryland Gazette)Folder 42810781959-10-29428(Los Angeles Times)Folder 42910791960-01-02429(Chicago Tribune)Folder 43010801960-01-26430(Chicago Tribune)Folder 43110811960-01-27431"Wilson Strikers Okay Pact; Union Will Lift All Pickets" (Evening World Herald, Omaha NE)Folder 43210821960-02-19432Scope and ContentsArticles about the decision by the United Packinghouse Workers of America to end their strike against Wilson and Company."I See Chessman Die" (Daily Mail, England)Folder 43310831960-05-03433Scope and ContentsArticles about the execution of convicted murder Caryl Chessman."Russians Cancel U.S. Trip" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 43410841960-05-14434Scope and ContentsArticles about the Soviets canceling a meeting with U.S. officials in Paris over the recent U-2 spy plane incident.(Chicago Tribune)Folder 43510851960-06-27435"Fire Rage Over Western U.S." (Iowa City Press-Citizen)Folder 43610861960-07-22436Scope and ContentsArticles about a forest fire that engulfed territory in nine western states."All-Night G.O.P. Fight Over Civil Rights Plank" (Des Moines Tribune)Folder 43710871960-07-25437Scope and ContentsArticle about GOP leaders, including presidential nominee Richard Nixon, debating their position on civil rights."Plank on Rights Debated" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 43810881960-07-26438Scope and ContentsArticle about GOP leaders, including presidential nominee Richard Nixon, debating their position on civil rights."Little Red Schoolhouse is Real Russian Threat" (Dayton Daily News)Folder 43910891960-08-21439Scope and ContentsArticles about the possibility of Soviets subverting American education."Here's Kennedy Farm Plan" (Chicago Daily News)Folder 44010901960-08-22440Scope and ContentsArticles about Democratic Presidential nominee John F. Kennedy's plan to help American farmers."Kennedy Victory Narrow" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 44110911960-11-10441Scope and ContentsArticles about John F. Kennedy's victory over Richard Nixon for the Presidency.(Los Angeles Times)Folder 44210921961-01-01442(Sunday World Herald, Omaha NE)Folder 44310931961-01-08443(Sunday World Herald, Omaha NE)Folder 44410941961-03-12444"1st Yank Shot Into Space Shepherd Returns Safely" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 44510951961-05-06445Scope and ContentsArticles about astronaut Alan B. Shepard's historic space flight."2nd Astronaut Shot in June" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 44610961961-05-07446Scope and ContentsArticles about the plan to send the second American astronaut into space.(Prairie Post, Maroa IL)Folder 44710971961-06-29447"Grissom Safe; Cone Lost" (Chicago TribuneFolder 44810981961-07-22448Scope and ContentsArticles about the second American manned space flight, piloted by Virgil "Gus" Grissom.  The capsule (or "cone") that carried Grissom back to Earth took on water and sank before it could be retrieved."West Takes Skeptical View of K's Bid to 'Honest Talk'" (Evening World Herald, Omaha NE)Folder 44910991961-08-08449Scope and ContentsArticles about the skepticism surrounding Soviet Premier Khrushchev's proposal to "negotiate in an honest way" on the Berlin issue."House OKs Air Piracy Bill" (Indianapolis Star)Folder 45011001961-08-22450"How Crash Took 78 Lives" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 45111011961-09-02451Scope and ContentsArticles about the crash of a Trans World Airlines Constellation plane shortly after departure from Midway Airport, Chicago."S. Texas Loss in Millions" (Light, San Antonio TX)Folder 45211021962-01-12452Scope and ContentsArticles about a winter storm that struck southern Texas, causing considerable damage to crops in the area."Col. Glenn Does It" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 45311031962-02-21453Scope and ContentsArticles about astronaut John H. Glenn's successful circling of the globe three times, the first human to achieve such a feat."Thank God! He Did It! Safe Lift Carpenter From Sea" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 45411041962-05-25454Scope and ContentsArticles about astronaut Malcom Scott Carpenter's successful orbiting of the Earth.(Chicago Tribune)Folder 45511051962-07-11455"Telstar Relays TV Pictures" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 45611061962-07-11456Scope and ContentsArticles about the first television satellite put into orbit."U.S. Not Ending Allied Occupation of Berlin" (Mainichi Daily News, Tokyo Japan)Folder 45711071962-07-14457(Dodge City Daily Globe)Folder 45811081962-08-09458"Nikolayev Becomes Premier Space 'Millionaire'" (Egyptian Gazette)Folder 45911091962-08-14459Scope and ContentsArticles about Soviet cosmonaut Andrian Nikolayev traveling over a million miles in space."Teachers' Strike Threat Looms" (East African Standard)Folder 46011101962-08-25460Scope and ContentsArticles about a possible Kenyan teachers strike."Greece: Future Bright" (Athens Daily Post)Folder 46111111962-08-29461Scope and ContentsArticles about the United States' favorable opinion on the future of Greece.(Los Angeles Times)Folder 46211121963-01-01462"Give Cooper 'Go' For All 22" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 46311131963-05-16463Scope and ContentsArticles about astronaut L. Gordon Cooper's reentry from space.(Chicago Tribune)Folder 46411141963-05-18464"Cooper Tells of Flight" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 46511151963-05-20465Scope and ContentsArticles about the space flight made by astronaut L. Gordon Cooper."Million-Dollar Mistakes on Rayburn Building" (Chicago Daily News)Folder 46611161965-04-24466Scope and ContentsArticles about construction mistakes made during the building of the Rayburn House Office Building, which contains offices for members of the House of Representatives and their staffs in Washington, D.C."Adali Stevenson is Dead" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 46711171965-07-15467(Honolulu Advertiser)Folder 46811181966-02-15468(Joplin [MO] News Herald)Folder 46911191966-03-04469(Fort Frances [Ontario] Times)Folder 47011201966-03-09470"Conferees Put Phone Levy Up, Hand LBJ $6 Billion War Tax" (Omaha World-Herald)Folder 47111211966-03-11471Scope and ContentsArticles about political maneuvering on behalf of the Senate and House to provide more money for the Vietnam War effort as requested by President Lyndon Johnson.Box 11Box 111160"Hunt Woman in Slaying; Fly Kennedy Body to N.Y." (Chicago Tribune)Folder 47211221968-06-07472Scope and ContentsArticles about the aftermath of the assassination of Robert F. Kennedy."Many Pay Last Respects" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 47311231968-06-07473Scope and ContentsArticles about the aftermath of the assassination of Robert F. Kennedy."Thousands View RFK Bier" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 47411241968-06-08474Scope and ContentsArticles about the aftermath of the assassination of Robert F. Kennedy."Last Rites for Kennedy" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 47511251968-06-08475Scope and ContentsArticles about the aftermath of the assassination of Robert F. Kennedy."Gov. Agnew in V.P. Race" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 47611261968-08-09476Scope and ContentsArticles about the selection of Spiro Agnew to be Richard Nixon's running mate as the Republican nominee for President."Assassinates U.S. Envoy" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 47711271968-08-29477Scope and ContentsArticles about the assassination of John Gordon Mein, the U.S. ambassador to Guatemala."Humphrey Picks Muskie" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 47811281968-08-30478Scope and ContentsArticles about Democratic Presidential nominee Hubert H. Humphrey picking Edmund Muskie as his running mate.(Arthur [IL] Graphic-Clarion)Folder 47911291968-09-19479(Bement [IL] Register)Folder 48011301968-06-19480(Milford [OH] Miami Valley News)Folder 48111311968-09-19481"Nixon Hopes to Unite U.S." (Chicago Tribune)Folder 48211321968-11-07482Scope and ContentsArticles about Richard Nixon's winning the Presidency."A Picture Guide to TV Today" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 48311331968-12-25483"Apollo Success Hailed" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 48411341968-12-28484Scope and ContentsArticles about the Apollo 8 mission around the moon."68's Historic Headlines" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 48511351968-12-31485Scope and ContentsA collection of important news stories from 1968."Nixon Tells Peace Goal" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 48611361969-01-21486Scope and ContentsArticles about Richard Nixon's inauguration.(Chicago Tribune)Folder 48711371969-03-04487"Mourn Eisenhower" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 48811381969-03-29488Scope and ContentsArticles about the death of former President Dwight D. Eisenhower."Ike Borne to Capital Bier" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 48911391969-03-31489Scope and ContentsArticles about the death of former President Dwight D. Eisenhower."Ike Funeral Service Held" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 49011401969-04-01490Scope and ContentsArticles about the death of former President Dwight D. Eisenhower."Eisenhower Laid to Rest" (News-Gazette)Folder 49111411969-04-02491Scope and ContentsArticles about the death of former President Dwight D. Eisenhower."Ogilvie's Service Tax Aim" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 49211421969-04-03492Scope and ContentsArticles about Illinois Governor Richard B. Ogilvie's plans to increase the state's income tax."Apollo 11 Right on Target" (News-Gazette)Folder 49311431969-07-17493"May Advance Moon Walk" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 49411441969-07-18494Scope and ContentsArticles about the Apollo 11 moon mission."New Perils for Astronauts" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 49511451969-07-20495Scope and ContentsArticles about the Apollo 11 moon mission."Spaceships Link Up" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 49611461969-07-22496Scope and ContentsArticles about the Apollo 11 moon mission."Nixon to Start World Trip" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 49711471969-07-22497"Adopt Teacher Race Plan" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 49811481969-07-24498Scope and ContentsArticles about accusations of faculty segregation in public schools."Astronauts Are Safe" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 49911491969-07-24499Scope and ContentsArticles about the aftermath of the Apollo 11 space flight."All Hail Moon Men" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 50011501969-07-25500Scope and ContentsArticles about the aftermath of the Apollo 11 space flight."Heroes of Moon Win City" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 50111511969-08-14501Scope and ContentsArticles about a Chicago parade held in honor of the astronauts from the Apollo 11 space flight."Nation Mourns for Dirksen" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 50211521969-09-08502Scope and ContentsArticles about the death of Senator Everett McKinley Dirksen."U.S. May Use Troops to Control Protestors" (St. Louis Globe-Democrat)Folder 50311531969-11-07503Scope and ContentsArticles about a proposed demonstration against the Vietnam War held in Washington, D.C."A Happy Ending!" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 50411541970-04-18504Scope and ContentsArticles about the successful resolution of the Apollo 13 space mission.(Atwood [IL] Herald)Folder 50511551970-12-24505"Truman Dies at 88" (Chicago Tribune)Folder 50611561972-12-27506Scope and ContentsArticles about the death of former president Harry S Truman."Second Term Begins" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 50711571973-01-21507Scope and ContentsArticles about Richard Nixon beginning second term as president."Flag is Furled in Vietnam" (News-Gazette, Champaign-Urbana IL)Folder 50811581973-03-29508Scope and ContentsArticles about the United States' ending its military presence in Vietnam.Picture Section (Chicago Tribune)Folder 5091159Date Unknown509Scope and ContentsColor reproductions of paintings depicting George Washington crossing the Delaware River and receiving notice of his election as president.

