<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.08Archon Finding Aid Title MC.08UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:35:46 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC08. Adlai  E. Stevenson, Campaign Speech Transcripts, April-December 1952
    
      Stevenson, Adlai
    
    MC.08
    14
    
      1.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1952
    Date acquired: 09/14/1979
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Transcripts of 228 speeches, addresses and remarks delivered by Illinois Governor Adlai E. Stevenson during his campaign for U.S. President in 1952.  Topics include domestic policy, off-shore oil deposits, McCarthyism, foreign policy and Korea.  Includes his welcoming address at the Democratic National Convention, speeches given during his campaign train tour and his concession speech to President-elect Eisenhower.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Mrs. T. R. McElwee  
  
    Speeches
    Transcripts
  
  Box 1Box 12215News Release, Dallas, 12 pFolder 122161952-04-221Speech, Commonwealth Club, San Francisco, 13 pFolder 222171952-05-052Welcoming Address, Democratic Convention, Chicago, 5 pFolder 322181952-07-213Nomination Acceptance, Chicago, 5 pFolder 422191952-07-254Statement on Leaving Blair House Morning After Nomination in Chicago, 1 pFolder 522201952-07-265Address Delivered on Governor's Day at Illinois State Fair, Springfield,  5 pFolder 622211952-08-146Remarks, Press Copy, Springfield, IL, 1 pFolder 722221952-08-187Speech, Asbury Park, NJ, 4 p; Speech, National Convention of American Legion, New York, 6 pFolder 822231952-08-278Remarks &amp; SpeechesFolder 922241952-08-289Scope and ContentsRemarks, Volunteers Luncheon, New York, 6 p
Speech, Liberal Party Convention, New York, 5 p
Speech, New York State Democratic Convention, New York, 7 pRemarks, Springfield, IL, 2 pFolder 1022251929-08-2910Labor Day Message, Springfield, IL, 2 pFolder 1122261952-08-3011Speech for Men and Women in Armed Forces Overseas, Springfield, IL, 8 pFolder 1222271952-08-3112SpeechesFolder 1322281952-09-0113Scope and ContentsSpeech, Detroit, 8 p
Speech, Flint, MI, 4 p
Speech, Grand Rapids, MI, 5 p
Speech, Hamtramck, MI, 4 p
Speech, Pontiac, MI, 3 pSpeech, Denver, 7 p; News Release, Denver, 9 p;  Speech, Colorado Volunteers for Stevenson, Denver, 7 pFolder 1422291952-09-0514Speech, Dinner, Colorado Volunteers for Stevenson, Denver, 9 p; Speech, National Plowing Contest, Kasson, MN, 7 p; Speech, Cheyenne, WY, 9 pFolder 1522301952-09-0615Telegram from George M. Romm, Massachusetts State Chairman of American Veterans CommitteeFolder 1622311952-09-0716SpeechesFolder 1722321952-09-0817Scope and ContentsSpeech, Portland, OR, 5 pp
Press Conference, Portland, OR, 4 p
Speech, Multnomah County Democratic Party Meeting, Portland, OR, 6 p
Speech, Seattle, WA, 7 p
Speech, Seattle, WA, 7 pSpeech, San Francisco, 9 pFolder 1822331952-09-0918Remarks &amp; SpeechFolder 1922341952-09-1019Scope and ContentsRemarks, Bakersfield, CA, 3 p
Remarks, Fresno, CA, 3 p
Remarks, Madera, CA, 2 p
Remarks, Merced, CA, 1 p
Remarks, Modesto, CA, 2 p
Speech, San Jose, CA, 2 p
Remarks, Tracy, CA, 2 p
Remarks, Tulare, CA, 2 pRemarks, Los Angeles (2639 Monmouth, Stevenson's Birthplace), 1 p; Speech, Los Angeles, 10 p; Speech, Los Angeles, 7 pFolder 2022351952-09-1120Speech, Phoenix, 6 p; Speech, Phoenix, 8 pFolder 2122361952-09-1221Speech, Hartford, CT, 8 pFolder 2222371952-09-1622Remarks &amp; SpeechFolder 2322381952-09-1823Scope and ContentsRemarks, Beacon Falls, CT, 1 p
Remarks, Bridgeport, CT, 5 p
Remarks, Bristol, CT, 2 p
Remarks, Nangatuck, CT, 1 p
Remarks, New Britain, CT, 3 p
Remarks, New Haven, CT, 3 p
Speech, Hartford, CT, 8 p
Remarks, Seymour, CT, 1 p
Remarks, Waterbury, CT, 4 pRemarks, East Hartford, CT, 1 p; Remarks, Enfield Village, CT, 2 p; Speech, Springfield, MA, 6 p; Speech, Springfield, MA, 7 pFolder 2422391952-09-1924Remarks, Fredericksburg, VA, 1 p; Remarks, Quantico, VA, 2 p; Speech, Richmond, VA, 8 p; Remarks, Washington, DC, 1 pFolder 2522401952-09-2025Box 2Box 22241Speech, American Federation of Labor Convention, New York, 7 pFolder 122421952-09-221Speech, Baltimore, 7 pFolder 222431952-09-232Speech, Baltimore, 7 pFolder 322441952-09-243Remarks &amp; SpeechesFolder 422451952-09-264Scope and ContentsRemarks, Evansville, IN, 1 p
Speech, Evansville, IN, 5 p
Remarks, Indianapolis (on being presented a flower	horseshoe by a neighborhood group), 1 p
Speech, Indianapolis, 9 pSpeech, Indianapolis, 3 p; Speech, Louisville, KY, 6 p; Speech, Paducah, KY, 5 pFolder 522461952-09-275Speech, Chicago, 9 pFolder 622471952-09-296Remarks, Champaign, IL, 5 pFolder 722481952-10-027SpeechesFolder 822491952-10-038Scope and ContentsRemarks, Covington, KY, 1 p
Remarks, Newport, KY, 1 p
Speech, Luncheon, Hamilton County Democratic Party, Cincinnati, OH, 9 p	
Speech, Columbus, OH, 7 pSpeech, Fort Dodge, IA, 9 p; Speech, Minneapolis, 6 p; Speech, St. Paul, 8 pFolder 922501952-10-049SpeechesFolder 1022511952-10-0710Scope and ContentsSpeech, Detroit, 7 p
Speech, River Rouge, MI (presentation of key to the city to Stevenson by Mayor Duncan), 5 p
Speech, Saginaw, MI, 6 p
Remarks, Wayne, MI, 3 p
Remarks, Willow Run Village, MI (during motorcade from Willow Run Airport to Detroit) l p
Speech, Ypsilanti, MI, 7 pSpeechesFolder 1122521952-10-0811Scope and ContentsSpeech, Lake Mills, WI, 3 p
Speech, Madison, WI, 5 p
Speech, Madison, WI, 9 p
Speech, Milwaukee, 8 p
Speech, Waukeshau, WI, 4 pRemarks &amp; SpeechesFolder 1222531952-10-0912Scope and ContentsRemarks, Alton, IL, 3 p
Remarks, Brooklyn, IL, 1 p
Speech, Granite City, IL, 2 p
Remarks, Wood River, IL, 1 p
Speech, St. Louis, 8 p
Speech, Kansas City, MO, 9 pStatement by Margaret Chase Smith, 2 p; Speech, New Orleans, 11 p; Address, Oklahoma City, 6 p; Address, Oklahoma City, 8 pFolder 1322541952-10-1013Speech, Miami, FL, 7 p; Speech, Tampa, Democratic Rally, 6 pFolder 1422551952-10-1114Remarks, Nashville, 7 p; Remarks, Fund-Raising Campaign, Democratic National Committee, Springfield, IL, 1 pFolder 1522561952-10-1215Speech, Salt Lake City, 3 p; Speech, Salt Lake City, 8 p; Remarks, Luncheon, Casper, WY, 1 p; Speech, Casper, WY, 7 pFolder 1622571952-10-1416Address, San Francisco, 6 p; Speech, Pendleton, OR, 4 p; Speech, Democratic Rally, Spokane, 8 pFolder 1722581952-10-1517Box 3Box 32259SpeechesFolder 122601952-10-161Scope and ContentsAddress, Democratic Rally, Berkely, CA, 3 p 
Speech, Los Angeles, 2 p
Speech, Democratic Rally, Los Angeles, 6 p
Speech, Los Angeles, 10 p
Speech, Richmond, CA, 2 p
Speech, Democratic Rally, Sacramento, 5 p
Speech, Vallejo, CA, 3 p
Speech, Oklahoma City, 8 pSpeech, Democratic Rally, San Diego, 3 p; Speech, Dallas, 8 p; Address, Democratic Rally, Fort Worth, 7 p; Speech, Grand Prairie, TX, 1 pFolder 222611952-10-172SpeechesFolder 322621952-10-183Scope and ContentsSpeech, Springfield, IL, 2 p
Speech, Houston, 6 p
Speech, San Antonio, 2 p
Speech, San Antonio, 4 p
Speech, Uvaldo, TX (home of former vice president John Garner), 2 pSpeech, Democratic Rally, Springfield, IL, 8 pFolder 422631952-10-204SpeechesFolder 522641952-10-215Scope and ContentsNews Release (on Sen. Russell's Prediction), 1 p
Speech, New York Herald Tribune Forum, Chicago, 5 p
Radio-Television Address, Chicago, 10 p
Speech, Decatur, IL, 6 p
Speech, Kankakee, IL, 6 p
Speech, Tolono, IL, 2 pSpeechesFolder 622651952-10-226Scope and ContentsPress Conference (Wilson Wyatt) on Train, 2 p
Remarks, South Bend, IN, 4 p
Speech, South Bend, IN, 6 p
Speech, Buffalo, NY, 8 p
Speech, Elyria, O, 4 p
Speech, Sandusky, O, 5 p
Remarks, Toledo, O, 5 pRemarks &amp; SpeechesFolder 722661952-10-237Scope and ContentsSpeech, Dunkirk, NY,  5 p
Speech, Akron, 5 p
Remarks, Ashtabula, OH, 3 p
Speech, Democratic Rally, Cleveland, 9 p
Remarks, Ravenna, OH, 2 p
Remarks, Youngstown, OH, 6 p
Remarks, Erie, PA, 4 pSpeechesFolder 822671952-10-248Scope and ContentsSpeech, Albany, 2 p
Remarks, Amsterdam, NY, 4 p
Remarks, Auburn, NY, 3 p
Speech, Canandaigua, NY, 4  p
Remarks, Geneva, NY, 3 p
Remarks, Little Falls, NY, 3 p
Speech, Niagara Falls, 3 p
Speech, Rochester, NY, 4 p
Remarks, Rome, NY, 3 p
Remarks, Schenectedy, NY, 4 p
Speech, Seneca Falls, NJ, 4 p
Remarks, Syracuse, NY, 4 p
Address, Troy, NY, 7 p
Remarks, Utica, NY, 6 pSpeechesFolder 922681952-10-259Scope and ContentsSpeech, Boston Globe Youth Forum, Boston, 7 p
Speech, Boston, 8 p
Remarks, Framingham, MA, 2 p
Remarks, Pittsfield, MA, 5 p
Visit to Hyde Park, NY, 2 p
Speech, Poughkeepsie, NY, 4 p
Remarks, Springfield, MA, 5 p
Remarks, Worcester, MA, 4 pBox 4Box 42269Remarks &amp; SpeechesFolder 122701952-10-261Scope and ContentsTelegram to B. J. Marketos, Boston, thanking him for endorsement
Speech, Volunteers for Stevenson, Boston, 4 p
Speech, Breakfast Sponsored by Veterans Organizations, Boston, 7 p
Remarks, Fall River, MA, 1 p
Remarks, New Bedford, MA, 1 pSpeechesFolder 222711952-10-272Scope and ContentsSpeech, Bridgeport, CT, 8 p
Speech, New London, CT, 3 p
Speech, Norwich, CT, 3 p
Speech, Putnam, CT, 3 p
Speech, Attleboro, MA, 3 p
Speech, Brockton, MA, 4 p
Speech, Quincy, MA, 4 p
Speech, Harlem, NY, 3 p
Speech, Providence, RI, 5 p
Speech, Woonsocket, RI, 4 pStatementsFolder 322721952-10-283Scope and ContentsStatements by Arthur Schlesinger and Steven A. Mitchell
Speech, Montgomery Gardens Housing Development, Jersey City, NJ, 2 p.
Speech, Newark, NJ, 2 p
Address, Paterson, NJ, 2 p
Speech, New York, 2 p
Speech, Madison Square Garden, New York, 7 p
Remarks, Luncheon for Women Volunteers, New York, 6 pRemarksFolder 422731952-10-294Scope and ContentsRemarks, Allentown, PA, 4 p
Remarks, Bethlehem, PA, 4 p
Remarks, Volunteers for Stevenson, Broadwood Hotel, Philadelphia, 5 p
Speech, Philadelphia, 6 p
Remarks, Scranton, PA, 4 p
Remarks, Wilkes Barre, PA, 5 pSpeechesFolder 522741952-10-305Scope and ContentsSpeech, sponsored by 1952 Campaign Committee of International Ladies 			Garment Workers Union, New York, 4 p
Speech, Lancaster, PA, 6 p
Speech, Pittsburgh, PA, 7 p
Speech, Pottstown, PA, 5 p
Speech, Reading, PA, 5 p
Speech, York, PA, 4Address &amp; SpeechesFolder 622751952-10-316Scope and ContentsAddress by Sen. William Fullbright delivered at Wilmington, DE, 7 p
Remarks by Sen. William Fullbright delivered at Silver Spring, MD, 5 p
Remarks, Brooklyn, NY, 9 p
Speech, Long Island, NY, 6 p
Speech, sponsored by Liberal Party, New York, 4 p
Remarks by Sen. William Fullbright at Martinsburg, WV, 4 pSpeechesFolder 722761952-11-017Scope and ContentsSpeech, Democratic Rally, Chicago, 6 p
Speech, Chicago Stadium, Chicago, 10 p
Remarks, Fort Wayne, IN, 4 p
Remarks, Gary, IND, 3 p
Speech, Alliance, OH, 3 p
Speech, Bucyrus, OH, 4 p
Remarks, Crestline, OH, 2 p
Speech, Lima, OH, 5 p
Speech, Mansfield, OH, 4 pAddressFolder 822771952-11-038Scope and ContentsAddress, radio and television, conclusion of Democratic Presidential Campaign, Chicago, 5 p
Message received by Stevenson from members of faculty of Ripon College, Ripon, WI, 1 p
Remarks, Halfday School, near Libertyville, IL, 2 pStatement conceding election to Dwight D. Eisenhower, Springfield, IL, 1 pFolder 922781952-11-059Speech, Canton, OH, 4 pFolder 1022791952-11-1110Speech, Kansas City, MO, 3 pFolder 1122801952-11-1411Address, Gridiron Club Dinner, Washington, DC, 6 pFolder 1222811952-12-1312Draft of speech on Civil Service (no date)Folder 13228213

