<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.11Archon Finding Aid Title MC.11UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:35:57 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC11. Henry Weinhoeft Papers, 1907-1925
    
      Weinhoeft, Henry
    
    MC.11
    17
    
      1.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1907-1925
    Date acquired: 05/00/1980
    1
    2
    3
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Steel worker and  contractor. Founding member of Local 46 of the International Association of Bridge and Structural Iron Workers. Local Union 46 includes correspondence, reports, financial records, workmen time books, day books, membership ledgers documenting routine  union business, the  Chicago Lockout of 1921, and Illinois Governor Len Small, the local's involvement in the Springfield School Districts 1921 elections ans specifications for the Elk's Club building. Also includes personal papers and letters regarding the Jennings Ford Dealership in Springfield, and Sears and Roebuck Company and 81 blueprints recording steel and structural work for buildings  in Springfield and other communities.  Also photographs concerning Weinhoeft, the construction of bridges in Montana, Arkansas and Iowa, and Lanphier and Springfield High Schools.  Also  a history of Weinhoeft Family, 1997. The Henry Weinhoeft Blueprints were originally part of this collection. They are shelved separately as MC11/1.  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Dean DeBolt  
  
    Correspondence
    Records
  
  Box 1Box 12283CorrespondenceFolder 122841914-19191CorrespondenceFolder 2228519202CorrespondenceFolder 3228619213Expense Account: Income and ExpendituresFolder 42287Oct. 20, 1914-June 19154Elks Club Building SpecificationsFolder 5228819225Illinois Steel Bridge Company: CorrespondenceFolder 6228919196Foreman's Daily Report: Moline Job for Illinois Steel Bridge CompanyFolder 72290Aug.-Nov. 19197International Association of Bridge, Structural and Ornamental Iron Workers:Folder 82291Jan.-April 19218Scope and ContentsCircular Letters, #349-355, 358Monthly Report of Financial SecretaryFolder 922921920-299Quarterly Audit Reports, Local 46Folder 1022931918-192310ReceiptsFolder 112294192011ReceiptsFolder 122295March-Dec. 192112ReceiptsFolder 132296192213ReceiptsFolder 142297Jan. 1, 1923-March 21, 192314Receipts, (canceled checks)Folder 152298192515Steward's Weekly ReportFolder 162299192116Workman's Time BookFolder 172300July 1910-Jan. 1911; March-April 192217Workman's Time BookFolder 182301Oct. 8, 1921-March 4, 192218Workmen's Time BookFolder 192302March 17, 1923-Sept. 1, 192319Bridgemen's Magazine (vol. 25 #2)Folder 202303February 192520Electric Hoist and Derrick Co., Primos, PA.Folder 21230421The Insley Idea, vol. 3 #1-4 (Insley Manufacturing Company, Indianapolis, Indiana)Folder 2223051923-192422Insley Mast Hoist Bucket Equipment (catalog #45)Folder 23230623Leschen's Hercules (Leschen Rope Company, St. Louis, MO.)Folder 242307August 192224Patterson Block Talks (no. 1 of a series), (W.W. Paterson Co., Pittsburgh, PA.)Folder 25230825Union FormsFolder 26230926Union-Related PublicationsFolder 27231027Weinhoeft: Personal PapersFolder 2823111919-192128Other MaterialsFolder 29231229Box 2Box 22313Scope and ContentsAccount Books and LedgersDay BookFolder 123141909-131Day BookFolder 223151916-212Scope and Contents(Oversize (BV))Membership LedgerFolder 323161909-113Membership LedgerFolder 423171916-194Membership LedgerFolder 523181920-215Membership LedgerFolder 623191922-246Box 3Box 32320Weinhoeft Family HistoryFolder 1232119971Pictures of Illinois Steel Bridge workers at Milk River, Malta, MontanaFolder 223228-22-19112Scope and Contents3 mounted printsIllinois Steel Bridge workers at War Eagle, ArkansasFolder 32323Feb.-Mar. 19083Scope and Contents5 mounted printsBridge construction, no placeFolder 42324no date4Bridge construction, Henman [?], IllinoisFolder 5232519075Picture of a river bluff, no dateFolder 623266Lanphier High School Springfield, Ill. no dateFolder 723277Caretaker's home at Lincoln's Tomb, Springfield, no dateFolder 823288unknown structure, no dateFolder 923299Construction workers (possibly Springfield High School) no dateFolder 10233010Construction workers, no dateFolder 11233111Mississippi River Power Company's dam construction. Keokuk, Iowa, 1912Folder 12233212

