<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.12Archon Finding Aid Title MC.12UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:36:03 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC12. Charles  M. Shepherd Papers
    
      Jones, John H.
    
    
      Sangamon State University
    
    
      Shepherd, Charles M.
    
    
      Barker, R-Lou
    
    MC.12
    19
    
      0.20 Cubic Feet
    
    1874-2007
    1976-2007
    Date acquired: 05/12/1980
    Blueprints
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Farmer and breeder  born in Woodside Township, Sangamon County, Illinois in 1841.  Purchased 188 acres of the Strawbridge Estate in 1883 including the homestead  built by Thomas Strawbridge Jr (1798-1880) in the 1840's.  UIS now stands on that farm.  Photocopy of a diary kept by Shepherd in 1878 regarding his farming and hunting activities, and trips to Springfield and the weather.  Also contains a student paper written by R-Lou Barker discussing the family history, a transcript of the C.M. Shepherd diary with copied photographs of members of the Shephard family and their homes, 1975; a student paper by  John H. Jones regarding Strawbridge/Shepherd and its residents, 1975;  a memorandum and letter regarding SSU's plans for the Shepherd properties; copies of photos and various county records pertaining to the Strawbridge-Shepherd House; and a pen and ink sketch of the house made in 1995 by James Murray, a faculty member from Lincoln Land Community College.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Jacob Lard Shepherd et al  
  
    Related Materials
See also:Richard E. Hart, The Strawbridge-Shepherd Farm Site. Cotton Hill on Sugar Creek Series [Springfield, Ill. : Elijah Iles House Foundation], c2007. Call number: Special Collections : NA 8208.52 S75 H37 2007.See also:James Welt, "National Register nomination and Springfield landmarking for the Strawbridge-Shepherd House." Master's Project, UIS History Department, 2015. Call Number: J54/50/5829.  
  
    Diary
    Maps
    Photographs
  
  Box 1Box 11983R-Lou Barker, "A Brief Shepherd Family History and Review of Charles Miller Shepherd's Handwritten Personal Diary of 1878"Folder 1198419751Scope and ContentsIncludes photocopy of Charles Shepherd's diary, 1878.Charles M. Shepherd - Photographs, maps, etc.Folder 219852John H. Jones, "The Strawbridge/Shepherd House"Folder 3198619753Scope and ContentsStudent PaperStrawbridge-Shepherd House Restoration EffortsFolder 4198720074Strawbridge-Shepherd House exhibit material, UIS ArchivesFolder 52792520075Sketch of Strawbridge-Shepherd House by James MurrayFolder 63570619956Richard E. Hart, The Strawbridge-Shepherd Farm Site. Cotton Hill on Sugar Creek Series [Springfield, Ill. : Elijah Iles House Foundation], c2007.Folder 7812647

