<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.13Archon Finding Aid Title MC.13UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:37:57 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC13. Willis J. Spaulding Papers, 1890-1937
    
      Spaulding, Willis J.
    
    MC.13
    20
    
      0.49 Cubic Feet
    
    1890-1937
    Date acquired: 00/00/1974
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Springfield Superintendent of Water Works, 1909-1911, and Commissioner of Public Property, 1911-1943.  Elevated the municipal water plant to one of national distinction, created the electric utility and placed it on a paying basis, and led the movement for the building of Lake Springfield.

Typescript carbon of "The Story of the City Records," compiled by Helen V. C. Blankmeyer in honor of the dedication of Lake Springfield and Spaulding Dam, 1935; a letter from playwright William Dodd Chenery acknowledging use of the Blankmeyer manuscript for writing the Springfield Centennial Pageant, 1937; programs for the dedication and pageant events; working papers of Georgia Ann Saylor consisting of annotated notes to the Illinois State Register- for 1890-1915; and a subject index to Saylor's notes.  Blankmeyer's and Saylor's work concerns the history of Springfield, especially the history of city government and adoption of the commission form, and development of city services, including water, gas, electric, streetcars and the park system.  Biographical information on Spaulding is included.  
  
    Arrangement Note
As received  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Frank Wilcox  
  
    Correspondence
    Records
    Reports
  
  Box 1Box 13677"The Story of the City Records, Compiled in Honor of the Dedication of Lake Springfield 		and Spaulding Dam," by Helen V. C. BlankmeyerFolder 136781Scope and Contents[typescript carbon, unnumbered pages, inscribed "Property of V. Y. Dallman, Springfield, Illinois"]History of the Springfield city government and development of city servicesFolder 236791821 - 19352Scope and ContentsParks, water, electricity, gas, streetcars"Lake Springfield Dedication Celebration"Folder 336801935-07-123Letter from William Dodd Chenery to Willis J. Spaulding thanking Spaulding for loan of "The Story of the City Records."Folder 436814Program of the Springfield Centennial PageantFolder 536821837 - 19375Scope and ContentsInscribed "To Springfield's Premier Benefactor, Willis J. Spaulding, from the author, William Dodd Chenery"Xerograph of "The Story of the City Records"Folder 636836Biographical matter on Willis J. SpauldingFolder 736847Box 2Box 23685Pencil-written notes by Georgia Ann Saylor* on news stories in Illinois State RegisterFolder 136861890-18991Scope and Contents*Used by Blankmeyer in compiling "The Story of the City Records"Notes by SaylorFolder 236871900-19032Notes by SaylorFolder 336881904-19083Notes by SaylorFolder 436891909-19134Notes by SaylorFolder 536901914-19155Subject index to Saylor's notes by Dean DeBoltFolder 6369119746

