<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.16Archon Finding Aid Title MC.16UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:38:13 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC16. Booth-Grunendike Family Collection, 1856-1956
    
      Booth-Grunendike Family
    
    MC.16
    23
    
      4.60 Cubic Feet
    
    1856-1956
    Date acquired: 12/05/1979
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Four generations of a prosperous family prominent in Springfield, Illinois. Many of the photographs were taken by Mary Esther Booth Grunendike (1865-1967). Prominently featured are her parents Amasa and Harriot Richardson Booth,  her husband Edward H. Grunendike and son E. Booth Grunendike.The collection contains approximately 4000 photographs, including cartes-de-visite, cabinet cards and cyanotypes, as well as scrapbooks, clippings and memorabilia documenting family members and friends, their business enterprises, homes, farms, travels, social values and activities. Photographic topics include farming activities; natural disasters and fires; Republican Party events; parades and festivals; buildings and monuments in Springfield, Decatur, Beardstown, Quincy and Chicago; President McKinley's 1898 visit to Springfield; Stuart School; Camp Tanner and soldiers of the Spanish-American War; Beardstown Flood; the 1908 Springfield Race Riot (including a postcard); and the Booth Drug Store.The collection is divided into two series: photographic prints, ca. 1870-1950, and Scrapbooks and memorabilia, 1856-1956.Series I: Photographic Prints, ca. 1870-1950 (boxes 1-9), consist of loose photographs arranged alphabetically by topic followed by 20 photo albums arranged in rough chronological order. Duplication exists between the loose prints and photos in the albums. The format of the photographs includes cartes-de-vistes, cabinet cards and cyanotypes, chiefly illustrating family members and friends, their social activities and their travels around the Midwest and abroad. Also pictured are rural scenes and farming activities; natural disasters and fires; Republican Party events; parades and festivals; and buildings and monuments in Springfield, Decatur, Beardstown, Quincy and Chicago, Illinois. Sangamon River at the Peoria Road bridge, north of Springfield, 1890s (now Carpenter Park)Photographs of particular note in the albums include the following: President McKinley's 1898 visit to Springfield (images #436-9, #2594-8, 4203-6); the Illinois State Republican Convention, 1898 (#4202); the burning of Stuart School in Springfield on Palm Sunday, 1898 (#2600-1, #556-9); Camp Tanner, 1898 (#4284-4323, #705-22); soldiers departing for and returning from the Spanish-American War (#723-6, #727-39); the Sangamon County Courthouse (Old State Capitol) on jacks, 1901 (#648-53, #2621-3); the Illinois River flooding at Beardstown, 1901 (#4237-40); the aftermath of the Springfield Race Riot of 1908 (#1066-77, #3147-58); a postcard of the Race Riot (#220, #2300); Decatur fire, 1911 (#656-60, #879-92, #3293-7); Governor Dunne's Inaugural Parade, 1913 (#261-3, #699-701), laying the cornerstone of the Centennial (now Howlett) Building, 1918 (#1290-3); cutting and threshing wheat in 1920 (#1463-9); Governor Green's Inauguration, 1941 (#2350); parade pictures with World War II slogans (#2500-11); the Booth Drug Store (#1674-7, #1927-28, #2640-3, #2831-2; Chicago scenes (#369-691, #4115-54); the A.S. Booth residence at 500 S. Sixth St. in Springfield (#268, #1490-5, #3078-80); interiors of the same (#4231-4235); and the old Booth homestead where Amasa Booth was raised, seven miles north of Springfield (#240-45).Series II: Scrapbooks and Memorabilia, 1856-1956 (boxes 9-14), contains scrapbooks including newspaper clippings, poems, obituaries, wedding announcements, magazine articles and pictures, compiled by Harriot Richardson Booth, Mary E. Booth Grunendike, and Helene Rogers. The scrapbooks contain material assembled over several years. The ones compiled by Harriot Booth and Mary Booth Grunendike contain numerous references to the Booth, Grunendike and related families.The series also contains a collection of drawing exercises (1886-88) executed by Amasa Booth Jr. as a youth; samples of business forms used by Booth and McCosker Carriage and Spring Manufacturers; a scrapbook of pictures of the World's Columbian Exposition of 1893; and two world atlases and two photographic travel books.  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Dean DeBolt &amp; Charles Strozier  
  Photographic PrintsSeries 11589ca. 1870-1950Box 1Box 11575AnimalsFolder 115761870-19501Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsBridges, boats, trains, automobileFolder 215771870-19502Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsBusinessesFolder 315781870-19503Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsCamp TannerFolder 4157919984Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsCandid portaits, one person, unidentifiedFolder 515801870-19505Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsCandid portraits, one person, unidentifiedFolder 615811870-19506Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsCandid portraits, plural, some persons identifiedFolder 715821870-19507Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsCemeteries and GardensFolder 815831870-19508Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsHistoric MonumentsFolder 915841870-19509Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsBox 2Box 21585Houses, buildings, streets, Native American and teepeeFolder 115861870-19501Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsHouse InteriorsFolder 215871870-19502Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsLandscapesFolder 315881870-19503Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsParades, festivals, Chicago Republican HeadquartersFolder 415901870-19504Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsPortraits, identified, cartes de visteFolder 515911870-19505Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsPortraits, identified, cabinet cardsFolder 615921870-19506Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsPortraits, identified, various mountingsFolder 715931870-19507Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsPortraits, unidentified, cartes de visteFolder 815941870-19508Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsBox 3Box 31595Portraits, unidentified, cabinet cardsFolder 115961870-19501Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsPortraits, unidentified, cabinet cardsFolder 215971870-19502Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsPortraits, unidentified, various mountingsFolder 315981870-19503Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsLog BuildingsFolder 415991870-19504Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsRural ScenesFolder 516001870-19505Scope and ContentsPhotographic printsPhoto AlbumFolder 616011890-19106Scope and Contents#2780-2888Box 4Box 41602Photo AlbumFolder 116031897-18981Scope and Contents#2512-2635Photo AlbumFolder 216041897-19122Scope and Contents#279-477Photo AlbumFolder 316051897-19123Scope and Contents#478-697Photo AlbumFolder 416061898-19004Scope and Contents#2636-2779Photo AlbumFolder 516071989-19015Scope and Contents#4113-4323Box 5Box 51608Photo AlbumFolder 116091898-19131Scope and Contents#698-892Photo AlbumFolder 216101899-19112Scope and Contents#1479-1679Photo AlbumFolder 316111902-19033Scope and Contents#2889-3023Photo AlbumFolder 416121907-19114Scope and Contents#3024-3297Box 6Box 61613Photo AlbumFolder 116141908-19111Scope and Contents#893-1077Photo AlbumFolder 216151909-19402Scope and Contents#2211-2392Photo AlbumFolder 316161910-19253Scope and Contents#1-189Box 7Box 71617Photo AlbumFolder 116181911-19131Scope and Contents#190-278Photo AlbumFolder 216191918-19192Scope and Contents#1271-1478Photo AlbumFolder 316201918-19503Scope and Contents#2393-2511Box 8Box 81621Photo AlbumFolder 116221920-19351Scope and Contents#2022-2210Photo AlbumFolder 216231927-19292Scope and Contents#1078-1270Photo AlbumFolder 316241929-19303Scope and Contents#1680-1826Box 9Box 91625Photo AlbumFolder 1162619361Scope and Contents#1827-2021Scrapbooks and MemorabiliaSeries 216271856-1956Scrapbook of Mary E. BoothItem 116471926-19591Scrapbook of Mary E. BoothItem 216481898-19522Scrapbook of Mary E. BoothItem 316491923-19323Scrapbook of Mary E. BoothItem 416501916-19324Shepp's Photographs of the WorldItem 5165118925Sights and Sounds of the WorldItem 6165218946Box 9Box 91628Scrapbook of Harriet Richardson BoothFolder 216291856-18892Scrapbook of Harriet Richardson BoothFolder 316301880-19233Loose papers from scrapbook of Harriet Richardson BoothFolder 416311880-19234Box 10Box 101632Scrapbook of Mary E. BoothFolder 116331882-19561Scrapbook of Mary E. BoothFolder 216341884-19162Loose papers from scrapbook of Mary E. BoothFolder 316351884-19163Geography textbookFolder 4163618784Box 11Box 111637Scrapbook of Mary E. BoothFolder 116381914-19341Family MemorabiliaFolder 216392Scope and ContentsIncludes etching of Jacob Booth residenceBusiness Forms, Booth &amp; McCosker Carriage and Spring Wagon ManufacturersFolder 316403Drawings by Amasa S. BoothFolder 416411886-18884Postcard to Edward Booth Grunendike from "Cousin Bell"Folder 57927019005Scope and ContentsB&amp;W Postcard shows the "birth room" in William Shakespeare's house in Stratford-on-Avon, England. Gift of William Gumm, 2015.Box 12Box 121642Scrapbook, Memorabilia of Columbian ExpositionFolder 1164318931Scope and ContentsInscribed to Ed and Mamie Grunendike from Mary HaworthBox 13Box 131644Peerless Atlas of the WorldFolder 1164518991

