<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.17Archon Finding Aid Title MC.17UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:38:18 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC17. Center for Alternative Education Records, 1970-1982
    
      Center for Alternative Education
    
    
      The Learning Community
    
    MC.17
    24
    
      3.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1970-1982
    Date acquired: 00/00/1983
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Not-for-profit alternative secondary school founded in Springfield in 1970 as the The Learning Community.  Name changed to the Center for Alternative Education in 1980.  In its early years, many students were children of Sangamon State University professors. Directors included Joe McHugh and Nancy Ranyard. Due to financial problems, the Center closed in 1982. 
Minutes, by-laws, articles of incorporation, reports, contracts, applications,  correspondence, schedules, journals, student transcripts, student course work, tests, financial records, photographs, notes, and collected material documenting the  school's philosophy and goals, student enrollment, curricula, course schedules, tuition, fundraising, student/teacher interactions, administrative activities and financial affairs. Two meeting books record student opinions on school rules, activities, and problems.  
See Biographical Note for more information about the Center.  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
Series IV (Boxes 8 &amp; 9) are restricted.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Joe McHugh &amp; J. Ranyard  
  
    Records
    Reports
    Correspondence
    Photographs
    Course Materials
    Papers
  
  ADMINISTRATIVE RECORDSSeries 140641971-82Scope and ContentsSeries I: The ADMINISTRATIVE RECORDS, 1971-82, (Boxes 1-3) consist of minutes, correspondence, by-laws, incorporation papers, reports, contract and enrollment forms, grant and scholarships records, personnel policies, resumes, State, Local and Community Education Training Act (CETA) compliance forms, grant information, personal notes, photographs, an appointment book, and printed material.  This series is arranged alphabetically by topic and documents the objectives, activities, and classroom instruction of the Center for Alternative Education and its predecssor, the The Learning Community. Also included are notes and correspondence regarding tuition and fundraising activities, especially Bingo games.  Of particular note, are The Learning Community Records, 1970-78, which document the founding of The Center of Alternative Education.Box 1Box 14068The Learning Community, administrative and financial recordsFolder 140691971-801Scope and ContentsPart 1 of 2The Learning Community, administrative and financial recordsFolder 240701971-802Scope and ContentsPart 2 of 2Articles of IncorporationFolder 340711980-813Board minutesFolder 44072Jan-Mar, 19824Board meeting minutesFolder 54073Apr-Aug, 19825By-lawsFolder 640746CETAFolder 740751980-827CETA subgrant applicationFolder 840761980-818Capitol Area Vocation CenterFolder 940771981-829CETA invoices for grant #6-81-008Folder 1040781980-8110School description for CETAFolder 11407911Charitable organization report, annualFolder 1240801975-8212Contract forms and tuition schedulesFolder 1340811979-8113Contracts signedFolder 1440821979-80-8114Contracts signedFolder 1540831981-8215CorrespondenceFolder 1640841979-8116Box 2Box 24085CorrespondenceFolder 140861981-821DonationsFolder 240871981-822Faculty evaluationFolder 340883Family Service Center - correspondence and check stubsFolder 440891981-824CAE final closing informationFolder 5409019825Forms and letterhead - blankFolder 640916Fundraising CAEFolder 740921979-827Fundraising fact sheetFolder 840938Fundraising, Bingo informationFolder 9409419829Fundraising, Bingo justificationFolder 104095198210Fundraising letter for moneyFolder 1140961980-8111Full Circle SchoolFolder 124097198112GrantsFolder 1340981981-8213Illinois State Board of EducationFolder 144099198214Illinois State Board of Education immunization surveyFolder 154100198215Immunization survey - needs to be done by Oct. 30Folder 16410116Graduation diploma and party noticeFolder 174102198117Legal Manual for Alternative SchoolsFolder 18410318Letters to parentsFolder 1941041981-8219Letters requesting info on CAEFolder 2041051980-8120Notes on CAE objectives and goals, n.d.Folder 21410621Not for Profit Corporation papers, T.L.C. to C.A.E. name changeFolder 224107198022Notice of school tripsFolder 23410823Ranyard, Nancy personal appointment book and other materialFolder 244109 1976-8224PhotographsFolder 25411025Personnel policies, n.d.Folder 26411126Recognition and accreditationFolder 2741121979-8027Release forms (field trips)Folder 28411328Resumes for DirectorshipFolder 294114198229Rules and regulationsFolder 304115198230School calendarFolder 3141161980-8131School descriptionFolder 324117198032Student-parent assembly meeting notesFolder 3341181980-8133Box 3Box 34119Textbook programFolder 141201981-821(TLC) enrollment application and agreement formsFolder 241211978-792Tuition and enrollment formsFolder 3412219753Tuition noticesFolder 441231980-824Tuition bill receipts, April n.d.Folder 541245XeroxFolder 6412519806CURRICULAR RECORDSSeries 240651980-82Scope and ContentsSeries II:   The CURRICULAR RECORDS, 1980-82, (Box 3) consists of sample course tests, class schedules, students schedules and assignments, and course reference notes and materials.  This series is arranged alphabetically and documents student and faculty curricular activities at The Center for Alternative Education.  Also included are two meeting books which document student opinions on school rules and school related problems, student ideas on curricular and school activities, and list student and faculty weekly clean-up jobs in the school building.Box 3Box 34126Biology, n.d.Folder 741277Class schedules, subjects for Spring 1981Folder 8412819808English test, n.d.Folder 941299The Meeting BookFolder 104130198010Meeting Book, n.d. [1981 ?]Folder 11413111Meeting and clean-up bookFolder 1241321980-8112Radical Therapy, n.d.Folder 13413313Radical Therapy - Thurs. morning, n.d.Folder 14413414Sexual awareness evaluations, Kevin's and other classroom evaluationsFolder 15413515Spring semester notesFolder 164136198216Student assignments, n.d.Folder 17413717Student plan sheetFolder 184138Spring 198218Student schedulesFolder 1941391981 and 1982?19Subjects and IdeasFolder 2041401980-8120Test, n.d.Folder 21414121Thank-you lettersFolder 224142198222Weekly schedulesFolder 234143198223FINANCIAL RECORDSSeries 34066Scope and ContentsSeries III:  The FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1970-82, (Boxes 4-7) consist of bank receipts and statements, cancelled checks, check stubs, account books, budget reports, bill receipts and paid bills, insurance papers, payroll records, petty cash records, federal tax return copies, income tax withholding forms, tax exemption forms, tuition records and vouchers, unemployment reports, correspondence, and pamphlets.  This series is arranged alphabetically by topic and documents the financial affairs of The Center for Alternative Education, and its predecessor, The Learning Community.  The Learning Community financial records precede those of the CAE, and are also arranged alphabetically by topic.Box 4Box 44144TLC bank deposit receiptsFolder 141451971-761TLC bank statementsFolder 241461970-772TLC cancelled checksFolder 341471971-723TLC cancelled checksFolder 4414819734TLC cancelled checksFolder 541491975-775TLC cancelled checksFolder 6415019786TLC checksFolder 741511970-717TLC checkbooksFolder 841521971-788The Learning Center, Treasurer's bookFolder 941539Account BookFolder 1041541977-7910Box 5Box 54155Account bookFolder 141561979-801Account bookFolder 241571980-812Bank deposit envelopesFolder 341583Bank statements (special acc.)Folder 441591980-814Billing receipts, finalFolder 541601982-06-015Bills (unpaid)Folder 6416119826BondingFolder 7416219807BudgetFolder 841631979-828CheckingFolder 9416419809CheckingFolder 104165198210Checking statementFolder 114166198111Checking stubsFolder 124167197912Check stubs and cash disburse journalFolder 1341681980-8113Box 6Box 64169Check stubsFolder 141701980-821Check book, sample pageFolder 241711980-822Close out package CETAFolder 34172Aug. 19803CETA unemploymentFolder 4417319814Deposit receipts and bank statements - First National BankFolder 541741978-805Employer's Quarterly Federal Tax Return, 941 formsFolder 641751972-826Forms needing completion and instructionsFolder 741761978-827Income taxFolder 8417719758InsuranceFolder 9417819809InsuranceFolder 1041791981-8210(Old) paid billsFolder 1141801980-8111Paid billsFolder 1241811981-8212Payroll recordFolder 1341821979-8013Box 7Box 74183Petty cashFolder 141841980-811Quarterly salary withholdingFolder 241852ReceiptFolder 341861981-823Receipt booksFolder 4418719814ReceiptsFolder 541881979-805Special accountFolder 6418919816Taxes, Employer's copyFolder 741907Tax Exemption FormsFolder 841911981 &amp; 19828Savings Account Book and StatementsFolder 941921979-829(Old Student) Tuition recordsFolder 1041931980-8110Tuition vouchers and correspondenceFolder 1141941974-7611UnemploymentFolder 1241951980-8112Unemployment tax return 940Folder 134196198113Withholding tables [n.d.]Folder 14419714STUDENT FILES (Restricted)Series 440671970-82Scope and ContentsSeries IV:  The STUDENT FILES, 1970-82, (Boxes 8-9) consist of student grades and credits, transcripts, evaluations, course schedules, test scores, course work, faculty course materials, correspondence, and journal entries arranged alphabetically by student name and then by topic. This series documents the academic expectations and course offerings of the school and the academic achievements and personal backgrounds of the students.  Of special interest is a diary kept by Director Nancy Ranyard, which documents her observations and perceptions of each student's emotional and behavioral functioning during a two week time span.  Student files prior to 1978 are not included in this series. THIS SERIES IS RESTRICTED

