<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.18Archon Finding Aid Title MC.18UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:38:23 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC18. Donner-Hill Family Papers, 1890-1982
    
      Donner-Hill Family
    
    MC.18
    25
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1890-1982
    Date acquired: 00/00/1982
  
  
    Scope and Contents
A Sangamon County family based in Loami. Descendants of the historically significant Donners whose 1846 emigrant trip to California ended tragically in the Sierra-Nevada Mountains.

Photographs, news clippings, memorial books, correspondence, recipes, a scrapbook, and a diary documenting family relationships, reunions, trips, personal events, and group activities in the lives of the Donners descending from Irven and Emma Martin Donner, and of the Hill family, as related to this branch of the Donners.  Among the topics included are late nineteenth-century camping, train, and steamboat trips;  the 1893 World's Columbian Exposition; interior and exterior views of an early twentieth-century schoolhouse and class;  and, a 1920-21 St. John's Nursing School graduation with related social activities.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Mr. &amp; Mrs. Walter Bridges  
  
    Photographs
    Book
    Diary
  
  Box 1Box 13856Irven Donner family photographsFolder 138571890-19151Scope and ContentsIncludes photos of a schoolhouse, ca. 1910Irven Donner family photographsFolder 238581915-19802Veta Donner Cloomer scrapbookFolder 3385919213Donner family news clippingsFolder 438601959-19824Scope and ContentsIncludes post card of Donner monument, emigrant trip articleMemorial Book, Gordon DonnerFolder 5386119605Memorial Book, Veta Donner CloomerFolder 6386219806Emma Hill trip diaryFolder 738631892-18937Hill family reunion Name Lists &amp; CorrespondenceFolder 838641952 &amp; 19568Scope and ContentsLoami and Decatur

