<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.07.07/123Archon Finding Aid Title J.07.07/123UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:39:24 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J7/7/123. Richard Dimond Papers, 1972-1982
    
      Dimond, Richard
    
    J.07.07/123
    379
    
      1.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1972-1982
    Date acquired: 00/00/1982
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The Richard Dimond papers include:  correspondence, information regarding M.A. program in Clinical Psychology, Illinois Psychological Association Workshops and Presentation, class schedules, handouts, exams.  The file also contains several papers by Richard Dimond, Ronald Havens, as well as other faculty members and students.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Topical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Richard Dimond  
  
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 171498CorrespondenceFolder 1714991974-751CorrespondenceFolder 2715001976-812Membership in Division 30:  Psychological HypnosisFolder 37150119793Employment of M.A. Psychologist Survey, and Employment/Curricula SurveyFolder 4715021974-754Empirically-based Masters ProgramFolder 5715031976-775Development and Evaluation of an Empirically based M.A. Program in Clinical PsychologyFolder 67150419766M.A. Project Outline, Program Guidelines, Program Standards, Questionnaires and Results.Folder 7715057Cluster Planning StatementFolder 87150619808Clinical Psychology at Sangamon State UniversityFolder 9715079M.A. Training Comparisons and the future of M.A.Folder 1071508197910Scope and ContentsPapers - "Controversial Issues and a Model of Practice and Training"," M.A. Program to Train Psychological Specialist", and" Empirical and Conceptual Arguments for Training in Assessment Skills", 1976.Papers - Psychotic and Psychoneurotic DisordersFolder 1171509n.d.11Papers - Family Therapy, n.d., and The Wechsler Adult Intelligence Scale Masculinity-Femininity IndexFolder 127151012Papers - A Critique of Rosenhans On Being Sane in Insane Places", n.d., and Distorted Body Image Perception in SchizophreniaFolder 137151113Paper - Limiting Effects of Conceptual ParadigmsFolder 147151214Paper and Correspondence - Characteristics of Sub-doctoral PsychologistsFolder 1571513197715Paper - Attitudes Toward Personal Therapy, and Community Psychology and ChangeFolder 167151416Paper and Correspondence - Prescriptive Eclecticism in PsychotherapyFolder 177151517Papers - Jourard's Self-Disclosure:  Where Do We Go From HereFolder 187151618Scope and ContentsBehavioral Measurement of Self-disclosure, An Investigation of the Relationship Between Self-Disclosure, Trust and Ordinal Position of Birth, n.d.Papers - Perceptual Defense:  Concept and Controversy, The Role of Imitation in Personality DevelopmentFolder 197151719Papers - The Concept of Man According to Gardner MurphyFolder 207151820Scope and ContentsSimilarities and Differences in Theory, and 
Experimental Studies of the Oedipus Complex, n.d.Papers - Hypothesis - Testing, and On the Alteration of States of ConsciousnessFolder 217151921Papers - How to Implement Improvements in State HospitalsFolder 2271520197422Scope and ContentsKeys to Creative Change:  Analyzing and Altering the Organization of Mental Hospitals, n.d.Papers - Humanism and Transpersonal PsychologyFolder 237152123Scope and ContentsCognition of Infancy:  The Concept of Object Permanence, 1974, and Assessing Intellectual Development with Piagetian Tasks, 1975Paper - Postpartum DisordersFolder 247152224Papers - Bioplasmic Energy, and Hypnosis and Kidney DialysisFolder 257152325Paper - The Goal of Brain FunctionFolder 267152426Paper - Psychotherapy:  What is Wrong?Folder 277152527Paper - New Perspective on Problem Formation and ResolutionFolder 287152628Paper and Correspondence - Clinical Training and Education ModelFolder 2971527197429Paper - An Integrative Perspective for Prescriptive Eclectic PsychotherapistFolder 307152830Paper - The Clinical CubeFolder 317152931Paper - MA Level Clinical Psychologist in Mental Health Facilities: A one-state surveyFolder 327153032Papers - The Prescriptive Application of Meditation as Indicated by Primary Representational SystemFolder 337153133Scope and ContentsInternship Report for Loraine Anderson, 1974, and Practicum , Michael Troy, September, 1973-May, 1974, Christian County Mental Health Association.Papers - An Empirical Assessment of the Need for M.A. Level Clinical Psychology in IllinoisFolder 3471532197634Scope and ContentsA Model of Psychological Practice for Ph.D. and M.A Professionals, n.d., and Ideological Conflict and the Decline of Psychological Testing 1976Paper -Prescriptive Eclecticism in Group PsychotherapyFolder 357153335Paper and Correspondence - "Teaching of Basic PsychologyFolder 36715341975-7636Paper -Evolution of the Current Evaluation Course FormatFolder 377153537National Endowment for the Humanities - Summer ProposalFolder 3871536197838Midwestern Psychological Association Meeting Proposal, Survey and CorrespondenceFolder 39715371977-7839Illinois Psychological Association Workshops and PresentationFolder 40715381977-7840IPA - M.A. ListFolder 4171539197841Psychology Program Minutes and CorrespondenceFolder 42715401978-8042PSY 451 - PsychopathologyFolder 43715411972-198243Scope and ContentsPSY 577 - Personality, PSY 510 - Philosophical Issues in Psychology (includes; handouts, tests and syllabi)PSY 344 - Personality Theory ExamsFolder 4471542197744PSY 553 - Individual Psychotherapy (lecture notes, exams, reading list and syllabi)Folder 45715431975-7945PSY 575 - Theory and Techniques and PSY 578Folder 467154446Scope and ContentsTest Interpretation (notes, bibliography, exams, handouts, syllabi, interview format)PSY 352 and PSY 451 - Abnormal Psychology (paper topics, syllabi, and exams)Folder 47715461974-7847Abnormal Psychology Proficiency ExamFolder 487154548Clinical Psychology ProgramFolder 49715471973-7649Scope and Contents(procedures, correspondence, operations manual for Psychological Clinic at Indiana State University)Psychology Program Review ReportFolder 5071548197950Health InsuranceFolder 51715491976-7951Relaxation StepsFolder 527155052Curriculum Vitae for Richard E. Dimond and Ronald A. HavensFolder 5371551197853Scope and ContentsResume for Dorothea C. Anthony

