<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.24Archon Finding Aid Title MC.24UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:39:30 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC24. Springfield Coalition for Fair Electricity Rates, Records, 1976-1981
    
      Springfield Coalition for Fair Electricity Rates
    
    MC.24
    31
    
      0.16 Cubic Feet
    
    1976-1981
    Date acquired: 00/00/1983
  
  
    Scope and Contents
A coalition of individuals and representatives of community formed in 1976 in response to the proposed rate hike by the municipally-owned utility, City Water, Light and Power (CWLP).  Dedicated to electric rate reform.

Correspondence, announcements, press releases, clippings, reports, pamphlets, position papers, rate schedules, minutes and agendas, comsumer cost comparisons, and sundry other documents concerning the proposed rate hike by CWLP and the oppositions to it by SCFER.  Also includes Springfield East Association news releases and minutes, a public hearing statement of the Mother Jones Chapter of the New American Movement and personal notes regarding opposition to the Capitol City Railroad Relocation Authority plans to relocate railroads on Springfield's Eastside, 1976; and a Capitol City Railroad Relocation Authority hearing document, 1981.  The Springfield East Association's 1976 project, "Public Dialogue on Alternative Organizational Forms for Springfield City Government" is also documented.  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
David Lasley  
  
    Correspondence
    Records
    Reports
  
  Box 1Box 15116Position papers, correspondence, press releases, minutes, agenda, &amp; testimonyFolder 151171C.W.L.P.:  General information, rates, positions, 1971-1976Folder 251182Book Chapter 8: "Automatic Fuel Adjustment Clause"Folder 351193Documents:Folder 451204Scope and Contents"Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act", Department of Housing &amp; Urban Development Notice, &amp; "A Ratepayer's Guide to PURPA" by Alden Meyer for the Environmental Action FoundationErnst &amp; Ernst Report and ResponsesFolder 551215Bertschi &amp; Knecht Report, 1977Folder 651226NAM Newsletter, questionnaire, &amp; statementsFolder 751237Newsclippings on CWLP &amp; SCFER, March - May, 1976Folder 851248Grant Application for Office of Consumer ServicesFolder 951259Dresden Nuclear Plant Decontamination, 1980Folder 10512610Railroad Relocation: General &amp; Hearing, 1976 &amp; 1981Folder 11512711

