<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.25Archon Finding Aid Title MC.25UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:39:32 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC25. DES Action Group Records, 1972-1976
    
      DES Action Group
    
    
      Sherard, Susan
    
    
      Sakolsky, Ron
    
    
      Merkin, Don
    
    MC.25
    32
    
      0.16 Cubic Feet
    
    1972-1976
    Date acquired: 00/00/1983
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The DES Action Group Records, 1972-76, consists of letters, brochures, timetables, newsletters, news clippings,  planning and meeting notes, and collected research material  documenting the Group's planning, purpose, and publicity efforts;  its public hearing on DES; and its preliminary application to the  American Cancer Society for a grant. Also includes some materials of the local "Action Faction" of the New American Movement,  including notes and newsletters documenting its relations with  the DES Action Group. 

A Springfield community organization organized to disseminate information to the public about the health hazards of DES (diethylstilbestrol) to women and their offspring, and to promote better and more accessible testing facilities for DES-related health problems. Founded in 1975. Included local representatives of the New American Movement, the Springfield City Health  Department, the People's Institute, the Illinois Department of  Public Health, the National Organization of Women, the Southern  Illinois University School of Medicine's Department of Health  Care Planning, and Planned Parenthood Springfield Area. 

Principal leaders included Susan Sherard of Planned Parenthood, Ron Sakolsky Assistant Professor at Sangamon State University, and Don Merkin, Assistant Professor at Southern Illinois University School of Medicine.  

Held a public hearing on the DES issue on April 27,  1976.  
  
    Arrangement Note
By subject  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
David Lasley  
  
    Related Materials
SEE ALSO:  P/Sakolsky - Ron Sakolsky Papers  
  
    Correspondence
    Records
    Newspaper Clippings
    Papers
    Newsletters
  
  Box 1Box 15128News clippings, newsletters, notes, correspondence, timetables, 1976Folder 151301Flyers and brochures, 1976Folder 251312New American Movement material, 1976-1977Folder 351333

