<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.26Archon Finding Aid Title MC.26UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:39:37 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC26. Streetside Boosters, Records, 1976-1985
    
      Streetside Boosters
    
    
      Townsend, Mike (Townsend, Michael Patrick)
    
    MC.26
    33
    
      7.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1976-1985
    1
    26
    2
    3
    4
    5
    6
    7
    8
    9
    10
    11
    12
    13
    14
    15
    16
    17
    18
    19
    20
    21
    22
    23
    24
    25
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The Streetside Boosters Records, 1976-85, consists of minutes, reports, correspondence, by-laws, membership lists, activity schedules, student papers, articles of incorporation, job descriptions, clippings, student papers, employment and legal records, poetry, manuscripts, musical compositions, thank-you notes, research records, newspapers, photographs, film, audio and video tapes, grant applications and financial records documenting the organization's philosophy and goals; civic, cultural and educational activities; and financial affairs. 

Topics include Springfield's Eastside neighborhood, juvenile delinquency, community organizing, minority youth and education in Springfield, neighborhood newspapers, and blues and African music; Blacks, Whites and Blues Festivals; Blues-in-the-Schools Program; opposition to the construction of the Madison Street Expressway through the John Hay Homes area; SSU student involvement with the Boosters, under the leadership of Townsend; redlining in Springfield; campaigns to save the East Branch Library and Palmer School; hiring practices of the Illinois State-Journal Register; juvenile involvement in the Springfield police and court systems; CETA employment of Springfield youth; Eastside murals and sculpture; publication of the Booster's newspapers, People's Press and Social Justice Reporter; and other neighborhood issues. 

Includes 47 audio and video tapes of musical performances at the Blues-in-the-Schools Program and the Blacks, Whites and Blues Festivals. 

Non-profit community organization operating on Springfield's Eastside, founded in 1975 as a SSU project by professor Michael Townsend. Dedicated to reducing the amount of crime and delinquency in census tracts 8, 15, 16 and 17, and to fostering Eastside citizen involvement in analyzing and remedying neighborhood problems.  Sponsored numerous cultural, civic, athletic and educational activities involving Eastside youth and their families, including the Blues-in-the-Schools program, and the annual Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival. 

     The collection has been divided into nine series: General Papers, 1976-85; Juvenile Delinquency Study Records, 1974-76; People's Press and Social Justice Reporter Records, 1975-84; Blues-in-the-Schools and Festival Records, 1977-85; C.E.T.A. Youth Employment Records, 1979-80; Madison Street Highway Records, 1979-85; Grant Applications and Financial Records,
1975-85; Photographs and Videotapes, 1976-85; and Oversize material.

Series Description

     Series I: The GENERAL PAPERS, 1976-85 (Boxes 1-3), consist of Board minutes, reports, correspondence, membership lists, by-laws, articles of incorporation, job descriptions, newspaper clippings, student papers, and employment and legal records. This series is arranged alphabetically by topic and documents the objectives, activities and programs of the Streetside Boosters, particularly in its work with the Springfield Eastside community.  Papers documenting SSU student involvement with the Boosters, under the leadership of Professor Mike Townsend, are included. 
Topics include redlining in Springfield, Booster campaigns to save the East Branch Library and Palmer School, and other neighborhood issues.

     Series II: The JUVENILE DELINQUENCY STUDY RECORDS, 1974-76 (Boxes 3-4), consist of collected data and census map profiles, reference material, computer cards and correspondence with the Sangamon County Circuit Court judge. The series documents the 1976 SSU class project which compiled statistical studies of juvenile involvement in the Springfield police and court systems and provided a profile by census tract of Springfield "Youth in Trouble" for the years 1974-75.

     Series III: The PEOPLE'S PRESS AND SOCIAL JUSTICE REPORTER RECORDS, 1975-84 (Boxes 5 and 5A) contain drafts of articles and poetry, manuscripts, correspondence, news releases, collected news clippings and reference material. This series is arranged alphabetically by topic and documents the publication of the Streetside Booster's neighborhood newspaper, which began publication in 1976 as the People's Press and was renamed The Social Justice Reporter in 1983.  Microfilm of the People's Press, 1976-79, and originals of both newspapers, 1976-84, is included.  (Also refer to Series IX.)

     Series IV: THE BLUES IN THE SCHOOLS AND FESTIVAL RECORDS, 1977-85 (Boxes 6-9), consist of biographical profiles, promotional material, correspondence, grant applications and proposals, personal notes and planning papers, and news clippings and financial records. This series is arranged in chronological order and documents the Illinois Humanities Council-sponsored Artists-in-Residence program, 1977-81, which brought blues and African musicians to conduct workshops in Springfield's elementary and high schools. Of note are the elementary school students' thank-you notes, and the high-school students' journals, musical compositions and evaluations of the Blues Program. This series also contains SSU students' self-evaluations from a course which focused on the Blues-in-the-Schools project.  Also documented are the Annual Blacks, Whites and Blues Festivals.  Audio and video tapes concerning the Blues-in-the-Schools Program and the Festivals can be found in the Archives' tape collection. Related photographs can be found in Series VIII.

    Series V: The CETA YOUTH EMPLOYMENT RECORDS, 1979-80 (Box 9), consist of applications, proposals, correspondence, evaluations, reference material, CETA regulations and financial records. This series is arranged chronologically and documents the training and/or employment of Springfield youth through the efforts of the Streetside Boosters. Also included in this series are the 1979 Summer Youth Program records concerning CETA youth working at SSU.

    Series VI: The MADISON STREET HIGHWAY RECORDS, 1979-85 (Boxes 9-10) consist of correspondence, reports, news clippings, posters, flyers, and reference material documenting the Streetside Booster's role in mobilizing opposition to construction of an eastside section of the Madison Street Highway through the John Hay Homes area. Collected pro-expressway letters, an environmental impact statement, tape and transcript of the 1980 public hearing, and tape of a protest at a 1985 Department of Transportation meeting are included.

    Series VII: The GRANT APPLICATIONS AND FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1975-85 (Boxes 10-14), consist of grant applications, project proposals, contracts, evaluation reports, correspondence, personal notes and news clippings. This series is arranged chronologically by grant received; for each funded grant, the general papers precede the financial and personnel records. Also included at the end of the series are grant proposals not having financial records, and sundry financial records of the Boosters.

    Series VIII: PHOTOGRAPHS AND VIDEOTAPES, 1976-85 (Boxes 15-24) consist of black and white and color photographic prints, negatives and slides chiefly concerning the Blues-in-the-Schools Program and the Blacks, Whites and Blues Festivals. The photographic prints have, where possible, been arranged alphabetically by event/topic; corresponding negatives have been assigned numbers (which are recorded as well on the back of each print) and are filed numerically. Of particular note is an 8mm film featuring preparations and activities at the 1977 Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival. 
   The videotapes consist mostly of 3/4" U-Matic videocassettes of the Blacks. Whites and Blues Festival of July 28, 1984, showing the Bogan-Armstrong Tennessee Blues String Band and Yank Rachel. 

   Series IX: OVERSIZE. Posters of Boosters events, copies of the newspapers "People's Press" and "Social Justice Reporter," and 1908 Springfield Race Riot research material. (Also refer to Series III.)  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Mike Townsend and the Streetside Boosters - Gifts of 1982 and 1985  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Additional items donated by M. Townsend in May &amp; June of 2012  
  
    Accruals and Additions
1982-1985, 4/20/2001, 5/15/2009, and 6/9/2010.  
  
    Records
    Photographs
    Reports
  
  General Papers, 1976-85Series 15370Box 1Box 15378Articles of IncorporationFolder 153791Athletic programs and activities, 1976-80Folder 253802Black History Celebrations, 1981, 1984Folder 353813Board minutes, by-laws, goals and objectives, and correspondence, 1978-82Folder 453824Board minutes, 1983-85Folder 553835Busing controversy, 1985Folder 653846Case Referrals, 1977, 1980Folder 753857Civil Rights/Voting Rights lawsuit against the city of Springfield, plaintiff's memorandum, 1985Folder 853868Community Outreach, CFC 448, Spring 1979, student project and papersFolder 9106909Cooperating agencies, 1976-80Folder 101069110Correspondence, 1978-82Folder 111069211Correspondence and general papers, 1983Folder 121069312Correspondence and general papers, 1984Folder 131069413Correspondence and general papers, 1985Folder 141069514Box 2Box 25393East Branch Library, Booster campaign to save East BranchFolder 153941Fundraisers, l978-Folder 253952Handbook, 1984Folder 353963Board of Directors HandbookFolder 4510181983-19854Scope and ContentsIntroduction, Goals and Objectives, Philosophy, Accomplishments, Grants, By-Laws, Policies, and Minutes &amp; Memos.Correspondence, By-Laws, Fundraising Plans, Budgets, and News ArticlesFolder 5510191975-19865State Certification and Deputy RegistrarsFolder 65102019846Haunted HouseFolder 753971979-19837Job Corps Center--Concordia Seminary, 1978Folder 853988Job descriptions and employment records, 1975-78Folder 953999LogosFolder 10540010Neighborhood issues, 1978, 1980Folder 11540111Streetside Booster's Neighborhood Oganization Board of Director's HandbookFolder 1276457198512Box 3Box 35402News clippings, 1978-Folder 154031Mural Project, "Our Time Has Come", 1984; correspondence, posters and news clippingsFolder 254042Booster campaign to save Palmer SchoolFolder 354053People's Fund, 1978Folder 454064Personal notesFolder 554075Pony League, Colt League Baseball, 1978Folder 654086Redlining in Springfield, 1983Folder 754097Summer 1978, student projects and papersFolder 854108Summer 1979, student projects and papersFolder 954119Spring 1979, student projects and papersFolder 10541210Student Papers, Photographs, and Camping Trip Proposal, 1976Folder 115102111Census Tract DataFolder 125191512State Journal Register article-1908 Race Riot ReferenceFolder 13519165/15/200913Scope and ContentsDave Bakke column references the Springfield Race Riot with article "Days after Race Riot, N.Y. Giants played here."  Refers to Giants manager receiving an actual piece of the rope used to lynch either William Donnegan or Scott Burton during the riots as a souvenir of his visit to the city.Juvenile Delinquency Study Records, 1974-76Series 25371Box 3Box 35413Census Tract Data, undatedFolder 12541412Box 4Box 45415Juvenile Center dataFolder 154161Juvenile Delinquency Study, correspondence and planning papers and reportFolder 254172Juvenile Delinquency study, pin map statisticsFolder 354183Police dataFolder 454194Police and census tract dataFolder 554205Reference materialFolder 654216Computer cards and keypunch instructionsFolder 754227People's Press and Social Justice Reporter RecordsSeries 35372Box 5Box 55423Collected news clippings and articles, 1976-80Folder 154241Outgoing correspondence, 1976-Folder 254252Incoming correspondence, 1976-Folder 354263Drafts, 1975-76Folder 454274Submitted manuscripts and articles, 1976-78Folder 554285Submitted manuscripts and articles, 1977-79Folder 654296Personal notes and planningFolder 754307Publication checklist and notesFolder 854318Reports, bulletins, announcements and reference material, 1978-79Folder 954329Newsletters and magazines, 1977-79Folder 10543310News releases, 1978-80Folder 11543411Submitted poetry and cartoons, 1976-78Folder 12543512Springfield Race Riot, 1908, research materialFolder 13543613Miscellaneous PapersFolder 145099814Scope and ContentsThe People's Press list of issues, manuscripts, poetry, news articles, masthead of The Eastside Social Justice Reporter, various graphics and clip art.Photographs, black and white, undatedFolder 155099915Scope and ContentsProf. Andy Edwards, Lincoln Library East branch, The Den Chili Parlor, John Hay Homes Springfield Housing Authority, group (classroom and outdoors), Martin Luther King, Jr., Siqusno Douglas, William Horton, and unknown people and locations.Cartoons - Big Government/Corporate spending and abuses, undatedFolder 165100016Cartoons - Military/Anti-Military, Communism &amp; Socialism, undatedFolder 175100117Miscellaneous newspaper cartoons and graphics, undatedFolder 185100218Miscellaneous newspaper articles and cartoonsFolder 19510031983-04-02 - 1988-07-1219Cartoons, Graphics and Original Artwork, undatedFolder 205100420Scope and ContentsRacism, poverty, unemployment and solidarity.Cartoons - Ronald Reagan, undatedFolder 215100521Cartoons - Social Services, poverty and unemployment, undatedFolder 225100622Cartoons - South Africa and Apartheid, undatedFolder 235100723Cartoons - Washington and FeifferFolder 24510081981 - 198724Box 26Box 2677209People's Press, [originals] 1976-80 and [microfilm] 1976-79; Social Justice Reporter [originals] 1983-84Item 1106991Scope and ContentsPeople's Press and the Social Justice Reporter were published by M. Townsend's classes in Social Action and Alternative Media at SSU in conjunction with the Eastside Booster's Club about issues concerning the east side of Springfield, Illinois
Multiple copiesThe People's Press, Vol. 1, No. 1Item 150983April 197611The People's Press, Vol. 1, No. 2Item 250984June 197612The People's Press, Vol. 1, No. 3Item 350985October 197613The People's Press, Vol. 1, No. 4Item 450987December 197614The People's Press, Vol. 2, No. 1Item 550986April 197715The People's Press, Vol. 6Item 675527June-July 197716The People's Press, Vol. 7Item 750988September-October 197717The People's Press, Issue 8Item 850989December/January 1977-7818The People's Press, Issue 9Item 950990Spring 197819The People's Press, Issue 10Item 1050991Summer 1978110The People's Press, Issue 11Item 1150992Fall 1978111The People's Press, Issue 12Item 1250993Spring 1979112The People's Press, Issue 13Item 1350994Summer 1979113The People's Press, Issue 14Item 1450995Winter 1979-1980114The Eastside Social Justice Reporter, Issue No. 15Item 1550996Spring 1983115The Eastside Social Justice Reporter, Issue No. 16Item 1650997Spring 1984116Blues in the Schools and Festival Records, 1977-85Series 45373Box 6Box 65437Blacks, Whites, Blues II, 1978Folder 154381Blacks, Whites, Blues III, 1979Folder 254392Blacks, Whites, Blues IV, 1980Folder 354403Blacks, Whites, Blues V, 1981Folder 454414Blacks, Whites, Blues VI, 1982Folder 554425Blacks, Whites, Blues VII, 1983Folder 654436Blacks, Whites, Blues VIII, 1984Folder 754447Blacks, Whites, Blues IX, 1985Folder 854458Blues workshops and concerts, 1977Folder 954469Scope and ContentsIllinois Arts Council grant #77-456Correspondence and planning papers, 1978-79Folder 10544710Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsNews clippings and posters, 1978-80Folder 11544811Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsStudent essays from Mr. Fred Nika, Lanphier High School, 1979Folder 12544912Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsBlues Who's Who: Partial list of performers appearing in Blacks, Whites, and Blues Festivals or Blues-in-the-Schools ProgramsFolder 138286113Box 7Box 75450Correspondence and planning papers, 1981Folder 154511Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsMusician promotional material, 1981Folder 254522Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsNews clippings and posters, 1981Folder 354533Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsPAC 434, self-evaluations, Spring 1980Folder 454544Illinois Arts Council Artist-in-Residence proposals, 1976-77Folder 554555Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsIllinois Arts Council papers and proposal, 1978Folder 654566Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsNews clippings and posters, 1980Folder 754577Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsCorrespondence and planning papers, 1980Folder 854588Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsCorrespondence and publicity, 1981Folder 954599Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsFinancial records acct. # 21-454Folder 10546010Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsThank-you letters from students, 1980Folder 11546111Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsElementary student letters to Suso, 1980Folder 12546212Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsElementary student letters to Suso, 1980Folder 13546313Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsBox 8Box 85464Elementary class evaluations, 1980Folder 154661Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsBlues in the Schools, 1979-80Folder 254672Financial records, 1979-80, acct. # 21-406Folder 354683Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsFinancial records, 1979-80, acct. # 21-406Folder 454694Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsFinancial records, 1978-79, acct. # 21-345Folder 554705Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsHigh-school student evaluations, journals and musical compositions, 1979Folder 654716High-school student evaluations, journals and musical compositions, 1979Folder 754727High-school student evaluations, journals and musical compositions, 1979Folder 854738High-school student evaluations, journals and musical compositions, 1979Folder 954749Planning notes, correspondence, applications, 1977-79, firstFolder 10547510Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsPosters, 1979-81Folder 11547611Scope and ContentsBlues in the SchoolsAfro-American Music (PAC 453): Student Papers and Exams, 1981Folder 125102812Breakfast Optimist Club letterItem 1510291981-11-29121Scope and ContentsRe: Donation to the "Blues in the Schools" program.Palmer, Delores.  "Eddie Boyd:  Great Pianist and Singer Popular in the 1950's"Item 2510311981-04-07122Beard, Blanch.  "Afro Americans Music Directory"Item 3510301981-05-13123Smith, Jim.  "Black and Blues Festival"Item 4510321981-07-27124Student answers to Afro-American Music Examination, ndItem 551033125Catalog, "African American Perspectives:  The Definitive Collection now on DVD"Item 651034ca. 2002126Correspondence, Notes, Contracts, Donations and FlyersFolder 13510351983-198413Festival Correspondence, Contracts, Licenses, Budgets, and News ArticlesFolder 1451036198514Festival Correspondence, Notes, Contracts, Flyers, Donations and BudgetsFolder 15510371986-1987, 199115Blues in the Schools Photographs, black and white, undatedFolder 165103816CETA Youth Program Records, 1979-80Series 55374Box 9Box 95477Summer Youth Program, 1979Folder 154781CETA Summer Youth employment, 1979, [financial]Folder 2547921980 Summer Youth ProgramFolder 354803CETA Youth Employment [youth education and training program evaluations, 1980]Folder 454814CETA public service employment [Title VI projects, 1980]Folder 554825Madison Street Highway Records, 1979-85Series 65375Box 9Box 95483Madison St. Project hearing, Springfield Housing Authority, November 13, 1980Folder 654846Audiocassette tape of Madison Street protest, Department of Transportation meetingFolder 754851985-09-097Box 10Box 1010584Reference material including maps and excerpts of draft environmental impact statement, 1980Folder 1105851Correspondence and collected pro-highway letters, 1979-85Folder 2105862Madison Street Improvement Project Environmental Impact Statement (draft) Illinois Department of Transportation, 1979Folder 3105873Neighbors Against the Expressway news clippings, posters and other opposition material, 1979-85Folder 4105884Correspondence, Petitions, News Articles, and NotesFolder 5510271979-11-21 - 1980-12-025Grants, Applications and Financial Records, 1975-85Series 75376Box 10Box 1010589Correspondence, Grant Applications and Project Proposals, 1977-1979Folder 6105906Scope and ContentsRevenue Sharing Fund, acct. # 21-220Financial Records, 1977-1978Folder 7105917Scope and Contents(1 of 2 Folders)
Revenue Sharing Fund, acct. # 21-220Financial Records, 1977-1978Folder 8105928Scope and Contents(2 of 2 Folders)
Revenue Sharing Fund, account # 21-220Correspondence and General Revenue Sharing Funds, Capitol TownshipFolder 9105931979-19809Scope and ContentsRevenue Sharing Fund, acct. # 21-380Box 11Box 1110594Capital Township acct. # 21-380, [1980]Folder 1105981Capitol Township Revenue Sharing Applications and contracts, 1983-85Folder 2105992Community Development Grant, acct. # 21-380, 1979Folder 3106003Community Development Grant, 1980Folder 4106014Community Development Lawsuit Papers, 1980Folder 5106025Community Development Grant, financial records, 1979-80Folder 6106036Community Development Grant, financial records, 1979-80Folder 7106047Community Development Grant, 1981Folder 8106058Box 12Box 1210595Grant -- Ill. Comm. on Delinquency Prevention, acct. # 21-194, 1976-77 [applications and correspondence]Folder 1106061Grant -- Ill. Comm. on Delinquency Prevention, acct. # 21-194, 1976-77Folder 2106072Grant -- Ill. Comm. on Delinquency Prevention, acct. # 21-194, 1976-77Folder 3106083Illinois Commission of Delinquency Prevention, 1981Folder 4106094Illinois Commission of Delinquency Prevention applications and correspondence, 1980Folder 5106105Community Development Grant, acct. # 21-304, applications and correspondence, 1977-78Folder 6106116Community Development Grant, acct. # 21-304, applications and correspondence, 1979Folder 7106127Community Development Grant, acct. # 21-304, financial records, 1978-79Folder 8106138Box 13Box 1310596Community Development Grant, acct. #21-304, financial records, 1978-79Folder 1106141Youth Outreach Project, Venture Fund proposal, 1975Folder 2106152Youth Outreach Project, acct. # 21-175, 1978-79Folder 3106163Youth Outreach Project, acct. # 21-175, 1979-80Folder 4106174Youth Outreach, 1982Folder 5106185Ill. Arts Council, acct. # 21-210, Booster's Blues Concert, financial records, 1977Folder 6106196Information Services, acct. # 21-403, financial recordsFolder 7106207Humanity Fund, July 1, 1980Folder 8106218Revision:  The Illinois Maximum Security Prison Project, 1982-83Folder 9106229Artist-in-Residence Folk Art Grant, 1981Folder 101062310C.E.T.A. applications for Community Service Workers, 1977-78Folder 111062411City Spirit Program Grant, 1975Folder 121062512Mural Project, "Corporate State, 1984," Summer 1982Folder 131062613Mott Foundation GrantFolder 1437146198014Correspondence and Grant Applications with the Illinois Arts CouncilFolder 15510391979, 1981, 1984, 198815Mural #1, "Corporate State": Correspondence, News Articles, Grant Applications and PhotographsFolder 1637147Summer 198216Scope and ContentsColor photograph includes: Mike Townsend, Sheila Ransom, Edwin Shields, David Ransom, Michael Tate, Ernestine Stewart, Troy Abernathy, and Tony Moore.Box 14Box 1410597Mural, "Our Time Has Come," 1984, grant application and correspondenceFolder 1106271Sculpture Project, 1985Folder 2106282Young Filmmaker's Project, 1983Folder 3106293Grant applications, proposals only [no financial records]Folder 4106304Booster account - bank statements, checks, deposits, bank booksFolder 5106315Booster account receiptsFolder 6106326Paid receipts for Booster activities, 1976-78Folder 7106337Insurance papers and property leaseFolder 8106348Correspondence, flyers, financial records, 1982Folder 9106359Correspondence, flyers, financial records, 1982-85Folder 101063610Correspondence, flyers, financial records, 1984-86Folder 111063711Box 25Box 2551040Mural #1, "Corporate State": News Articles and Email CorrespondenceFolder 1510411984, 1988, 2001, 20041Mural #2, John Hay Summer Mural Project: Correspondence, Grant Applications, Receipts, Budgets, Photographs and NegativesFolder 25104219842John Hay Homes Sculpture Project, "Circle of Dreams": Correspondence, Grant Application, Artist Agreements and News ArticlesFolder 351043Summer 19853"Circle of Dreams" Sculpture, WICS NBC Ch. 20 NewsVideotape 1510441985-08-28Scope and ContentsInstalled 8/22/85; Dedicated and aired on news 8/28/85.Corporate StateCD 1742861984Scope and ContentsPictures of slides from various phases of the project creating the of "Corporate State" mural in 1984"Circle of Dreams" Sculpture, 35mm slidesSlide 151045Scope and ContentsImages of various phases of the project, from creation to completion.Photographs &amp; Videotapes (Includes Blacks, Whites &amp; Blues Festival Tapes)Series 853771976-85Box 15Box 1510638Athletic eventsFolder 1106471[Blacks, Whites and Blues], Eastside Festival, 1976Folder 2106482Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival, 1977Folder 3106493Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival, 1978Folder 4106504Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival, 1979Folder 5106515Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival, 1980-81Folder 6106526Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival, 1982Folder 7106537Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival scrapbook, 1982Folder 8106548Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival, 1983Folder 9106559Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival, 1984Folder 101065610Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival, 1984 #300-329Folder 111065711Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival, 1985Folder 11.101065911.10Skating Stadium Dance, Fenton Robinson and Magic Slim, October 22, 1976Folder 121065812Suso photographs, 1979Folder 131066013Blues in the Schools, 1979Folder 141066114Blues in the Schools, Fenton Robinson, 1979Folder 151066215Blues in the Schools, Fenton Robinson, photos and film, 1979Folder 161066316Suso at SSU, Spring 1979 or 1980Folder 171066417Blues in the Schools, 1980Folder 181066518Blues in the Schools, 1980Folder 191066619Box 16Box 1610639Blues musicians, n.d., [removed from financial records account # 21-210]Folder 1106671Blues in the Schools, 1981Folder 2106682Comprehensive Training Employment Act [CETA] Youth Employment, 1979Folder 3106693Chicago tour, 1978Folder 4106704Chicago Area Project Tour, 3/26 - 3/27/1976Folder 5106715Chicago tour # 3, Dec. 1977Folder 6106726ChildrenFolder 7106737Delinquency Prevention Conference, SSU, 1/26 - 1/27/77Folder 8106748Group photographsFolder 9106759Eastside Sports Banquet, Masonic Lodge, Oct. 1977Folder 101067610Halloween and Haunted House, 1977-Folder 111067711Illinois Times class photographs, 1976Folder 121067812Individual portraitsFolder 131067913Lake of the Ozarks camping trip, Aug. 1980Folder 141068014Mural Project, "Corporate State, 1984," 1982Folder 151068115Mural Project, "Our Time Has Come," 1984Folder 161068216Neighborhood Art Show (pre-Booster event)Folder 171068317People's Press [includes Palmer School photos], 1976-Folder 181068418SSU Graduation Dance, May 1979Folder 191068519Sculpture Project 1985, "Circle of Dreams"Folder 201068620State Golden Gloves Tournament, 1984Folder 211068721Miscellaneous photosFolder 221068822Unidentified musiciansFolder 231068923Scope and ContentsFenton RobinsonPhotographic negatives, #1-150Box 1710640Photographic negatives, #150-299Box 1810641Photographic negatives, #300-Box 1910642Slide tray A - Blues in the SchoolsBox 2010643Slide trays B-C, Blacks, Whites, Blues 1982Box 2110644Slide Tray D – Streetside BoostersBox 2210645Scope and ContentsAlso Includes:   Illinois Arts Council; Mural Project; "Corporate State 1984"; Painted on Neighborhood; Facilities Building, 1411 E. Jefferson; Summer 1982; Artist-in-Residence; John Yancy (Chicago)Slide, Prints, Negatives, Contact Prints: Performance and FestivalsBox 2310646VideotapesBox 2444112Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival, 35 mm slidesItem 1510161984-081Scope and ContentsVarious shots of bands, crowd and activities.Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival, 35 mm slidesItem 2510171985-082Scope and ContentsVarious shots of bands, crowd and activities.Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival 1984; Yank Rachel and the Blues Masters, 7-27-84Videotape 110575Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival 1984; Yank Rachel and the Blues Masters, 7-27-84Videotape 210576Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival 1984; Bogan-Armstrong Tennessee Blues String Band, 7-28-84Videotape 310577Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival 1984; Bogan-Armstrong Tennessee Blues String Band, 7-28-84Videotape 410578Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival 1984; Bogan-Armstrong Tennessee Blues String Band Yank Rachel "Sittin'-in", 7-28-84Videotape 510580Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival 1984; Bogan-Armstrong Tennessee Blues String Band, with Yank Rachel "Sittin'-in", 7-28-84Videotape 610581WICS-TV; Blacks, Whites and Blues, 7-27-84 through 7-28-84, 10 pm news and raw tapeVideotape 710582Prairie Media, "No Title" 8-30-85Videotape 810583Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival 1983 shot by Kool TVVideotape 951009Scope and ContentsFootball, RAP contest, (Dewayne Readus) Dance contest, fashion show, Henry Miles &amp; Band, miscellaneous shots of crowd and mural, and Chicago Raiders vs. Springfield Mudkickers.Blacks, Whites and Blues FestivalVideotape 1051010Scope and ContentsBlacks, Whites and Blues Festival (1983); Channel 20 News coverage of Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival (1984); and Apple-a-day Summer Computer Project (1984).Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival 1983 shot by Kool TVVideotape 1151011Scope and ContentsDaytime shots and talent contest.Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival, 1983Videotape 1251012Scope and ContentsEddie Tate interviews of Sheila Ransom, Coach John Howell, Harvey Richards, and others.Blacks, Whites and Blues FestivalVideotape 13510131984-07-28Scope and Contents(Tape 1 of 2)  Various activities, Bogan-Armstrong String Band, Yank Rachel and the Blues Masters.Blacks, Whites and Blues FestivalVideotape 14510141984-07-28Scope and Contents(Tape 2 of 2)  Various activities, Bogan-Armstrong String Band with Yank Rachel.Blacks, Whites and Blues FestivalVideotape 15510151985-08-30Scope and ContentsVarious activities (no audio).Oversize Flat File (drawer 5)Series 910696Scope and ContentsItem (C) People's Press newspapers moved to Series 3, Box 26(A) Black History Celebration postersItem 11069719841(B) Haunted House photo collage (People's Press)Item 21069819782(D) Springfield Race Riot research material [photos of and original newspapers]Item 4107004(E) Blacks, Whites and Blues Festival postersItem 5107011977-855(F) Blues in the Schools postersItem 6107021976-816(G) Cartoons published in People's PressItem 7107031979-807(H) Our Time Has Come scale sketchItem 84779919848(J) BWB Poster, Wendell Smith Streetside BoostersItem 95141619849(K) The Final Round: A Springfield Boxing Legend RemeberedItem 1075523201010(L) Angela Davis in SpringfieldItem 117552411(M) SSU Moral Laxity Cited!: Resolution for Restoration of Common Sense and Decency in Public EducationItem 1275525197612(O) There's a New Gang in the Neighborhood: Springfield's Streetside BoostersItem 1375526197613

