<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.27Archon Finding Aid Title MC.27UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:39:46 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC27. Brainchild Collective Records,  1973-1985
    
      Brainchild Collective
    
    
      SSU Women's Studies Committee
    
    MC.27
    34
    
      0.16 Cubic Feet
    
    1973-1985
    Date acquired: 00/00/1982
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The Brainchild collective was a women's writing group founded in 1972 to provide a supportive environment for female writers in Springfield. Initially affiliated with Sangamon State University. Members have included Patin Hilton, Peg Knoepfle, Sandra Martin and Rosie Richmond. Also included are documents from Rosemary F. Richmond's memorial service and business "Richmond Staff Development."Publications, flyers, news clippings, calendars, postcards, photographs and poetry documenting the collective's activities are included.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Brainchild Collective and  SSU Women's Studies Committee  
  
    Accruals and Additions
I added publications and documents from Rosemary F. Richmond's business: Richmond Staff Development. They were culled from disposed SSU Continuing Education files. Chris Schnell 8/18/17.  
  
    Posters
    Flyers/Brochures
    Newspaper Clippings
  
  Box 1Box 15328BrainchildFolder 1533519731Scope and ContentsBooklet of poems
Advertising material: Poster and brochureBrainchild IIFolder 27714619752Scope and ContentsBooklet of poemsBrainchild IIIFolder 3533619763Scope and Contents5 copiesBrainchild IVFolder 4533719774Scope and Contents4 copiesBrainchild VFolder 5533819785Scope and ContentsWomen's Work Calendar
Not a booklet of poems as in previous years but a year long calendar with poems on each month
4 copiesBrainchild flyersFolder 677147no date6Scope and ContentsFlyer: Red Herring Poets Present - Writers of Brainchild - Rosemary Richmond, Katherine Lawson, Jessica Weber held on June 23 but no year; at the Channing-Murray Foundation in Urbana.  3 copies
Flyer: Brainchild at the Beau - held on Friday June 20 but no year; at 613 E. Capitol. 1 copyRosie Richmond - A Celebration of Rosie's LifeFolder 7771483/9/19947Scope and ContentsRosie was a contributor to the Brainchild series.  Remembrance brochure of Rosemary Richmond (1944-1994) - A Celebration of Rosie's Life, articles on Rosie, and song lyrics.  Rosie was a contributor to the Brainchild series. Also includes publications and documents from Richmond's business: Richmond Staff Development culled from disposed SSU Continuing Education files.Brainchild poems in IGPA QuarterlyFolder 88356119778Scope and ContentsWinter 1977 issue cotains poems by Carla Cravens (p.34) and Roberta deKay (p.35).

