<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.31Archon Finding Aid Title MC.31UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:40:08 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC31. William H. Logan Jr., Papers, 1968-1979
    
      Logan, Willis H. Jr.
    
    MC.31
    37
    
      0.16 Cubic Feet
    
    1968-1979
    Date acquired: 00/00/1984
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Director of the Community Development and Program Department for the City of  Springfield beginning in 1979.  Community activities included work with the Springfield-Sangamon County Regional Planning Commission, the Capital City Railroad Relocation Authority and the Springfield East Association.  Served as Managing Editor of The Spirit of Black Springfield, a community newspaper affiliated with the Black Action Movement of Springfield and published in the late sixties.  Also served as Associate Director of Springfield's Progressive Movement of Youth, a coalition of local activists responsible for publishing The Springfield Progressive in the late sixties. 

Formerly, Equal Employment Opportunity and Affirmative Action Specialist for the Illinois Department of Conservation; Assistant Director of Program Services for the State Department of Children and Family Services; and Executive Director of the Springfield Human Relations Commission.  Also has held position with Illinois Office of Education, the Illinois Office of Minority Business Enterprise, the Sangamon County Community Action Agencies, and the Springfield Urban League.  

Papers include complete set of issues of The Spirit of Black Springfield (seven issues dating from August 1968-October 1969); photocopies of statement regarding purposes of the Progressive Movement of Youth and one issue of The Springfield Progressive (vol. 1, no. 6), ca. 1968, including Logan's article, "Black Power;" a statement on the proposed City, Water, Light and Power rate increase by the Springfield East Association, the Ministerial Alliance and Frontiers International, n.d.; and a 1979 news clipping announcing Logan's appointment as Director of Springfield's Community Development and Program Department.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
William H. Logan Jr.  
  
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 113066The Spirit of Black SpringfieldFolder 1130671Scope and ContentsSeven issues dating from August l968-October l969Other PapersFolder 2130682

