<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.07.08/05Archon Finding Aid Title J.07.08/05UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:40:22 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J7/8/5. Social Justice Seminar "Delinquency Prevention: The Coming Decade." Video Tapes, 1977
    J.07.08/05
    381
    
      1.00 Cubic Feet
    
    Date acquired: 02/00/1995
    All
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The video tape collection from the 1977 conference on Delinquency Prevention.  This two day event featured speakers, panelists, dsicussion and material related to the field of delinquency.  
  
    Arrangement Note
N/A  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  Box 1Box 171332Scope and ContentsDelinquency Prevention: The Coming Decade, a conference sponsored by SSU and The Illinois Commission on Delinquency Prevention.  This two-day event was held at Brookens Library Auditorium, Wednesday, January 26, and Thursday, January 27, 1977.  The goal of the conference was to discuss Delinquency prevention, where it was at then and where it would be in the future.

Key panelist included James F. Short, JR., Simon Dinitz, Harold Finestone, Walter Miller, Solomon Kobrin, Irving Spergel.Sociological Criminology: Opening Session," speakers Dr. Miller and Dr. ShortVideotape 171333January 26, 1977Scope and ContentsFirst tape in the series., 60 min 3/4" black/white video cassette.Sociological Criminology, continued tape twoVideotape 271334January 26, 1977Scope and ContentsSpeakers Dr. Dinitz, Dr. Kobrin, Dr. Spergel, Dr. Miller, Dr. Finestone, Dr. Miller.  60 min 3.4" bl/wh video cassette.Delinquency Prevention: Present and Future DirectionsVideotape 371335January 26, 1977Scope and ContentsPresentations by Dr. Kobrin and Irving Spergel. 60 min 3/4" bl/wh video cassetteDelinquency Prevention: Present and Future Directions, ontinued. Panel discussionVideotape 471336January 26, 1977Scope and Contents60 min 3/4" bl/wh video cassetteDelinquency Research: Implications for Program PlanningVideotape 571337January 27, 1977Scope and ContentsPresentation led by Dr.	Dinitz and Dr. Short. 60 min 3/4" bl/wh video cassetteDelinquency Research: Implications for Program Planning, continuedVideotape 671338January 27, 1977Scope and ContentsPresentation led by Dr. Dinitz and Dr. Short. 60 min 3/4" bl/wh video cassetteDelinquency Research. Panel DiscussionVideotape 771339January 27, 1977Scope and Contents60 min 3/4" bl/wh video cassette

