<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.39Archon Finding Aid Title MC.39UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:40:51 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC39. Cookie Monster Day Care Center Records, 1974-1982  RESTRICTED
    
      Cookie Monster Day Care Center
    
    MC.39
    45
    
      2.82 Cubic Feet
    
    1974-1982
    Date acquired: 00/00/1983
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Not-for-profit cooperative which encouraged parental involvement  to foster the educational, social and physical development of  preschool children.  Founded as the Cookie Monster Day Care Cooperative in l972.  Closed in 1982. 

Collection contains organization documents, by-laws, minutes, annual reports, photographs, curricular records, children and personnel records, and grant and contractual program records documenting the Cookie Monster Day Care Center's organizational structure, history and development, objectives, operations and policies, membership standards and rates, publicity, curriculum, day-to-day operations and activities, compliance with state regulations, and finances.  Its relationships with the Comprehensive Employment and Training Act (CETA), the Springfield Public Schools, the Illinois Department  of Children and Family Services, the Illinois State Board of  Education's Child Care Food Program, and the Illinois Department  of Public Aid are recorded. 

SERIES I:  The General Administrative and Curricular Records, l974-82 (Boxes l-3), consist of alphabetically arranged bylaws, minutes, annual reports, contracts, agreements, photographs,
roster, curricular material, song sheets, attendance reports, evaluations, manuals, and time, sign-up, supply, and rate sheets.  The series documents the organization and operation of the Center, including its history and development; administrative structure and leadership, objectives and policies; curriculum; membership standards and rates; publicity; financial situation; and day-to-day operations and activities.  Of special note are the curricular-related material, which include songs, games and educational objectives of the Center; and two folders (Box l, Folder 24; Box 2, Folder l) of photographs of children who attended Cookie Monster.  Also included are records of two of the organizations with which Cookie Monster had grant and contractual programs:  the Comprehensive Employment and Training Act (CETA) and the Springfield Public Schools.

SERIES II:  Department of Children and Family Services Compliance Records include forms and correspondence made in compliance with standards set by the Illinois Department of Children and Family Services which licensed and regulated the Center (see Box 3, Folder 7, "Working at Cookie Monster" for a list of the records required to be kept).

SERIES III:   Child Care Food Program Records include forms, memos and manuals involving Cookie Monster's compliance with and operation of the Child Care Food Program, a federally-funded nutrition program operated by the State Board of Education which provided free and reduced-price meals for needy children.

SERIES IV:  Department of Public Aid Contractual Records include contracts, invoice vouchers, grouping sheets, and other forms documenting the operation of a contractual program whereby the Illinois Department of Public Aid paid Cookie Monster for services the Center provided to needy persons.

SERIES V:  Financial Records include bookkeeping records, bank statements, canceled checks, financial statements, receipts, deposit tickets, account books, and tax forms documenting the routine financial transactions and operations of the Center.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
RESTRICTED:  Access to student records.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Maureen Brennan  
  
    Records
  
  General Administrative and Curricular Records, l974-82Series 113146Box 1Box 113151Annual Reports, 1975-82; change of registered agent certificate and applicationFolder 1131521By-Laws and administrative structureFolder 2131532Census – Social Services, 1977; Group Day Care Center Survey, 1978Folder 3131543CETA Fall Subgrant agreement, 1980Folder 4131554Scope and ContentsComprehensive Employment and Training ActCETA-Ruth McDonald; Summer Youth Employment Program, l980Folder 5131565Clean-up instructionsFolder 6131576ContractsFolder 7131587Cooperative Education Program and Home Economics Occupations TrainingFolder 8131598Scope and ContentsCaren Bolden, Cookie Monster, 1982Cooperative Education Program, Senior Aides Project and Lincoln Land Community College Child Care Services; Employee &amp; Aid Information, 1976-78Folder 9131609Curriculum ObjectivesFolder 101316110Department of Public Health Inspection Report, 1976-78Folder 111316211Evaluation Forms and time sheets, Caren BoldenFolder 121316312Game Ideas:  Finger plays/arts and craftsFolder 131316413Harmon, Marilyn:  "Where Parents Participate"Folder 141316514Insurance--Millers Mutual, 1978-82Folder 151316615Lease 1979, 1981Folder 161316716Literature—Cookie MonsterFolder 171316817Lunch &amp; Clean-up Sign-up sheets, November 1980-October 1982Folder 181316918Lunch GuidelinesFolder 191317019Membership PoliciesFolder 201317120New member formsFolder 211317221Old Rosters of children at Cookie Monster, 1979-82Folder 221317322Parents' Meeting Minutes, 1974-January 31, 1982; and letter to parentsFolder 231317423Photo Album:  Cookie Monster, 1825 S. 5th, Springfield, 1973-79Folder 241317524Box 2Box 213176Photo Album:  Cookie Monster, 312 Apple Orchard, Springfield, 1979-82Folder 1131771Rate SheetsFolder 2131782Schedules of daily eventsFolder 3131793Sign-in Sheets:  Children, March 4, 1974?; February 7-24, May 2-27, 1977Folder 4131804Sign-in Sheets:  Children and Shift-workers, May 5-July 3, l980Folder 5131815Sign-in Sheets:  Children and Shift-workers, July 7-August 29, l980Folder 6131826Sign-in Sheets:  Children and Shift-workers, September l-November 26, l980Folder 7131837Sign-in Sheets:  Children and Shift-workers, December l, l980-January 30, l98lFolder 8131848Sign-in Sheets:  Children and Shift-workers, February 2-April 3, l98lFolder 9131859Sign-in sheets:  Children and Shift-workers, April 6-May 29, l98lFolder 101318610Sign-in Sheets:  Children and Shift-workers, June l-July 3l, l98lFolder 111318711Sign-in Sheets:  Children and Shift-workers, August 3-October 30, l98lFolder 121318812Sign-in Sheets:  Children and Shift-workers, November 2, l98l-January 29, l982Folder 131318913Sign-in Sheets:  Children and Shift- workers, February l-April 30, l982Folder 141319014Oversize A: Sign-in sheets:  Children, July 25, l978?; October 22-November l2, l979Item 1131911Oversize B: Sign-in Sheets: Children, November l3-30, l979Item 2131922Box 3Box 313193Sign-in Sheets: Children and Shift-workers, May 3-July 2, l982Folder 1131941Sign-in Sheets:  Children and Shift-workers, July 6-September 3, l982Folder 2131952Sign-in Sheets:  Children and Shift-workers, September 6-November l2, l982Folder 3131963Snack suggestionsFolder 4131974Song SheetsFolder 5131985Weekly Supply SheetsFolder 6131996Working at Cookie Monster Notes Work InstructionsFolder 7132007Department of Children and Family Services Compliance RecordsSeries 213147Box 3Box 313201Medication Forms, 1980-82Folder 8132028Licensing Standards, 1981-82Folder 9132039Cookie Monster Employee Forms (shiftworkers too)Folder 101320410Fire Regulations &amp; Inspection Correspondence, 1976-81Folder 111320511Time SheetsFolder 121320612C&amp;FS Form #428, Record of Child InformationFolder 131320713C&amp;FS Medical Consent Form #593Folder 141320814Medical Forms #600; Certification of Child Health ExamFolder 151320915Food Handler Shiftworker Forms; Medical Report on an Adult or Child in a Licensed Child Care FacilityFolder 161321016Accident and Inquiry Reports, 1980Folder 171321117DCFS Licensing Standards and Insurance Policy; correspondence, 1978-1982Folder 181321218DCFS – Contract; invoice vouchers, monthly enrollment report, authorization for payment and correspondenceFolder 191321319Scope and ContentsDepartment of Human Rights memoranda, 1981-82Time Sheets. 1976-82; receipt stubs and receiptsFolder 201321420Staff Records, 1977-82Folder 211321521Box 4Box 413216Children's Records, A-DFolder 1132171Children's Records, E-KFolder 2132182Children's Records, L-SFolder 3132193Children's Records, T-ZFolder 4132204Child Care Food Program RecordsSeries 313148Box 4Box 413221Child Care Food Program, Administrative HandbookFolder 5132225CCFP, Audit 1981Folder 6132236CCFP, Ledger; monthly food inventories and expenses, 1981-82Folder 7132247Child Care Workshop!  menus and recipes, 1980Folder 8132258Scope and ContentsFederal Register, Part V, Department of Agriculture, Food and Nutrition Service, Child Care Food ProgramFormula Newsletter, 1980-1982Folder 9132269Illinois State Board of Education Audit Material, 1981Folder 101322710ISBE, CCFP Application and Agreement; correspondence and site informationFolder 111322811ISBE, CCFP Daily Menus, ca. Jan 1982-June 30, 1982 (folder 1 of 2)Folder 121322912Box 5Box 513230ISBE, CCFP Daily Menus, Jul1 1, 1982-Nov 12, 1982 (folder 2 of 2)Folder 1132311ISBE, CCFP Labor Cost Sheets, Oct 1981-Nov 1982Folder 2132322ISBE, Monthly Food Inventories, Jan-Nov 1982Folder 3132333ISBE Printouts that come with checks, 1981-82Folder 4132344ISBE Reimbursement ClaimFolder 5132355Meal RequirementsFolder 6132366Memos from SBE, Dec 17, 1981-Dec 17, 1872Folder 7132377Monthly and Weekly Attendance Sheets, CCFP Manuals and Nutritional GuidelinesFolder 8132388Monthly Food Inventories Expenses with Receipts, 1981Folder 9132399News Release, Feb 26, 1981Folder 101324010On-Site Operational AuditFolder 111324111Parent Application Forms (Current) and Memoranda, 1981-92Folder 121324212Parent Application Forms (Past) and Correspondence, 1981Folder 131324313Department of Public Aid Contractual RecordsSeries 413149Box 5Box 513244Public Aid, Attendance – Payment Records and Invoice Vouchers, 1977-78Folder 141324514Public Aid, Child Care Statement Form #544Folder 151324615Public Aid Contract, 1977-81Folder 161324716Public Aid Grouping Sheets, 1977-81Folder 171324817Public Aid Grouping Sheets, Child Care Statement and Attendance Report, 1981-82Folder 181324918Public Aid Invoice – Vouchers, 1977-80Folder 191325019Public Aid Monthly Child Care Statements, 1977-80Folder 201325120Financial RecordsSeries 513150Box 6Box 613252Bank Statements, Checking Account Deposit Tickers, Checking Deposit Receipts, and Canceled Checks, Sept 20, 1979-Apr 13, 1981Folder 1132531Bank Statements, Checking Account Deposit Tickers, Checking Deposit Receipts, and Canceled Checks, Apr 12, 1981-Feb 7, 1982Folder 2132542Bookkeeping Record, 1977Folder 3132553Bookkeeping Record, 1978Folder 4132564Bookkeeping Record, 1979Folder 5132575Bookkeeping Record, 1980Folder 6132586Bookkeeping Record, 1981Folder 7132597Bookkeeping Record, 1982Folder 8132608Bookkeeping Record, CETAFolder 9132619Cash Books, Apr 19, 1976-Nov 14, 1982Folder 101326210Box 7Box 713263Checkbook Balancing, 1974-76Folder 1132641Checkbooks, Checking Account Deposit Ticket Receipts, and Blank Checks, Oct 1, 1979-Feb 2, 1983Folder 2132652Financial Statements, Oct 1978-Sept 1982Folder 3132663Receipts, 1974-75 (folder 1 of 2)Folder 4132674Receipts, 1974-75 (folder 2 of 2)Folder 5132685Receipts, 1976Folder 6132696Receipts, 1977 (folder 1 of 2)Folder 7132707Receipts, 1977 (folder 2 of 2)Folder 8132718Box 8Box 813272Receipts, 1978Folder 1132731Receipts, 1979Folder 2132742Receipts, 1980Folder 3132753Receipts, 1981Folder 4132764Receipts, 1982Folder 5132775Tax, Employees Withholding Allowance Certificate W-4 Forms, 1976-82Folder 6132786Tax, Federal Income, Quarterly Return of Withheld Form 941-E, 1976-83Folder 7132797Tax, Income, Return of Organization Exempt Form 990, 1976-82Folder 8132808Tax, State and Federal Unemployment, 1976-77Folder 9132819Tax, State Sales, Exemption Information, 1977-79Folder 101328210Tax, Exempt Application and Letter, 1976-77Folder 111328311Tax Return, Quarterly Illinois Withholding IL-94, 1877-82Folder 121328412Tax Statements, Transmittal of income W-3, 1977-82Folder 131328513Utilities, 1981-Nov 1982Folder 141328614

