<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.40Archon Finding Aid Title MC.40UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:40:55 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC40. Women's International League for Peace &amp; Freedom, Springfield Branch, Records, 1954-1989
    
      Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (WILPF)
    
    MC.40
    46
    
      4.49 Cubic Feet
    
    1954-1989
    1
    2
    3
    4
    5
    6
    7
    8
    9
    10
    11
    12
    13
    14
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Founded by Jane Addams in 1915, the WILPF is dedicated to working by non-violent means for international peace and freedom. The Springfield chapter was founded in 1947 by Francis Blane Hurie.  Members have comprised black and white Springfield women, including Mary and Emma Kreider, Docia Ashurst, Martha Tranquilli, Isabel Patrick, Agnes Howarth, Alice Kaige and Mary Johnston. 

Minutes, constitutions, by-laws, correspondence, newsletters, bulletins, committee records, membership lists, clippings, press releases, photographs, financial records and collected literature documenting the administrative structure, philosophy, activities of the Branch and its relationships with other community organizations and the regional and national WILPF offices.  Topics include efforts to end racial discrimination in Springfield by demanding the integration of blacks in Springfield schools and public facilities; the Branch's opposition to the Vietnam War, the selling of war toys and military buildup are recorded; the activities of the Jane Addams Centennial Committee; the imprisonment of Martha Tranquilli for income tax evasion; race relations, housing and education in Springfield. 

Also includes a 35 mm slide show on the history of the WILPF, and audio tapes of oral history interviews of 25 members of  the Springfield chapter in 1976, including Martha Tranquilli, Agnes Howarth, Blanche Murphy, Mary Kreider, Eloise Wright, Isabel Patrick, and Docia Ashurst. Also a collection of anti-war literature from a variety of sources.

Oral History project on members of WILPF Springfield branch conducted in 1976, original tapes in this collection.  In 2010, tapes copied to digital form and are available in the UIS Oral History Project Supplemental collection.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical, Chronological  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Springfield WILPF &amp; Alice Kaige  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Acquisition Dates:  1984 &amp; 1993
10/10/2011: Donation of WILPF papers from Lincoln Public Library, Sangamon Valley Collection by Curtis Mann from papers originally donated to library by Alice Kaige.  
  
    Related Materials
SEE ALSO:  MC 37 Alice Kaige Papers  
  
    Records
    Reports
    Correspondence
    Flyers/Brochures
    Letters
    Newspaper Clippings
    Photographs
    Audio Tapes
    Slides
    Reel to Reel Tapes
  
  Minutes, Reports, and Organizational DocumentsSeries 185891954-1984Box 1Box 18590Board MeetingsFolder 185911954-19631Scope and ContentsIncludes minutes, notes and agendas]Board MinutesFolder 285921964-19732Branch Minutes and AgendasFolder 385931957-19693Branch MeetingsFolder 485941970-19784Business MeetingsFolder 5859519615Scope and ContentsIncludes minutes and agendasBranch Annual MeetingsFolder 685961957-19786Scope and ContentsIncludes minutes, agendas, notes and announcementsBranch Minutes and Agendas, 1981-1985Folder 7344867Branch Annual ReportsFolder 885971954-19628Branch Annual ReportsFolder 985981955-19729Report of Branch ChairmanFolder 1085991956-195710Suggested Plan of Organization for Springfield Branch WILPFFolder 1186001954-0511Springfield Branch ConstitutionFolder 1286011954, 1962, 196812Local Branch By-laws &amp; amendmentsFolder 1386021955, 1961, 196813WILPF - Springfield Branch HistoryFolder 1473969196214Scope and ContentsHandwritten notes by Alice Kaige on history of the Springfield branch of WILPF.
Includes proposal for a tape and slide program for 30 years of WILPF, Springfield branch.
Includes Illinois Humanities Council Grant Application to obtain oral histories of members of the Springfield branch of WILPF.
Includes copy of MS. magazine, Winter 2006, Vol XVI, #1 with article on history of WILPF.WILPF - "Principles and Policy," pamphletFolder 15860315WILPF, Springfield Branch: Bulletins and NewsletterSeries 286041954-1984Box 1Box 18612BulletinsFolder 1586051954-195515BulletinsFolder 1686061955-195616BulletinsFolder 1786071956-195717BulletinsFolder 1886081959-196118BulletinsFolder 1986091961-196219BulletinsFolder 2086101962-196320BulletinsFolder 2186111963-196421Box 2Box 28613BulletinsFolder 186141964-19661BulletinsFolder 286151967-19682BulletinsFolder 386161968-19693BulletinsFolder 486171969-19704BulletinsFolder 586181970-19715NewslettersFolder 686191971-19776NewslettersFolder 786201978-19827Scope and ContentsIncludes "Peace-Work" a newsletter for peace advocates in central Illinois.
Vol. #1, Issue #1
Vol. #1, Issue #2
Vol. #1, Issue #3NewslettersFolder 8739701982-2003, 20068Administrative and Program RecordsSeries 386211954-1986Box 2Box 28622Activities (folder 1 of 2)Folder 986231957-19869Scope and ContentsIncludes flyers, programs, press releases, membership lists and surveysActivities (folder 2 of 2)Folder 10739731957-198610Scope and ContentsIncludes flyers, programs, press releases, membership lists and surveysBallotsFolder 1186241956, 195911Biennial Meeting attendance listFolder 1286251981-0612Branch Activities ReportFolder 138626197513Committee OfficersFolder 1486271954-196014Community Police Relations-Latin American StudiesFolder 1586281969-197015Scope and ContentsIncludes handbook and reportsCorrespondenceFolder 1686291955-196316Scope and ContentsYWCA, Adlai StevensonCorrespondenceFolder 178630196517Scope and ContentsDean Rusk, Paul FindleyBox 3Box 373974CorrespondenceFolder 186311966-19671Scope and ContentsLetter to Illinois State Journal concerning non-violent toy advertisementsCorrespondenceFolder 2863219682Scope and ContentsSen. Charles Percy, Decatur Monthly Meeting, Paul FindleyCorrespondenceFolder 3739711962-1992, 20073Scope and ContentsSen. Paul Douglas, President Kennedy, Treaty with Soviet Russia to ban Nuclear Testing, general events announcementCorrespondenceFolder 4863419694Scope and ContentsSchool District # 186CorrespondenceFolder 586351970-19715Scope and ContentsNAACP, Springfield Education AssociationCorrespondenceFolder 6863619726Scope and ContentsWorld Federalists, Springfield Elks Club, and letters concerning war filmsCorrespondenceFolder 786371973-19747Scope and ContentsMartha Tranquilli Defense Fund, Paul FindleyCorrespondenceFolder 886381976-19868Correspondence with Elected OfficialsFolder 986401978-19869Box 4Box 48633DiGirolamo, JaniceFolder 1864119811Scope and ContentsLetter to editor and membershipForm letters to membershipFolder 286422Grant Proposal: Thirty Years of the Springfield BranchFolder 386433Heloise Brainerd Scholarship FundFolder 4864419634Human Rights CommitteeFolder 586451955-19655Scope and ContentsIncludes correspondence, reports, and statementsLegislative CommitteeFolder 686461955-19566Scope and ContentsReportMembership CommitteeFolder 7864719577Membership listsFolder 886481954-19888Scope and ContentsPhone treeMemorandum to the Superintendent of Schools and the Member of the Board of EducationFolder 986491955-07-069National Annual MeetingsFolder 1086501954-196910Newspaper clippingsFolder 1186511954-198211Scope and ContentsIncludes local and national news on racial inequality, disarmament; letters to the editor from branch members; biographical information on CongressmenNewspaper clippings about WILPF and other topicsFolder 1286521971-198612Newspaper clippings, note cards about WILPF membersFolder 1386531952-198613Newspaper clippings, articles about WILPF membersFolder 14739671962-200714Nominating CommitteeFolder 1586541954-1955, 196915Peace BoothFolder 168655197516PhotographsFolder 17865617News ReleasesFolder 18739721962-196318PublicityFolder 1986571953-196919Scope and ContentsLocal newspaper clippings pertaining to WILPF, the United Nations, and various activitiesQuarterly Legislative Action ReportFolder 208658196920Questionnaire about Springfield and WILPF's Activity in the CommunityFolder 218659198021Regional MeetingFolder 2286601972-01-3122Scope and ContentsIncludes notes, membership lists, and mapReport on National Conference, Boston, MassachusettsFolder 238661195923Box 5Box 58662Second General Session of Conference of Illinois Branches of WILPFFolder 186631970-05-021SpeakersFolder 286641954-19672Scope and ContentsIncludes information about WILPF sponsored events, memoranda, photographs, and newspaper clippingsSpringfield Branch Twentieth AnniversaryFolder 386651967-05-183Steering CommitteeFolder 486664Scope and ContentsMembership listTranquilli, MarthaFolder 586671957-19815Scope and ContentsIncludes correspondence, Tranquilli tax evasion case and defense fundU.N.and World Relations CommitteeFolder 686681954-19576Scope and ContentsIncluded programs, reports and suggestions for committeeWILPF Fortieth AnniversaryFolder 7866919557WILPF Fiftieth AnniversaryFolder 8867019658WILPF Sixtieth AnniversaryFolder 9867119759WILPF Seventieth Anniversary CampaignFolder 108672198310World Development and Disarmament CommitteeFolder 11739751957-195811Jane Addams Centennial RecordsSeries 486731959-1964Box 5Box 58674ActivitiesFolder 1286751960-196112Collected literature on Jane AddamsFolder 1386761959-196713CorrespondenceFolder 1486771959-196414Jane Addams Centennial CommitteeFolder 1586781959-196115National File on Jane Addams CentennialFolder 1686791959-196116Nationally-produced literature on Jane AddamsFolder 17868017Research RecordsSeries 586811949-1975Box 5Box 58682Alternatives for Peace in the Middle EastFolder 1886831967-197518Condition and Availability of Public and Private Housing for Minority Groups in Springfield, ILFolder 198684196819History of Race Relations in Springfield, IllinoisFolder 2086851949-09-2920Israel's Arab MinorityFolder 2186861970-197421Mayor Nelson Howarth radio talksFolder 2286871968-196922Neighborhood Service Center Evaluation Committee ReportFolder 2386881968-1023Newsletter - Medical Aid for IndochinaFolder 248689197324Newspaper Clippings &amp; Projects About IndochinaFolder 25739761975-7625National Organization for Women, Springfield ChapterFolder 268690197326Out Front SpeakersFolder 278691ca. 197427School Enrollment Composition Study Committee, Springfield School District # 186, and NAACP statistical fact sheet on educational segregationFolder 288692197028Women's Alliance NewslettersFolder 298693198129World Affairs CenterFolder 3086941967-197030Financial RecordsSeries 686951954-1980Box 6Box 68696Treasurer's ReportsFolder 186971954-19831Financial RecordsFolder 286981960-19652Financial RecordsFolder 386991965-19743Receipts and DisbursementsFolder 487001962-19684Cancelled checksFolder 587011968-19735Financial RecordsFolder 687021970-19786Bank statementsFolder 787031971, 1973, 1974-19787Paid and unpaid branch listsFolder 887041973-19808Cancelled checksFolder 987051974-19789WILPF Literature FileSeries 787061954-1981Box 7Box 78707Action BulletinsFolder 187081968-1969, 19751Scope and ContentsGenerated by Legislative Office of WILPFAnnual Reports and letters to MembersFolder 287091986-19872BrochureFolder 3871019773Childhood EducationFolder 487111960-19714Collected literatureFolder 587121965-19865Disarmament packetFolder 687131980-19816Fifteenth International CongressFolder 7871419627Scope and ContentsIncludes original reports and speechFour LightsFolder 887151966-19698Scope and ContentsNational newsletterGround ZeroFolder 987161981-19849Leader's Manual for U.S. SectionFolder 108717196810Midwest Peace and FreedomFolder 1187181987-198811National ConstitutionFolder 128719193412National LettersFolder 1387201966-197513National produced literatureFolder 1487211964-196914Notebook-United Nations ConferenceFolder 158722197515Women in the Peace Movement by Lucy CarnerFolder 1673977197516Scope and ContentsSome notes on women in the peace movement, WILPFBox 8Box 88723Pax Et LibertasFolder 187241957-19661Scope and ContentsInternational newsletterPeace and Freedom Newsletter (folder 1 of 2)Folder 287251973-19832Scope and ContentsPublished by the National Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, Philadelphia, PA.  
Begins with Vol. XXXIII. No. 6, July 1973
Ends with Vol. 46, No. 7, October 1986Peace and Freedom Newsletter (folder 2 of 2)Folder 3739781973-19833Scope and ContentsPublished by the National Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, Philadelphia, PA.  
Begins with Vol. XXXIII. No. 6, July 1973
Ends with Vol. 46, No. 7, October 1986Political Action HandbookFolder 4872619694Report of the International Congress of WomenFolder 5872719155Report of Mrs. Joseph Tranquilli on First Year at Sam Brown Memorial HospitalFolder 6872819686Reports to Annual MeetingFolder 7872919697Stamps, Pax Seals, Button and Photo (WILPF Banner)Folder 8873019858Stationery, WILPF-SpringfieldFolder 987319United Nations Principles and PoliciesFolder 1087321969-197110U.S. WILPF - Legislative OfficeFolder 1187331964-197111Washington NewsletterFolder 1287341971-197312Box 9Box 98736Scope and ContentsContains files on individual WILPF Springfield branch members, some include release forms for the oral history project in 1976WILPF CommitteesFolder 187351965-19751Women for Peace, Chicago Area WILPF BulletinFolder 2344871981-19862Scope and ContentsFebruary 1981
May 1981
February 1982
April 1982
August 1982
June 1982
July 1982
November 1982
March 1983Women as Peacemakers by Margaret BaconFolder 373979May 7, 19753Scope and ContentsSpeech delivered at Women United for Peace: Disarmament and Its Social Consequences, an IWY Seminar at the United Nations, May 7-9, 1975Andreasen, Dorothy (Putter)Folder 487371971-19814Scope and ContentsOral History Tape Release formAshurst, Docia (Steele)Folder 587381974-19815Scope and ContentsOral History Tape Release formBorman, AdalinFolder 687391969-19856Coffin, GladysFolder 787401963-19717Detzer, DorothyFolder 8874119818Scope and ContentsObituaryDigirolamo, JaniceFolder 9874219819Fenley, Margaret (Lippert)Folder 1087431976-198210Scope and ContentsOral History Tape Release formGillman, CarolFolder 118744198211Horney, Joyce (Caldwell)Folder 128745197612Scope and ContentsOral History Tape Release formHowarth, Agnes (Hand)Folder 138746198213Scope and ContentsObituaryHurie, Frances BlaneFolder 148747197714Johnston, Mary (Boyce)Folder 1587481976-198515Scope and ContentsOral History Tape Release formKnack, Ruth E.Folder 168749197516Kolp, Mary (Graham)Folder 1787501955-197517Kreider, MaryFolder 188751197318Lee, Geraldine E. (Mrs. Ediwin Lee)Folder 198752197719Matheny, Edith (French)Folder 208753197020Scope and ContentsObituaryMurphy, BlancheFolder 218754197721Scope and ContentsOral History Tape Release formMyers, VioletFolder 228755197222Noll, JeanFolder 23875623Patrick, Isabel (Goins)Folder 2487571977-198524Roblee, GraceFolder 258758198225Taborn, Alice (Williams)Folder 2687591971, 198526Scope and ContentsOral History Tape Release formWeir, ElizabethFolder 278760198227Withey, MildredFolder 28876128Scope and ContentsObituaryWood, Mary Jane (Lovas)Folder 2987621978-198629Scope and ContentsOral History Tape Release formWright, Eloise (Gard)Folder 3087631973-197730Scope and ContentsOral History Tape Release formWILPF Oral History TapesSeries 887641976-1977Box 10Box 108765Women's Peace Oral History ProjectFolder 1879819871WILPF Springfield Branch Oral History ProjectSub-Series 18766Scope and ContentsInterviews (dubbed copies)
Note: digital format available for these interviews in UIS Oral History Project Supplemental Collection (2010)Andreasen, Dorothy; Zanelle ZimmermanAudiotape 187671976-08-03; 1976-08-11Scope and Contents2 copiesAshurst, DociaAudiotape 287681976-08-25Scope and Contents2 copiesAshurst, DociaAudiotape 38769Scope and Contents2 copiesFenley, PegAudiotape 487701976-08-17Scope and Contents2 copiesHorney, JoyceAudiotape 587711976-08-16Scope and Contents2 copiesHowarth, AgnesAudiotape 687721977-05-16Scope and Contents2 copiesHowarth, AgnesAudiotape 787731977-05-23Scope and Contents2 copiesJohnston, MaryAudiotape 887741976-08-16Scope and Contents2 copiesKaige, AliceAudiotape 98775Scope and Contents2 copiesKolp, MaryAudiotape 1087761976-09-17Scope and Contents2 copiesKreider, MaryAudiotape 1187771976-08-19Scope and Contents2 copiesMurphy, BlancheAudiotape 1287781976-08-13Scope and Contents2 copiesPatrick, IsabelAudiotape 1387801976-08-27Scope and Contents2 copiesRoblee, GraceAudiotape 1487811976-09-20Scope and Contents2 copiesTranquilli, MarthaAudiotape 15739861976-08-15Tranquilli, MarthaAudiotape 16739871976-08-15Wood, Mary Jane; Dickinson, MarjorieAudiotape 1787821976-08-01; 1976-08-02Scope and Contents2 copiesWright, EloiseAudiotape 1887831977-01-29Scope and Contents2 copiesWright, EloiseAudiotape 1987841977-01-30Scope and Contents2 copiesOther TapesSub-Series 38788Gillman, CarolAudiotape 187891976-08-05Scope and Contents2 copiesJohnston, WesAudiotape 287901976-08-17Scope and Contents2 copiesJohnston, WesAudiotape 387911976-08-19Scope and Contents2 copiesSmith, GeorgeAudiotape 473988Scope and ContentsFormer POW; on cassette and master reel to reel tapeHiroshima MediationAudiotape 58792Scope and Contents2 copiesAnnual Meeting at Unitarian Church on Elliot St.Audiotape 68786Annual MeetingAudiotape 787871977Mexican Cassette Tape and master reel to reel tapeAudiotape 88799Scope and ContentsOrgan Music on cassette and master tapeOrgan Music Tape and master reel to reel tapeAudiotape 98797Scope and Contents1. Organ Music
2. Conversations about Nixon and Viet Nam War at someone's home
3. Bangladesh songA History of WILPF in SlidesSeries 98801Box 11Box 1134489A History of WILPF: slide DocumentationFolder 1739821Scope and ContentsDescription of each slide in carouselA History of WILPF: 1 slide carouselItem 1344901Note cards - WILPF, Springfield Branch historyItem 2739802Slide Box - Slides of WILPF Headquarters on Geneva, SwitzerlandItem 37398119793Scope and ContentsAlso article about Edith Sampson, Cook County Circuit Court Judge, 1962-78Publications of WILPF and other peace organizationsSeries 1034488Box 12Box 128804Women's International League for Peace and FreedomFolder 188051954-19881American Friends Service Committee, Inc.Folder 2880619772The NonviolentFolder 388071985-19903Peace and Freedom NewsletterFolder 488081984, 1988, 19894Scope and ContentsA publication of the U.S. Section of the Women's International League for Peace &amp; Freedom
Vol. 44, No. 1 Jan-Feb 1984
Vol. 44, No. 2 March 1984
Vol. 44, No. 7 October 1984
Vol. 44, No. 8 November 1984
And some 1984 Spfld branch newsletters
Vol. 48, No. 4 June 1988
Vol. 48, No. 5 July/Aug 1988
Vol. 48, No. 6 Sept/Oct 1988
Vol. 48, No. 7 Nov/Dec 1988
And some 1988 Spfld branch newsletters
Vol. 49, No. 1 Jan/Feb 1989
Vol. 49, No. 2 Mar/April 1989
Vol. 49, No. 3 May/June 1989
Vol. 49, No. 4 July/Aug 1989
Vol. 49, No. 5 Sept/Oct 1989
Vol. 49, No. 6 Nov/Dec 1989
Midwest Peace &amp; Freedom, April 1989Peace and Freedom NewsletterFolder 588091990-19915Scope and ContentsMagazine of the Women's International League for Peace and Freedom
Vol. 50, No. 1 Jan/Feb 1990
Vol. 50, No. 2 March/April 1990 [75th Anniversary Issue]
Vol. 50, No. 3 May/June 1990
Vol. 50, No. 4 July/Aug 1990
Vol. 50, No. 5 Sept/Oct 1990
Vol. 50, No. 6 Nov/Dec 1990
And some 1990 Spfld branch newsletters
Vol. 51, No. 1 Jan/Feb 1991
Vol. 51, No. 3 May/June 1991
And some 1991 Spfld branch newslettersPeace and Justice JournalFolder 688101989-19906Scope and ContentsAn American Friends Service Committee publication serving Illinois, Indiana, Kentucky, Michigan, Ohio and Wisconsin.
Vol. 3, No. 4 April/May 1989
Vol. 3, No. 5 June/July 1989
Vol. 3, No. 6 Aug/Sept 1989
Vol. 4, No. 1 Oct/Nov 1989
Vol. 4, No. 2 Dec 1989/Jan 1990
Vol. 4, No. 3 Feb/March 1990
Vol. 4, No. 4 April/May 1990
Vol. 4, No. 5 June/July 1990
Vol. 5, No. 1 Oct/Nov 1990
Vol. 5, No. 2 Dec 1990/Jan 1991
Vol. 5, No. 3 Feb/March 1991
Vol. 5, No. 4 Summer 1991Peace ProtestFolder 788111990-19917War Resisters LeagueFolder 888121984-19918Box 13Box 138813Calendars - War Resisters LeagueItem 188171968-19891Scope and Contents"Out of the War Shadow"
"Days of Gandhi"
"Days of Civil Disobedience"
"Changes"
"In Woman's Soul"
"50 Years of Nonviolent Resistance"
"As Long as the Rivers Shall Flow"
"Where Am I Going?"
"to secure peace and liberty"
"What Did You Learn in School Today . . ."
"Nonviolent Struggle Around the World"
"While there is a Soul in Prison . . ."
"80 Years of Political Art in the U. S."
"When You Put Fire to the World"
"Dancing in the Streets"
"There is No Way to Peace, Peace is the Way"
"Against the Tide" (Pacifist Resistance in WW II)
"How Shall We Live Together?"
"The Pen is Mightier than the Sword"
"WRL Presents Films for Peace and Justice"
"A Matter of Freedom"
"365 Reasons Not to Have Another War"Box 14Box 1473983Pamphlet: "To establish justice and to insure domestic tranquillity"Folder 18814ca. 19691Scope and ContentsIntroduction and Summary of Recommendations from the Final Report of The National Commission on the Causes and Prevention of ViolencePencil Drawing of Martin Luther King, Jr. by Dan WakefieldFolder 27396519842Scope and ContentsUsed in flyer for World House Program, 1/13/1985Another Mother's Datebook for PeaceItem 188161970-19711Scope and Contents"War is Not Healthy for Children and Other Living Things," Another Mother for Peace - a nonprofit non partisan association whose goal is to eliminate war as a means of settling disputes between nations, peoples, and ideologies.Appointment CalendarItem 2881519842Scope and Contents"Peace and Freedom," WILPFBook: Pioneers for Peace, Women's International League for Peace &amp; Freedom 1915-1965; a record of fifty years' workItem 37398419803Scope and Contentsby Gertrude Bussey and Margaret Tims
Alden Press, Oxford 1980Book: Women for All Seasons, The Story of the Women's International League for Peace &amp; FreedomItem 47398519894Scope and Contentsby Catherine Foster
University of Georgia Press, Athens &amp; London 1989

