<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.42/1Archon Finding Aid Title MC.42/1UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:41:33 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC42/1. Steven R. Carter Papers, 1972-1975
    
      Carter, Steven R.
    
    MC.42/1
    49
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1972-1975
    Date acquired: 00/00/1995
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Professor of English at  University of Carolina at Wilmington, University of Sassari (Italy), University of Puerto Rico and Salem State College in Massachusetts. While working on his PhD dissertation for Ohio State University on the novelist James Jones, Carter met the author and subsequently corresponded with him. 

Photocopies of 14 letters from James Jones to Carter, 1972-1975, in which Jones comments at length on Carter's questions about and analyses of Jones's novels From Here to Eternity, Some Came Running, and The Thin Red Line. Jones also describes his works in progress, Viet Journal, WWII and Whistle. 

Also included is a copy of Carter's PhD dissertation, "James Jones, An American Master: A Study of His Mystical, Philosophical and Artistic Views" (Ohio State University, 1975). The dissertation was published, in revised form, as James Jones: An American Literary Orientalist Master (Urbana: University of Illinois Press, 1998). See Special Collections PS3560.O49 Z64 1998  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Steven R. Carter  
  
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 19330Carter, Steven R. James Jones, An American Master: A Study of His Mystical, Philosophical, Social and Artistic Views. Ph.D Dissertation, Ohio State University, 1975.Folder 193311Scope and ContentsChapters 1 and 2Carter, Steven R. James Jones, An American Master: A Study of His Mystical, Philosophical, Social and Artistic Views. Ph.D Dissertation, Ohio State University, 1975.Folder 293322Scope and ContentsChapter 3Carter, Steven R. James Jones, An American Master: A Study of His Mystical, Philosophical, Social and Artistic Views. Ph.D Dissertation, Ohio State University, 1975.Folder 393333Scope and ContentsChapters 4 and 5LettersSub-Series 19334James Jones' recommendation of Steven R. Carter for an academic position and as a teaching lecturer abroad.Folder 493354JJ to SRCFolder 593361972-07-245Scope and ContentsHe tells Carter he is going to Greece but will be back after Sept. 6, and would like Carter to call him when he is in Paris.JJ to SRCFolder 693371972-10-176Scope and ContentsDiscussion of Carter's piece of criticism of Ross MacDonald, Carter's dissertation, personal advise regarding Carter's girlfriend Margret.Kathryn L. Weissberger (JJ's Secr.) to SRCFolder 793381972-11-077Scope and ContentsShe explains her notes and questions made on Carter's bibliographical notes and asks for clarification on several points.JJ to SRCFolder 893391973-07-088Scope and ContentsJones' response to literary analysis pieces by Carter on From Here To Eternity and Some Came Running, which Jones generally called "exactly correct."JJ to SRCFolder 993401973-07-149Scope and ContentsMore praise for Carter's analysis of Some Came Running. Jones' thoughts on some of the causes and effects of "masculinity crisis theory."JJ to SRCFolder 1093411973-09-2410Scope and ContentsDiscussion of The Thin Red Line, Carter's analysis of Eternity and Jones' work on Viet Journal. Jones trying to get Delacorte Press interested in Carter's work.JJ to SRCFolder 1193421973-11-1911Scope and ContentsJones sending Carter a corrected manuscript copy of Viet Journal.JJ to SRCFolder 1293431973-12-0512Scope and ContentsWorking hard on Whistle. Brief comments on Greater Love (short story).JJ to SRCFolder 1393441974-01-2413Scope and ContentsCarter should get the first five reworked chapters of Whistle from Carter rather than the first three from Matt Bruccoli. Jones getting into Whistle as he writes it, accepted position at FIU as writer-in-residence. Discussion of A Touch of Danger and WhistleJJ to SRCFolder 1493451974-02-1514Scope and ContentsDiscussion of Whistle as the "dark side" of Jones' WWII trilogy. Jones will be in N.Y. to publicize Viet Journal and will discuss publication of Carter's dissertation as a book with Delacorte Press.JJ to SRCFolder 1593461974-05-2415Scope and ContentsDiscussion of Carter's analysis of Widowmaker, and getting Carter's dissertation published by Delacorte or Dell.JJ to SRCFolder 1693471973-06-2316Scope and ContentsDell declines to publish Carter's dissertation. Explanations and apologies.JJ to SRCFolder 1793481974-07-0317Scope and ContentsRegarding Carter's pieces on Viet Journal.JJ to SRCFolder 1893491974-09-0118Scope and ContentsJones filled out recommendations for Carter. Jones got a good deal ($50,000 advance) for writing text to a WWII book.JJ to SRCFolder 1993501975-07-2119Scope and ContentsDiscussion of Carter's completed dissertation and his second reader's "qualms." Jones busy with Whistle and work on WWII book.

