<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.01.15/05Archon Finding Aid Title J.01.15/05UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:41:55 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J1/15/5. Intersession Papers "Individual Freedom and the State" 1978
    
      Academic Affairs
    
    J.01.15/05
    398
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1978
    Date acquired: 03/04/1980
  
  
    Scope and Contents
In addition to audio tapes of all sessions, this record group includes administrative working papers.  Intersession speakers are: Robert C. Spencer, Frances Fox Piven, Russell Kirk, A.E. Neier, Mulford Sibley, John Gerassi, Irving Horowitz, William Domhoff, James O'Connor, Carl Stokes, Thomas Szasz, Michael Novak, Kristin Lems, Peggy Lipschultz, Thomas Gerety, Lois Lipton, and Thea Barton.
Topics included individual freedom in the U.S., the historical and philosophic perspective of individualism, the right to control, the right to be different, and the right to be left alone.  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Media  
  Box 1Box 168217PamphletsFolder 1682511Robert C. Spencer, Introduction; Frances Fox PivenAudiotape 168218Frances Fox Piven, Question and AnswerAudiotape 268219Question and Answer; Russell KirkAudiotape 368220Russell Kirk, Question and Answer; Panel DiscussionAudiotape 468221Panel DiscussionAudiotape 568222A.E. Neier; Panel Discussion; Question and AnswerAudiotape 668223A.E. Neier; Panel Discussion; Question and AnswerAudiotape 768224Welcome, Kopecky; Intro., Golden; Mulford SibleyAudiotape 868225Mulford Sibley, Q &amp; A; Kopecky, Welcome-back; Bartollas, Intro; John GerassiAudiotape 968226John Gerassi; Panel DiscussionAudiotape 1068227Panel DiscussionAudiotape 1168228Panel Discussion; Irving HorowitzAudiotape 1268229Irving HorowitzAudiotape 1368230Welcome, Kopecky; Intro., Foss; William DomhoffAudiotape 1468231William Domhoff, Question and Answer; Welcome, Kopecky; Intro., SipeAudiotape 1568232Intro., Sipe; James O'ConnorAudiotape 1668233James O'Connor; Panel DiscussionAudiotape 1768234Panel Discussion; Intro., Sipe; Carl StokesAudiotape 1868235Carl Stokes, Question and AnswerAudiotape 1968236Question and AnswerAudiotape 2068237Welcome, Kopecky; Intro., Smith; Thomas SzaszAudiotape 2168238Thomas Szasz, Question and AnswerAudiotape 2268239Thomas Szasz, Panel DiscussionAudiotape 2368240Thomas Szasz, Panel Discussion; Welcome, Kopecky; Intro., Wenz; Michael NovakAudiotape 2468241Michael Novak, Question and Answer, Panel DiscussionAudiotape 2568242Michael Novak, Panel DiscussionAudiotape 2668243Welcome, Keiser; Intro., Smith; Kristin Lems and Peggy LipschutzAudiotape 2768244Kristin Lems and Peggy LipschutzAudiotape 2868245Kristin Lems and Peggy LipschutzAudiotape 2968246Welcome, Kopecky; Intro., Dworak; Thomas Gerety, Question and AnswerAudiotape 3068247Thomas Gerety, Question and Answer; Panel Discussion, Lois Lipton vs Thea BartonAudiotape 3168248Lois Lipton vs Thea BartonAudiotape 3268249Lois Lipton vs Thea BartonAudiotape 3368250

