<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>J.01.15/08Archon Finding Aid Title J.01.15/08UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:41:58 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    J1/15/8. Intersession Papers "The Energy Decade" 1981
    J.01.15/08
    399
    
      1.16 Cubic Feet
    
    1981
    Date acquired: 07/11/2002
    1
    2
    3
    4
  
  
    Scope and Contents
PAC 481, Intersession: "The Energy Decade: Food, Resources and Environment in the 1980s" (March 14-21, 1981) consists of brochures, programs, a readings book entitled, "Food, Resources, and the Environment in the 1980's," and a description of the video program: "Season of the Sangamon".  
Also included are 11 3/4" U-matic video tapes of guest speakers:  Robert Engler, who spoke on the petroleum industry and energy conservation after the nuclear age, Winona LaDuke, who spoke on the pollution of Indian reservation lands with uranium mining, Wilson Clark, who spoke on the adaptation of energy conservation used in European countries for the U.S., Douglas Ensminger, who spoke on the need for expanding food resources, Kirkpatrick Sale, who spoke on the need for developing alternatives to petroleum and nuclear power as energy sources, Eleanor Humes Haney, who spoke on energy conservation from a feminist perspective, and Valerie Pope Ludlum on the "solarization" of poor communities.  The sessions also featured SSU faculty members Luther Skelton (as primary mediator), David Hilligoss, James Stewart, John Munkirs, and Wilma Scott Heide, who also served as a mediator.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Subject, Chronological  
  Box 1Box 168093BrochuresFolder 1680951Seasons of the Sangamon video programFolder 2680962Scope and Contents"Food, Resources, and the Environment" Readings book (3 copies)Box 2Box 268094The Energy Decade (Tape 1 of 3)Videotape 1680973-16-1981Scope and ContentsGuest speakers Eleanor Humes Haney, a feminist from Harvard, and Dr. Robert Engler, a professor of political science from the City University of New York. The lectures featured discussions on the Petroleum industry, and energy conservation after the nuclear age. Mediated by faculty member Luther Skelton. 60 minute ¾" U-MaticThe Energy Decade (Tape 2 of 3)Videotape 2680983-16-1981Scope and ContentsGuest speaker, Douglas Ensminger, a food distributor for the World Food Fund. His lecture was entitled: Poverty, Hunger, and Food Sources.  His lecture was followed by a question/answer session and a panel discussion among Douglas Ensminger, Eleanor Humes Haney, Robert Engler, and John Munkirs. 60 minute ¾"U-Matic.The Energy Decade (Tape 3 of 3)Videotape 3680993-16-1981Scope and ContentsA continuation of the previous panel discussion. 60 minute ¾"U-MaticThe Energy Decade (Tape 1 of 3)Videotape 4681003-17-1981Scope and ContentsTape 1 out of 3 featured Winona LaDuke, Wilson Clark, Douglas Ensminger, and featured faculty members David Hilligoss, and James Stewart as a mediator. The topics of discussion covered the U.S. and North America; and featured lectures by Winona LaDuke on the problem of uranium poisoning on Native American reservations, and Wilson Clark discussing alternative energy methods used by other countries such as Germany. 60 minute ¾" U-maticBox 3Box 368103The Energy Decade (Tape 2 of 3)Videotape 1681013-17-1981Scope and ContentsTapes 2 and 3 of this group were a continuation of the previous panel discussions and featured question and answer sessions with the audience. 60 minute ¾" U-maticThe Energy Decade (Tape 3 of 3)Videotape 2681023-17-1981Scope and ContentsTapes 2 and 3 of this group were a continuation of the previous panel discussions and featured question and answer sessions with the audience. 60 minute ¾" U-maticThe Energy Decade (Tape 1 of 3)Videotape 3681053-18-1981Scope and ContentsThe  first tape of  the March 18 Intersession featured guest speakers-Kirkpatrick Sale, and Eleanor Humes Haney (introduced by Wilma Scott Heide). The mediator was Luther Skelton. The main topic of discussion was "Alternative Futures in the U.S." 60 minute ¾" U-maticThe Energy Decade (Tape 2 of 3)Videotape 4681063-18-1981Scope and ContentsTape 2 out of 3 for March 18th,  featured the last of Haney's speech, and was then followed by Luther Skelton's introduction of Kirkpatrick Sale.  Sale is a noted author, and his topic of discussion covered: "The Crisis of Natural Resources".  The tape concluded with a panel discussion featuring:  LaDuke, Sale, Ensminger, Haney, and Heide, as a moderator. 60 minute ¾" U-matic.Box 4Box 468104The Energy Decade (Tape 3 of 3)Videotape 1681073-18-1981Scope and ContentsTape 3 of March18th, featured the continuation of the previous panel discussion. 60 minute ¾" U-matic.The Energy Decade (Tape 1 of 2)Videotape 2681083-21-1981Scope and ContentsThe first was a "Energy and Self-Reliance" Workshop which was filmed in black and white, and lasted for about 30 minutes. 60 minute ¾" U-matic.The Energy Decade (Tape 2 of 2)Videotape 3681093-21-1981Scope and ContentsThe second tape was a continuation of the "Energy and the Environment" Intersession, dated 3/21/1981, which featured guest speaker Valerie Pope Ludlum on "Solarizing" Poor Neighborhoods.  Valerie Pope Ludlum was introduced by Linda Wags.  A question and answer session followed Ludlum's presentation, and a panel discussion also featured David Morris. 60 minute ¾" U-matic.

