<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.46Archon Finding Aid Title MC.46UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:42:16 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC46. First National Bank, Springfield, Illinois Records, 1919-1969
    
      First National Bank, Springfield
    
    
      Associated Colleges of Illinois
    
    
      Springfield Association of Commerce and Industry
    
    
      Committee for Higher Education in Central Illinois
    
    
      Hemle and Hemle, Architects
    
    MC.46
    54
    
      1.63 Cubic Feet
    
    1919-1969
    Date acquired: 11/00/1979
    33mm Negatives
    All Boxes
    Glass Negatives
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Photographs, glass plate negatives, printing plates documenting the First National Bank of Springfield, particularly the lobby at Sixth and Washington Streets (ca. 1917-1919), interior of the building constructed at Fifth and Adams in 1919, and building exteriors.  Includes award certificates from the Associated Colleges Of Illinois, Springfield Association of Commerce and Industry, and Committee for Higher Education in Central Illinois; and an architect's sketch of the building by Hemle and Hemle. Glass negatives are in the Fragile materials file. 35 mm negatives made from plates in photograph collection.  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Linda E. Dickson, FNB  
  
    Photographs
  
  Box 1Box 110225Working PapersSeries 110226Scope and ContentsContains copies of the photographs made from the glass plate negatives and the printing plates; this is a working file for users to view prints.PhotographsSeries 210227Scope and Contents8 x 10 glossy black and white photographs made from the glass negatives.Photo-File NegativesSeries 310228Photograph 1Item 110229ca. 1917-19191Scope and ContentsInterior of First National Bank at corner of Sixth and Washington Streets (SE), Springfield, Illinois. Shows left side of lobby looking out on Washington Street and Vice President's Office.Photograph 2Item 210230Ca. 1917-19192Scope and ContentsInterior, central lobby of First National Bank, Sixth and Washington Streets, Springfield. Shows central portion of lobby with windows for collections, receiving and paying.Photograph 3Item 310231ca. 1917-19193Scope and ContentsInterior, right side of lobby, First National Bank, Sixth and Washington Streets, Springfield. Shows teller cage for Paying and corridor on right side of bank.PrintsSeries 410232Scope and ContentsMade from printing plates, done by David Robinson and class.Plate 1Item 1102331Scope and ContentsSignature of _________________Plate 2Item 2102342Scope and ContentsAddress stamp. "First National Bank/Fifth Street at Adams/SPRINGFIELD, ILL." Decorated side margins.Plate 3Item 3102353Scope and ContentsView of First National Bank on southwest corner of Fifth and Adams; Fifth Street on left and Adams on right.Plate 4Item 4102364Scope and ContentsA line drawing of First National Bank on corner of Fifth and Adams Street. Labeled "First National Bank BLDG" with "Register" in corner. Dates some time in 1930s as shows streetcar and Model T's.Plate 5Item 5102375Scope and ContentsInterior lobby of First National Bank, Fifth and Adams.Plate 6Item 6102386Scope and ContentsView of walk-in safe door to safety deposit vaults, basement, First National Bank, Fifth and Adams.Plate 7Item 7102397Scope and ContentsCentral stairway from basement with view of vault area. First National Bank, Fifth and Adams.Plate 8Item 8102408Scope and ContentsCentral stairway entrance in lobby. First National Bank, Fifth and Adams.Plate 9Item 9102419Scope and ContentsUnknown, may be a reception area, an executive conference area, etc.Plate 10Item 101024210Scope and ContentsUnknown, may be a meeting room.Plate 11Item 111024311Scope and ContentsReproduction of parchment with Arabic or Hebrew characters. Untranslated.Plate 12Item 121024412Scope and ContentsArchitect sketch of First National Bank, Fifth and Adams. "Helmle &amp; Helmle ARCHITECTS' in lower left corner.Box 2Box 210245PlatesSeries 110246Scope and ContentsOriginal printing plates. Some may have been used in newspaper articles or publications; others may have been used in advertising. Prints from the plates are in Box 1 with a viewing set in the Working Papers folder of Box 1.Plate 1Item 1102471Scope and ContentsUnmounted, zinc plate, 3/8" x 2 7/8" Signature of ______Plate 2Item 2102482Scope and ContentsMounted on wood, 3/4" x 2" x 3/4" high. Address plate.Plate 3Item 3102493Scope and ContentsMounted on wood, 2 1/4" x 3 1/16" x 7/16" high. Cut made from screened photograph.Plate 4Item 410250ca. 19304Scope and ContentsMounted on wood, 2 1/8" x 3 1/4" x 7/8" high. Line cut of First National Bank BuildingPlate 5Item 5102515Scope and ContentsZinc plate, made from screened photograph.Plate 6Item 6102526Scope and ContentsZinc plate, made from screened photograph. 3 1/16" x 4 1/16"Plate 7Item 7102537Scope and ContentsZinc plate, made from screened photograph. 6/1/16" x 4 1/2"Plate 8Item 8102548Scope and ContentsZinc plate, made from screened photograph. 6" x 4 1/2"Plate 9Item 9102559Scope and ContentsZinc plate, made from screened photograph. 6 1/16" x 4 1/2"Plate 10Item 101025610Scope and ContentsZinc plate, made from screened photograph. 6 1/16" x 4 1/2"Plate 11Item 111025711Scope and ContentsZinc plate. 6 9/16" x 8 1/4". Reproduction of parchment with Hebrew or Arabic letters.Plate 12Item 121025812Scope and ContentsZinc engraving made from architect sketch. 6 7/8" x 11' Architectural sketch of First National Bank building, Fifth and Adams Street; "Helmle &amp; Hemle ARCHITECTS" in lower right-hand corner. Circa 1919. (Helmle &amp; Helmle were awarded the contract for designing new building in 1919).PhotographsSeries 210259Scope and ContentsGlass negatives are carefully packed and stored in the Archives Fragile Materials file. Glossy photographs are in Box 1 along with working photocopies. In addition, 35mm negatives to print new glosses are stored in the Archives Photo Collection. All three were taken the same day.Photograph 1Item 110260ca. 1917-19191Scope and ContentsGlass plate negative, black and white, 8 x 10. Interior, First National Bank, left-side of lobby.Photograph 2Item 210261ca. 1917-19192Scope and ContentsGlass plate negative, black and white, 8 x 10. Interior, First National Bank, central lobby.Photograph 3Item 310262ca. 1917-19193Scope and ContentsGlass Plate negative, black and white, 8 x 10. Interior, First National Bank, central lobby, right side.CertificatesSeries 310263"Award for Distinguished Corporate Citizenship presented to the First National Bank . . . on occasion of its fifth annual grant to the fund of Associated Colleges of Illinois, Inc. . ."Item 1102641960-12-191Scope and ContentsFramed certificate, light tan wood frame, 11 3/4" x 15". Glass."Certificate of membership in the Century of Commerce Club of the Springfield Association of Commerce and Industry."Item 2102651964-02-272Scope and ContentsFramed certificate, dark brown frame, 10 1/2 x 12 1/2". Glass."Certificate of Appreciation presented to First National Bank of Springfield for cooperation and support of Lincoln Land Community College and Sangamon State University by the Committee for Higher Education in Central Illinois."Item 3102661979-11-013Scope and ContentsFramed certificate, light tan and gold frame, 10 1/2" x 13 3/4". Glass. Signed by George Hatmaker, Robert Spencer, and Robert Poorman.

