<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.49Archon Finding Aid Title MC.49UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:42:30 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC49. Walt Whitman Collection, 1860-1971
    
      Feinberg, Charles E.
    
    
      Whitman, Walt
    
    MC.49
    57
    
      0.16 Cubic Feet
    
    1860-1971
    Date acquired: 00/00/1983
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Advertising circular, envelopes, offprints, posters, handbills, literary criticism, lithographs, letters, framed pictures and portraits, printed announcement, and lecture program; program and menu for Whitman's seventieth birthday party (1889); proofs of labels and autographs; admission tickets for a Robert Ingersoll lecture (1890);  and a facsimile of a Whitman letter. 

The material was collected by business executive and Whitman scholar, Charles E. Feinberg of Detroit, Michigan. Donated in memory of SSU Creative Arts professor Bruce Magidsohn. 
The bulk of the Feinberg-Whitman Collection is located at the Special Collections Division of the Library of Congress.  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Charles E. Feinberg  
  
    Related Materials
The Walt Whitman Collection has been added to the CARLI online digital collections.  To view, click on the link below.http://library.uis.edu/archives/collections/digital/index.html  
  OversizeSub-Series 185332 stereoscopic photographs of WhitmanItem 3185341872-0931Scope and ContentsIn wooden frame, 16.5" x 13.5"Cover page of Leaves of Grass, Author's Edition, Camden, NJ, 1876, and photograph of Whitman, Sept. 1872, Brooklyn, NY, by G.F.E. Pearsall together in a wooden frameItem 32853532Scope and Contents16" x 12.5"Walt Whitman Books posterItem 33853633Scope and Contents23.5" x 18"Framed engraving of WhitmanItem 34853734Scope and ContentsFrom frontispiece of the 1860 edition of Leaves of Grass, 7" x 9"Framed engraving of WhitmanItem 35853835Scope and Contents8.5" x 11.5"Poem Describing a Perfect SchoolItem 36853936Scope and ContentsFrames, 10" x 17.5"Whitman Books shelved in Special CollectionsSub-Series 28540AS 36 I3849 no. 26 1951Item 185411Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
Whitman and Rolleston: a correspondence / edited with an introduction and notes by Horst Frenz. Bloomington: Indiana University, 1951. (Indiana University Publications, humanities series; no. 26)E 457.9 W618 1923Item 285422Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
Memories of Lincoln. Girard, Kansas: Haldeman-Julius Co., 1923.E 457.9 W62 1912Item 385433Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
Memories of President Lincoln. Portland, Maine: Thomas B. Mosher, 1912.M 1533 G4 S3 1953Item 485444Scope and ContentsGeoffray, César.
Salut au Monde: cantate pour chœurs chantés et parles à voix mixtes et a voix égales avec instruments à vent sûr un texte adapté librement de poèmes de Walt Whitman / par Raphael Passaquet ; musique de César Geoffray. Vocal score. Paris: Les Presses d'Île-de-France, c1953.PS 3201 1872Item 585455Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt
Leaves of Grass. Washington, DC ; New York:  Smith &amp; McDougal, 1872.PS 3201 1881Item 685466Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt
Leaves of Grass. Boston: J.R. Osgood; 1881-82.PS 3201 1882Item 785477Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt
Leaves of Grass. Philadelphia: Ress Welsh, 1882.PS 3201 1883Item 885488Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt
Leaves of Grass. Glasgow: Wilson &amp; McCormick, 1883.PS 3201 1884Item 985499Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt
Leaves of Grass. Philadelphia: D. McKay, 1884.PS 3201 1888Item 10855010Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt
Leaves of Grass. Philadelphia. D. McKay, c1888.PS 3201 1889Item 11855111Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt
Gems from Walt Whitman / selected by Elizabeth Porter Gould. Philadelphia: D. McKay, 1889.PS 3201 1900Item 12855212Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt
Walt Whitman's poems.  Girard, Kansas.: Appeal to Reason, c1900.PS 3201 1900aItem 13855313Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
Leaves of Grass: Including a Facsimile Autobiography, Variorum Readings of the Poems and a Department of Gathered Leaves / Walt Whitman.  Philadelphia: D. McKay; c1900.PS 3201 1900bItem 14855414Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
Leaves of Grass / Walt Whitman.  New York: H.M. Caldwell, 1900.PS 3201 1909Item 15855515Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
Leaves of Grass / by Walt Whitman. London; New York: Cassell, 1909.PS 3201 1913Item 16855616Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
Poems from Leaves of Grass / by Walt Whitman; the Coloured Illustrations by Margaret C. Cook.  London: J.M. Dent &amp; Sons, Ltd. ; New York: E.P. Dutton &amp; Co., 1913.PS 3201 1924Item 17855717Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
Poems of Walt Whitman / Edited, with an introduction and notes, by Nelson Antrim Crawford.  Girard, Kansas : Haldeman-Julius Co., c1924.PS 3201 K4 1926Item 18855818Scope and ContentsKennedy, William Sloane.
The Fight of a Book for the World: A Companion Volume to Leaves of Grass / William Sloane Kennedy.  West Yarmouth, Mass.: Stonecraft Press, 1926.PS 3202 1888Item 19855919Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
Democratic Vistas and Other Papers / by Walt Whitman. London: W. Scott, 1888.PS 3203 M3Item 20856020Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
The Half-Breed: and other Stories / by Walt Whitman; Now First Collected by Thomas Ollive Mabbott; Woodcuts by Allen Lewis. New York: Columbia University Press, 1927.PS 3203 R8 G44 1956Item 21856121Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
Opere Alese / Walt Whitman; Traducere Si Prezentare de Mihnea Gheorghiu. Bucharest: Editura di Stat pentru Literatura si Arta, 1956.PS 3204 M3 1926Item 22856222Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
The Wisdom of Walt Whitman / Selected and Edited, with introduction by Laurens Maynard.  New York: Brentano's, 1926.PS 3204 W5 1900zItem 23856323Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
Twenty-three Poems / Walt Whitman; selected by Gwen Williams; with estimates by R.W. Emerson, R.L. Stevenson, etc.  London: Athenaeum Literature Dept., 19--.PS 3205 F7 B3 1914Item 24856424Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
Poèmes de Walt Whitman / version Française de Léon Bazalgette. Paris: F.Rieder &amp; Cie, 1914.PS 3205 G4 J3 1920Item 25856525Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
Grashalme / Walt Whitman; mit 13 Orginallithographien von Willi Jaeckel. Berlin: E. Reiss, 1920?PS 3205 I8 G3Item 26856626Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
Foglie di Erba: Con le Due Aggiunte e Gli "Echi della Vecchiaia" Dell'edizione del 1900 / Versione di Luigi Gamberale. Milano: R. Sandron, 1907.PS 3214 A1 1891Item 27856727Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
Good-bye My Fancy: 2nd Annex to Leaves of Grass. Philadelphia: D. McKay, 1891.PS 3217 A1 1889Item 28856828Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
November Boughs / by Walt Whitman. Paisley:  A.Gardner, 1889.PS 3220 A1 1883Item 29856929Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
Specimen Days &amp; Collect / by Walt Whitman.  Glasgow: Wilson &amp; McCormick, 1883.PS 3220 A1 1887Item 30857030Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
Specimen Days in America / by Walt Whitman.— Newly Revised by the Author, with Fresh Preface and Additional Note. London: W. Scott, 1887.PS 3222  A28 1871Item 31857131Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
After all, Not to Create only / Recited by Walt Whitman on Invitation of Managers, America Institute, on opening their 40th Annual Exhibition, New York, noon, September 7, 1871. Boston: Roberts Brothers, 1871.PS 3222 C7 1924Item 32857232Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
Criticism: An Unpublished Essay / by Walt Whitman.  Amenia, NY : Privately Printed at the Troutbeck Press, 1924.PS 3222 P7Item 33857333Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
Prose Nature Notes/ Walt Whitman. Girard, Kansas : Haldeman-Julius Company, 19--.PS 3222 S6 1904Item 34857434Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt.
Song of Myself. . . / Walt Whitman. East Aurora NY : Done into print by the Roycrofters, 1904.PS 3222 T8Item 35857535Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt
Two Rivulets: Including Democratic Vistas, Centennial Songs, and Passage into India. Author's ed.  Camden, NJ, 1876.PS 3231 A1 C38 1903Item 36857636Scope and ContentsCatalogue of a Collection of Books, Letters, and Manuscripts Written by Walt Whitman: in the Library of George M. Williamson, Grand View on Hudson.  Jamaica, NY : The Marion Press;   New York: Dodd, Mean &amp; Co., 1903.PS 3231 A1 W37 1955Item 37857737Scope and ContentsWalt Whitman: A Catalog Based Upon the Collections of the Library of Congress: with Notes on Whitman Collections and Collectors.  Washington, DC: Library of Congress Reference Department, 1955.PS 3231 A5 1892Item 38857838Scope and ContentsWhitman, Walt
Autobiographia: or, the Story of a Life / by Walt Whitman. New York: C.L. Webster, 1892.PS 3231 F4 1955Item 39857939Scope and ContentsFeinberg, Charles E.
Walt Whitman, a selection of the manuscripts, books, and association items / Gathered by Charles E. Feinberg.  Detroit: Detroit Public Library, 1955.PS 3231 H4 1924Item 40858040Scope and ContentsHamblen, Emily S.
Walt Whitman, Bard of the West/ Emily S. Hamblen. Girard, KS: Haldeman-Julius Co., c1924.PS 3231 S8 1893Item 41858141Scope and ContentsSymonds, John Addington.
Walt Whitman, a Study/ by John Addington Symonds. London: Nimmo, 1893.PS 3231 T5 1910Item 42858242Scope and ContentsThomson, James.
Walt Whitman, The Man and the Poet / by James Thomson ("E.V."): with an introduction by Bertram Dobell. London: The Editor, 1910.PS 3232 J6 1917Item 43858343Scope and ContentsJohnston, John.
Visits to Walt Whitman in 1890-1891/ by two Lancashire Friends, J. Johnston, MD and J.W. Wallace.  London: G. Allen &amp; Unwin, 1917.PS 3233 H3 1895Item 44858444Scope and ContentsHartmann, Sadakichi.
Conversations with Walt Whitman / by Sadakichi. New York: E.P. Coby &amp; Co., 1895.PS 3235 T65 1892Item 45858545Scope and ContentsAt the Graveside of Walt Whitman, Harleigh, Camden, New Jersey, March 30th, and Sprigs of Lilac / Edited by Horace L. Traubel.  Philadelphia: Billstein &amp; Son, 1892.PS 3238 L4 1916Item 46858646Scope and ContentsLegler, Henry Eduard.
Walt Whitman, Yesterday &amp; Today by Henry Eduard Legler. Chicago: Brothers of the Book, 1916.PS 3238 O35 1930Item 47858747Scope and ContentsO'Higgins, Harvey Jerrold.
Alias Walt Whitman/ by Harvey O'Higgins. Newark, NJ: Carteret Book Club, 1930, c1929.Z 8971.5 A6Item 48858848Scope and ContentsAmerican Library in London.
Walt Whitman: Catalogue of an Exhibition Held at the American Library, London, March-April 1954.  London: United States Information Service, 1954.Box 1Box 18502Engraving of WhitmanFolder 185031Scope and Contents5" x 8""Ah, Not This Granite Dead and Cold"Folder 285041885-022Scope and ContentsFinal proofNotes on Walt Whitman, As Poet and PersonFolder 385053Scope and ContentsBy  John Burroughs, 2nd. Ed., 1871 proof signature"Foreign Criticisms on an American Poet"Folder 485064Scope and Contents1 page about WhitmanProof sheets from November BoughsFolder 5850718895Scope and Contents"What Lurks Behind Shakspere's Plays?"
"Some War Memoranda"
"Abraham Lincoln"
"The Bible as Poetry"Presentation page from "Memoranda During the War"Folder 6850818716Scope and Contents(Rememberance Copy with Personal Note)Engraving of WhitmanFolder 785097Scope and ContentsWith facsimile signature and four line quote from Leaves of Grass"My Book and I"Folder 885108Scope and ContentsProof signature from magazine article"During the War"Folder 985119Scope and ContentsProof signatureFacsimile of the original Emerson letter exhibited on the occasion of the Grolier Club's visit to the home of Mr. and Mrs. Charles E. FeinbergFolder 1085121963-05-0310Scope and ContentsDetroit, MichiganMounted photograph of WhitmanFolder 118513ca. 187311Scope and ContentsTaken by F. Gutekunst, Philadelphia, 6" x 9""Walt Whitman on Abraham Lincoln"Folder 1285141886-04-1512Scope and ContentsProgram from the lecture at the Chestnut Street Opera House, PhiladelphiaAdvertisement cardsFolder 13851513Scope and ContentsFor Complete Poems &amp; Prose, 4.5" x 4"
For Leaves of Grass, and Specimen Days and Collect, 3.75" x 2.25"Facsimile of letter from Whitman to Dr. JohnstonFolder 14851614Program and menu from Whitman's seventieth birthdayFolder 1585171889-05-3115Scope and ContentsMorgan's Hall, Camden, NJAdvertisement page for Complete Poems and Prose, Leaves of  Grass, and Portraits from LifeFolder 16851816Scope and ContentsWith Autobiographical Note on backRobert Ingersoll lecture at Horticultural HallFolder 1785191890-10-2117Scope and ContentsPlaybill, 5.75" x 5.75"
Ticket number 1374, 4" x 1.5"
Ticket, 3.5" x 2.25"Envelopes used by Whitman when he was a member of the U.S. Christian Commission as a nurse in the Civil WarFolder 18852018Scope and ContentsReturn address: Walt Whitman, Camden, New Jersey
Return address: U.S. Christian Commission, Office in Washington, D.C., 343 Pennsylvania Avenue"You Lingering Sparse Leaves of Me," and "After the Supper and Talk," proof sheetsFolder 198521188819Engraving of WhitmanFolder 20852220Scope and Contents5.5" x 8"49th Congress, House of Representatives, Report No. 3856  to accompany Bill H.R. 10707 for the relief of Walt WhitmanFolder 21852321Tributes to William Carlyle and Thomas Jefferson Whitman:Folder 22852422Scope and Contents"The Dead Carlyle," one column
"An Engineer's Obituary" (from The Engineering Record NY, Dec. 13, 1890), for his brother, one columnWalt Whitman's Poetic PlatformFolder 23852523Scope and ContentsProof sheet about Whitman's article, "The Poetry of the Future""Shakespeare for America"Folder 2485261890-09-1524Scope and ContentsOffprint, Poet-LoreLeaves of GrassFolder 25852725Scope and ContentsTitle signature, 1888 Ed."Souvenirs of Democracy"Folder 26852826Scope and ContentsProof sheet"Shakspere-Bacon's Cipher"Folder 27852927Scope and ContentsProof sheet, correction fourth line by WhitmanIntercalations used in Centennial Edition of Leaves of GrassFolder 288530187628American Transcendental Quarterly #12, Fall 1971Folder 29853129Scope and ContentsPart 1American Transcendental Quarterly #12, Fall 1971Folder 30853230Scope and ContentsPart 2

