<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.50Archon Finding Aid Title MC.50UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:42:35 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC50. New American Movement, Mother Jones Chapter, Springfield, Illinois, Records, 1972-1981
    
      New American Movement
    
    
      Mother Jones Chapter, Springfield IL
    
    MC.50
    58
    
      1.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1972-1981
    Date acquired: 00/00/1984
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Springfield, Illinois chapter of the New American Movement, organized in 1975. Goal was "to act as a catalyst to bring about a strong, class conscious, working class movement in Springfield." Worked with other organizations such as Citizens for a Representative Government, DES Action Group, Springfield East Association, Springfield Coalition for Fair Electric Rates, People's Institute, and Streetside Boosters. Members included Peter MacDowell, Millicent Quam, Michael Quam, Doug Kamholz, Larry Golden, Lynn Novotnok, Sue Croteau, David Lasley, Kathy Wood, Ron Sakolsky, Becky McGovern, Ron Ettinger, Ted Cloak, and Ralph Stone. 

Correspondence, minutes, agendas, notes, membership lists, constitution, advertisements, and strategy statements documenting efforts to recruit members, to organize the people of Springfield with issues such as electric rate reform and the reorganization of city government, to sponsor speakers and movies with a socialist perspective, and create alliances with other community organizations. The group's use of self-criticism and concern that is was a "clique" of "SSU radical intellectuals" are documented. Individual members' personal goals and activity statements, and copies of the NAM Discussion Bulletin (1973-1980) are included. 

Series I:  The Working File, 1975-1977, consists of outgoing and incoming correspondence, minutes and agendas of their meetings, the constitution and draft constitution, handwritten notes, the one-year plan for the local chapter, and advertisements for activities sponsored by the Mother Jones Chapter of the New American Movement.  The files are arranged chronologically whenever possible.  Some notes are not dated.  Of particular interest is the DES Action Group file which documents the problem and the group's early efforts to organize in the community.  

Series II:  The Reference File, 1975-1977, consists of publications from various NAM chapters, NAM convention papers, DES Action Group information, and assorted news clippings.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Ralph Stone  
  
    Records
  
  Working File, 1975-1977Series 114909Scope and ContentsThe Working File, 1975-1977, consists of outgoing and incoming correspondence, minutes and agendas of their meetings, the constitution and draft constitution, handwritten notes, the one-year plan for the local chapter, and advertisements for activities sponsored by the Mother Jones Chapter of the New American Movement.  The files are arranged chronologically whenever possible.  Some notes are not dated.  Of particular interest is the DES Action Group file which documents the problem and the group's early efforts to organize in the community.Box 1Box 114911Activities Sponsored, 197?-1977Folder 1149121Constitution and Draft Constitution, n.d.Folder 2149132Correspondence, 1975-1977Folder 3149143Correspondence (outgoing), 1976-1977Folder 4149154DES Action Group of the New American MovementFolder 5149161972-19775Handwritten Notes, 1975-1977Folder 6149176Handwritten Notes, n.d.Folder 7149187Minutes and Agendas, 1975-?Folder 8149198Planning PapersFolder 9149201976-19779PublicationsFolder 1014921197710Scope and Contents"The Electric Agitator" Vol. 1, No. 3
"The Prairie Provacateur" Vol. 1, No. 1Reference File, 1975-1977Series 214910Scope and ContentsSERIES II:  The Reference File, 1975-1977, consists of publications from various NAM chapters, NAM convention papers, DES Action Group information, and assorted news clippings.Box 1Box 114922New American Movement's One Year Plan, 1975-1977Folder 111492311NAM Convention, 1975Folder 121492412Activities Sponsored by NAM, n.d.Folder 131492513Publications from various NAM branches, 1974-1977Folder 141492614News Clippings, 1976-?Folder 151492715Box 2Box 214928Discussion Bulletin (NAM):  Nos. 4, 7, &amp; 8Folder 1149291973-741Discussion Bulletin (NAM):  Nos. 9, 10, &amp; 11Folder 21493019752Discussion Bulletin (NAM):  Nos. 14, 15, &amp; 16Folder 31493119763Discussion Bulletin (NAM):  Nos. 17, 18, &amp; 19Folder 4149321976-774Discussion Bulletin (NAM):  Nos. 20, 22, &amp; 23Folder 5374241977-785Box 3Box 314933Discussion Bulletin (NAM):  Nos. 25, 27, &amp; 29Folder 1149341978-791Discussion Bulletin (NAM):  Nos. 30, 31, &amp; 32Folder 21493519802Discussion Bulletin (NAM):  Nos. 33, 34, &amp; 35Folder 3149361980-813NAM:  Notes, Working Papers, and ResolutionsFolder 4149371977-804

