<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.51Archon Finding Aid Title MC.51UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:42:37 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC51. Marie Porter Wheeler Papers, 1876-1926
    
      Wheeler, Marie Porter
    
    MC.51
    59
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1876-1926
    Date acquired: 00/00/1984
    1
    Oversize Items
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Afro-American woman born in Carbondale, Illinois in 1913. Graduated from high school in Metropolis in 1930.  Attended Southern Illinois University and Kentucky State University. Taught in secondary schools in Belgrave and Chester, Illinois. Married Luther Wheeler in 1937, and moved to Springfield in 1942. 

Diplomas, certificates, photograph albums and memorabilia documenting Wheeler's childhood, family members, and educational activities.  Also certificate and diplomas documenting educational activities of her grandfather, B.F. Porter, a medical doctor and certified hypnotist.  
Of note is a rejected claim for pension in 1902 from the Department of the Interior, Bureau of Pension – War with Spain.  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Marie Porter Wheeler  
  
    Papers
    Memorabilia
    Photographs
    Records
  
  Box 1Box 114938Memorabilia and Loose ItemsFolder 1149411Scope and Contents.20th Wedding Anniversary Invitation
"Mr. and Mrs. James Ferrell request your presence at the celebration of the Twentieth Anniversary of their Marriage at their home in Elkville, December 12, 1908, at the hour of 6 p.m." (with envelope addressed to Mrs. Lizzie A. Porter, Metropolis, Ill.)
. Department of the Interior, Bureau of Pensions Letter
Letter to Mr. B. F. Porter from the Department of the Interior, Bureau of Pensions, about "ratable disability" regarding his service during the Spanish-American War. (with envelope)
. B. F. Porter's Bank Savings Book from the Louisville Saving Bond Company
. American Express Company receipt
. Calling Card:  Maria J. PotterPhoto Album #1 (Red):  Porter Family AlbumItem 1149391Scope and ContentsComments on album #1:
There is no trace of memory on Marie's part of any of the people in it, nor does she remember being told anything about her father's family.  She inherited it simply because she was his only child.Photo Album #2Item 2149402Scope and ContentsComments on album #2¬:
Neighbors of the Roberts family were white families (one picture shows a white neighbor girl with Marie).  "We didn't have any colored neighbors," Marie stated; "The family across the street were from Canada."  When the pictures in the album are of group gatherings, these were often Sunday, after church scenes.  People frequently `dropped over' for social visits at that time.  Plus, there were the Sunday school outings, as indicated.Diploma of Massac County/Education issued to Marie Porter, June 1, 1926Item 1149471Certificate from the Board of Education issued to Marie Porter, June 1, 1926Item 2149482Certificate of Commission as Aide-de-camp of the Grand Army of the Republic issued to B. F. Porter, December 8, 1893Item 3149493Diploma from the College of Hypnotism issued to B. F. Porter, March 9, 1899Item 4149504Diploma for Doctor of Medicine issued to Benjamin F. Porter, Jr., July 1878Item 5149515

