<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.52Archon Finding Aid Title MC.52UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:42:39 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC52. Central Illinois Public Service Company Records, 1928-1941
    
      Central Illinois Public Services Company
    
    MC.52
    60
    
      1.49 Cubic Feet
    
    1928-1941
    Date acquired: 00/00/1984
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Large private utility serving central Illinois. Originally, a very diversified corporation providing electric, gas, ice and water service. Founded in Springfield in 1912.

Reports, photographic negatives and prints, charts, maps, notes, service area maps for various utilities, CIPS organizational charts, sales quotas, reports, telegrams, and research files documenting the sales policies, plans, and procedures of CIPS; its participation in award competitions; its research on other privately owned utilities in the Midwest; the extent of municipal and private electric service in Illinois; and all aspects of the company's operations for 1930. Topics include CIPS commercial and residential rates and sales; municipal elextric plants' rates and sales; and establishment and ownership of Illinois power plants. Of particular note are Municipal Utility Opposition Files, 1930-1941, consisting of clippings, wall posters, handbills, mass meeting reports, brochures, drafts of posters, articles and reports, handwritten notes, and a legal brief documenting the opposition of CIPS, as a corporate entity and under various pseudonyms, to the construction and operation of municipal utility plants in Auburn, Bushnell, Harrisburg, Herrin, and Petersburg. Results of some local municipal utility referenda; typescript summaries of meetings held in favor of municipal utility plants; and a CIPS vs. City of Bushnell legal brief are included.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Alphabetical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Steve Slack  
  
    Records
  
  Box 1Box 19351Sales Policies and Procedures of a Representative CompaniesFolder 193521929-19301Analysis of Domestic and Commercial Lighting Revenue and Kilowatt Hour SalesFolder 2935319302Reports-Analyses R. B. TulpinFolder 393541930-19313Mr. Johnson's ReportFolder 4935519304T.[?] E. Maddox ReportFolder 5935619305CIPS Customer and Rate DataFolder 6935719356Scope and ContentsCities and Towns Having Municipal Electric Service IllinoisBusiness Development PlanFolder 7935819397Coffin Award Negatives for YearFolder 8935919288Coffin Award Negatives for YearFolder 9936019299Charles A. Coffin Foundation Competition, Presentation of Wisconsin Power and Light Co.Folder 109361192910L.E. Myers AwardFolder 119362192911Charge to L.E. Myers AwardFolder 129363ca. 193112L.E. Myers Award Statement, Application of Central Illinois Public Service Company, Springfield, IllinoisFolder 1393641931-05-0113Box 2Box 29365L.E. Myers Award, Exhibits, Application of Central Illinois Public Service CompanyFolder 193661931-05-011General ReportFolder 19367193011Annual ReportFolder 29368193012Electric Service Schedule 9AFolder 39369193013Analysis of Domestic and Commercial Lighting Revenue and Kilowatt Hour SalesFolder 49370193014Industrial Development ReportFolder 59371193015Rural Service ActivitiesFolder 69372193016Annual Report Home Service Dept.Folder 79373193017Annual Report Public Information Dept.Folder 89374193018Annual Report Purchasing and Stores Dept.Folder 99375193019Annual Report of Merchandise Sales Dept.Folder 1093761930110Annual Report Chicago and Joliet Electric Railway Company, Chicago and Joliet Transportation Company, Dellwood Park CompanyFolder 1193771930111Ice Appliance Merchandising ProspectFolder 1293781931112Policies and Rules Governing Farm and Rural CustomersFolder 1393791931113Box 3Box 39380Auburn Water Works FileFolder 193811933-19361Bushnell Municipal Water, Mr. Chiles Working papersFolder 293821930-1931, 1938-19412Not Complete BushnellFolder 39383ca. 19383Bushnell Working Papers, C.W.C. [C.W. Chiles]Folder 4938419384Municipal Personal Working Papers, C.W. ChilesFolder 59385ca. 19385Report of Special Meeting to Consider Municipal Light Plant Ordinance Bushnell, IllinoisFolder 6938619386Wall Poster: "Vote No..." (Harrisburg)Folder 7938719337Box 4Box 49388Herrin Municipal Light Plant, Working PapersFolder 1938919391Paris Municipal ClippingsFolder 2939019352Petersburg Municipal Work FileFolder 3939119363(Duplicates Box #1)Box 59392Scope and ContentsContains duplicates of some items in the collection.

