<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.54Archon Finding Aid Title MC.54UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:42:55 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC54. J. L. Usow, Home movies, ca. 1931-1933; 1955.
    
      Usow, J. L.
    
    MC.54
    62
    
      0.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1931-1955
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Six reels of 16 mm. color and black-and-white film documenting travels in Europe, the western United States, Canada, Alaska and Mexico. Scenes include the passenger ship Leviathan leaving New York Harbor and entering a British port, London and Paris, ca. 1931-33; South Dakota Badlands; Prince Ruppert, Canada; Juneau, Alaska; Los Angeles, San Diego and San Francisco, California. Also included are scenes in Ensenada, LaPaz, Mazatlan and Magdalena, Mexico.  
Of special interest are wildlife scenes in South Dakota; street, boat and fish processing in Alaska; village life scenes in Mexico and battleships in the San Francisco area. No audio.  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Source Unknown  
  
    Home Movies
    Reel to Reel Tapes
  
  Box 1Box 114960Leviathan, Strand, boat to London, guards in London, 1931Item 1149611Scope and Contents16 mm. color and black and white home movie filmScenes in Paris, Medlaid, Armistice Day 1930, Louvre-Paris, 1931Item 2149622Scope and Contents16 mm. reel color and black and white home movie filmOriginal [Western United States including Badlands, South Dakota; Yellowstone National Park (?), Mission at San Juan  Capistrano], n.d.Item 3149633Scope and Contents16 mm. reel color and black and white home movie filmPrince Ruppert [Rupert] [British Columbia, Canada]; Sitka, Shagway, Jueneau [Juneau], Alaska, n.d.Item 4149644Scope and Contents16 mm. reel color and black and white home movie filmMexzico [Mexico], Insenata [Ensenada], [La Paz], Masatland [Mazatlan], Magdalina Bay [Magddalena], n.d.Item 5149655Scope and Contents16 mm. reel color and black and white home movie filmLions Farm, Lake Arrow Head, Exposition Park, Golden Gate, n.d.Item 6149666Scope and Contents16 mm. reel color and black and white home movie film

