<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.55Archon Finding Aid Title MC.55UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:42:56 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC55. Alfred Kamm Papers, 1962-1971
    
      Kamm, Alfred
    
    MC.55
    63
    
      0.66 Cubic Feet
    
    1962-1971
    Date acquired: 00/00/1984
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Long-time employee of the Illinois Office of Public Instruction, chair of the Sub-committee on Special Education of the Springfield Board of Education's School Survey Committee, 1962-63. Kamm, a native of Latvia, received a B.S. from the University of Illinois in 1926, an M.A. from the Teachers College of Columbia University in 1931, and an Ed.D. from New York University in 1944. 

Chiefly announcements, correspondence, clippings, printed material, reports, research files and surveys of the Special Education Sub-Committee, documenting its activities and survey findings regarding services being offered to handicapped children in District 186 by community agencies, public schools and school health units.  Reports and recommendations of the Springfield Citizens Committee for School Improvement, a city-wide community group independently formed in 1971 to address problems in the school system, concern problems in the school system, particularly the physical facilities of the schools.  Transcripts of WMAY radio talk shows presented by Springfield Mayor Nelson Howarth, 1968-1971, are also included.  
  
    Arrangement Note
By subject  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Alfred Kamm  
  
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 113687Working Papers and CorrespondenceFolder 1136881962-19631Subcommittee Preliminary ReportsFolder 21368919632Kamm's Reference MatrialFolder 3136901962-19633Springfield Public Schools, Guides and ManualsFolder 4136911962-19634Sub-Committee on Special Education Records, Draft Reports, Correspondence, and Working PapersFolder 51369219635Sub-committee on Special Education Survey Instructions and Preliminary ReportsFolder 61369319636Sub-committee on special Education: Grade Schools Survey DataFolder 71369419637Sub-committee on Special Education: Junior High Schools, Survey DataFolder 81369519638Sub-Committee on Special Education: Senior High Schools Survey DataFolder 91369619639Sub-committee on Special Education: Community Agency Questionnaires, Survey DataFolder 1013697196310Sub-committee on Special Education: Health Services School Survey DataFolder 1113698196311Citizen's Committee for School ImprovementFolder 12136991971-197212Box 2Box 213706Mayor Nelson Howarth Radio Talk Show TranscriptsFolder 11370719681Mayor Nelson Howarth Radio Talk Show TranscriptsFolder 21370819682Mayor Nelson Howarth Radio Talk Show TranscriptsFolder 31370919693Mayor Nelson Howarth Radio Talk Show TranscriptsFolder 41371019694Mayor Nelson Howarth Radio Talk Show TranscriptsFolder 51371119705Mayor Nelson Howarth Radio Talk Show TranscriptsFolder 61371219706Mayor Nelson Howarth Radio Talk Show TranscriptsFolder 71371319717Health SurveyFolder 81371419658Task Group on Personal Health Needs of the AgingFolder 9137159Springfield-Sangamon County Health Services Action Study Assessment of Health Services - Report No. 2Folder 1013716196410Springfield-Sangamon County Health Services Action Study MaterialFolder 11137171964-196711Radio Talks - HowarthFolder 1213718196912Springfield, Illinois School SurveyFolder 1313719196413Career Programs at Illinois Junior Colleges (chart)Folder 1413720197014

