<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.57Archon Finding Aid Title MC.57UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:43:06 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC57. Thea Chesley Papers, AFSCME Representation Material,  1983-1985
    
      Chesley, Thea
    
    MC.57
    65
    
      0.16 Cubic Feet
    
    1983-1985
    Date acquired: 02/00/1990
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The Thea Chesley papers: SSU clerical Employees AFSCME representation election materials, 1983-1985.  

Materials consist of letters from AFSCME; SSU president Durwald Long, Carl Long, Chairperson of the advisory committee on Collective bargaining. AFSMCE literature consists of brochures, memeos, flyers and pamphlets.  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Thea Chesley  
  
    Papers
    Flyers/Brochures
    Correspondence
    Programs
  
  Box 1Box 114967Folder 1Folder 1149681S.S.U. Materials consisting of: S.S.U. Staff Senate By-lawsItem 11500111List of Staff Senate Members, Spring 1984Item 21500212Minutes Staff Senate, June 8, 1984Item 31500313Staff Senate Agenda, July 13, 1984Item 41500414By-laws Faculty Senate; List of Faculty Senate, 1984-85Item 51500515By-laws and memo, 1984Item 61500616Scope and ContentsBy-laws S.S.U. University Assembly; &amp; Memo from Henry Smorynski, Chairperson, Committee on Committees, August 15, 1984, concerning University Committee Service Needs, 1984-85Booklet: "It's your union"; Newspaper Clipping May 14, 1983, "EIU Clerical Workers say 'Yes'"; Public Employee Vol. 48, No. 8, August 1983 &amp; Vol. 49, No. 3, March 1984Item 71500717Scope and ContentsAmerican Federation of State, County &amp; Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO (AFSCME), Il. Council 31, PublicationsFlyer, AFSCME University - Update, December 14, 1983Item 81500818Scope and ContentsAmerican Federation of State, County &amp; Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO (AFSCME), Il. Council 31, PublicationsPamphlet: AFSCME in the public service - "Q. A."Item 91500919Scope and ContentsAmerican Federation of State, County &amp; Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO (AFSCME), Il. Council 31, PublicationsButton: Join AFSCMEItem 1015010110Scope and ContentsAmerican Federation of State, County &amp; Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO (AFSCME), Il. Council 31, PublicationsUnion Fact Sheet #1 - "Get the Facts!"; #2 - "We Have the Right to Organize"; #3 - "Steps to a Union"; #4 - "Collective Bargaining - Our Job"Item 1115011111Scope and ContentsAmerican Federation of State, County &amp; Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO (AFSCME), Il. Council 31, PublicationsAnnouncement of Meeting for S.S.U. Employees Wed., July 27, 1983 in response to Administrative Bulletin - Office of the President, June 30, 1983 and notes on backItem 1215012112AFSCME Flyer: 7/29/83, "AFSCME Wins Legislative Victories for University Employees"Item 1315013113Scope and ContentsAmerican Federation of State, County &amp; Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO (AFSCME), Il. Council 31, PublicationsAFSCME: Il. University FAIR Salaries Campaign letter to University Employees from Irma Ryan, International Representative, Aug 17, 1983Item 1415014114Scope and ContentsAmerican Federation of State, County &amp; Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO (AFSCME), Il. Council 31, PublicationsReminder of Organizing Committee Meeting, Sept. 13, 1983, in S.S.U. CafeteriaItem 1515015115AFSCME Il. Council 31 letter to Sang. State Employees from Employee Organizing Committee: Thea Chesley, Mike Puma, &amp; Theresa Guy, Dec. 12, 1983Item 1615016116Scope and ContentsAmerican Federation of State, County &amp; Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO (AFSCME), Il. Council 31, PublicationsMemo to All Civil Service Staff from Pamela MillerItem 1715017117Meeting Notice Sangamon State Civil Service Employees, Jan. 24, 1984Item 1815018118AFSCME "Update for Higher Education Employees, April 1984Item 1915019119Scope and ContentsAmerican Federation of State, County &amp; Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO (AFSCME), Il. Council 31, PublicationsPamphlet: "Your work keeps the universities running.  Isn't it time you were paid fairly for the work that you do?"Item 2015020120Scope and ContentsAmerican Federation of State, County &amp; Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO (AFSCME), Il. Council 31, PublicationsCirculars: "AFSCME at S.S.U." &amp; "Looking for another job?" 8-20-84Item 2115021121Scope and ContentsAmerican Federation of State, County &amp; Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO (AFSCME), Il. Council 31, PublicationsS.S.U. AFSCME Organizing Committee Notes, Aug. 29, 1984 &amp; 2 Bulletins with Collective Bargaining Authorization CardItem 2215022122AFSCME Update for Board of Regents Employees, Sept.- Oct. 1984Item 2315023123Scope and ContentsAmerican Federation of State, County &amp; Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO (AFSCME), Il. Council 31, PublicationsAFSCME University Update - Dec. 1984 &amp; March 1985Item 2415024124Scope and ContentsAmerican Federation of State, County &amp; Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO (AFSCME), Il. Council 31, PublicationsPromotional Flyer from Il. Federation of TeachersItem 2515025125UPI Faculty Action - Legislative Special Mid-June 1985Item 2615026126AFSCME Bulletin - "EBA/925 Delays Election Again!" &amp; "8% increase for university employees! Another victory for AFSCME backed Fair Salaries Campaign!"Item 2715027127Scope and ContentsAmerican Federation of State, County &amp; Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO (AFSCME), Il. Council 31, PublicationsAFSCME Il. Council Letter, Aug. 22, 1985 &amp; FlyerItem 2815028128Scope and ContentsAmerican Federation of State, County &amp; Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO (AFSCME), Il. Council 31, PublicationsLetter from Advisory Committee, Oct. 3, 1985Item 2915029129Scope and ContentsLetter from Advisory Committee on Civil Service Staff Collective Bargaining, Carl Long, Chairperson, Subject: Collective Bargaining Election to Thea Chesley, Oct. 3, 1985List of Advisory Committee on Civil Service Collective BargainingItem 3015030130Letter to Thea Chesley from Carl E. Long, Oct. 18, 1985Item 3115031131Letter to Thea Chesley from the Advisory Committee on Collective Bargaining for Civil Service, Carl Long, ChairpersonItem 3215032132Letter from S.S.U. President Durward Long to Thea Chesley, Nov. 11, 1985Item 3315033133Folder 2Folder 2149692How The Fair Labor Standards Act Applies to State and Local Government Employees, June 1985Item 11497921Scope and ContentsKirschner, Weenberg, Dempsey, Walters &amp; Willig - General Council AFSCME"Fair Salaries and University Raises - Fiscal 1987"Item 21498022Letter from Secretary, Kathy Grantham, U. of Iowa to Thea Chesley, Sept. 6, 1985Item 31498123University Conference Board Meeting - Sept. 11, 1985Item 41498224Report: Meeting of AFSCME University Conference Board, Sept. 11, 1985Item 51498325AFSCME University Update, Aug. 1985 &amp; PamphletsItem 61498426Letter to S.S.U. Employees from AFSCME Il. Council 31, Sept. 23, 1985Item 71498527S.S.U. "Headcount" by positionsItem 81498628Letter to Thea Chesley from Advisory Committee on Civil Service Staff Collective Bargaining, Oct. 16, 1985Item 91498729AFSCME Il. Council 31 - Announcement of Meeting on Oct. 30, 1985, about AFSCME RepresentationItem 1014988210Letter to Charlton J. Brandt, Oct 29, 1985Item 1114989211Scope and ContentsLetter to Charlton J. Brandt from Carl Long, Chairperson for the Advisory Committee on Collective Bargaining for Civil Service Staff, Oct 29, 1985Letter to Paul Booth, Oct. 30, 1985Item 1214990212Scope and ContentsLetter to Paul Booth from Gilbert A. Cornfield, Attorney with Cornfield &amp; Feldmen, Chicago, Il., Oct. 30, 1985Letter to Thea Chesley from Brad Long, LTA III, OCLC Cataloging - Il. Universities Fair Salaries CampaignItem 13149912132 AFSCME FlyersItem 1414992214Flyer to Board of Regents Employees from Employees of the Il. State Scholarship Commission, Nov. 4, 1985Item 1514993215Letter to All S.S.U. Civil Service Employees from S.S.U. Employees in Support of Collective Bargaining, Nov. 5, 1985Item 1614994216Il. University Fair Salaries Campaign to Thea Chesley from Chuck Campbell, NSTA U of Il., Nov. 5, 1985Item 1714995217Letter to Vote "No" to Colleagues from Shirley Maurath, S.S.U. - LTA 11, Nov. 5, 1985Item 1814996218Letter to Vote "No" from Mary Ann Armstrong, S.S.U. - LTA 111, Nov. 6, 1985Item 19149972193 AFSCME FlyersItem 2014998220"Response to Olson Commentary (10/31/85)"Item 2114999221Letter from Ron Ettinger, Nov. 7, 1985Item 2215000222Scope and ContentsLetter from Ron Ettinger, Chapter President - Nov. 7, 1985, regarding "The Upcoming Collective Bargaining ElectionFolder 3Folder 3149703Letter to Thea Chesley from S.S.U. President Durward Long, Nov. 14, 1985Item 11497331Memo to Nancy Hunt from Thea Chesley, 11/15/85Item 21497432AFSCME Flyer on Nov. 12 VotingItem 31497533Agreement Booklet, July 1, 1981 to June 30, 1983Item 41497634Scope and ContentsAgreement for RC-06-OCB, RC-09-OCB, RC-14-OCB, RC-27-OCB, RC-28-OCB Between State of Il. Department of Personnel &amp; American Federation of State, County &amp; Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO (AFSCME), July 1, 1981 to June 30, 19832 Illinois AFSCME Collective Bargaining Authorization CardsItem 51497735Senate Bill 536, 7-1-1984Item 61497836Scope and ContentsSB 536 Enrolled - Copy of "7-1-84 Act by the General Assembly regulating labor relations                    between public employees &amp; creating the Illinois Labor Relations Board in connection therewith"Folder 4Folder 4149714AFSCME Organizing MaterialsItem 11497241Scope and Contents"AFSCME - Professional Representation" Report;  Nov. 5, 1985, Memo to All S.S.U. Civil Service Employees from S.S.U. Employees in Support of Collective Bargaining; 2 "Fair Wages" Flyers;  AFSCME Flyers

