<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.58Archon Finding Aid Title MC.58UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:43:09 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC58. Sangamon County Conservation District Committee Records, 1972-1974
    
      Sangamon County Conservation District Committee
    
    MC.58
    66
    
      0.49 Cubic Feet
    
    1972-1974
    Date acquired: 04/00/1986
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Formed in 1972 to campaign for a referendum that would establish a conservation district in Sangamon County, Illinois by levying taxes to purchase undeveloped lands for the purpose of conservation and recreation. Major campaign strategists of the Committee were Madeline Dorosheff and her son, Nicholas Dorosheff.  Referendum was defeated in 1974. 
Memoranda, correspondence, membership and mailing lists, promotion and campaign notes, organizational plans, speech transcripts, brochures, petitions, a ballot, clippings, slides and slide narrative, press releases, summaries and excerpts of the Illinois Conservation District Act, and personal notes documenting the Committee's membership, supporters, campaign strategies and work in support of the County Conservation Act referendum of March 19, 1974, and its use of the Macon County Conservation District as a model. Includes correspondence generated by the Sangamon Conservation Council. 
Series I:  The Administrative Files (1972-1974), Box 1, consist of brochures, ballots, petitions, plans, booklets, slides, slide narratives, newspaper clippings, and sundry research materials collected and generated by the District Committee.
Series II:  Mailing lists include local conservation mailing cards (active, in-active, official individuals, and out-of-town groups and supporters), mailing lists for official individuals, private individuals, groups in the city and county, projected lists (along with copies of materials mailed).  The series documents the Committee membership, supporters, and general campaigning.  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Records
    Flyers/Brochures
    Correspondence
    Newspaper Clippings
    Reports
    Slides
  
  Administrative File, 1972-1974Series 115034Box 1Box 115036County Conservation District Meetings and Existing CCD'sFolder 1150371Scope and ContentsCounty Conservation District Meetings and Existing CCD's; CCD Macon County Law - Summaries and Excerpts; Promotion - Remainder; Examples of Brochures; Publicity - Media, TV, Radio, Newspapers;                          Publicity Printed for CCD--locally [these folders include newspaper clippings]Council Executive Session, Feb. 18Folder 2150382County Conservation District Meeting, March 6, 1974Folder 3150393Ballot &amp; PetitionsFolder 4150404Scope and ContentsIncludes copy of Circuit Court petition to organize Sangamon County Conservation DistrictSCC - Nature Areas Booklet (Proposed)Folder 5150415Scope and ContentsIncludes copy of the Illinois Nature                         Preserves System Act [SCC-Sangamon Conservation Council]Fact BookletFolder 6150426Scope and ContentsSpeaker's Booklet (Background For) [includes Fact Booklet for the County Conservation District]Talks/BookletFolder 7150437CCD Follow-up PlansFolder 8150448Scope and ContentsIncludes Preston Schellback's talk on CCD on March 6, 1974; Sangamon County Survey of Historic Sites]Promotional (Future)Folder 9150459Research--Recreation and Facts about CCDFolder 101504610Scope and ContentsIncludes an Appraisal of Potential for                  Outdoor Recreation Development for Central Illinois]Slides and Slide NarrativeFolder 111504711Scope and ContentsCommittee for the Establishment of a Conservation and Recreation DistrictLoose Newspaper ClippingsFolder 121504812Mailing Lists, datesSeries 215035Box 2Box 215049Mailing lists and copies of memos and materials mailedFolder 1150501Scope and ContentsA group of four folders of separate listings; mailings - official individuals, individuals (private), groups (city and county), mailings on CCD, (finished and projected)Local conservation list (active list) removed from file card boxFolder 2150512Local Conservation ListFolder 3150523Scope and ContentsLocal Conservation List [removed from file card box] Groups Out-of-Town [Inactive?] Individuals - Official

