<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.59Archon Finding Aid Title MC.59UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:43:11 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC59. John Hay Tenants' Rights Association, Records
    
      John Hay Tenants' Rights Association
    
    MC.59
    67
    
      1.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1982-2005
    Date acquired: 01/21/1986
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Formed in 1986 to improve the standard of living and quality of life for the residents of the John Hay Homes public housing project in Springfield, and to promote athletic, artistic, charitable and civic activities. Articles of incorporation documenting the organization's founding, the leaflet and press release distributed at a Voting Rights Rally on July 4, 1986 protesting Springfield's commission form of government and actions by the City Council and Illinois State Journal-Register.The collection has been divided into five series, all contained in Box 1:  General Papers, 1982-2005; Voting Rights Lawsuit, 1986-1989; Police Review Commission, 1980-1984; and Marcus Garvey School and Malcolm X Library, 1988-2005.Series DescriptionSeries 1:  General Papers, 1982-1993, consist of pre-T.R.A. demographic data, correspondence, notes, constitution of the John Hay Home Resident Council, news articles, petitions, Lincoln School Bus Case, family background information, and legal papers against Springfield District #186; Articles of Incorporation and Certification forming the T.R.A.; T.R.A. correspondence, monthly reports, news articles, press releases, newsletters, notes, board meeting notes, grant applications to the Campaign for Human Development (CHD) and other various organizations, meeting minutes, and photographs.Series 2:  Voting Rights Lawsuit, 1986-1989, consists of correspondence, news articles, case study research for legal precedent, and court documents regarding cases #85-23-65 and #87-2488, including petitions, motions, docket entries, orders/decrees, legal fees, memorandums, and affidavits.Series 3:  Police Review Commission, 1980-1984, consists of correspondence and news articles regarding the deaths of the Hoskins family, Gerald Clemons, and Markadee R. Kelly.  These deaths led T.R.A. members to seek formation of a "watchdog" group to oversee police conduct.  Research of police review commissions were conducted by examining case studies, laws, guidelines, model legislation, petitions, the Berkeley Police Review Commissioners' Handbook, and local/national news articles.  This series also includes SSU van ban correspondence and news articles due to SSU students involvement in the protest march held regarding the deaths of Clemons and Kelly.Series 4:  Marcus Garvey Liberation School and Malcolm X Library, 1988-2005, consists of correspondence, summer school schedules, programs, news articles, flyers, annual reports, photographs and negatives.  Papers documenting SSU student involvement with the Marcus Garvey School, under the leadership of Professor Mike Townsend, are included.  The Marcus Garvey Liberation School originally was named the Marcus Garvey Freedom School.  This series also includes materials pertaining to the Malcolm X Children's Library and Experimental Reading Center.Series 5:  VHS and Audiocassette Recordings and 35mm Slides.  VHS recordings consist of Marcus Garvey 17th Graduation in 2002 and Rites of Passage, 15th anniversary celebration of the school, and the Malcolm X Library painting projects.  Audiocassette recordings consist of the SSU van ban following student protests of the deaths of Clemons and Kelly.  The 35mm slides are of the Marcus Garvey School children at the goat barn.  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
John Hay Tenants' Rights Association  
  
    Accruals and Additions
5/15/2009 and 6/9/2010  
  
    Records
  
  Box 1Box 112742General Papers, 1982-1993Series 150725Pre-T.R.A.: Demographic DataFolder 1127431982-01-01 - 1985-12-011John Hay Concerned Citizens for a Better GovernmentFolder 25073019852Scope and ContentsPre-T.R.A.  Correspondence, notes, constitution of the John Hay Home Resident Council, newspaper articles, and AST Final Evaluation.Photocopy of Constitution of Warner Homes Tenant Rights CouncilItem 1507311985-02-1221Scope and ContentsAttachments include Notice to all residents of Col. John Warner Homes and Tenant Council Election.Photocopy of Constitution and By Laws of the John Hay Home Resident Council, ndItem 25073222Memorandum from Springfield Housing Authority (S.H.A.) to Kay Readus, Resident CouncilItem 3507331985-09-0623Scope and ContentsRe: Usage of Community Center VanLetter from Sherry Keys of the Springfield Housing Authority to Kay Readus, President of John Hay Resident CouncilItem 4507341985-09-0924Scope and ContentsRe: The newly formed Youth Advisory Council.Letter from Peggy Ingram, Republican Committee-Person and Sherwin Haywood, Democratic Committee-Man to unknownItem 5507351985-09-1025Scope and ContentsRe: Relocation of polling place.R.C.P. Resident Council Preschool Program, ndItem 65073626Scope and ContentsIncludes program location, date and times, volunteer requirements, names of child and parent, and address of parent.Letter from Tanjila S. Readus, Neighborhood Watch Chairperson, to John Hay Residential CouncilItem 7507371985-09-1327Departmental Correspondence from Community Center Director to John Hay Resident CouncilItem 8507381985-09-1328Scope and ContentsRe: Availability of van and usage policy.Letter from John Hay Resident Council to Springfield Mayor and Council MembersItem 9507391985-09-2429Letter from John Hay Resident Council to Henry Morris, Executive Director of S.H.A.Item 10507401985-09-27210Handwritten note from Kay Readus to Mike Townsend, ndItem 1150741211Springfield's Voice, pp. 7-10Item 12507421985-10-10212Letter from Dewayne Readus and Mike Townsend to Rev. Willie Barrow, Operation P.U.S.H.Item 13507431985-10-18213Scope and ContentsRe: Requesting materials concerning the formation of an Operation P.U.S.H. Chapter in Springfield.The Pure-News, Vol. 3, No. 11Item 14507441985-11214Mike Townsend's handwritten notes, ndItem 1550745215Letter from John Hay Concerned Citizens for a Better Government to City Council MembersItem 16507461985-11-26216Proposal to Springfield Housing Authority from the Residents of the John Hay HomesItem 17507471985-12217Scope and ContentsRe:  A new election of John Hay Homes Resident Council members; attached S.J.R. article, 12/13/85, "SHA board discusses legal options on unit that violates zoning rules".Haire, Gerald.  AST Final EvaluationItem 18507481985-12-16218Correspondence, Petitions, and News ArticlesFolder 35074919853Scope and ContentsSome Pre-T.R.A.; includes Lincoln School Bus Case.Springfield Housing Authority - John Hayes Resident Council, Daily Bus Route and ScheduleItem 1507501985-01-0631Scope and ContentsIncludes dates, times, addresses, grades, and drivers' names.Petition from John Hay Homes Concerned Parents for Better Education to Springfield School District #186Item 2507511985-0232Scope and ContentsRe: Obtaining safe transportation of John Hay Homes children to McClernand Elementary School.Letter from Donald Miedema, Superintendent of Schools, to John Hay Concerned Parents for Better EducationItem 3507521985-02-2733Memorandum from Mike Townsend to John Hay Concerned Parents for Better Education FileItem 4507531985-02-2734Scope and ContentsRe:  School Board Strategy Meeting - February 26, 1985.Letter from Co-Chairpersons of the John Hay Concerned Parents for Better Education Committee to John Hay residentsItem 5507541985-03-0135Scope and ContentsRequesting residents and their children to attend a protest before the elected School Board at its next meeting, Monday March 4th."Hay Homes parents demand school bus for safety", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 6507551985-03-0536"School board to ask for OK for bus route to McClernand", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 7507561985-03-0937Letter from Co-Chairpersons of the John Hay Concerned Parents for Better Education Committee to the seven elected School Board MembersItem 8507571985-03-1138Letter from Melvin Schumacher to Agnes HoustonItem 9507581985-03-1139John Hay Concerned Parents for Better Education Comments, ndItem 1050759310List of parents' names and addresses, ndItem 1150760311Scope and ContentsIncludes names of children."186 board OKs repairs at Matheny", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 12507611985-03-26312Mike Townsend's handwritten notes, ndItem 1350762313Letter from John Hay Resident Council to Dr. Donald Miedema, Superintendent of Springfield School District #186Item 14507631985-09-05314Petition from John Hay Homes Concerned Parents for Better Education to Springfield School District #186Item 15507641985-09-05315Scope and ContentsRe: Obtaining safe transportation of John Hay Homes children to Lincoln Elementary School.Letter from Donald Miedema, Superintendent of Schools, to Kay Readus, President John Hay Homes Resident CouncilItem 16507651985-09-13316"Group urges Hay Homes school bus route", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 17507661985-09-18317Letter from John Hay Resident Council to Judy Stephens, President of Springfield's School BoardItem 18507671985-09-19318Letter from Judy Stephens, President of Board of Education, to Dewayne Readus of John Hay Resident CouncilItem 19507681985-09-20319"Hay Homes school bus route urged", Springfield AdvertiserItem 20507691985-09-25320Mike Townsend's handwritten notes, ndItem 2150770321Scope and ContentsSchool Board Points, School Bus Observation Mon. 10/7/85, and Lincoln School Parents Information Sheet.Fact Sheet: Lincoln School Bus Issue by John Hay Parents for Safe Education, ndItem 2250771322Letter from Dewayne Readus, John Hay Resident Council, to Judith Stephens, President of Board of EducationItem 23507721985-09-26323"3 school board incumbents take heat", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, IL, ndItem 2450773324"School board again starts action against Linda McCoy", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 25507741985-10-08325Petition from John Hay Parents for Safe Education to Dr. Donald Miedema, School SuperintendentItem 26507751985-10-14326Scope and ContentsPetition signed by parents seeking to obtain safe busing of their children attending first grade at Lincoln Elementary School."Hay Homes group again seeks bus service", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 27507761985-10-23327Mike Townsend's handwritten notesItem 28507771985-10-28328Scope and ContentsRe: Bus schedule at 12th &amp; Madison and Lincoln School, includes bus number, time, route and number of children aboard.Letter from Dewayne Readus, John Hay Parents for Safe Education, to Donald Miedema, Superintendent of Springfield School District #186Item 29507781985-10-29329Scope and ContentsRe: Results of on-site survey of bus route and riders."Hay Homes group won't buy bus plan", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 30507791985-11-05330Letter from Dewayne Readus, John Hay Parents for Safe Education, to William Roberts, Sangamon County State's AttorneyItem 31507801985-11-08331Note from Melvin Schumacher, van driver, to Parents for a Safe EducationItem 32507811985-11332Scope and ContentsRequesting attendance and organizing transportation of residents to the 11/18/85 school board meeting."Hay Homes Parents keep Pressure on School Board", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 33507821985-11-19333"District 186 eyes 'Early Start' funds", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 34507831985-11-19334Proposal from the Residents of the John Hay Homes to the Springfield Housing Authority, ndItem 3550784335Scope and ContentsRe:  The Need for Laundry Facilities in the John Hay Homes.List of Properties with Resolutions Passed by City Council for Demolition or RepairItem 36507851985-11-25336Scope and ContentsSpringfield Dept. of Public Health and Safety-Housing's list of placarded, pending structures includes inspected address, type of structure, apt., CT, Plac Date, and Plac Type.Petition from 50 Residents of Springfield School District #186 to Illinois State Board of Education, Legal DepartmentItem 37507861985-11-27337Scope and ContentsRe: Discrimination of 22 minority first graders attending Lincoln Elementary School.Letter from J. William Roberts, State's attorney, to Dewayne ReadusItem 38507871985-12-02338Letter from Dewayne Readus to J. William Roberts, State's attorneyItem 39507881985-12-11339"Our kids need a bus", Illinois TimesItem 40507891985-12-12 - 12-18340John Hay Parents for Safe Education, Lincoln School Bus Case: Family Background InformationFolder 450790ca. 19864Correspondence, Notes, and News Articles re: Lincoln School Bus CaseFolder 55079119865Letter from Michael Mangan, Illinois State Board of Education, to Dewayne Readus, John Hay Resident CouncilItem 1507921986-01-0251Scope and ContentsRe: Complaint filed by residents citing discrimination."We love our kids", Illinois TimesItem 2507931986-01-03 - 01-0852Legal Papers, Springfield District #186Item 350794198653Scope and ContentsNotice of Opportunity for Hearing and Designation of Hearing Officer, 1/8/86, sent via certified mail from Illinois State Board of Education to Dewayne Readus; and letter from Dewayne Readus to Charles Given, Hearing Officer.Letter from Jack Billington, attorney, to Superintendent Ted SandersItem 4507951986-01-1554"Officials face subpoena in Hay Homes complaint", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 5507961986-01-1555"On Hay Homes group's complaint - Attorney:  No jurisdiction for ed board", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 6507971986-01-2856"Hay Homes group discusses compromise with district", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 7507981986-02-1157Letter from Charles M. Given, Hearing Officer, to John A. Billington, attorneyItem 8507991986-04-1058"Court battle is shaping up over school bus route", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 9508001986-04-1059"Hearing set May 12 on school bias complaint", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 10508011986-04-12510Letter from Jack Billington, attorney, to Charles GivenItem 11508021986-05-06511List of Parents and Children involved in Lincoln School Transportation, ndItem 1250803512Mike Townsend's handwritten notes, ndItem 1350804513Scope and ContentsQues. for David Gates, Ques. for St. Bd. (State Board), Ques. for Sch. Bd. Mems (School Board Members), Questions for Miedema, and Additional Ques. for Stephens.Press Release from John Hay Tenants' Rights AssociationItem 14508051986514Scope and ContentsIncludes news article, "Hay Homes area nets victory of sorts in its school bus battle", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, IL, 05/10/1986, and letter from Dewayne Readus to William Roberts, State's attorney."Group plans challenge of school board voting", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 15508061986-05-14515Scope and ContentsJohn Hay Homes Tenants Rights Association plans a petition drive to force a referendum on whether to continue electing school board members at large in order to obtain better representation.Mike Townsend's handwritten notes, ndItem 1650807516Letter from J. William Roberts, State's attorney, to Dewayne ReadusItem 17508081986-06-27517Miedema:  Aid cust unlikely to unbalance education fund", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 18508091986-08-01518Articles of Incorporation and CertificationFolder 6508101986-01-166Correspondence, Monthly Reports, News Articles, Press Releases, Newsletters, and NotesFolder 75081119867John Hay Tenants' Rights Association, LetterheadItem 15081271John Hay Tenants' Rights Association, Announcement, ndItem 25081372Memorandum from Dewayne Readus, President of John Hay Tenants' Rights Association, to Springfield Housing Authority Board of CommissionersItem 3508141986-01-0873Scope and ContentsRe:  Monthly Report of Activities and Concerns.Letter from Dewayne Readus to Editor of Illinois State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 4508151986-01-1574Scope and ContentsRe: Pete Ellertsen's political column, "Black Coalition Boosting Houston".John Hay Tenants' Rights Association, NewsletterItem 5508161986-0275John Hay Tenants' Rights Association, Press ReleaseItem 6508171986-02-2576Letter from Dewayne Readus to Ms. Print, Jamaica Arts CenterItem 7508181986-02-2677Letter from Dewayne Readus to Poster ProjectItem 8508191986-02-2678Letter from Dewayne Readus to Red Table PrintsItem 9508201986-03-0379Letter from Dewayne Readus to Red PepperItem 10508211986-03-03710Letter from Henry Morris, Springfield Housing Authority, to Dewayne Readus, President of John Hay Tenants' Rights AssociationItem 11508221986-03-27711Second Letter from Henry Morris, Springfield Housing Authority, to Dewayne Readus, President of John Hay Tenants' Rights AssociationItem 12508231986-03-27712Scope and ContentsRe:  JHTRA Requests with SHA Responses.Letter from Michael Townsend to Springfield Election CommitteeItem 13508241986-03-28713Scope and ContentsRe: Reinstatement of Tanjila Readus as a deputy registrar.John Hay Tenants' Rights Association, Budget Fiscal Year 1986Item 1450825714Scope and ContentsFiscal year 4/1/86 - 3/31/87Memorandum from Dewayne Readus, President of John Hay Tenants' Rights Association, to SHA Board of CommissionersItem 15508261986-04-08715Scope and ContentsRe: Summary of activitiesLetter from Charles M. Given, Hearing Officer, to John A. Billington, attorneyItem 16508271986-04-10716Scope and ContentsRe: Transportation of Certain First Grade Students in Springfield District #186"Good clean fun?", Illinois TimesItem 17508281986-04-10 - 4-16717"8 sites eliminated in scattered homes project", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 18508291986-04-11718"Hay Homes group told to move office", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 19508301986-04-16719Letter from I.J. Feber, attorney, to Dewayne ReadusItem 20508311986-04-16720Memorandum from Dewayne Readus, President of John Hay Tenants' Rights Association, to SHA Board of CommissionersItem 21508321986-05-08721Scope and ContentsRe: Monthly Report of ActivitiesFlyer, "Victory over the School Board Celebration"Item 22508331986-05722Scope and ContentsSponsored by TRA"Hay Homes area nets victory of sorts in its school bus battle", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 23508351986-05-10723John Hay Tenants' Rights Association, Press ReleaseItem 24508341986-05724Scope and ContentsRe: 5/10/86 State Journal-Register articleLetter from Dewayne Readus to William Roberts, State's attorneyItem 25508361986-05-12725John Hay Tenants' Rights Association, Press ReleaseItem 26508371986-06-16726Scope and ContentsRe: Superintendent Miedema and the Westside School BoardFlyer, "July 4 Voting Rights Rally and March to Lincoln's Home"Item 27508381986-06727Scope and ContentsSchedule of rally event.  Rally, march and demonstration co-sponsored by People for Progress, John Hay Tenants' Rights Association, NAACP, Span and Women's International League for Peace &amp; Freedom.Letter to John Hay Tenants' Rights Association from the Internal Revenue Service District DirectorItem 28508391986-06-20728Scope and ContentsRe: Exemption from Federal income tax under section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code."High Stakes", Illinois TimesItem 29508401986-07-17 - 7-23729Mike Townsend's handwritten letter draft to Bruce StrattonItem 30508411986-08-18730Mike Townsend's handwritten letter draft to Council Members, ndItem 3150842ca. 1986731"35 picked for leadership training program", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 32508431986-08-26732"Council tentatively OKs bonds for 2 projects", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 33508441986-09-03733"SHA awards three contracts for Hay Homes improvements", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 34508451986-09-19734Campaign for Human Development, ApplicationItem 35508461986-11-24735Scope and ContentsIncludes Explanation of CHD Proposal Evaluation Form and Comparative Figures from 5/27/86.Mike Townsend's handwritten expenses and notes, ndItem 3650847736John Hay Tenants' Rights Association, ContractItem 37508481986-11737Scope and ContentsRe: Furniture and Appliance Revolving Loan ProgramCampaign for Human Development, 1987 CHD Funding BookletItem 3850849738Scope and ContentsTo be used only by Applicants Completing the Pre-App Process, or currently funded projects.Correspondence, Monthly Reports, News Articles, Press Releases, and Notes, 1987Folder 8508508Letter from John Hay Tenants' Rights Association to The United WayItem 1508511987-01-1381Scope and ContentsRe: Funding from the Unmet Needs Committee.Letter from John Hay Tenants' Rights Association to James Craven, attorneyItem 2508521987-01-2282Scope and ContentsRe: City Council and the Madison Street Project with an attached copy of the State Journal-Register's 1/21/87 article, "Council OKs final stretch of Madison Street Corridor"."Letters from Readers:  Parents upset over bus route", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 3508531987-02-1883Memorandum from Dewayne Readus, President of John Hay Tenants' Rights Association, to SHA Board of CommissionersItem 4508541987-02-1984Scope and ContentsRe: Monthly Report of Activities and ConcernsLetter from Carol Petrucci, Project Coordinator, to Richard Gage, Artist-in-Education Coordinator of the Illinois Arts CouncilItem 5508551987-03-1385Scope and ContentsRe:  Journal application for an artist-in-residence to administer the summer mural project based on the theme of Peace and Justice.  Includes Artists-in-Education 1987-88 Sponsor Application.Letter from Vincent Dunn, Grants Officer of the Illinois Arts Council, to Dewayne ReadusItem 6508561987-04-0386Scope and ContentsRe: Grant applicationState Board of Education, State of Illinois, OrderItem 7508571987-04-0687Scope and ContentsRe:  The transportation of certain First Grade Students in Springfield District #186"Brandon Drive's preschool of hard knocks", Illinois TimesItem 8508581987-04-30 - 05-0688Flyers, Precinct 76 Committee Election, DemocratItem 950859198789Scope and ContentsDewayne Readus, Jackie Readus, Melvin Schumacher, and John "Luther" Howell.Press Release, Readus for City Council Campaign Committee (draft)Item 10508601987810Flyer, John Hay Resident Council ElectionItem 11508611987-08811Flyer, John Hay Tenants' Rights AssociationItem 12508621987-10812Scope and ContentsReminder to vote on Tuesday, Nov. 4 Election DayJohn Hay Tenants' Rights Association Statement to Springfield City CouncilFolder 9127441987-03-249Board Meetings, 1987Folder 10508631987-07-21 and 11-2510Scope and ContentsIncludes grant application to Ms. Foundation for Women and BudgetsCampaign for Human Development (CHD)Folder 11508641987-198811Scope and ContentsFirst CHD Project ever funded in Springfield.  Includes correspondence, application, quarterly reports, and CHD's 1988 Funded Projects book.Correspondence, Newsletters, News Articles, and Notes, 1988Folder 125086512Letter from Dewayne Readus to Henry Morris, Executive Director of SHAItem 1508661988-01-10121Scope and ContentsRe: "Tenant Management" conference in Washington, D.C. on February 1-3, 1988.  Includes copies of National Center for Neighborhood Enterprise's invitation and conference materials."Attorneys:  SHA's late rent policy violates rules", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 2508671988-02-26122"Partial demolition of Hay Homes studied", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 3508681988-03-03123"Police probe city shooting incidents", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 4508691988-03-08124"Group seeks panel to help prevent police brutality", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 5508701988-03-31125"Will SHA let tenants run Hay Homes?", Illinois TimesItem 6508711988-03-31 - 04-06126Letter from Mike Townsend to Mayor Ossie LangfelderItem 7508721988-04-01127"John Hay Youngsters go to College", Illinois TimesItem 8508731988-04-04 - 04-10128WTRA, Inc., Articles of IncorporationItem 9508741988-04-14129Letter from Mike Townsend to Eileen LunaItem 10508751988-04-151210Letter from Dewayne Readus to Stewardship Committee for the Poverty, Justice and Peace Fund, Dominican SistersItem 11508761988-04-151211Letter from Mike Townsend to Mayor Ossie LangItem 12508771988-05-191212Scope and ContentsIncludes handwritten vita for J. Dewayne Readus, handwritten and formal typed drafts of letter to Mayor, and a typed vita for Elizabeth A. Langen.Letter from Mike Townsend to Mayor Ossie LangItem 13508781988-05-221213Letter from Dewayne Readus to Henry Morris, Executive Director of SHAItem 14508791988-05-221214Memorandum from Mike Townsend to Dean SteelItem 15508801988-06-061215Scope and ContentsRe:  Support for student field work projects.Letter from Mike Townsend to Mayor Ossie LangfelderItem 16508811988-06-081216Letter from Dewayne Readus to Mayor Ossie LangfelderItem 17508821988-06-201217Scope and ContentsRe: Freedom of Information Act Request.Letter from Dewayne Readus to J. R. Bartylak, Executive Director, Land of Lincoln Legal AssistanceItem 18508831988-07-281218"Anti-drug program planned for Hay Homes", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILItem 19508841988-08-141219Letter from Dewayne Readus to Editor, Illinois TimesItem 20508851988-09-201220Scope and ContentsAttachments include "Doomsday" poem written by Dewayne Readus, copy of Illinois Times' 9/22/88 article "Republicrats strike again", copy of Illinois Times' 9/29-10/5/88 article "Push forward", copy of The Pure-News' October 1988 article "Fair Election", and copies of Dewayne Readus' 10/4/88 and 10/25/88 letters to the Editor of the Illinois Times.Letter from Dewayne Readus to the Editor, Illinois TimesItem 21508861988-10-041221Letter from Dewayne Readus to the Editor, Illinois TimesItem 22508871988-10-251222Letter from Mike Townsend to ?, ndItem 2350888ca. 19881223Letter from Dewayne Readus to Editor, Illinois TimesItem 24508891988-10-261224Letter from Mike Townsend to Editor, Illinois TimesItem 25508901988-10-281225"Two-headed parasite", Illinois TimesItem 26508911988-11-3 - 11-91226Memorandum from Dewayne Readus, President of John Hay Tenants' Rights Association, to SHA Board of CommissionersItem 27508921988-11-101227Scope and ContentsRe: Proposal for Initiating the Drug Abuse Prevention Program."Tenants' Rights Group Disputes Election Results", Illinois TimesItem 28508931988-11-10 - 11-161228Letter from Dewayne Readus to U.S. Catholic Conference, CHDItem 29508941988-11-111229Letter from Dewayne Readus to Editor, Illinois TimesItem 30508951988-11-111230"No halo", Illinois TimesItem 31508961988-11-17 - 11-231231"Soviet visitors", Illinois TimesItem 32508971988-12-8 - 12-141232Memorandum from Gary Storm, SSU Faculty Sponsor, to New &amp; Potential Members of "Higher Horizons"Item 33508981988-12-151233Scope and ContentsRe: Organizational Meeting:  Directions for the Future.Memorandum from Mike Townsend to TRA Board MembersItem 34508991988-12-291234Scope and ContentsRe: December Board MeetingMeeting minutes, Correspondence, and Activity Sheet, 1989Folder 135090013Memorandum from Mike Townsend to TRA Board MembersItem 1509011989-01-26131Letter from Dewayne Readus to Mary Ann Coombe, Chairperson of Positive Youth Development ProgramItem 2509021989-01-26132Scope and ContentsIncludes Activity Sheet and typed note from Dewayne Readus.Mike Townsend's handwritten draft of Letter from Dewayne Readus to Mary Ann Coombe, Chairperson of Positive Youth Development ProgramItem 3509031989-01133Scope and ContentsIncludes draft of Activity Sheet.Memorandum from Mike Townsend to Campaign for Human DevelopmentItem 4509041989-02-28134Scope and ContentsRe: Grant #88-D-06-01John Hay Tenants' Rights Association, Statement to the PressItem 5509051989-04-17135Letter from Dewayne Readus to Richard Berning, Chief City EngineerItem 6509061989-07-13136Scope and ContentsRe: Human Rights march to be held 7/17/89.Letter from Dewayne Readus to American Business ClubItem 7509071989-07-31137Letter from Dewayne Readus to Springfield Air RendezvousItem 8509081989-10-11138Scope and ContentsRe: Funding.Correspondence, 1990Folder 145090914"Saving the John Hay Homes:  SHA has big plans to use federal grant", The State Journal-Register, Springfield, ILFolder 15509101993-12-1915Project Tenant Self-Management Proposal Narratives to CHD, ndFolder 165091116TRA Daily Log, March 1 - 28, year unknownFolder 175091217Photographs, undatedFolder 185091318PR MaterialsFolder 197554219Scope and ContentsThree posters related to the activities of the John Hay Tenants' Rights Association and a parody letter written from the perspective of city politician.Voting Rights Lawsuit, 1986-1989Series 250726Correspondence, News Articles, and Case Study ResearchFolder 1509141986-01-21 - 10-311Correspondence and News ArticlesFolder 2509151987-01-22 - 10-222Court Documents, Correspondence, and News ArticlesFolder 3509161986-19873Scope and Contents(1 of 2 Folders)
Case #85-23-65 and #87-2488.
Includes Petitions, Motions, docket entries, Orders/Decrees, Legal Fees, Memorandums, Affidavits, etc.  News articles regarding case and legal precedents.Court Documents and CorrespondenceFolder 4509171988-19894Scope and Contents(2 of 2 Folders)
Case #85-23-65 and #87-2488.
Includes Petitions, Motions, docket entries, Orders/Decrees, Legal Fees, Memorandums, Affidavits, etc.Correspondece and News ArticlesFolder 5755401986-19875Police Review Commission, 1980-1984Series 350727Correspondence and News Articles, Hoskins' DeathsFolder 1509181987-03-09 - 04-041Correspondence and News Articles, Gerald Clemons' deathFolder 2509191989-03-30 - 03-312Correspondence and News Articles, Markadee R. Kelly's deathFolder 3509201989-07-113ResearchFolder 4509211984-01-17 - 1985-06-284Scope and Contents(1 of 4 Folders) Various national news articles regarding civilian review of police activities.ResearchFolder 550923ca. 19805Scope and Contents(2 of 4 Folders)  Laws, guidelines, model legislation, and petition format.Research, ndFolder 6509246Scope and Contents(3 of 4 Folders)  Case studies.ResearchFolder 7509257Scope and ContentsBerkeley Police Review Commission:  Commissioners' Handbook.  Ordinance 4644 established a police review commission and was adopted by the people of Berkeley on April 17, 1973; subsequently amended April 15, 1975 and December 3, 1982; annotated June 9, 1976.News Articles, local and nationalFolder 8509221986-07-24 - 1992-02-058Marcus Garvey Liberation School and Malcolm X Library, 1988-2005Series 450728Correspondence and Summer School SchedulesFolder 1509261988-19891Correspondence and News ArticlesFolder 25092719892Scope and ContentsIncludes SSU Van Ban.Correspondence, Flyers, and 1994 Annual ReportFolder 3509281993-04-09 - 19963Malcolm X Children's Library &amp; Experimental Reading CenterFolder 4509311989-19934Scope and ContentsArticles of Incorporation dated 7/10/89, informational program brochures, and correspondence.Marcus Garvey Liberation School, Photographs and NegativesFolder 55092919945Scope and ContentsPhotographs of Joe Wright and friends, Dewayne Readus, Dickson Mounds field trip, Scovill Zoo trip, school group (outdoors and classroom), and camping.Marcus Garvey Freedom School, Certificates of MeritFolder 6509301989-08-116Student Papers, 1988Folder 7509327Tate, Hope.  "Summing Up the Marcus Garvey Summer School Program" (CFC 340), 1988Item 15093371Student Papers, 1992Folder 8509348Marcus Garvey Freedom School ProgramItem 15093581Scope and ContentsIntroduction, mini-biography of Marcus Garvey, list of faculty and staff, field trip schedule, list of Group I - IV teachers and students, Frederick Douglass quotation, and meal menu.Mitchell, Donna.  "Comments Regarding Students in Group II", 1992Item 25093682Unknown author.  Untitled manuscript, 1992Item 35093783Scope and ContentsRe: Challenging old thinking and beliefs in the search for truth.Unknown author.  "Save the Children!", 1992Item 45093884Unknown author.  Untitled manuscript, 1992Item 55093985Scope and ContentsRe: Experience gained from intern teaching in the Marcus Garvey Freedom School.Unknown author.  Untitled manuscript, 1992Item 65094086Scope and ContentsRe: Experience gained from intern teaching in the Marcus Garvey Freedom School.Reynolds, Mary.  "Marcus Garvey Freedom School, 1992" (CFC 340), Summer 1992Item 75094187Student Papers, 1994Folder 9509429Marcus Garvey Liberation School 1994 ProgramItem 15094391Scope and ContentsIntroduction, mini-biography of Marcus Garvey, list of faculty and staff, field trip schedule, list of Group 1 - 5 teachers and students, Carter G. Woodson quotation, and meal menu.Lathan, Gina.  "CFC Field Work 2, Marcus Garvey Summer Camp", 1994Item 25094492Johnson, Edith.  "Fieldwork II, Marcus Garvey School", Summer 1994Item 35094593McWilliams, Ann.  Untitled manuscript, 1994.Item 45094694Scope and ContentsRe:  Marcus Garvey Liberation School internship experience, and includes a weekly summary of daily activities.Student Papers, 1995Folder 105094710Marcus Garvey Liberation School 1995 Program, 10th AnniversaryItem 150948101Scope and ContentsIntroduction, mini-biography of Marcus Garvey, list of faculty and staff, camp schedule, list of Group 1 - 4 teachers and students, Frederick Douglass quotation, and Carter G. Woodson quotation.Brizendine, Chris.  "Journal Marcus Garvey School", 1995Item 250949102Brizendine, Chris.  "Marcus Garvey Liberation School 10th Anniversary, Summer 1995, Field Work I".Item 350950103Scope and ContentsIncludes list of activities and outings made during school, Summer 1995.Henry, Shexry.  "The Marcus Garvey Liberation School:  My Experience", 22 October 1995Item 450951104Scope and ContentsIncludes typewritten manuscript and handwritten journal notes.Student Papers, 2000Folder 115095211Linscott, Steve.  "Journal Entries" (CFC 513), May 2000Item 150953111Linscott, Steve.  "Summary - Social Action Project"Item 2509542000-05-11112Klotz, Nataliya.  "A journal" (CFC 513), 2000Item 350955113Scope and ContentsJournal entries for year 2000 dated 2/5, 2/11, 2/24, 3/1, 3/4, 3/11, 3/25, 4/1, 4/8, 4/14, 4/21, and 4/29.Klotz, Nataliya.  "The final paper" (CFC 513)Item 4509562000-04-30114Student Papers, 2004Folder 125095712Cerniglia, Georgianna.  "The Marcus Garvey School of Human Rights:  Curriculum Development and Facility ExpansionItem 1509582004-11121Scope and ContentsA Graduate Project Proposal, Department of Human Services, Social Service Administration.  Includes Table of Contents, manuscript draft with proofreading/editing remarks, and appendices.Correspondence, Budgets, Notes and 15th Anniversary ProgramFolder 13509591997-200013Letter from Carolyn Blackwell, President of Delta Sigma Theta Sorority, Inc., to Mbanna Kantako (a/k/a Dewayne Readus)Item 1509601997-07-23131Senseia Kankaji Human Rights Club 1997Item 250961132Scope and ContentsList of students and teachers, Groups 1A - 4B.Marcus Garvey School of Human Rights and Malcolm X Tutor Program, Annual Budget, 1997Item 350962133"Freedom Schools:  The Black Community Crusade for Children", from Children's Defense FundItem 4509631998134Memorandum from Mike Townsend to Wayne Penn, Provost, University of Illinois at SpringfieldItem 5509641999-03-26135Scope and ContentsRe: Marcus Garvey School Project.Email correspondence from Michael Townsend to UIS CampusItem 6509651999-03-25136Account Statement: Summer Youth ProgramItem 7509661999-03-31137Memorandum from Wayne Penn, Provost, UIS, to Michael TownsendItem 8509671999-04-09138Scope and ContentsRe: Marcus Garvey School Project.Memorandum from Wayne Penn, Provost, UIS, to Larry Stonecipher, Dean College of Health &amp; Human ServicesItem 9509681999-05-20139Scope and ContentsRe: Marcus Garvey School Project.Memorandum from Larry Stonecipher, Dean, and Michael Townsend, Coordinator of Marcus Garvey School Project, to Wayne Penn, Provost, UISItem 10509691999-05-241310Scope and ContentsRe: Projected Budget.Email correspondence from Candace Powers to Rebecca WilkinItem 11509701999-12-081311Scope and ContentsRe:  Youth Outreach Programs.Letter from Carolyn Blackwell, President of Delta Sigma Theta Sorority, Inc., to Mbanna Kantako (a/k/a Dewayne Readus)Item 12509712000-05-251312Scope and ContentsRe: Youth Enhancement grant.Marcus Garvey School of Human Rights Club, 15th Anniversary, 1986-2000Item 13509721313Scope and ContentsMini-biography of Marcus Garvey; Rites of Passage Program schedule; African Pledge; song verses for "Our Elders", "Respect", "We are your Children", "Uncle Sam's Slaves", "Brothas", "Raise the Fist for the Fight", "Family Reunion" (8/24/99), "P.R.I.D.E.", "Soul Fighting" (7/3/99), "Black is a State of Mind", "Marcus Garvey" (11/26/99), "When Satan Rides from Springfield" (2/8/00), "Slaves on the Run" (12/18/99), "The Yellow Brick Road" (12/11/99), "A Warrior not a Man", "Mercenaries", "2 for Human Rights" (3/2/00), "Black Within" (2/21/00), and "We Won't Take it No More"; Volunteer thank you; and Frederick Douglass quotation.Youth Outreach Program, BPS Account Level Detail ReportItem 14509732001-03-281314Letter from Mbanna Kantako to Delta Sigma Theta Sorority, Inc.Item 15509742001-05-181315Letter from Carolyn Blackwell, Chairperson Youth Enhancement Program Committee, to Mbanna KantakoItem 16509752002-03-201316Scope and ContentsRe: Youth Enhancement grant.Email correspondence from Rebecca Wilkin to Aaron Shures and Pattie SimsItem 17509762002-07-011317Scope and ContentsRe: Marcus Garvey School, etc.Form letter from Mike Townsend, Project Manager, to DonorItem 18509772004-20051318Scope and ContentsRe: Charitable donation of books, audio and visual materials for sale to benefit the Marcus Garvey School, includes an estimated value of donation for tax purposes.Flyer, "Pig Out!  SSU Tutor Program Used Book and LP Sale!!", ndItem 19509781319Flyer, "Malcolm X Children's Library, Charity Book Sale", ndItem 20509791320Poster, The Malcolm X Children's Library and Experimental Reading Center, Springfield, Illinois, Liberation Summer 1993Folder 145098214VHS and Audiocassette Recordings and 35mm SlidesSeries 55072935mm Slides, Marcus Garvey School at Goat Barn, ndItem 1507231Tearing Down John Hay: Last View of John HayDVD 175541November 23, 1996Van BanAudiotape 1509801989-08SSU News, Van BanAudiotape 2509811990-04Marcus Garvey 17th Graduation, 2002Videotape 150719Malcolm X LibraryVideotape 2507201994-10-18Scope and ContentsPainting.Malcolm X LibraryVideotape 3507211994-11-01Scope and ContentsPainting.Marcus Garvey School, Brookens Auditorium, ndVideotape 450722Scope and Contents"Rites of Passage"

