<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.73Archon Finding Aid Title MC.73UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:44:04 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC73. Chicago Area Project Records, 1935-1980
    
      Chicago Area Project
    
    
      Shaw, Clifford R.
    
    
      Sorrentino, Anthony
    
    
      McKay, Henry D.
    
    
      Illinois Institute for Juvenile Research
    
    
      Illinois Youth Commission
    
    MC.73
    81
    
      2.00 Cubic Feet
    
    1935-1980
    Date acquired: 00/00/1988
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Organization founded on Chicago's North Side in 1932 to reduce juvenile delinquency through community committees, governed and operated by neighborhood residents rather than outside agencies. Administration, research and field work for the project was conducted by professionals, including Clifford R. Shaw, Anthony Sorrentino, Henry D. McKay, and staff members of the Illinois Institute for Juvenile Research and the Illinois Youth Commission. The files includes annual reports of the project, data books and activity reports of community committees, programs, and research reports on juvenile delinquency, drug abuse, and crime. Also includes the memoirs of a "petty con man" written ca. 1935, and photocopies of articles concerning juvenile delinquency and the Chicago Area Project.  
  
    Arrangement Note
By subject  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Mike Townsend  
  
    Records
  
  Box 1Box 19393Community Committees Data Books, Annual ReportsFolder 193941949-19541Community Committees Data Books, Annual ReportsFolder 293951945, 1959-19612Community Committees Data Books, Annual ReportsFolder 393961961-1965, 19683Community Committees, Summary of ActivitiesFolder 493971967-19704Programs for dinners held at Near Northwest Side, North West Side and Mangini Youth Centers in ChicagoFolder 593981975-19765"My Life as a Petty Con Man by E.M."Folder 69399ca. 19356"Criminal Careers of Former Juvenile Delinquents"Folder 79400ca. 19357"The Area Project" (History of Chicago Area Project after 10 Years)Folder 894011943-11-098"Drug Addiction among Young Persons in Chicago"Folder 994021953-109Reports on the Chicago Area Project from the U.S. Senate Committee on the JudiciaryFolder 109403196010Illinois Youth Commission, Division of Community Services, Cook County Unit--Staff ConferenceFolder 1194041965-10-2011McKay, Henry D., ed.: Subsequent Arrests, Convictions, and Commitments among Juvenile DelinquentsFolder 129405196712Sorrentino, Anthony: "How to Organize the Neighborhood for Delinquency Prevention"Folder 139406197613Haffron, Dennis: "Early Years of the Chicago Area Project on the Northside"Folder 149407197614Ostrander, Lee: The Gauntlet for the Little BastardsFolder 159408198015Reference Articles (photocopies)Folder 1694091925-196416Reference Articles (photocopies)Folder 1794101959-1970s17Juvenile Delinquency Research (photocopies)Folder 1894111930s-1970s18Juvenile Delinquency Research (photocopies)Folder 1994121940s-1970s19Juvenile Delinquency Research (photocopies)Folder 2094131960s-1970s20Box 2Box 29414An Overview of the Chicago Area ProjectFolder 194151Brochures for the Chicago Area ProjectFolder 294162Brief History of the Chicago Federation of Community CommitteesFolder 394173Community Committees—Members and Officers 1974Folder 4941819754Chicago Area Project Board of DirectorsFolder 594191973-19805"Relationship of Chicago Area Project and Community Committees"Folder 694206Working Agreement between Illinois Youth Commission and Chicago Area Projects and Community CommitteesFolder 794217Suggested by-laws for a neighborhood committeeFolder 894228Constitution and by-laws of the Chicago Federation of Community CommitteesFolder 994239Brochures describing different Community CommitteesFolder 10942410Financial Statements for Trumbull Park Community CommitteeFolder 11942511Loscutio, Joseph: "The Mid North Story"Folder 129426196112Raymond, Ray: "The Near North Story"Folder 139427194813Beatrice Caffrey Youth Services, Inc—programs 1974-75, President's annual reportFolder 149428197414Shaw, Clifford R: excerpts from "Methods, Accomplishments, and Problems of the Chicago Area Project"Folder 159429194415Short, James F. Jr.: "The Chicago Area Project as a Social Movement"Folder 169430196916Articles relating to the Chicago Area ProjectFolder 17943117Korbin, Solomon: "The Chicago Area Project-A 25 Year Assessment"Folder 189432195918"Questions and Answers regarding the Chicago Area Project"Folder 19943319Information about Clifford ShawFolder 20943420Morris, Henry: Masters Degree Graduation Project "The Chicago Area Project"Folder 21943521Correspondence of Ray RaymondFolder 2294361950s-1980s22Schlossman, Steven and Sedlak, Michael: "The Chicago Area Project Revisited"Folder 2394371983-0123Report of Division of Community Services Cook County Unit Illinois Youth CommissionFolder 2494381963-07-01 - 1964-11-2024News clippings-ChicagoFolder 2594391969, 197425Correspondence and news clippingsFolder 26944026Scope and ContentsMerger of Chicago Area Project with the Department of Children and Family ServicesAgreement for SSU to begin an Oral History of the Chicago Area ProjectFolder 27944127Finding Aid for Chicago Area Project collection at the Chicago Historical SocietyFolder 28944228"Some Area Project Assumptions Concerning the Causes of Delinquent Behavior in Low Income Areas"Folder 29944329Youth in Trouble-Overall StatisticsFolder 30944430Tunley, Roul: excerpts from Kids, Crime and ChaosFolder 319445196231Flyer for the First National Conference on Delinquency PreventionFolder 329446197532Delinquency prevention articlesFolder 33944733Dinitz, Simon: "Nothing fails like success"Folder 349448197734Delinquency prevention organizationsFolder 35944935Correspondence of Mike Townsend—Chicago Area Project and Illinois Commission on Delinquency PreventionFolder 3694501970s36Illinois Commission on Delinquency Prevention—founding informationFolder 37945137Slane, Edna H.: Report on Commission on Delinquency PreventionFolder 38945238Staff Directory of Illinois Commissions on Delinquency PreventionFolder 39945339Commission on Delinquency Prevention BudgetFolder 4094541980-198140Illinois Commission on Delinquency Prevention-Grants-in-aid programFolder 41945541Illinois Commission on Delinquency Prevention Monthly Narrative Report, Region IV QuincyFolder 4294561976-1242A Survey of Social Problems in Springfield, ILFolder 439457196543Legislation regarding delinquency prevention—national and stateFolder 44945844Short, James F. Jr.: "Life History, Autobiography, and the Life Cycle"Folder 45945945Democratic and Republican platformsFolder 469460198046Tomaino, Louis: "The Five Face of Probation"Folder 47946147Press ReleasesFolder 489462ca. 198048Quincy history and history of the Quincy Area ProjectFolder 49946349Quincy Area Project – Neighborhood NewsFolder 5094641976-198250Scope and Contents(Incomplete)Correspondence of the Quincy Area ProjectFolder 5194651970s-1980s51News clippings—The Quincy Area ProjectFolder 5294661970s52National Center for Neighborhood EnterpriseFolder 53946753Townsend, Michael: "Community Organization and Delinquency Diversion"Folder 54946854Letters, Articles pertaining to drugs and delinquencyFolder 55946955Bibliography on Narcotics and Drug Abuse Illinois Department of CorrectionsFolder 569470197156Its an Inside Job: CorrespondenceFolder 5775543197557Scope and ContentsLetters from Mike Townsend dealing with the subject of the book, Its an Inside Job: Crime Control by Community Organization on Chicago's New West Side.Its an Inside Job: Intro-Chapter 4Folder 5875544197458Its an Inside Job: Chapter 5-Chapter 8Folder 5975545197459Its an Inside Job: Chapter 9-Chapter 10Folder 6075546197460Anthony Sorrentino Book Chapters: Chapter 2-3Folder 617554761Scope and ContentsChapter from a book on youth and delinquency by Anthony Sorrentino. Chapter 2 and 3 are entitled Youth in American Society and Delinquency Ares respectively.Murial Runyen Chapter Ten: Public Relations and PublicityFolder 627554862Scope and ContentsChapter from a book written by Murial Runyen on public relations.

