<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.77Archon Finding Aid Title MC.77UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:44:15 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC77. Nelson O. Howarth Papers, 1944-1989
    
      Howarth, Nelson O.
    
    MC.77
    85
    
      2.33 Cubic Feet
    
    1944-1989
    Date acquired: 00/00/1994
  
  
    MC77. Nelson O. Howarth photograph: 1964
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Papers of Nelson Howarth, Assistant State's Attorney for Sangamon County, Illinois 1948-1949, Mayor of Springfield 1955-1959 and 1963-1971. Born in Green County, Indiana and raised on farms in Illinois, he received a law degree from the University of Illinois in 1934 and was an attorney in private practice when not in public office. 

Correspondence, transcripts of speeches and radio broadcasts, court records, clippings, photographs, brochures, programs and memorabilia documenting Howarth's activities combating vice as Assistant State's Attorney, his mayoral campaigns, and his efforts as Mayor to promote civil rights and develop the recreational facilities and historical sites of Springfield. 

As Mayor, Howarth championed civil rights and impartial law enforcement. He strove to integrate the police department, fire department, municipal band and choir. Howarth urged the annexation of Springfield suburban developments, and added 10,000 acres to the city during his terms. Under his leadership, the city expanded Capital Airport, built the Prairie Convention Center, and added Riverside Park and Lincoln Greens Golf Course to the park system. He also played active roles in the restoration of the Old State Capitol, the establishment of Sangamon State University, and the creation of the Lincoln Home National Historic Site. 

Also included are memorabilia of  Howarth's service during WWII on the U.S.S. Lexington, 1944-1945, including a copy of the ship's log and his letters home to Mrs. Howarth. Also published statements, briefs, arguments and abstracts presented by Howarth before the Illinois Supreme Court, 1950, 1953. 

Of note are photos, clippings and other material relating to the visit of Martin Luther King to Springfield, October 7, 1965.  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological &amp; Topical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Mrs. Nelson Howarth  
  
    Method of Acquisition
Addition made 2/28/2011 by Phyllis Eubanks (copies of speeches)  
  
    Papers
  
  Box 1Box 11190U.S.S. Lexington, Log and MemorabiliaFolder 111911944-45, 19711U.S.S. Lexington Log (photocopy)Item 111921945-10-25 - 1945-12-1511Photocopy re Commander Thomas Anthony AhroonItem 2119312Howarth's notes re actions of U.S.S. LexingtonItem 3119413Correspondence with Rep. Paul Findley re copying of Lexington log at National ArchivesItem 41195197114Letters to Mrs. HowarthFolder 211961945-04-082Scope and ContentsPage 2 onlyLetters of Congratulation and of AppreciationFolder 3119719553Scope and Contents1 of 4Letters of Congratulation and of AppreciationFolder 4119819554Scope and Contents2 of 4Letters of Congratulation and of AppreciationFolder 5119919555Scope and Contents3 of 4Letters of Congratulation and of AppreciationFolder 6120019556Scope and Contents4 of 4Mayoral Election BrochuresFolder 712011955-19667Scope and Contents"It's Time for Action!," "Springfield On Target!," "Lets Light Up Our Streets"Layout and estimate for new streetlights on Courthouse	Square in SpringfieldFolder 8120219558Scope and ContentsBy Dean WislederCorrespondenceFolder 9120319569Scope and Contents1 of 2CorrespondenceFolder 101204195610Scope and Contents2 of 2LettersFolder 1112051952-195811Howarth to William F. DonohueItem 112061952-01-18111Scope and Contentsre Republican politics in Thornton Township, Bloom Township, and Cook CountyJohn E. Grosboll to Senator Everett M. DirksenItem 212071952-12-23112Scope and Contentsre Recommendation of Howarth for U.S. District Attorney for the Southern District of Illinois.Howarth to Nina TempleItem 312081953-09-04113Scope and Contentsre Daughter Susan at U of I.O.J. Keller to HowarthItem 412091955-01-24114Scope and Contentsre Sewer ProgramHowarth to O.J. KellerItem 512101955-02-05115Scope and Contentsre Sewer ProgramHowarth to J. E. BohnItem 612111956-04-20116Scope and Contentsre Springfield Sewer Bond IssueHowarth to Milton D. FriedlandItem 712121958-01-14117Scope and Contentsre WICS-TV public service program "Your Council Reports".Robert A. Campbell to HowarthItem 812131958-02-25118Scope and Contentsre To appear on a panel 8 March 1958 "Youth Wants to Know" discussing youth driving.Letters of Congratulation and of AppreciationFolder 1212141956-195812Scope and ContentsIncludes photocopy of letter from Senator Edward Kennedy, 1968.Letters, Clippings, Speeches, MemosFolder 1312151957-198713Scope and Contents1 of 2Citizens for EisenhowserItem 11216131Scope and ContentsLetterheadNews Release on Closing of Three Midway Games at the State FairItem 21217132Scope and ContentsPhotocopyClippingsItem 312181956-1957133Scope and Contents"Mayor Howarth-Lists Accomplishments of City During 1956"; "Springfield Among Seven Safer Cities," (2 photocopies).Howarth to Bishop Wm J. O'ConnorItem 412191957-12-19134Scope and Contentsre in reference to letter and holiday greetingsSection of Illinois State JournalItem 512201957-04-30135Scope and Contents"Building for a Greater Springfield: Your City Council Reports, April 1955-April 1957""Boy Scout Day"Item 612211958-02-10136Scope and ContentsPhotograph with Scout Mayor Steve Kwedar, his Council and Appointed Officials.Ed Morrison to HowarthItem 712221958-11-21137Scope and Contentsre Announcement for Municipal ElectionGolf Course Certificate DonorsItem 81223138Scope and ContentsOriginal and 2 photocopiesLincoln Greens Certificate HoldersItem 912241963-01-02139Scope and ContentsPhotocopyJohn Hunter to HowarthItem 1012251963-06-241310Scope and Contentsre Lake SpringfieldHowarth to John HunterItem 1112261963-06-271311Scope and Contentsre Lake SpringfieldClippingItem 1212271963-07-071312Scope and ContentsChicago's American, "Politician, Honest-That's Mayor Howarth," (2 photocopies).Robert Stuart to HowarthItem 1312281963-09-131313Scope and Contentsre Carpenter ParkHowarth to Robert StuartItem 1412291963-09-171314Scope and Contentsre Carpenter ParkHowarth to Charles L. LockbaumItem 1512301963-11-121315Scope and Contentsre River LandsIrvin Smith to City CouncilItem 1612311964-04-281316Scope and Contentsre Swimming PoolsHowarth to Robert HarrisItem 1712321964-04-301317Scope and Contentsre Swimming PoolsHowarth to William McKuneItem 1812331964-04-301318Scope and Contentsre Swimming PoolsHowarth to E.J.D'AboyItem 1912341964-05-221319Scope and Contentsre Swimming PoolsHowarth to Irvin SmithItem 2012351964-05-251320Scope and Contentsre Swimming PoolsSection of Illinois State JournalItem 2112361964-11-251321Scope and Contents"Capital of Lincolnland: Your City Council Report"Howarth to Herschel MooreItem 2212371965-11-031322Scope and Contentsre Advisory Committee Lincoln Greens Golf CourseHowarth to Dr. W.C. TelfordItem 2312381965-11-081323Scope and Contentsre Advisory Committee Lincoln Greens Golf CourseHowarth to Charles L. LockbaumItem 2412391965-11-301324Scope and Contentsre Advisory Committee Lincoln Greens Golf CourseHowarth to Members of Lincoln Greens Advisory CommitteeItem 2512401966-01-191325Scope and Contentsre Organization of the CommitteeSpeechItem 2612411966-09-221326Scope and Contents"Eulogy of DeWitt S. Crow, Judge, Emeritus, Sangamon County Circuit Court"ClippingsItem 2712421967-01-151327Scope and ContentsJournal, Campaign HeadquartersClippingsItem 2812431967-02-191328Scope and ContentsSpringfield Sun, Primary Returns"Resolution Pledging Complete Economic, Civic, and Local Government Support for Program Establishing Downstate Senior College in Springfield Area"Item 2912441967-04-181329Howarth to Dr. Byron WeisbaumItem 3012451967-12-191330Scope and Contentsre Swimming PoolsPress ReleaseItem 3112461968-02-291331Scope and Contentsre Parking MetersIrv Smith to Pool CommitteeItem 321247ca. 19681332Scope and Contentsre Swimming PoolsHowarth to Ralph HirwitzItem 3312481968-06-061333Scope and Contentsre Swimming PoolsHowarth to Marshall Field IVItem 3412491968-06-061334Scope and Contentsre Newspaper story on Illinois Crime Commission Hearings in SpringfieldSpeechItem 3512501968-12-031335Scope and Contents"Remarks Made by Mayor Nelson Howarth on the Occasion of Dedicating Old State Capitol"ClippingsItem 361251ca. 19701336Scope and Contents"11 in Powell's Office After Death"ClippingsItem 371252ca. 19701337Scope and Contents"Uncashed Checks Add to Powell Mystery," photocopyClippingsItem 38125319711338Scope and ContentsAlumnus of the Month for U of I, photocopyCitation of Appreciation to Howarth from Senior Citizens Commission of SpringfieldItem 3912541971-02-181339ClippingsItem 401255ca. 19711340Scope and ContentsSecretaries of the Mayor; Tribute to Howarth (2 copies)SpeechItem 4112561971-04-101341Scope and Contents"Valedictory Prophecies of the Springfield of 2021 A.D.," by Howarth"Speech by Mayor Nelson Howarth on the Occasion of Sangamon County Historical Society Celebration of Springfield's 150 Anniversary"Item 4212571971-04-101342WMAY EditorialItem 4312581971-04-151343Scope and Contentsre Retirement of Mayor HowarthAmerican Society for Public Administration Central Illinois Chapter Distinguished Service AwardItem 4412591971-05-251344Scope and ContentsAwarded to Nelson HowarthRetirement as Mayor, rough draft of speechItem 451260ca. 1971-041345Letters, Clippings, Speeches, MemosFolder 1412611957-198714Scope and Contents2 of 2Newspaper Focus #4Item 11262ca. 1970-71141Scope and Contents"An Interview with Howarth: The Anatomy of a Liberal"; "...The Good Old Days," (3 copies)Concession Speech - Mayoral ElectionItem 212631975-04142FlyerItem 31264ca. 1974-1975143Scope and Contents"Elect Nelson Howarth"Howarth to A.W. Banton Jr.Item 412651976-03-12144Scope and Contentsre Fixing Sidewalks in Front of OfficeClippingItem 51266ca. 1986145Scope and Contents"An Obituary Brought to Life: Louis Schwartz 1893-1986," (photocopy).Howarth to publicItem 612671987-10146Scope and Contentsre Recommendation of Ossie Langfelder for Mayor, 3 copiesOssie Langfelder to Howarth and MaryItem 712681987-10-28147Scope and Contentsre Campaign and ElectionHowarth to publicItem 812691987-11148Scope and Contentsre Election of Ossie LangfelderHowarth to O.C. LangfelderItem 912701987-10-17149Scope and Contentsre Springfield Housing and Redevelopment ProgramsHowarth to Joe FlechterItem 1012711987-12-161410Scope and Contentsre Oral History of HowarthHowarth to The Springfield HeraldItem 1112721988-04-201411Scope and Contentsre The Reported Disrespect for "Old Glory"Howarth to Richard DurbinItem 1212731989-05-021412Scope and Contentsre Japanese, Potsdam Declaration of 1945 and their help with U.S. military aircraft constructionHarvey L. Davis Jr. to Mrs. HowarthItem 1312741993-11-171413Scope and Contentsre Gratitude of Mr. Howarth, (original and photocopy)Lawsuit on Commission Form of GovernmentItem 141275ca. 19871414Things to be DoneItem 1512761415Things to be Done by NOHItem 1612771416"Development of the City of Springfield by NOH During the Period 1955-1971" and "Items to be Developed for Publication by NOH."Item 1712781417"Special Improvements in the Civil Rights of Negroes Completed by Mayor Nelson Howarth During His Term in Office Beginning April 1955 and Ending April 1971 - (All of These are Firsts)."Item 1812791418"Statement of Mayor Nelson Howarth in reply to Statement of John Clarke, Publisher Illinois State Journal-Registar."Item 1912801419ClippingItem 2012811420Scope and ContentsIllinois Times, "Facing Springfield's Upcoming Garbage Crunch""My Memories of Early Days of Springfield Jaycees"Item 2112821421Scope and ContentsOne page onlyClippings from the Chicago Sun-TimesFolder 1512831959-03-0115Scope and Contentsre wife-beating rumor circulated by supporters of Lester CollinsCorrespondenceFolder 1612841955-198616Howarth to Carl KrampItem 112851955-05-18161Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal BandHowarth to Louis HahnItem 212861955-05-21162Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal BandHowarth to Theodore SchlittItem 312871955-05-23163Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal BandHowarth to C. Leo ShaughnessyItem 412881955-05-23164Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal BandHowarth to Joseph WilsonItem 512891955-05-23165Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal BandHowarth to Mrs. James P. BollingerItem 612901955-05-24166Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal BandHowarth to Mark HobbsItem 712911955-05-24167Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal Band integrationMark Hobbs to HowarthItem 812921955-05-21168Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal Band integrationHowarth to Louis HahnItem 912931955-05-31169Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal BandMemo for FileItem 1012941955-06-081610Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal Band integrationHowarth to Louis HahnItem 1112951955-07-211611Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal Band integrationHowarth to Louis HahnItem 1212961955-07-271612Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal BandHowarth to Louis HahnItem 1312971955-08-021613Scope and ContentsLetters Re Songs for the Springfield Municipal BandHowarth to Louis HahnItem 1412981955-07-041614Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal BandHowarth to F. Keith NelchItem 1512991955-07-121615Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal BandHowarth to Mark HobbsItem 1613001956-03-021616Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal BandHowarth to Lou HahnItem 1713011956-03-211617Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal Band budgetCal Bolinger to Jack WicksItem 1813021956-04-101618Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal BandCal Bolinger to Charles HustonItem 1913031956-04-101619Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal BandHowarth to Lou HahnItem 2013041956-04-301620Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal Band rehersalsHowarth to Lou HahnItem 2113051956-07-131621Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal BandHowarth to Charles H. MiddenItem 2213061956-08-061622Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal BandCharles H. Midden to HowarthItem 2313071956-08-021623Scope and ContentsLetters Re Springfield Municipal BandHowarth to John M. SmithItem 2413081957-11-181624Scope and Contentsre Police Department (2nd page only)Howarth to Whom It May ConcernItem 2513091955-12-161625Scope and Contentsre Arthur M. and Nellie D. FitzgeraldHowarth to Whom It May ConcernItem 2613101955-12-161626Scope and Contentsre Arthur M. and Nellie D. FitzgeraldAlbert A. Chambers to HowarthItem 27131105-311627Scope and Contentsre knee injury"Statement by Nelson Howarth, Mayor of Springfield"Item 2813121964-01-161628Scope and Contentsre Declining to run for Illinois Secretary of StateHowarth to Harvard Club of BostonItem 2913131966-06-131629Scope and Contentsre billHowarth to Paul FindleyItem 3013141966-10-261630Scope and Contentsre HR-51 preservation of the Indiana DunesSpeechItem 3113151968-05-021631Scope and Contents"Statement by Mayor Nelson Howarth at Press Conference"Press ReleaseItem 3213161971-04-051632Scope and Contentsre restoration of Lincoln Home Area; map of Lincoln Area; statement by Howarth to Sub-Committee on National Parks and Recreation, House of Representatives on restoration of Lincoln AreaJ. Michael Houston to HowarthItem 3313171986-08-201633Scope and Contentsre radio talk on "What Happened to the Municipal Swimming Pool?"Committeemen Precincts to Corneal A. DavisItem 3413181959-03-031634Scope and Contentsre Race Opportunities in Springfield; Support of HowarthHowarth to The Loveable Brassiere Co.Item 3513191955-12-211635Scope and Contentsre not concerning the Mayor's office"Survey of Commercialized Prostitution Conditions"Item 3613201970-051636Charles David Maley to HowarthItem 3713211966-10-111637Scope and Contentsre Appreciation of Eulogy of DeWitt S. CrowJoan Hancock to HowarthItem 3813221638Scope and Contentsre pamphlet"Statement by Former Mayor Nelson Howarth..."Folder 1713231962-12-1817Scope and ContentsAnnouncement of Candidacy"Much Ado About Something Or Let Them Come Unto Me and Suffer"Folder 18132418Scope and ContentsCollected Literary References to Lawyers"Subjects I Desire to Write and Develop"Folder 19132519Scope and ContentsList of topicsCorrespondence and ClippingsFolder 201326196420Scope and ContentsTrip to Peru sponsored by the United America Committee for Better Hemispheric                         Understanding (1 of 3).Correspondence and ClippingsFolder 211327196421Scope and ContentsTrip to Peru sponsored by the United America Committee for Better Hemispheric                         Understanding (2 of 3).Correspondence and ClippingsFolder 221328196422Scope and ContentsTrip to Peru sponsored by the United America Committee for Better Hemispheric                         Understanding (3 of 3).Peru Trip, Photos and Map of LimaFolder 231329196423Scope and ContentsIllinois Municipal Review, article re Peru trip.Development of Lincoln Home and EnvironsFolder 2413301963-197124Abraham Lincoln AssociationFolder 2513311964, 1965, 196725Scope and ContentsBanquet ProgramsLetters and MemosFolder 2613321964-196826Howarth to Avis Rent-A-Car CompanyItem 113331964-03-23261Scope and Contentsre Car rentalHowarth to George E. DrachItem 213341964-03-29262Scope and Contentsre Springfield as a Capital CityWalter L. Oblinger to HowarthItem 313351964-05-26263Scope and Contentsre Taxation of Radio and TelevisionHowarth to Sgt. Hobart RogersItem 413361964-06-03; 1964-05-22264Scope and Contentsre Swimming Pool Program; with attached letter: Silver Suarez to Howarth, 22 May 1964, re Swimming Pool Program.Howarth to All CommissionersItem 513371964-10-21265Scope and Contentsre Equal Opportunities Act-Neighborhood Youth CorpsHowarth to Jack HowardItem 613381964-09-25266Scope and Contentsre Equal Opportunities Act-Neighborhood Youth CorpsHowarth to Commissioner John H. HunterItem 713391964-10-01267Scope and Contentsre One million gallon water storage tankHowarth to All Council Members and Bradley B. TaylorItem 813401964-12-01268Scope and Contentsre neighborhood Urban Renewal ProjectsRex M. Whitton to HowarthItem 913411965-12-14269Scope and Contentsre Proposed rerouting of Interstate Highway 55Howarth to John N. PearceItem 1013421966-04-092610Scope and Contentsre Old Illinois StatehouseHowarth to Karl F. Heimke, Mayor of WheatonItem 1113431966-10-052611Scope and Contentsre Fair Housing OrdinanceKarl F. Heimke to HowarthItem 1213441966-09-282612Scope and Contentsre Fair Housing OrdinanceDraft Letter to the People of Country Club Acres and Adjacent AreaItem 1313451967-022613Howarth to Ruth G. ShechterItem 1413461967-06-232614Scope and Contentsre Civil Rights provisions and open housing ordinance; Dr. Joseph H. Albrecht and Farries Morrison re Human Relation pamphlet.Howarth to FileItem 1513471967-07-262615Scope and Contentsre 25 July 1967 meeting on Civil Rights-Human Relations problemsHowarth to All Members of Historical Sites CommissionItem 1613481967-08-252616Scope and Contentsre Historic Homes of SpringfieldHowarth to Charles MiddenItem 1713491967-09-252617Scope and Contentsre Police UnionHowarth to Herschel MooreItem 1813501967-10-192618Scope and Contentsre Urban Beautification ProgramsHowarth to Robert L. MurphyItem 1913511967-11-092619Scope and Contentsre Ice skating Facility, Winterland ArenaRobert L. Murphy to HowarthItem 2013521967-11-072620Scope and Contentsre Winterland ArenaHowarth to Dr. Joseph H. AlbrechtItem 2113531967-11-092621Scope and Contentsre CommitteeHowarth to Robert A. Stuart and Allen PryorItem 2213541968-03-022622Scope and Contentsre Public golf courseHowarth to Commissioners Cellini, Dunham, Hunter and KnoxItem 2313551968-01-022623Scope and Contentsre Special Assessment BondsHowarth to Herschel MooreItem 2413561968-04-192624Scope and Contentsre Recreation for Youth of SpringfieldHowarth to Steve KoskyItem 2513571968-06-212625Scope and Contentsre Third Street ParkingInscriptionsItem 2613581967-19682626Scope and ContentsFor Hon. Ramsey Clark and Hon. Charles Evers, 8 Feb 1968; Cooper T. Holt, 11 Feb 1968; Mrs. Marjorie Merriweather Post, March 1967; Hon. Michael J. Howlett, 11 Apr 1967; Hon. Mark O. Hatfield, 27 Nov 1967.Irv Smith and Frank England to VotersItem 2713592627Scope and Contentsre Re-elect Howarth; recommendationsMartin Luther King in SpringfieldFolder 2713601965-10-0727Scope and ContentsPhotos, Clippings, Speech delivered at AFL-CIO convention at the Armory; Howarth's comments on King's assassination, 1969; Pure-News issue on King Jan 1989.Ordinances and Resolutions prohibiting racial discrimination in housing in SpringfieldFolder 2813611965-196728Journal Editorial and WTAX Editorial on Lincoln HomeFolder 291362196729Lincoln Home Historic SiteFolder 3013631967-197130Scope and ContentsCorrespondence re National Park Service, HUD, CongressLetters to Howarth from Significant PeopleFolder 3113641966-197131Scope and ContentsPhotocopiesA.L. Sargent to HowarthItem 113651963-12-04311Scope and Contentsre Illinois Municipal League Committee to study the feasibility of training for police recruitsR.G. Soderstrom to HowarthItem 213661965-10-13312Scope and Contentsre Picture of the "Key to the City" presentation to Dr. Martin Luther King; Civil RightsHubert H. Humphrey to HowarthItem 313671966-12-12313Scope and Contentsre Holiday GreetingsReverend William Edward Krueger to HowarthItem 413681968-10-12314Scope and Contentsre Howarth as MayorAdolph H. Lubin to HowarthItem 513691968-09-24315Scope and Contentsre Admiration and respect, duties as Mayor, report to the people "The Problem in Justice-Not Law and Order"Ivan R. Levin to HowarthItem 613701968-09-25316Scope and Contentsre Radio talk programAbraham L. Marovitz to HowarthItem 713711969-02-13317Scope and Contentsre Abraham Lincoln Association Dinner, 12 Feb 1969Chief Justice Warren to HowarthItem 813721969-06-27318Scope and Contentsre Howarth's letter on Warren's retirementDenny M. Kelley to HowarthItem 913731969-12-30319Scope and Contentsre PlazasWilliam S. Foster to Carrol C. HallItem 1013741970-01-153110Scope and Contentsre Howarth; Mayor's/City Manager's dutiesLydon to HowarthItem 1113751970-01-243111Scope and Contentsre Compliments HowarthPaul M. Angle to HowarthItem 121376ca. 19713112Scope and Contentsre Radio talks and retirementJ.W. Peltason to HowarthItem 1313771971-02-093113Scope and Contentsre "Alumnus of the Month", Feb 1971, University of Illinois, College of Law.J.A.O. Preus to HowarthItem 1413781971-05-103114Scope and Contentsre Success and happinessAlan J. Dixon to HowarthItem 1513791971-05-203115Scope and Contentsre Howarth returning to law practicePaul Findley to HowarthItem 1613801971-07-193116Scope and Contentsre Passage of H.R. 9798 billFarewell Speeches, Other Speeches, Radio Talks for Special OccasionsFolder 3213811963-197132"The Republican Party and the Future," Republican Women's Luncheon ClubItem 113821963-08-07321Scope and ContentsSpeech outlineSpeech by Howarth in Presenting a Key to the City to Charles E. Becker in recognition of his civic contributions to the Springfield CommunityItem 213831964322"Springfield's Interstate Highway Problems"Item 313841965-08-29323Scope and Contents4 min. radio broadcastInvitation to dedicate a plaque for Lincoln Greens Golf Course from The Playground and Recreation CommissionItem 413851966-06-05324"Railroad Blockades"Item 513861966-07-17325Scope and Contents4 min. radio broadcast"Let's Light Up Our Streets"Item 613871966-05-15326Scope and Contents4 min. radio talkSpeech for The Federal Union 1966 Convocation DinnerItem 713881966-06-11327Scope and ContentsPresentation of Keys to the City to the principal speaker, Prime Minister, Leslie B. Pearson, CanadaRough draft of The Federal Union 1966 Convocation Dinner speechItem 813891966-06-11328Speech Testimonial Dinner for HowarthItem 913901967-01-07329"The Mayor's Role in Our Commission Government"Item 1013911967-01-213210Scope and ContentsTV and radio talk"Accomplishments, 1963-67 City Council"Item 1113921967-01-243211Scope and ContentsTV and radio talk; partial copy of 28 Jan 1967, TV and radio talk.TV and Radio speechItem 1213931967-02-133212Scope and Contentsre Re-electionTV and Radio talkItem 1313941967-03-173213Scope and Contentsre Re-electionTV and Radio talkItem 1413951967-03-223214Scope and Contentsre Re-electionTV and Radio talkItem 1513961967-03-293215Scope and Contentsre Re-electionWelcoming Remarks by HowarthItem 1613971968-10-203216Scope and ContentsFor the dedication of V.Y. Dallman Power Plant"Catalog of a Career in Municipal Government"Item 1713981971-03-253217Scope and ContentsRadio talkFarewell Speech to the City Council as MayorItem 1813991971-04-063218Howarth Testimonial DinnerFolder 3314001967-01-0733Scope and ContentsPlans and ProgramCorrespondenceFolder 3414011967-196934Scope and ContentsHuman Relations Commission, Civil Rights Matters, etc.Re-Opening Performance at Ford's Theatre, Washington D.C.Folder 3514021968-01-3035Scope and ContentsProgramClipping and TelegramFolder 3614031968-0136Scope and ContentsState Crime Investigation of Gambling in Springfield and Sangamon County"For Illinois 1968"Folder 37140437Scope and ContentsSesquicentennial Poem by Gwendolyn Brooks (2 copies, Autographed)Letter from Nelson RockefellerFolder 3814051968-08-2038Scope and ContentsPhotocopyLetter from Louise A. MeyerFolder 3914061968-09-2539Scope and Contentsre George WallaceProgramFolder 4014071968-10-0540Scope and ContentsIllinois Sesquicentennial Mansion Benefit DinnerPersonal CorrespondenceFolder 4114081969-197141Scope and ContentsCourtesy letters and routine personal businessMartin Luther King Memorial Service and EulogyFolder 4214091969-04-1342Correspondence and ClippingsFolder 431410197043Scope and ContentsAll-American City AwardNews ReleasesFolder 4414111967-11; 1971-0444Scope and Contentsre Lincoln Home Area and Model Cities ProgramBookletFolder 451412197145Scope and Contents"Tour of Historic Springfield"J. Krohe Tribute on Howarth's Retirement from OfficeFolder 461413197146Abraham Lincoln AssociationFolder 471414197247Scope and ContentsLetter and Minutes of 1972 MeetingEncomium, Springfield United Churchmen's Prayer FellowshipFolder 4814151972-0548Condemnation of Fitzpatrick Property (near Lincoln Home); Howarth's ProtestsFolder 491416197549Campaign Announcements and EndorsementsFolder 501417197550Race Relations in SpringfieldFolder 511418ca. 198551Scope and ContentsAnecdotes and ReflectionsMayor Nelson Howarth Radio Talk on WMAYFolder 5257247January 18, 196852Statement by Mayor Nelson Howarth at Press ConferenceFolder 5357248May 2, 196853Box 2Box 21419Memo form Mayor HoustonFolder 114201981-121Scope and Contentsre Open Meeting ActProgramsFolder 214211984; 1986; 19892Scope and ContentsMartin Luther King Memorial BreakfastLetter from Senator DixonFolder 314221986-093Scope and Contentsre NicaraguaAbstract of Deposition on Civil Rights in SpringfieldFolder 414231986-08-074Scope and ContentsUncertifiedCertified Abstract of Deposition on Civil Rights in SpringfieldFolder 514241986-08-175Letter to Carlos Romero-Barcelo, Former-Governor of Puerto RicoFolder 6142519876Capital Airport Adviser (Souvenir Issue)Folder 714261987-11-027The Weekend JournalFolder 814271988-10-218Scope and ContentsCover story on HowarthLettersFolder 914281987-19889"The Challenge of a New Form of Government"Item 11429198791Scope and Contentsre Endorsement of Ossie Langfelder as Springfield MayorHowarth to Helen HornItem 214301987-10-1692Scope and Contentsre Horn's propertyPaul Simon to Mary W. HowarthItem 314311988-03-2193Scope and Contentsre Presidential contributionNews ClippingsFolder 101432198910Document FragmentsFolder 111433198911Howarth Obituary, Journal-RegisterFolder 1214341991-10-1712Supreme Court of the State of IllinoisFolder 131435195013Scope and ContentsPublished Statements, Briefs, Arguments and Abstracts (two books)Supreme Court of the State of IllinoisFolder 141436195314Scope and ContentsPublished Statements, Briefs, Arguments and Abstracts, (five books and seven pamphlets)Box 3Box 31437List of Radio TalksFolder 114381967-701Mailing List for Radio Talk ScriptsFolder 214391987-012Radio and Television TalksFolder 3144019553Scope and ContentsDelivered, drafted and proposedSelected IssuesFolder 414411965-19714Scope and ContentsContains radio talks broadcast from WMAYAugust 1967, November 1967 and February 1968Folder 514425Scope and ContentsContains radio talks broadcast from WMAYMay-AugustFolder 6144319676Scope and ContentsContains radio talks broadcast from WMAYSeptember-DecemberFolder 7144419677Scope and ContentsContains radio talks broadcast from WMAYJanuary-JuneFolder 8144519688Scope and ContentsContains radio talks broadcast from WMAYFebruary-JuneFolder 9144619689Scope and ContentsContains radio talks broadcast from WMAYJuly-DecemberFolder 101447196810Scope and ContentsContains radio talks broadcast from WMAYJuly-DecemberFolder 111448196811Scope and ContentsContains radio talks broadcast from WMAYJanuary-FebruaryFolder 121449196912Scope and ContentsContains radio talks broadcast from WMAYBox 4Box 41450February-JuneFolder 1145119691Scope and ContentsContains radio talks broadcast from WMAYOctober-DecemberFolder 2145219692Scope and ContentsContains radio talks broadcast from WMAYJuly-JanuaryFolder 314531969-19703Scope and ContentsContains radio talks broadcast from WMAYJanuary-JuneFolder 4145419704Scope and ContentsContains radio talks broadcast from WMAYJuly-DecemberFolder 5145519705Scope and ContentsContains radio talks broadcast from WMAYJanuary-AprilFolder 614561970-19716Scope and ContentsContains radio talks broadcast from WMAYJanuary-AprilFolder 7145719717Scope and ContentsContains radio talks broadcast from WMAYMarch-AprilFolder 814581969-19718Scope and ContentsContains radio talks broadcast from WMAYBox 5Box 51459Selected Radio TalksFolder 114601969-19711Scope and ContentsParts I &amp; II (also labeled "II &amp; III"): "Purpose of Local Government: The Community - Executive Functions"Selected Radio TalksFolder 214611969-19712Scope and ContentsPart IV: "Basic Local Governmental Problems Suggested Solutions"Selected Radio TalksFolder 314621969-19713Scope and ContentsPart V: "Law and Local Government" and Part VI: "Federal-State and Local Government Relations - The Eternal Triangle"Selected Radio TalksFolder 414631969-19714Scope and ContentsPart VII: "Civil Rights - Law and Order (and Justice too)" and Part VIII: "Civil Rights - Housing, Recreational and Educational Problems"Selected Radio TalksFolder 514641969-19715Scope and ContentsPart IX: "Freedom of the Press - Local Government and the First Amendment"; Part X: "The New Illinois Constitution and Local Government"; and Part XI: "Review"Radio Commentaries Broadcast from WSSRFolder 6146519856Radio Commentaries Broadcast from WSSRFolder 714661985-19877Oversize FileBox 61467"Patronatos Tradicionalistas De America Diploma d Honor Y flor D Oro Amancay"Folder 1146819641Scope and ContentsFrom visit to Lima, Peru

