<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.80Archon Finding Aid Title MC.80UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:44:36 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC80. Eugene B. Redmond Papers, 1977-1994
    
      Redmond, Eugene B.
    
    MC.80
    88
    
      0.40 Cubic Feet
    
    1977-1994
    Date acquired: 00/00/1995
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Poet laureate of East Saint Louis, Illinois and professor of English and Africana Studies at Southern Illinois University in Edwardsville. Redmond is the author or editor of 18 volumes, founding editor of Drumvoices Revue, and and associate publisher of  Literati Internationale and The Original Blues Annual.  In 1993 he won the American Book Award for The Eye in the Ceiling and he serves as the literary executor of the Henry Dumas estate. 

Programs, bulletins, memoranda, clippings, personal notes, planning material, brochures, newsletters, publications, proposals, press releases, leaflets, flyers, booklets and memorabilia documenting the activities of Redmond and the Eugene B. Redmond Writers Club. Includes a B &amp; W photo of Redmond.  
  
    Arrangement Note
By subject  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Maria Mootry  
  
    Papers
    Correspondence
    Letters
    Newspaper Clippings
    Memorabilia
    Flyers/Brochures
    Newsletters
    Press Releases
  
  Box 1Box 115608Personal Letter to Maria Mootry and one B &amp; W photograph of Eugene B. Redmond, 1994Folder 1156091St. Louis area material concerning literary events, 1990-1992Folder 2156102Educational lesson plans and outlines of Eugene B. Redmond, 1988-1994Folder 3156113Memorabilia of the Eugene B. Redmond Writers Club, 1989-1994Folder 4156124Awards programs/guides of the awards given to or presented by Eugene B. Redmond, 1988-1994Folder 5156135Literary workshops attended to or given by Eugene B. Redmond (some photocopies) 1988-1994Folder 6156146Public Speaking, poetry readings, and lectures by or involving Eugene B. Redmond 1977-1994Folder 7156157Published Writings of Eugene B. Redmond 1990-1992Folder 8156168Literary submissions and literary journal forms, 1990-1992Folder 9156179Newspaper articles, reviews and interviews given to or conducted with Eugene B. Redmond (photocopies) 1989-1994Folder 101561810Newspapers, newspaper clippings, articles written by or conducted with Eugene B. Redmond  (some photocopies) part 1 of 4 1988-1994Folder 111561911Newspapers, newspaper clippings, articles written by or conducted with Eugene B. Redmond  (some photocopies) part 2 of 4 1988-1994Folder 121562012Newspapers, newspaper clippings, articles written by or conducted with Eugene B. Redmond ( some photocopies) part 3 of 4 1988-1994Folder 131562113Newspapers, newspaper clippings, articles written by of conducted with Eugene B. Redmond  (some photocopies) part 4 of 4 1988-1994Folder 141562214

