<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.81Archon Finding Aid Title MC.81UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:44:38 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC81. Robert Guymon Collection, 1831-1968
    
      Guymon, Robert
    
    MC.81
    89
    
      0.16 Cubic Feet
    
    1831-1942
    Date acquired: 00/00/1995
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Collection of documents and postcards related to the history of Springfield, Illinois, including letters written by Springfield founding father Elijah Iles (1831), Illinois Governor and Senator Shelby Cullom (1880), Illinois Congressman William Springer (1883), Springfield businessman Jabez Capps (1874), and Logan Hay (1942);  documents related to the Post #1 of the Grand Army of the Republic in Decatur and the Freemasons of Springfield; sixteen historic postcards of Springfield scenes, 1877-1911; a 1901 menu from Springfield's Leland Hotel; and color snapshots of graves of noted Springfield figures in Oak Ridge Cemetery. See a web exhibit of postcards of Springfield, ca. 1905-06.  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Robert Guymon  
  
    Related Materials
An online exhibit of sixteen historic postcards of Springfield scenes can be found at the link below.http://www.uis.edu/archives/mc81postcards.htm  
  
    Papers
    Letters
    Correspondence
    Photographs
    Newspaper Clippings
  
  Box 1Box 11509Folder 1Folder 115101Scope and ContentsLetter of Elijah Iles to Sangamon County Commissioners, 1831Folder 2Folder 215112Scope and ContentsAgreement between James Watson and Mathias Foyner, 1853 (re trip to CA)Folder 3Folder 315123Scope and ContentsFacsimile of A. Lincoln's Fire Insurance Policy, 1861Folder 4Folder 415134Scope and ContentsSangamon County Deed: Lucy Camp to Jane Camp, 1862Folder 5Folder 515145Scope and ContentsFacsimile of Charter for G.A.R. Post 1, Decatur, IL, 1866Folder 6Folder 615156Scope and ContentsDanson v. Danson, 1870, Sangamon County Circuit Court Jury Verdict, Signed by Presco Wright, et al.Folder 7Folder 715167Scope and ContentsNotary Public Commission for Andrew Dalton, Signed by Shelby CullomFolder 8Folder 815178Scope and ContentsLetter of Gov. Shelby Cullom to A.B. Cornell of New York, 1880Folder 9Folder 915189Scope and ContentsLetter from Illinois Congressman William Springer to William Maybury of Michigan, 1883Folder 10Folder 10151910Scope and ContentsPostcards of Springfield Scenes, 1877, 1906-1911Folder 11Folder 11152011Scope and ContentsPostcard and Menu from Leland Hotel, Springfield, 1901, 1908Folder 12Folder 12152112Scope and Contents6th Annual Reunion of Ancient and Accepted Scottish Rite of Freemasonry, Valley of Springfield, 1912Folder 13Folder 13152213Scope and ContentsBusiness Correspondence, Jabez Capps, Sattley Mfg. Co., Taylorville Coal Co., 1874-1898Folder 14Folder 14152314Scope and ContentsLetter from Logan Hay to Robert Guymon, 1942Folder 15Folder 15152415Scope and ContentsNewspaper clipping regarding Isaac Diller estate, 1968, and R.F. Herndon HomeFolder 16Folder 16152516Scope and ContentsColor snapshots of graves in Oak Ridge Cemetery: Elijah Iles, Pascal Enos, John Riley, etc.Folder 17Folder 17152617Scope and ContentsColor snapshots of grave of William Hamilton, son of Alexander Hamilton, Sacramento, CA

