<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.84Archon Finding Aid Title MC.84UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:44:51 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC84. Clarence W. Klassen,  Love Canal Collection,  1981-1996
    
      Klassen, Clarence W.
    
    MC.84
    91
    
      2.16 Cubic Feet
    
    1981-1996
    Date acquired: 00/00/1997
    1
    2&amp;3
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Chief Sanitary Engineer for the State of Illinois, 1935-1970, first director of the Illinois Environmental Protection Agency and environmental consultant. Served as an expert witness at a trial, 1979-1994, regarding the dumping of toxic wastes at Love Canal in Niagara Falls, New York. Love Canal was dug in the 1890s, used as a chemical dump, and later filled in and developed for housing. The area was declared unsafe and 239 families were evacuated in 1978. The Federal Government, State of New York and other interested parties went to court in 1979 to recover the costs of tests, the purchase of homes, clean-up, and other expenses. 

Includes material from the trial United States et al vs. Occidental Chemical Corporation et al, held in U.S. District Court in Buffalo, New York, 1979-1994, including memoranda, depositions, transcripts of examinations and testimony, exhibits, and reports. Klassen was an expert witness for the State of New York. Also includes a scrapbook of clippings, articles and other material on the history of the Love Canal incident, other collected articles and reports, a book on the subject, (Craig E. Colton and Peter N. Skinner, The Road to Love Canal (Austin: University of Texas Press, 1996)), and information on toxic waste dumps in Calumet City and Winnebago County, Illinois.  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Clarence W. Klassen  
  
    Related Materials
SEE ALSO: Oral History Collection, K666 Clarence Klassen Memoir.  
  
    Records
    Reports
  
  Box 1Box 13590Scope and Contents(Forward and Table of Contents, dated October 1996, provided by Mr. Klassen, to the
contents of Box 1)Love Canal: A Special Report to the Governor and Legislature, Frances Tarlton &amp; John J. Cassidy, eds.Folder 135911981-041"Love Canal: A Retrospective" by Gerald B. Silverman in Environmental ReporterFolder 235921989-09-152"Love Canal: 10 Years Later", reprinted from The ConservationistFolder 3689719883Habitability DecisionFolder 468981988-09-274Scope and ContentsLove Canal Emergency Declaration Area by the NYS Dept. of HealthLove Canal Emergency Declaration AreaFolder 568991988-095Scope and ContentsDecision on Habitabilty, NYS Dept. of HealthFact SheetFolder 669001988-096Scope and ContentsLove Canal EDA Habitability, NYS Dept. of HealthQ. &amp; A.Folder 769011988-097Scope and ContentsLove Canal EDA Habitability, NYS Dept. of HealthSummary of Habitability Conclusions, NYS Dept. of HealthFolder 869028Potential Cross-Examination QuestionsFolder 969091991-03-109Scope and ContentsMemorandum from Peter Skinner, P.E. to C.W. KlassenMemorandum dated December 28, 1990 from Peter Skinner, P.E. to Michael Bryce andFolder 10691010Scope and ContentsAlternatives to Land DisposalRCRA, CERCLA, SARA, Emergency Planning and Community Right-to-Know Act of 1986Folder 11691111Scope and ContentsPublic Health Law, Conservation LawTechnical Documents Regarding Hazardous WasteFolder 12691212New York Trial TeamItem 1369031991-03-2013Scope and ContentsPhotograph taken outside U.S. Courthouse, Buffalo, NY"One In Every Four," from Carson's Silent SpringItem 14690414Table of Wastes Disposed of in Love CanalItem 15690515Chemical Residue Disposal TechnologyItem 16690616Thionyl Cloride production toxicityItem 17690717Additional Benzene Hexachloride toxicity dataItem 18690818Box 2Box 26913"Mr. Love's Dream"Folder 169141985-02-031Scope and ContentsA brief resume of Love Canal's origin, from B.E.N. magazineCohen's ReportFolder 269152Scope and ContentsHistory of Love Canal, prepared for litigation under advise of attorneyOpening Trial Statement by Defendants' Counsel in USAFolder 369163Scope and ContentsNYS, and UDC-Love Canal, Inc. v. Occidental Chemical Corpo ration, City of Niagara Falls, et al (Hereafter referred to as NYS v. OCC)Post Trial Memo (NYS) Supporting Punitive Damages ClaimFolder 469171991-08-094OCC's Memo in Opposition to Punitive Damages ClaimFolder 569181991-09-125Summations by OCC/Hooker and NYS Regarding Punitive DamagesFolder 669191991-04-166Proposed Findings of Facts (NYS) in Support of Claim for Punitive DamagesFolder 769201991-08-097Proposed Findings of Facts (OCC) in Opposition to (NYS's) Claim for Punitive DamagesFolder 869211991-09-128Decision and Order of District Judge CurtinFolder 969221994-03-179Statement of Facts (NYS)...for the Phase I TrialFolder 1069231990-10-0910Love Canal Inactive Hazardous Waste Site: A Remedial ChronologyFolder 1169241990-0311Consent Judgement Between NYS and OCCFolder 1269251994-0512Memoranda from Peter Skinner to Michael Bruce and Eugene Martin-LeffFolder 1369261990-12-28 and 1991-02-21, respectively13Clarence Klassen's Expert Rebuttal ReportFolder 1469271990-06-2214Klassen's Direct ExaminationFolder 1569281991-03-1915Scope and Contents(pp. 7685-7760)Klassen's Cross ExaminationFolder 1669291991-03-1916Scope and Contents(pp. 7761-7803)Klassen's Recross ExaminationFolder 1769301991-03-2017Scope and Contents(pp. 7804-7892)Trial Exhibits for Cross Examination of Clarence W. KlassenFolder 18693118Trial Exhibits for Direct Examination of Clarence W. KlassenFolder 19693219Dwight Metzler Testimony (OCC), Vol. 1,Folder 2069331991-03-0620Dwight Metzler Testimony (OCC), Vol. 2Folder 2169341991-03-0621Folder 2269351989-03-1422Scope and ContentsReport of Richard W. Eldredge, P.E., 3/14/1989Trial Exhibits for Wesley E. Gilbertson, P.E., D.E.E.Folder 2369361989-08-02 - 1990-03-0623Wesley E. Gilbertson Examination, Vol. 1Folder 2469371989-08-0224Wesley E. Gilbertson Examination, Vol. 2Folder 2569381989-08-0325Wesley E. Gilbertson Examination, Vol. 3Folder 2669391989-12-1326Wesley E. Gilbertson Examination, Vol. 4Folder 2769401989-12-1427War Department Landfill BulletinFolder 2869411943-12-2828Hooker (OCC) Incineration R &amp; DFolder 2969421941-197929"Illinois Landfill Sites" by Clarence KlassenFolder 3069431991-03-1530Illinois Industrial Wastes in the Calumet Area, 1869-1970: A Historical GeographyFolder 3169441985-0931Historical Industrial Waste Disposal Practices in Winnebago County, Illinois: 1870-1980Folder 3269451986-0932James E. Etzell Testimony, Vol. 1Folder 3369461989-07-2733James E. Etzell Testimony, Vol. 2Folder 3469471989-07-2834Box 3Box 36948James E. Etzell Testimony, Vol. 3Folder 169491989-10-101Kirk W. Brown - Robert M. Cohen Testimony (NYS), Vol. 1Folder 269501990-12-52Robert M. Cohen (NYS) Testimony, Vol. 2Folder 369511990-12-053Robert M. Cohen (NYS) Testimony, Vol. 3Folder 469521990-12-064Robert M. Cohen (NYS) Testimony, Vol. 4Folder 569531990-12-065Robert M. Cohen (NYS) Testimony, Vol. 5Folder 669541990-12-106Robert M. Cohen (NYS) Testimony, Vol. 6Folder 769551990-12-117Robert M. Cohen (NYS) Testimony, Vol. 7Folder 869561990-12-118Jerome Wilkenfeld (OCC) Testimony, Vol. 1Folder 969571991-01-109Jerome Wilkenfeld (OCC) Testimony, Vol. 2Folder 1069581991-01-1010Jerome Wilkenfeld (OCC) Testimony, Vol. 3Folder 1169591991-01-1511Jerome Wilkenfeld (OCC) Testimony, Vol. 4Folder 1269601991-01-1512Eugene Vohwinkle (OCC) Testimony, Vol. 1Folder 1369611991-02-2613Eugene Vohwinkle (OCC) Testimony, Vol. 2Folder 1469621991-02-2614George R. Amery (OCC) TestimonyFolder 1569631991-02-2715Clarence W. Klassen (NYS) Deposition, Vol. 1Folder 1669641990-08-2216Clarence W. Klassen (NYS) Deposition, Vol. 2Folder 1769651990-08-2317Wesley E. Gilbertson Examination, Vol. 5Folder 1869661990-02-1518Wesley E. Gilbertson Examination, Vol. 6Folder 1969671990-02-1619Richard W. Eldredge Testimony, Vol. 1Folder 2069681989-03-1420Richard W. Eldredge Testimony, Vol. 2Folder 2169691989-03-1521Richard W. Eldredge Testimony, Vol. 3Folder 2269701989-10-1122Dwight Metzler Exhibits 1-12Folder 2369711990-0523Dwight Metzler Exhibits 14-25Folder 2469721990-0524Dwight Metzler Videotaped Deposition (transcript), Vol. 1Folder 2569731990-05-1625Dwight Metzler Videotaped Deposition (transcript), Vol. 2Folder 2669741990-05-1626Dwight Metzler Videotaped Deposition (transcript), Vol. 3Folder 2769751990-05-1727Definitions for TermsFolder 2869761991-02-2028Study and Clean Up Program: Love Canal Landfill (newsletters) by NYS Dept. of Environmental ConservationFolder 2969771983-02 - 1988-0329The Road to Love CanalFolder 306978199630Scope and ContentsBy: Craig E. Colten and Peter N. Skinner. Austin: Univ. of Texas PressLove Canal Scrapbook containing newspaper clipping relating to the disaster and trialFolder 31697931

