<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.85Archon Finding Aid Title MC.85UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:44:54 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC85. City Water, Light and Power/Lake Springfield, Records, 1939-1974
    MC.85
    92
    
      0.16 Cubic Feet
    
    1939-1974
    Date acquired: 00/00/1977
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Maps, brochures, publications and reports concerning Willis J. and Charles H. Spaulding, City Water, Light and Power, Lake Springfield and the development of the gas, electric and street railway business in Springfield. Also a bibliography on CWLP and a proposed environmental policy for Lake Springfield (1974). Published items include "Rules, Regulations and Official Map of Lake Springfield" (ca. 1970), "Official Map of the City of Springfield, Illinois - Souvenir Edition" (ca. 1968), "A History of  Your Municipal Light and Water 1839-1939" (1939), and "Annual Report 1961, dedicated to Willis J. Spaulding...a man with a dream" (1961).  
  
    Arrangement Note
Topical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Johnson, Walt  
  
    Existence and Location of Originals
"A History of Your Municipal Light and Water 1939-1939" (1939) has been added to the CARLI Digital Collection.  It has been scanned and uploaded to be viewed in its original state.  A link to the collection is listed below.http://www.uis.edu/archives/digitalcollections.html  
  
    Related Materials
SEE ALSO:  MC 34 Charles Herbert Spaulding Papers, MC 13 Willis J. Spaulding Papers.  
  
    Reports
    Flyers/Brochures
    Journal Articles
    Maps
  
  Box 1Box 115623City Water, Light and Power/ Lake SpringfieldFolder 1156241Scope and Contents"Rules, Regulations and Official Map of Lake Springfield"; "Official Map of the City of Springfield, Illinois" Published by CWLPProposed Environmental Policy for Lake SpringfieldFolder 2156252Scope and ContentsFinal Report on Proposed Environmental Policy for Lake Springfield, December 30, 1974- report; Third Public Draft Final: December 30, 1974 - report; Proposed Environmental Policy for Lake Springfield, June 1, 1974- reportCity Water, Light and PowerFolder 3156263Scope and Contents"A History of Your Municipal Light and Water; 1839-1938"- publication; Bibliography of CWLP- publication; Brief Local History of the Development of the Gas, Electric and Street Railway Business in Springfield."- report; "One of the Oldest Water Works in Illinois Continues to Produce for the Capital City'- reportWillis J. Spaulding and Charles SpauldingFolder 4156274Scope and ContentsBibliography of Charles G. Spaulding; Bibliography of Willis J. Spaulding; "Annual Report 1961 Dedicated to Willis J. Spaulding."- publication

