<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.86Archon Finding Aid Title MC.86UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:44:59 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC86. Michael Townsend, Micro-Radio Collection
    
      Townsend, Mike (Townsend, Michael Patrick)
    
    MC.86
    93
    
      6.20 Cubic Feet
    
    1989-2002
    Date acquired: 10/26/1998
    1
    2
    3
    4
    5
    6
    7
    8
    9
    10
    11
    12
    13
    14
    15
    16
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Records, collected literature, and audio and videotapes concerning the unlicensed, low-power radio station of Mbanna Kantako of Springfield, Illinois, and the micro-radio movement in general. The efforts of the FCC to shut down Kantako's radio station attracted international press attention. 

This material was largely collected or created by Michael Townsend, an associate professor of Child, Family and Community Services at UIS. Its primary  focus is Mbanna Kantako (originally named DeWayne Readus), who began transmitting WTRA at a power of 4 watts from his apartment in a public housing development in Springfield in 1987. WTRA was later renamed Zoom Black Magic Radio, Liberation Radio, Black Liberation Radio, and Human Rights Radio. 

The collection includes audiotapes of radio station shows from 1996 to 1998; legal records documenting the defense by Kantako and supporters against efforts by the FCC and other bodies to silence his unlicensed radio station; audio and videotapes of coverage by local and national media showing Kantako at his radio station, speaking about police brutality, injustice, capitalism, race, free speech, and other issues; letters, periodical and newspaper articles, press releases, newsletters, memos, and printouts of web pages related to Kantako and other micro-radio broadcasters, collected from the U.S., Britain, Germany and Italy; correspondence of Townsend requesting legal and financial support for Kantako, involving Noam Chomsky, Edward Hermann, Marable Manning, Ben Bagdikian, Sidney Wilhelm, Peter Franck, and many others. 

The boxes in this collection are divided into three categories:
1 - Periodical &amp; web articles, legal materials and correspondence
2 - VHS Recordings
3 - Audiocassette &amp; CD Recordings

Also includes a 2000 video documentary, "free radio," by San Francisco filmmaker Kevin Keyser, featuring Kantako, Stephen Dunifer and others.
Added to the collection in 2011 is Sort Stue material: articles, lyrics to song, t-shirt for 25th anniversary of Human Rights Radio, and photos of band in St. Petersburg, Russia [all located in Box 7].  
Sort Stue (a musical group from Copenhagen) released an album in April 2011 entitled "Viva Kantako Destroy Sony."  Copies of excerpts from Amy  Spencer's "DIY: The Rise of Lo-Fi Culture."  
  
    Arrangement Note
Chronological &amp; Alphabetical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Michael Townsend  
  
    Accruals and Additions
4/20/01, 4/01/02, 7/01/02, 5/15/2009, 5/28/2009, 6/1/2009 and 6/9/2009, 8/9/2010, 7/13/2011, 8/20/2011  
  
    Records
    Correspondence
    Audio Tapes
    Audio CDs
    Videotapes
  
  Box 1Box 17749General articles about micro-radioFolder 177501988-19971Scope and Contents1 of 2Newstalk radio affiliate listItem 1775111Panaxis catalog pageItem 2775212"How to be a radio pirate"Item 3775313Create your own radio, by Luke HikenItem 4775414Tom Reveille's "Community Broadcaster's Notice and Declaration of First, Fourth, and Ninth Amendment Rights"Item 57755199115Black Liberation Radio manual for constructing and operating low-watt radio stations without a license, compiled by Keidi Obi AwaduItem 6775616Television/Radio Age, "Power of Ethnic Radio Seen"Item 7775717Television/Radio Age, "Black radio programmers moving heavily into syndicated television productions"Item 87758198818Burning Toddlers, anarchist periodicalItem 97759198919National Lawyers Guild PractitionerItem 1077601989110Whole Earth Review, "Real Honest True Deregulation of Broadcasting"Item 1177611990111"Free Radio in Japan," by Tetsuo KogawaItem 127762112Article on economic differences between blacks and whitesItem 137763113Sound ChoiceItem 1477641990114General articles about micro-radioFolder 277651988-19972Scope and Contents2 of 2Communications News, "Nearby Marketing with FM"Item 177661990-0221"New York City Teacher of the Year Speech, John Taylor Gatto"Item 277671990-01-3122Fifth Estate, "Radio Free Detroit"Item 37768199123"Statistical Analysis of Minority Owned Commercial Broadcast Stations Licensed in the United States"Item 47769199024"Power of the pirates:  Black Radio"Item 5777025Nation, Alexander Cockburn letter on low-watt radioItem 677711991-06-1026Interadio, (newsletter of world association of community broadcasters) v.3:  no.2Item 77772199127Interadio, v.3:  no.3Item 87773199128Sound ChoiceItem 97774199129Z Papers, "Democratic Media," by Edward HermanItem 1077751992210National Lawyers Guild Committee on Democratic Communications,  newsletterItem 1177761992211"Report on Inter-Regional Communications Consultation, Quezon City, the Philippines, January 8-15, 1992"Item 127777212Scope and ContentsBy Colleen Roach (member of the National Lawyers Guild)Mother Jones, "Journalism of Joy," by Ben BagdikianItem 1377781992213"The Hitchhikers Guide to Radio," by Ford PrefectItem 1477791995-09214Radio Resistor's Bulletin, "De-constructing Consent:  Job of Radio Free Maine," by Frank HaulgrenItem 1577801996215TRANET, (alternative and transformational movements)Item 1677811996-05216Radio Free Maine, (Listing of) "Audio and VHS video tapes of the 14th Annual Socialist Scholars Conference"Item 1777821996-04217"Grassroots Radio Conference," flyerItem 1877831996-07218Interadio, v.8:  no.1Item 1977841996219NASW (National Association of Social Workers) Illinois Chapter BulletinItem 2077851996-1997220Chicago Tribune, "Defiant radio pirates tuning out FCC"Item 2177861997-02-08221Interadio, subscription formItem 2277871996222Free Radio Network NewsItem 2377881997223Fundraising and financing, order forms, check copiesFolder 377891992-19933Legal materialsFolder 477901989, 19904Scope and Contents1 of 5State of Illinois Articles of Incorporation of WTRAItem 177911988-04-1441Memo from Paul Holtzman to the Executive Directors of the Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights Under LawItem 277921990-06-2742Scope and Contentsre Supreme Court's ruling on racial preference policies of the Federal Communications Commission (FCC)Washington Post, "FCC Defends Minority License Policies"Item 377931990-03-2943New York Times, "FCC Tilt to Minorities Weighed by High Court"Item 477941990-03-2944List of letter writers to Peter Franck (of the National Lawyers Guild) on behalf of WTRAItem 5779545"FCC begins issuing fines for 'aiding and abetting'," by Don BishopItem 677961991-0146Letter from Colleen RoachItem 777971990-11-3047Scope and Contentsre Unesco, the New World Information Order, and the "DeWayne Readus case" and the "Prague statement of the MacBride Round Table."  Enc.:  Draft resolution of Readus caseLetter from Steven Egger to Peter FranckItem 877981990-12-0548Scope and Contentsre taking up Kantako caseLetter from Brandon Jones to Peter FranckItem 977991990-11-2849Scope and Contentsre taking up Kantako caseLetter from Robert Bracken to Peter FranckItem 1078001990-11-12410Scope and Contentsre taking up Kantako case.  Enc.:  letter from Townsend to BrackenLetters from and to Ralph StoneItem 1178011990-11-07411Scope and Contentsre urging Franck to take up Kantako caseLetter from Paul Korntheuer to Peter FranckItem 1278021990-11-07412Scope and Contentsre taking up Kantako case.  Enc.:  Letter to KorntheuerLetter to Guillermo KuhlItem 1378031990-11-13413Scope and Contentsre thanking him for writing to Peter Franck.  Enc.:  Kuhl letterLetter from Marty Cooper to Peter FranckItem 1478041990-11-03414Scope and Contentsre taking up Kantako case.  Handwritten note from Cooper to TownsendLetter from Lee Ballinger (Rock &amp; Roll Confidential) to Peter FranckItem 1578051990-11-02415Scope and Contentsre taking up Kantako caseLetter from John Ohliger to Peter FranckItem 1678061990-11-05416Scope and Contentsre taking up Kantako caseLetters to Peter FranckItem 1778071990-1991417Scope and Contentsre media attention and taking up Kantako caseLetters from Peter FranckItem 1878081990418Scope and Contentsre preliminary legal memorandum on Readus/Kantako case. Enc:  Legal memorandum draftLetter to Peter FranckItem 1978091990-08-09419Scope and Contentsre Kantako caseLetters to Peter FranckItem 2078101990420Scope and Contentsre Columbia Journalism Review article and Kantako caseLetter to Mark SilversteinItem 2178111990-06-07421Scope and Contentsre meeting with himLetter to Rich Shereikis and Ron SakolskyItem 2278121990-05-08422Scope and Contentsre Peter FranckU.S. District Court, Central District of Illinois—Springfield DivisionItem 2378131990-03-30423Scope and ContentsJudgment against Readus for $750 on non-licensed stationLetter to Peter FranckItem 2478141990-04-03424Scope and Contentsre taking up Readus case to courtU.S. District CourtItem 2578151990-03-21425Scope and ContentsDocket entry for Readus to appear in courtLetter from Assistant U.S. Attorney James Lewis to ReadusItem 2678161990-02-23426Scope and ContentsUrging Readus to come to 2 Mar hearingU.S. District CourtItem 2778171990-02-22427Scope and ContentsNotice of 2 Mar depositionU.S. District Court, Judge Richard MillsItem 2878181990-02-20428Scope and ContentsReadus again urged to appear in courtU.S. District Court Civil Docket CaseItem 2978191990-02-15429Scope and ContentsPlaintiff's memorandum of law in support of motion for judgmentU.S. District Court, Deposition SubpoenaItem 3078201990-01-12430U.S. District Court, Judge Mills' request to comply with future discovery requestsItem 3178211990-01-10431U.S. District Court, Deposition Transcription, U.S. v. DeWayne ReadusItem 3278221989-12-18432U.S. District Court, Deposition SubpoenaItem 3378231989-12-01433Letter from U.S. District Court on notice of right to consent to disposition of a civil case by a U.S. magistrateItem 347824434U.S. District Court Notice of DepositionItem 3578251989-12-18435U.S. District Court Answer of DefendantItem 3678261989-11-30436Letter from Readus to ACLUItem 3778271989-11-20437Scope and Contentsre asking ACLU representing him against the FCCU.S. District Court summonsItem 3878281989-11-09438Letter from U.S. District Court to ReadusItem 3978291989-10-04439Scope and Contentsre operating radio station without a licenseLetters to and from FCC to Rep. Dick Durbin regarding Readus and licensing of radio stations; letter from Durbin to TownsendItem 4078301989440Letters from FCC to ReadusItem 4178311989441Scope and Contentsre payment of $750 fineLetter from Readus to FCCItem 4278321989-05-09442Scope and Contentsre reasons for not paying fineWarning from Will Gray of the FCC to ReadusItem 4378331989-04-06443Legal materialsFolder 578341991-19925Scope and Contents2 of 5FCC Bill of Collection to ReadusItem 178351992-11-1851Letter to Derrick BellItem 278361992-11-1752Scope and Contentsre attorneys who would be willing to assist ReadusLetter from Sally Harms (National Lawyers Guild, Committee on Democratic Communications - NLG-CDC) to KantakoItem 378371992-09-2353Scope and Contentsre Kantako sending tapes to sympathetic lawyersNLG-CDC newsletterItem 47838199254Letter from Peter Franck to KantakoItem 578391992-08-0455Scope and Contentsre rough draft of  Intervention before Human Rights Subcommission of the United Nations, which is enclosedMemo from Franck to Sally HarmsItem 678401991-03-1556Scope and Contentsre Kantako caseLetter to Bob Perry from FranckItem 778411991-03-1857Scope and Contentsre work on the legislative angle on the Kantako caseLetter from Howard EngelskirchenItem 878421991-02-2758Scope and Contentsre micro-radio and legal issuesMemo from Franck to NLG CommitteeItem 978431991-11-2659Scope and Contentsre Mbanna/WTRA.  Enc. Letter from Franck to Marjorie Heins of ACLU, 26 Nov 1991, re thanking her for memo from Jay Brown, and memo from Jay Brown of the ACLULetter from FranckItem 1078441991-08-20510Scope and Contentsre Kantako case. Enc.:  Case summary distributed at NLG Committee on Media Monopoly, Disinformation and the First AmendmentLetter from Sandra Coliver (London's International Centre Against Censorship) to FranckItem 1178451991-08-28511Scope and Contentsre amicus memo on Zoom Black Magic Radio caseMemo from Andrew Scoble to NLG-CDCItem 1278461992-02-06512Scope and Contentsre Kantako case and availability of international foraLetter from Franck to KantakoItem 1378471992-05-29513Scope and Contentsre Human Rights AdvocatesMemo from Ralph Hoenle to NLG-CDCItem 1478481992-05-19514Scope and ContentsKantako case and international human rightsInterview with Louis Hiken of NLG by unknownItem 157849515Scope and Contentsre Kantako and Dunifer casesLegal materialsFolder 678501991-19926Scope and Contents3 of 5Letter from Franck to KantakoItem 178511992-05-2961Scope and Contentsre enc. of memos and taking case to international human rights bodies.  Enc.: MemosLetter from FranckItem 278521992-04-0662Scope and Contentsre CDC newsletter and expanding mailing listNLG-CDC newsletterItem 378531991-1163Letter from Franck to NLG-CDC Legal SubcomitteeItem 478541991-11-2664Legal draft by Prof. Howard Engelskirchen of the NLGItem 57855ca. 199165Letter from FranckItem 678561991-08-2066Scope and Contentsre Kantako's participation at NLG convention and update on case.  Enc.:  NLG convention leaflet, Istanbul meeting report, and NLG case summaryLetter to Andrew Scoble of Human Rights AdvocatesItem 778571991-11-0667Scope and ContentsAssisting Black Liberation Radio legal caseLetter to FranckItem 87858ca. 199168Scope and Contentsre telephone consultation with KantakoLetter from Nina (Adams)Item 978591991-11-0669Scope and Contentsre help of ACLUFax from FranckItem 1078601991-07-31610Scope and Contentsre telephone interview questions with KantakoOutline for briefItem 117861ca. 1991611Scope and Contentsre Black Liberation RadioState Journal-Register, "Radio station draws attention in wake of riots"Item 1278621992-06-03612Scope and ContentsCopy sent to FranckLegal materialsFolder 778631991-19927Scope and Contents4 of 5Minutes of NLG-CDC meetingItem 178641992-01-0571"Report of Inter-Regional Communications Consultation, Quezon City, Philippines"Item 278651992-0172Letter to FranckItem 378661991-12-1373Scope and Contentsre Tom Reveille.  Enc.:  Reveille press releaseLetter from IRS to John Hay Tenants Rights AssociationItem 478671990-11-1274Scope and Contentsre tax returnsLetter from Howard Engelskirchen to FranckItem 578681991-03-2275Scope and Contentsre Kantako case and micro-radio issuesU.S. District Court Motion for Judgment, Affidavit, Notice of Deposition, Deposition SubpoenaItem 67869199076Scope and Contentsre Kantako/FCC caseLetter from Franck to Townsend and KantakoItem 778701991-06-2077Scope and Contentsre case updateLetter from Franck to Trudy HaleItem 878711991-06-2078Scope and Contentsre local legal representationNLG Committee on Media Monopoly case summaryItem 978721991-04-0979Letter from Howard EngelskirchenItem 1078731991-06-08710Scope and Contentsre Bertold Brecht quote on radioLetter from Tom Reveille to J.R. Zoulek of the FCCItem 1178741991-04-25711Scope and Contentsre FCC trying to shut his radio station down.  Enc.:  FCC letter to ReveilleLetter from Mark SilversteinItem 1278751991-04-13712Scope and Contentsre NLG progress on Kantako caseLetter to Gwen ?Item 1378761991-05-08713Scope and Contentsre her school paper on micro-radio.  Enc.:  Howard Engelskirchen letter, nd, re Gwen ?NLG-CDC newsletterItem 1478771992714NLG article, "Zoom Black Magic Makes Waves," by Sally HarmsItem 157878715NLG-CDC newsletterItem 1678791991-11716"Report on NLG Representation at Istanbul Meeting on Media Democracy and the New World Information and Communications Order," by Colleen Roach of Committee on Media MonopolyItem 1778801991-07-30717NLG Media Issues, Cultural Environment Movement, prospectusItem 1878811991-05-21718Legal materialsFolder 878821991-19938Scope and Contents5 of 5NLG-CDC Case Summary of "Zoom Black Magic Radio/WTRA vs. Federal Communications Commission"Item 178831991-04-0981NLG-CDC fax "U.S. Court of Appeals Pumps Up the Volume"Item 278841993-11-3082Scope and Contentsre Dougan v. USA-FCC, in which the U.S. Court of Appeals ordered the FCC to address the issue of whether Americans have the right to broadcast from their micro radio stationsNews release from Andrew Yoder, unlicensed radio station operatorItem 378851993-04-0683Scope and Contentsre  his arrest and fine by the FCC for $17,500 FCC Bill for Collection, re $750 fineTom Reveille's petitioner's informal brief for the U.S. Court of AppealsItem 478861993-06-2584Scope and ContentsNLG-CDC newsletter, (6 parts)"Proceedings of the Symposium on Media Accountability under International  Law," by the Union for Democratic Communications/NLGItem 578871989-06-1485Scope and Contentsre the worldwide movement for grass-roots communicationsMbanna Kantako legal brief on why FCC regulations are unconstitutionalFolder 9788819989Scope and ContentsFCC acting in an illegal and unconstitutional manner;  First Amendment  issues;  Telecommunications Act as unconstitutional;  exclusion of the poor and minorities from the airwaves;  increase in corporate monopolization of the airwaves;  U.N. Declaration of Human Rights and the right of Kantako to communicate;  history of Kantako and WTRA;  history of communications regulations;  FCC as a historically racist institution;  homogenization of viewpoints.Mailing lists of publications, individuals, professorsFolder 10788910Media contacts with correspondence and periodical articlesFolder 1178901989-199011Scope and Contents1 of 2Telephone messages from Greg Cockrell of KFI radio and John Amen of Newstalk Radio Network-WNTR, Washington, D.C.Item 17891ca. 1990111List of TV and Radio interviews with KantakoItem 278921989-1991112Lies of Our Times, "Microwatt Revolution," by TownsendItem 378931991-01113Scope and ContentsIncludes original manuscriptLetter from Lee Ballinger of Rock &amp; Roll ConfidentialItem 478941990-11-13114Scope and ContentsInquiries from California.  Letter to Ballinger from Townsend.Atlanta News Weekly, "Community Development:  One of Many Solutions," by Brandon Astor JonesItem 578951991-01115Utne Reader, "Radio Free America"Item 678961991116Letter from Ed HermannItem 778971990-11-08117Scope and Contentsre Townsend writing an article for Lies of Our TimesNote on Avveniminti (Italian) magazine articleItem 878981990-11-15118Syracuse Herald American, "Blind man telecasts defiance"Item 978991990-09-23119Scope and ContentsLetter to Don Bishop of Intertec Publishing, 24 Oct 1990, re articles he had publishedPostcard from Anna MariaItem 1079001990-10-291110Scope and Contentsre publishing articles in Italian newspapersLetter to Harald KuhlItem 1179011990-11-071111Scope and Contentsre German daily newspaper article die tageszeitung.  Stapled with letter from Kuhl, 22 Oct 1990;  die tageszeitung article;  letter from Kuhl, 1 Oct 1990, re Radio Von Unten article;  letter to Kuhl, 10 Oct 1990, re German National Radio interview, U.S. NPR;  letter to Kuhl, 7 Sept 1990;  letter from Kuhl, 27 Aug 1990, re WTRA photos and T-shirts;  letter to Kuhl, 27 Aug 1990;  letter from Kuhl, 6 Aug 1990, initial inquiry into WTRA  Factsheet Five, #37, Aug 1990"Hidden Hits," by John Ohliger, original manuscript of article in Adult &amp; Continuing Education TodayItem 1279021990-10-221112Letter from Joe Richman (HEAT of National Public Radio) to KantakoItem 1379031990-09-261113Scope and Contentsre doing a story for the late-night programLetter to Connie Powell of KFYI AMItem 1479041990-09-261114Scope and Contentsre sending materialsLetter to CBC Radio in TorontoItem 1579051990-09-261115Scope and Contentsre sending materialsLetter to Mr. Hitt of Harper'sItem 1679061990-10-191116Scope and Contentsre sending NPR tape.  Enc.: Letter from Jack Hitt of Harper's to Rich Shereikis, 27 Sept 1990, re his piece for the magazine;  letter from Hitt to Kantako, 4 Sept 1990, re doing a piece;  letter to Hitt, 11 Sept 1990, re homemade videoLetter to Gary Covino of National Public RadioItem 1779071990-09-111117Scope and Contentsre sending materialsLA Weekly, "Free Christian Slater!"by RJSItem 1879081990-081118Scope and Contentsre "Pump Up theVolume" and real-life radio piratesRadio and Records, "Illinois Radio Pirate Defies FCC"Item 19790919901119Playboy, "Fast Tracks," by Barbara NellisItem 2079101990-091120Scope and Contentsre "Pump up the Volume" and the real-life ReadusPhone message for TownsendItem 2179111990-08-231121Scope and Contentsre schedule for MTV program on ReadusIllinois Times, "Shorts"Item 2279121990-08-231122Scope and Contentsre MTV program on ReadusLetter to Ann Hartley of MTVItem 2379131990-08-021123Scope and Contentsre MTV doing a program on Readus;  letter to Hartley, 3 Aug 1990, re article on ReadusLetter from Robert Cusolito of Fox TV programItem 2479141990-08-091124Scope and Contentsre "Personalities" TV program piece;  stapled with letter to Gordon Lewis Fox, 19 July 1990, re Fox doing a program on ReadusLetter to Lee Ballinger of Rock &amp; Roll ConfidentialItem 2579151990-08-271125Scope and Contentsre legal developments and articles;  stapled with letter to Ballinger, 25 June 1990, re Columbia Journalism Review article;  letter to Ballinger, 13 June 1990, re 10 watt transmitter;  letter to Ballinger, 18 May 1990, re thanks for the music and support;  letter to Ballinger, 22 Mar 1990, re rap spots promoting WTRA;  letter to Ballinger, 2 Mar 1990, re video;  letter to Ballinger, 6 Feb 1990, re piece in Rock &amp; Roll Confidential and Chicago Tribune;  letter to Ballinger, 25 Jan 1990, re videotapes, sending music, and Black Rose's potentialLetter to John Woods of "Rock Out Censorship"Item 2679161990-08-271126Scope and Contentsre Kantako on MTV, Henry Morris of SHA being fired, and Napoleon Williams station in Decatur;  stapled with Woods' letter to Kurt Loder of MTV, 24 July 1990, re them doing a piece on Zoom Black Magic Radio;  Woods' letter to Henry Morris of SHA, 24 July 1990, re SHA harassment of ReadusLetter to Tony Campbell of KFPT radioItem 2779171990-08-271127Scope and Contentsre interviewLetter to George Biswell of KKFI Vietnam Veterans Radio NetworkItem 2879181990-07-231128Scope and Contentsre more information on KKFI;  stapled with KKFI flyerLetter to Lu Palmer of WVON ChicagoItem 2979191990-07-231129Scope and Contentsre interviewLetter to James Sengstacke of Chicago DefenderItem 3079201990-07-231130Scope and Contentsre them doing a storyLetter to Melvin Wallace of Serious Hip-Hop MagazineItem 3179211990-07-161131Scope and Contentsre writing an articleLetter to Lewis Beale of the Detroit Free PressItem 3279221990-08-031132Scope and Contentsre them writing an article;  stapled with letter from Beale, 13 July 1990, re "Pump Up the Volume" copy of review;  letter to Beale, 11 July 1990, re people in Detroit wanting to start a micro radio station;  letter to Readus from Julie Herrada of Detroit, 21 June 1990, re starting a radio station; letter to Beale, 5 June 1990, re him writing an article;  letter to Lewis of Fox TV, 19 July 1990, re TV program on ReadusLetter to David Barnes of Emerge magazineItem 3379231990-07-061133Scope and Contentsre doing an articleLetter to Thom Jurek of Detroit Metro TimesItem 3479241990-07-121134Scope and Contentsre response to their article;  stapled with letter to Jurek, 28 June 1990, re articleLetter to Jon BekkenItem 3579251990-07-031135Scope and Contentsre his front page write-up and representing WTRA at the Dublin conference;  stapled with letter from Bekken, 25 June, re community radio station in Champaign, IL;  discussion paper written by Bekken on WEFT in Champaign;  letter to Bekken, 21 May 1990, re Readus;  letter from Bekken, 24 April 1990, re community radio; letter to Bekken, 24 Apr 1990, re WTRA publicity and demise of community radio;  letter from Bekken, 26 Mar 1990, re WEFT, WTRA, ACLU, and legal challenge to FCCLetter to Susie Day of the Post AmericanItem 3679261990-06-071136Scope and Contentsre WTRA materialsLetter to Clifford Kelly of WGCI in ChicagoItem 3779271990-06-071137Scope and Contentsre Readus interviewAuthor's Tear Sheets for the Columbia Journalism Review, written by Rich ShereikisItem 3879281990-05-081138Letter to Denny McClain of WXYT in MichiganItem 3979291990-06-011139Scope and ContentsEnclosing articles for assistance for interview with KantakoLetter to Melanie Imani of KSTP in St. Paul, MNItem 4079301990-06-011140Scope and Contentsre background information on ReadusLetter to Kate Pemberton of CBC RadioItem 4179311990-06-011141Scope and Contentsre background info Mother Jones, "Radio Free Radio"Letter to Sharon Fennell of KHSU of Humboldt State University in Arcata, CAItem 4279321990-05-161142Scope and Contentsre interview with KantakoDemocratic Communique newsletter (NLG-UDC)Item 43793319901143Letter from David Ciaffardini of Sound ChoiceItem 4479341990-05-141144Scope and Contentsre an article on setting up a micropower radio stationLetter to Rich Shereikis and Ron SakolskyItem 4579351990-05-081145Scope and Contentsre NLG and Peter Franck's interest in using WTRA as a test case in the courts;  stapled with letter to Franck, 8 May 1990, re materials relevant to the case and Readus' vision of micropower radio's futureLetter to Joel ? of In These TimesItem 4679361990-04-301146Scope and Contentsre response to their article, "Dewayne Readus:  Radio Rebel"Letter to Tom Jurek of Detroit Metro TimesItem 4779371147Scope and Contentsre information on micro radioEditorial copy of Rich Shereikis' article for Mother JonesItem 48793819901148Letter from Mary Carlin of WSSU (now WUIS)Item 4979391990-03-061149Scope and Contentsre public radio's New Voices program piece on ReadusMedia contacts with correspondence and periodical articlesFolder 1279421989-199512Scope and Contents2 of 2Handwritten note on Black Radio Hall of Fame's Nelson George and T.R. Frazier of "Afro-American History, Primary Sources"Item 17984121Letter to Sonja Spear of Mother JonesItem 279851990-03-28122Scope and Contentsre upcoming articleLetter to David Ciaffardini of Sound ChoiceItem 379861990-03-28123Scope and Contentsre his article in Sound Choice, "Radio Activist Defies FCC"Letter to Ron Sakolsky from Peter Petrisko of Factsheet FiveItem 47987124Scope and Contentsre Sakolsky writing an articleFactsheet Five, #34Item 57988ca. 1990125Scope and ContentsUntitled article on ReadusERNewsletter, "Pirate Radio Activities"Item 679891990-01126First draft of article for "national magazine" by Rich Shereikis, "Project Radio"Item 779901990-02127Scope and Contents24 pagesLetter to Readus from Bob ? of People's TribuneItem 87991128Scope and Contentsre articlePeople's Tribune, "Pump It Up!  Pirate radio takes on police brutality and homelessness"Item 979921990-02-12129"Low-Watt/Long Range Radio," draft of article by Rich ShereikisItem 1079931990-07-261210Scope and Contents5 pagesZenger (underground paper out of Madison, WI), "Feds Try to Kill Community Radio"Item 11799419901211Illinois Times, Letters to the editorItem 1279951990-011212Scope and Contentsre 11 Jan 1990 feature article on WTRAIllinois Times, "Readus joins other radio radicals in network of anti-mainstream stations"Item 1379961990-01-251213Scope and Contentsre association with Black Rose of Fresno, CAIllinois Public Radio news release, "Dewayne Won't Talk"Item 1479971990-01-221214Scope and Contentsre refusal to communicate with the U.S. District Court on FCC caseCover letter sent to over 50 organizations and individuals on WTRA mailing listItem 1579981990-01-161215Scope and Contentsre update on Readus and solicitation for legal adviceIllinois Times, "United States vs. WTRA," feature articleItem 1679991990-01-111216Guardian, ("independent radical newsweekly"), "Along the Color Line," column by Manning Marable, "Liberation Radio Shut Down"Item 1780001989-08-021217Final Call, "Guerrilla Radio," by James MuhammedItem 1880011989-09-11218State Journal Register, "Timing by the FCC is Highly Suspect"Item 1980021989-04-201219Statement to the Press, by Dewayne ReadusItem 2080031989-04-171220Scope and Contentsre civil disobedience in face of FCC shutdown;  stapled with "Some Historic Perspectives on Civil Disobedience"Announcement of Press ConferenceItem 2180041989-04-171221Scope and Contentsre arrest for civil disobedience in face of defiance of FCC licensing regulationsIllinois Times, "FCC pulls plug on east side radio station critical of city police"Item 2280051989-04-131222Letter from Bill Blank of Fifth Estate (Detroit, MI)Item 2380061992-10-261223Scope and Contentsre Radio Free DetroitWMAY/WNNS Editorial, "SSU and Pirate Radio"Item 2480071992-12-141224"Paper Tiger TV Extra"Item 258008ca. 19921225Scope and Contentsre videotapes for sale, including one on low power radioFriends of Radio Free Detroit flyerItem 268009ca. 19921226Letter from Larry Talbot of Friends of Radio Free DetroitItem 2780101992-04-071227Scope and Contentsre update on RFDFifth Estate, "Sound of Rebel Radio:  Radio Free Detroit"Item 288011ca. 19921228Statesman-Journal (Salem, OR), "Coast radio station is jewel to seniors," by Frank KingItem 2980121993-08-051229Letter from Harold HallikainenItem 3080131993-11-081230Scope and Contentsre articles submitted to Radio World;  stapled with "Fairness of Spectrum Leases," and "License Free Microbroadcasting"Paper, "Black Liberation Radio," by Ron SakolskyItem 31801419931231Current, "Micro Radio:  Free Speech Struggle"Item 3280151993-121232Slingshot (Berkeley, CA), "Taking back the airwaves - Micro power broadcasting continues to grow"Item 33801619931233Extra, "Micro Radio:  Filling Gaps in the Commercial Broadcast Spectrum," by Jesse DrewItem 34801719931234Interadio (newsletter of AMARC - world association of community radio broadcasters), v.6:no.1Item 35801819941235Scope and ContentsNo article on KantakoLetter to Kantako from Greg Boozell of Chicago public access TVItem 3680191994-03-051236Scope and Contentsre writing an article for AfterimageCover letter from Association of Clandestine Radio Enthusiasts (ACE) periodicalItem 378020ca. 19941237Scope and Contentsre subscription renewalRadio Resistors Bulletin, (general article on micropower radio)Item 3880211994-121238Interadio, v. 6: no. 3Item 39802219941239Scope and ContentsNo article on Kantako"A Tale of Two Broadcasters"Item 4080231240Scope and ContentsSyndicated column by Jeff Cohen and Norman Solomon of FAIR, re Jack Welch of GE-NBC and Stephen Dunifer of Free Radio BerkeleyVoiceItem 4180241995-01-101241Scope and ContentsReview of John Fiske's book, Media Matters:  Everyday Culture and Political ChangeCorrespondence with sympathizers and mediaFolder 1380251989-199013Scope and Contents1 of 2Memo sent to special supporters of WTRAItem 180261990-08-30131Scope and Contentsre update on WTRA and micropower radio movement;  on back is list of names memo was sent toLetter to Peter FranckItem 280271990-08-30132Scope and Contentsre updates on WTRA;  stapled with photocopied picture of Napoleon Williams, and State Journal-Register article on WEAI Jacksonville station manager and him wanting to "help" Kantako, 9 Aug 1990State Journal-Register, "Bush:  TV Marti will go on despite jamming threats"Item 38028133Scope and Contentsre speech in front of National Assn. of BroadcastersWhite House, "Remarks of the President to the National Association of Broadcasters"Item 480291990-04-02134Scope and Contentsre state of American news broadcasting and Radio Free Europe and Radio LibertyPhotocopy of photo of Dewayne Readus, by Ken BurnetteItem 58030135"Action Plan to Free WTRA," by John Hay Tenants' Rights AssociationItem 68031136Decatur Herald &amp; ReviewItem 780321990-09137Scope and Contents"Girl claims man paid her for sex," "Guardian's past goes unchecked," "Police plot probe to kill," re charges against Napoleon Williams of child sexual abuse and alleged plot to kill two police officersLetter to Prof. Colleen Roach of FordhamItem 880331990-11-08138Scope and Contentsre articles on micro-power radioLetter to the Glasgow, Scotland Media GroupItem 980341990-11-08139Scope and Contentsre Kantako caseLetter to Prof. Herbert Schiller of U of CAItem 1080351990-11-081310Scope and Contentsre micro radioLetter to Prof. Debra Evenson of DePaulItem 1180361990-11-081311Scope and Contentsre micro radio movementLetter to Prof. Charles Simmons of CA State UItem 1280371990-11-081312Scope and Contentsre micro radioLetter to Prof. Howard Frederick of CA Institute of Tech.Item 1380381990-11-081313Letter to Prof. Kaarle Nordenstreng of University of Tampere, FinlandItem 1480391990-11-081314Scope and Contentsre Kantako and the micro radio movementLetter to Wolfgang Kleinwatcher of Karl Marx U of Leipzig, GermanyItem 1580401990-11-081315Scope and Contentsre Kantako and the micropower radio movementLetter to George ZellerItem 1680411990-08-271316Scope and Contentsre article in ACE (Association of Clandestine Radio Enthusiasts)Letter from Harald Kuhl of Clandestine Calling (German)Item 1780421990-08-061317Scope and Contentsre reading article on ACE and doing an article for the German publicationLetter to George ZellerItem 1880431990-07-311318Scope and Contentsre information on Kantako's stationLetter from George ZellerItem 1980441990-07-231319Scope and Contentsre upcoming article in ACELetter from George ZellerItem 2080451990-03-021320Scope and Contentsre information on ReadusLetter to Noam ChomskyItem 2180461990-10-111321Scope and Contentsre NPR, AP news, and international media's attention to Kantako's radio station;  stapled with letter from Edward Herman, 10 Sept 1990, re article in Lies of Our Times;  letter to Herman, 27 Aug 1990, re his financial contribution and legal developments; letter to Herman, 3 Aug 1990, re MTV and Playboy attention;  letter from Herman, 30 July 1990, re marginalization of dissident thought in electronic mediaLetter from Edward HermanItem 2280471990-09-151322Scope and Contentsre Townsend giving a paper at the NLG-UDC conference;  stapled with conference leaflet and letter from Herman, 11 June 1989, re supporting Readus and spreading informationLetter to Edward HermanItem 2380481990-09-271323Scope and Contentsre recent events at WTRALetter from Ben BagdikianItem 2480491990-01-211324Scope and Contentsre advice on legal proceedings for WTRA;  stapled with letter to Noam Chomsky, 11 Oct 1990, (see above)Letter from Noam ChomskyItem 2580501990-10-221325Scope and Contentsre Kantako's videotapeLetter from Noam ChomskyItem 2680511990-10-111326Scope and Contents(See above);  stapled with letter from Chomsky, 9 Sept 1990, re Decatur station;  letter to Chomsky, 27 Aug 1990, re legal developments and Decatur station;  letter from Chomsky, 16 July 1990, re micro radio updates;  letter to Chomsky, 9 July 1990, re press contacts "paying off";  letter to Chomsky, 17 Apr 1990, re FCC and attention from magazine articles;  letter from Chomsky, 8 Mar 1990, re "thanks for the video";  letter to Chomsky, 1 Mar 1990, re enclosed video with Readus and Townsend explaining how they plan to spread micropower radio around the country;  letter from Chomsky, 6 Feb1990, re legal advice;  letter to Chomsky, 16 Feb 1990, re WTRA info.; letter from Chomsky, 9 June 1990, re press strategy;  biographical sketch on ChomskyLetter to Dr. Len Jeffries of City College of NYItem 2780521990-10-101327Scope and Contentsenc. materialsLetter to Ron SakolskyItem 2880531990-10-111328Scope and Contentsre national and international coverageLetter to Oscar GandyItem 2980541990-03-141329Scope and Contentsre WTRA updates;  stapled with letter from Gandy, nd, re video;  letter to Gandy, 2 Mar 1990, re videotapeLetter to Sidney WillhelmItem 308055ca. 19901330Scope and Contentsre NPR story;  letter to Willhelm, 27 Aug 1990, re legal developments, Readus' new name - Kantako, and Decatur station;  stapled with letter to Willhelm, 8 May 1990, re playing tapes of his books on the air, legal developments, and use of university vans for Marcus Garvey Summer Freedom School;  letter from Willhelm, 4 May 1990, re Bill Wilson's sociological theories, white elites genocide against blacks; letter to Willhelm, 6 Mar 1990, re genocide conference, FCC;  letter from Willhelm, 3 Mar 1990, re genocide convention, Readus, and black incarceration rates;  letter from Willhelm, 5 Dec 1989, re black socio-economic conditions;  page on black economic conditionsLetter to George ParsonsItem 3180561990-08-271331Scope and Contentsre legal and radio developmentsLetter to Alderman McGee of Milwaukee, WIItem 3280571990-05-031332Scope and Contentsre Readus' model of micro-radio and Alderman Melvin Platt interviewLetter to Ward ChurchillItem 3380581990-04-231333Scope and Contentsre interview and contact with activistsLetter to Rep. Richard Durbin from Richard Smith of the FCCItem 3480591990-03-291334Scope and Contentsre licensing of low powered radio stations;  stapled with letter to Townsend from Durbin, 14 Mar 1990, re WTRALetter to Steve LeBlanc of V90Item 3580601990-03-141335Scope and Contentsre interview;  stapled with letter from LeBlanc to Readus, 24 Feb 1990, re interview;  press release from V90, nd;  Boston Phoenix, 22 Dec 1989, "The Situationist Local"Letter from Lerone Bennett, Jr. of EbonyItem 3680611990-01-181336Scope and Contentsre rejection of article on ReadusLetter from Julius Chambers of NAACP Legal Defense and Educational FundItem 3780621990-01-311337Scope and Contentsre rejection of help for ReadusLetter to Spike Lee (filmmaker)Item 3880631990-01-251338Scope and Contentsre his help for spreading the model of Readus' micro radioLetter from John CriglerItem 3980641990-01-181339Scope and Contentsre rejection of legal help for ReadusLetter from Manning Marable of U. of Colorado at BoulderItem 4080651990-01-181340Scope and Contentsre legal adviceLetter to Manning Marable from Townsend and ReadusItem 4180661989-07-141341Scope and Contentsre article in "Along the Color Line"Letter from Manning MarableItem 4280671989-06-261342Scope and Contentsre drafting an article on Readus for his "Along the Color Line" column;  stapled with draftLetter to Lynn ? of National Federation of Community BroadcastersItem 4380681989-11-091343Scope and Contentsre her possible legal assistanceCorrespondence with sympathizers and mediaFolder 1480691987, 1989, 1990, 199214Scope and Contents2 of 2Letter from George ? of Quincy, ILItem 180701989-10-21141Scope and Contentsre advice to "be watchful and reasonably paranoid" of those in power;  stapled with New York, "Sweatshirt Justice:  How the War on Crime is Expanding to Crush Some Rights," 2 Oct 1989Letter from Andrea Taylor of the Ford FoundationItem 280711989-07-11142Scope and Contentsre inability to support of establishment of low watt radio stations throughout U.S.Letter from Benjamin Hooks of NAACPItem 380721989-06-29143Scope and Contentsre "it would be inappropriate for me to become involved" in support of low watt radioLetter from Matthew Bromberg of Business and Society ReviewItem 480731989-06-26144Scope and Contentsre Townsend writing an article for the journalLetter from secretary of Bill Cosby (actor-comedian)Item 580741989-06-22145Scope and Contentsre the "impossibility" of his support of the concept of low watt radioLetter from Sen. Paul SimonItem 680751989-06-21146Scope and Contentsre WTRA situationLetter to Readus from JoNina Abron of Black ScholarItem 780761989-06-16147Scope and Contentsre submitting an articleLetter from Lerone Bennet of EbonyItem 880771989-06-16148Scope and Contentsre rejection of article on WTRALetter from Julius Chambers of NAACP Legal Defense FundItem 980781989-06-12149Scope and Contentsre possible assistance for WTRA.  "Never heard anything" Townsend later wrote on this letterNote on National Urban League and SCLC (Southern Christian Leadership Conference) never responding to their lettersItem 1080791410Letter to the ProgressiveItem 1180801989-04-181411Scope and Contentsre possible articleFMedia, "FM Industry News"Item 1280811989-091412ACE, "Pirate Radio Directory-1990 Edition"Item 138082ca. 1990-011413Black EnterpriseItem 1480831989-011414Scope and Contents"Broadcast News:  Though FCC policies to encourage minority media ownership are under siege, these entrepreneurs are meeting the challenge of staying on the air"New York Daily News MagazineItem 1580841989-12-171415Scope and Contents"Smokey and the Pirate"Note on minority radio information from NABItem 1680851416St. Louis Post-Dispatch, "Clemency appeal gets no response"Item 1780861990-02-061417Scope and Contents(WTRA covered this case of Lee Otis Griffin who claimed he was wrongly convicted of murder and asking to be released from prison);  stapled with Post-Dispatch, "Pickets Ask Governor To Free Man Convicted of 3 Killings,";  letter to Readus from Griffin, 12 Feb 1990, re: circumstances surrounding his trial;  State Journal-Register, "Rally calls on governor for clemency decision," 6 Feb 1990Letter to Campaign for Human Development from ReadusItem 1880871989-06-281418Scope and Contentsre never receiving forms for reapplying for funds from this Catholic charity (post-it note says, "How we lost $30,000…";  letter to CHD from Readus and Townsend, 28 June 1989, re Noam Chomsky's support and legal help; letter to Readus from Springfield Catholic Charities, 11 July 1989, re CHD grant check and issues holding up that check;  letter to CHD from Readus and Townsend, 14 July 1989, re how CHD funds were expended;  letter to Springfield Catholic Charities from Readus, 25 July 1989, re WTRA, community support for Tenants Rights Association, and leadership training for TRA;  letter to Readus from Sister Linda Hayes of Sacred Heart Convent, 2 Oct 1989, re reasons for cutoff of grant fundsNote on Broadcast Services of Pawnee, ILItem 1980881419USA Today, "How radio turns us on" bar graphItem 2080891420Dimension Cable FM Stereo ListItem 218090ca. 1980s1421Scope and ContentsWith black radio notationsChicago Tribune, :"WGN radio back to top of Arbitron ratings"Item 2280911987-10-101422Scope and ContentsWith black radio notationsChicago Sun-Times, "Chicago Housing Authority weighs in-house radio"Item 2380921987-10-121423Chicago Tribune, "Costly radio station swamps CHA in static"Item 2480931987-09-281424"Broadcast Media Positions in Southern States and California"Item 2580941425Note from Ron Sakolsky on "cheap" radio equipment from Panaxis ProductionsItem 268095ca. late 1980s1426Copy of entry on Telecommunications Research and Action CenterItem 2780961427Petition for WTRAItem 2880971989-11-151428Scope and Contentsre unfair FCC regulationsCivil Disobedience (monograph), Paul Harris, ed.Item 2980981429The WireItem 30809919901430Scope and ContentsAdvertising the national summit on genocide;  stapled with letter to The Wire, ca. 1990, re Sidney Willhelm as speakerNote on WTRA issuesItem 3181001431Scope and Contentsre issues of day care, medical clinic, police brutality cases, critiquing NAACP and Urban League, Madison St., et alNLG-UDC Media Accountability Under International Law SymposiumItem 3281011989-06-141432LPB (?) newsletterItem 3381021433Scope and Contents"Considerations in Educational FM Broadcast Equipment"LPB (?) newsletterItem 3481031434Scope and Contents"Campus Radio—AM or FM"NFCB NewsItem 3581041988-101435Scope and ContentsNewsletter"Participant Membership in the NFCB"Item 368105ca. 19891436Scope and Contentsre representation, consultation, dues, et al"NFCB Associate Membership Program"Item 378106ca. 19891437"Radio Activity" column, by Chris MerrickItem 3881071438Scope and Contentsre community radioAMARC newsletter, "Pirate (Readus) challenges FCC"Item 3981081990-011439Draft of article AMARC newsletter, untitled, by Bruce GirardItem 4081091440Scope and Contentsre WTRALetter from Bruce GirardItem 4181101989-11-011441Scope and Contentsre AMARC article;  stapled with AMARC "Who We Are" membership form, ca. 1989Letter to Readus from GirardItem 4281111989-10-311442Scope and Contentsre AMARC membershipUDC Democratic Communique, "Grassroots Communication with Community Radio"Item 43811219891443Letter to BLR newsletter editor from Laurie Ouellette of Harper'sItem 4481131444Scope and Contentsre publicity for BLRCorrespondence, alphabetical by letter writer A-GFolder 158114199015Scope and Contents1 of 3 Alphabetically by surname of letter  writer; includes other items such as cash donations list, videotapes mailing list, and grassroots people list.Sub-Series 1Sub-Series 18121Scope and ContentsThe following list shows the names of letter writers in rough alphabetical order. Generally, these letters request tapes and latest updates on Kantako and his station, as well as donating money for the cause.  Some wish to start up a station.  Responses are written by Townsend.  Almost all letters date from 1990, with a few from 1994.Adebule, Lemmy - Los Angeles, CAItem 18122151Alexander, Danny - Overland, KSItem 28123152Alden, Tom - San FranciscoItem 38124153Allen, Dave - La Canada, CAItem 48125154Amos, Kevin - Pittsburgh, PAItem 58126155Anderson, Ray - Wichita, KSItem 68127156Askari, Iri - Los Angeles, CAItem 78128157Athearn, Steve - Jobstown, NJItem 88129158Bennet, James - University of ArkansasItem 98130159Berg, Bernie - Easton, PAItem 1081311510Bettencourt, Michael - Manchester, NHItem 1181321511Bluestone, William - Woodbridge, NJItem 1281331512Bost, Walt - University of North CarolinaItem 1381341513Bracken, Rob - Burlington, NCItem 1481351514Branfman, Judy - Boston, MAItem 1581361515Brian (?) - Warwick, RIItem 1681371516Brockway, Sandi - Macrocosm USA, Cambria, CAItem 1781381517Brooks, Shirley - Detroit, MIItem 1881391518Brown, Bill - Stanford UniversityItem 1981401519Brundige, Akeeda - Lincoln, NEItem 2081411520Butzon, Mark - Bradley UniversityItem 2181421521Shepp-Cardoza, Ana - Amherst, MAItem 2281431522Carney, Brian - Athens, GAItem 2381441523Colvin, Kenneth - Chicago, ILItem 2481451524Cooper, Marty - Citrus Heights, CAItem 2581461525DVS Communications, John Arthur, Belfast, NYItem 2681471526Dacus, Wesley - Omaha, NEItem 2781481527Dash, Mike - Seattle, WAItem 2881491528Daima, Tumika (Joy Williams) - St. Louis, MOItem 2981501529Danton, William - Landon, OHItem 3081511530Doherty, Kaleigh - Framingham, MAItem 3181521531Drassler, Leo - Kenosha, WIItem 3281531532Eric ? - Madison, WIItem 3381541533Forkner, Sue - Hazel Crest, ILItem 3481551534Frezza, Joe - Detroit Metro Times, Berkley, MIItem 3581561535Franle, Dave - We the People, South Bend, INItem 3681571536Gee, Philip - ?Item 3781581537George, Alexander - Amherst, GAItem 3881591538Goodman, Charles - Grover Beach, CAItem 3981601539Gorin, Zeev - Bradley UniversityItem 4081611540Unsigned hate letterItem 181151990-08-27151Scope and ContentsWith photocopyCash donations listItem 28116152Memo to supporters of WTRAItem 381171990-08-30153Scope and Contentsre microradio update"NPR tapes sent to" listItem 48118154"Videotapes sent to" listItem 581191990155Scope and ContentsStapled with cover letter to sendee"Grassroots People" listItem 68120156Correspondence, alphabetical by letter writer G-MFolder 168162199016Scope and Contents2 of 3Gowens, Pat - Milwaukee, WIItem 18163161Gunther, James - Temple City, CAItem 28164162Haney, Michael - McLoud, OKItem 38165163Hargitai, Henrik - HungaryItem 48166164Harrison, Richard - Winter Park, FLItem 58167165Haypenny Press and Dawn Conti - West Paterson, NJItem 68168166Hefter, Richard - Chicago, ILItem 78169167Herman, Ed - MAItem 88170168Herrada, Julie - Detroit, MIItem 98171169Hofeling, Keven - Taylorsville, UTItem 1081721610International Music Workers Union - Tucson, AZItem 1181731611Jackson, Lee - Richmond, VAItem 1281741612Johnston, Dick &amp; Mary - ?Item 1381751613Jones, Brandon Astor - Jackson, GAItem 1481761614Jordan, Val - Chicago, ILItem 1581771615Kearney, Elizabeth - Gardiner, MTItem 1681781616Kelly, Charles Rick - Dallas, TXItem 1781791617Keul, Jim - Anaheim, CAItem 1881801618Kogawa, Tetsuo - Tokyo, JapanItem 1981811619Scope and Contents(includes Japanese article on Kantako)Kubweza, Jahi - Richmond, VAItem 2081821620Kuhl, Guillermo - Daly City, CAItem 2181831621Laursen, Chris - Tofield, Alberta, CanadaItem 2281841622Le Count, Suzanne - Forest Knolls, CAItem 2381851623Levi, Jamila - Pittsburgh, PA (of Free Mumia Abu-Jamal)Item 2481861624Lewis, George - San Luis Obispo, CAItem 2581871625Lindner, Ron - West Springfield, MAItem 2681881626Marignay, Bisola - Chicago IL (of Flame Productions)Item 2781891627Massa, Michael - Nederland, COItem 2881901628Maxwell, L.E. - St. Louis, MOItem 2981911629McClellan, Cheryl - Detroit, MI (of Metroplex Records)Item 3081921630McDonald, Tony - Detroit, MIItem 3181931631McGuff, Luke - Seattle, WAItem 3281941632Mendoza, Gloria - Los Angeles, CAItem 3381951633Merdinian, Christine - Laramie, WYItem 3481961634Correspondence, alphabetical by letter writer M-YFolder 178197199017Scope and Contents3 of 3Merrill, Frank - Macomb, ILItem 18198171Mucha, Dan - Hudson, OHItem 28199172Muhammed, Halif - Chicago, ILItem 38200173Myers, J.P. - Long Beach, CAItem 48201174Nigro, Brian - Tempe, AZ (Alternative Voice)Item 58202175Pace, Christopher - Juneau, AKItem 68203176Pascucci, John - Sheridan, ORItem 78204177Peacott, Joe - Boston, MAItem 88205178Peterson, Brian - Elgin, ILItem 98206179Pierce, Mark - Sun Valley, CAItem 1082071710Porter, Tyrone - Quincy, ILItem 1182081711Potts, Bert - Chicago, ILItem 1282091712Powell, Todd - Chicago, ILItem 1382101713Power, Hilton - Lewiston, MEItem 1482111714Prince, Tony - Oak Park, ILItem 1582121715Pringle, Chris - Ft. Lauderdale, FLItem 1682131716Ra, Amen - Chicago, ILItem 1782141717Radio Pirate-Woman - Galway City, IrelandItem 1882151718Razzi, Cactus - Santa Barbara, CAItem 1982161719Readus, Julius - Memphis, TNItem 2082171720Scope and Contents(Dewayne's father)Rech, Mary Ellen - Livonia, MIItem 2182181721Reveille, Tom - San Francisco, CA (Radio Free Venice)Item 2282191722Revis, Lamar - Richmond, VAItem 2382201723Rodman, Gil - Champaign, ILItem 2482211724Ross, Clinton - Isla Vista, CAItem 2582221725Ryan, Pat - Kirkwood, CAItem 2682231726Sanders, Mike - Dallas, TX (Midnight Radio)Item 2782241727Schoedel, Ronald - Maumee, OHItem 2882251728Scope and Contents(starting a small station)Schwing, Lee - Los Angeles, CAItem 2982261729Scope and Contents(addressed to Christian Slater)Sellick, Matthew - Milwaukee, WIItem 3082271730Sharif, A.K. - Omaha, NE ("Rockin' Ronald Reagan Rap")Item 3182281731Sheldon, Arroyo ("EXIA") - Indiana, PAItem 3282291732Shields, Steven - Whitewater, WI (Assistant Professor)Item 3382301733Stewart, Clinton - Scooba, MSItem 3482311734Stone, Ralph - Missoula, MT (former SSU professor)Item 3582321735Strowig, Jim - West Bend, WIItem 3682331736Students for Social Revolution at U. of CA Santa BarbaraItem 3782341737Swartz, Joel - Rochester, NYItem 3882351738Scope and Contents(radio broadcaster)Taylor, Nat - Oakland, CAItem 3982361739Trummell, Kevin - Springfield, MOItem 4082371740Scope and Contents(1994 e-mail)Tucker, Jim - Arcata, CAItem 4182381741Scope and Contents(starting a radio station)Turner, Mary - ?Item 4282391742Wilson, Ernie - CA (Panaxis)Item 4382401743Verbeek, Christiaan - San Diego, CAItem 4482411744Scope and Contents(starting a station)Viera, Eric - West Barnstable, MAItem 4582421745Watkins, Marlin - CAItem 4682431746Wilson, Jo Ann - Washington, D.C.Item 4782441747Wood, Robert - ?Item 4882451748XYZ, Carlo - Comptche, CAItem 4982461749Scope and Contents(starting a station)Yarbray, Tony - Corpus Christi, TXItem 5082471750Yoder, Andrew - Slanvesville, WVItem 5182481751Correspondence, alphabetical by letter writer A-WFolder 1882491991-199618Scope and Contents(Alphabetically by surname of addressee. All letters written by Townsend.)Adams, Nina (SSU/UIS professor)Item 182501992-01-10181Scope and Contentsre academic legitimacy of BLRBellecourt, VernonItem 282511991-09-13182Scope and Contentsre his "radio adventure"Bennett, Dr.Item 382521992-02-18183Scope and Contentsre "pioneering writing"Blackwell, Robert (Director of Springfield Housing Authority)Item 482531991-02-20184Scope and Contentsre "letting Kantako do his thing"Cameron, Mr.Item 582541992-01-30185Scope and Contentsre enclosed materialsChomsky, NoamItem 682551992-03-22186Scope and Contentsre article on micro-radio movement;  14 Dec 1992, re interview on BLR;  18 Dec 1992, re enclosed tape;  6 Jan 1995, re spread of micro-radio, and possibility of Chomsky giving a speech at SSU (enc. of ACE subscription form)Coliver, SandraItem 782561991-11-05187Scope and Contents(Article 19, London's International Centre Against Censorship), re their support and NLG materialsCooper, MaryItem 882571992-12-14188Scope and Contentsre Bo Gritz, the U.S. government's involvement in the drug trade, and Chomsky interviewDavis, MikeItem 982581992-10-08189Scope and Contentsre interview about weed and seed programDesai, BarneyItem 1082591991-11-011810Scope and Contents(Corresponding Secretary of Pan Africanist Congress), re spreading micro-radio movement to AzaniaFiske, JohnItem 1182601994-03-251811Scope and Contents(U. of Wisconsin), re donation, and his book Power Plays donation, and his book Power PlaysFranck, PeterItem 1282611991-12-131812Scope and Contents(NLG), re Tom Reveille and Japan micro-radioHerman, EdItem 1382621992-04-161813Scope and Contents(Manufacturing Consent),Tetsua Kogawa's micro transmitter;  17 Nov 1993, re Stephen Dunifer (cc: Dunifer)Hunter-Gault, CharleneItem 1482631992-07-271814Scope and Contents(PBS' MacNeil/Lehrer News Hour), re interview with Kantako for her "Can We All Get Along?" seriesJackson, TerranceItem 1582641992-12-141815Scope and Contentsre his bookKogawa, TetsuaItem 1682651992-11-021816Scope and Contents(Professor), re his work and Paper Tiger TVLeCount, SuzanneItem 1782661991-08-231817Scope and Contentsre updates on BLRLeisner, RogerItem 1882671992-01-031818Scope and Contentsre his Radio Free Maine and broadcasting his tapes;  letter from Leisner, nd, re tapes of radical scholars;  enc. lists of tapesRadio Free LoisaidaItem 1982681992-02-221819Scope and Contentsre their groundbreaking micro-radio effortsLewis, GeorgeItem 2082691991-08-231820Scope and Contentsre donation and updatesMarable, Dr. ManningItem 2182701991-09-041821Scope and Contentsre establishment of "Freedom Schools" and Marcus Garvey SchoolPan African Telecommunications UnionItem 2282711991-10-171822Scope and Contentsre BLR informationOnslaught (white supremacist organization)Item 2382721992-02-111823Scope and Contentsre wanting to know more about their organization;  enc. Onslaught propaganda;  Townsend letter to Professor Judy Everson, 7 Feb 1992, re Onslaught "message" stuck in his office doorRadio Free DetroitItem 2482731992-02-221824Scope and Contentsre NLG, legal advice, and donation to RFDRick ?Item 2582741991-02-191825Scope and Contentsre BLR informationRoach, ColleenItem 2682751991-12-131826Scope and Contents(NLG), re micro-radio movement, Japan, Turkey and MacBride roundtableSauda, TykymItem 2782761991-08-291827Scope and Contentsre building more African traditions in the freedom schoolSavage, BryanItem 2882771992-03-241828Scope and Contentsre "Kantako clause" in new leaseSwartz, JoelItem 2982781992-11-021829Scope and Contentsre his commitment to grassroots radioTucker, BenItem 3082791991-12-111830Scope and ContentsCopy of money order from himWillhelm, SidneyItem 3182801992-04-091831Scope and Contentsre his speech at SSU in June on genocide against blacks, and Gov. Edgar eliminating the general assistance welfare program;  19 Apr 1992, re Shadows book;  3 Jan 1992, re Amos Wilson's Black on Black Crime and Kantako co-hosting a radio talk show from Washington D.C.Wilkes, JonItem 3282811992-02-211832Scope and Contentsre photo art for posterWilson, ErnieItem 3382821991-05-011833Scope and Contentsre new transmitter that he could sell;  on same letter, Wilson writes that FCC has been "troublesome" and cannot advise them on transmitterWyatt, TahirItem 3482831992-01-301834Scope and Contentsre contact for him to meet in Philadelphia about information on BLRYehoaddanItem 3582841992-01-301835Scope and Contentsre tape of Yahweh Ben Yahweh interview on BLRIncoming correspondenceFolder 1982851991-199619Haney, NickItem 18286191Scope and ContentsBothell, WA, re information on BLROngoren, MahmutItem 282871991-11-15192Scope and ContentsHuman Rights Foundation of Turkey, re establishment of micro-radio station in AnkaraAlvarez, MaxItem 382881992-01-18193Scope and ContentsIndependent filmmaker, re his suggestions on how to go about filming Kantako and his familyTalbot, Larry of Radio Free DetroitItem 482891992-04-07194Scope and Contentsre updates on their station; RFD leaflet and Fifth Estate articleShabazz, Muhammad Al AkimItem 582901992-05-21195Scope and ContentsLetter to Kantako re listening to his broadcasts on police brutality and the Weed and Seed programChomsky, NoamItem 682911992-12-28196Scope and Contentsre interview with Kantako;  22 July 1993, re BLR T-shirtSmith, JoelItem 782921994-09-23197Scope and Contentsre London's Illuminations Television doing a piece on KantakoYoder, AndrewItem 882931995-01-27198Scope and Contents(ACE magazine) re his book Pirate Radio Stations:  Tuning In To Underground Broadcasts and request for permission to use Ken Burnette's photo of Kantako;  stapled with order form from Welfare Warriors;  Steve ? of Otisville, MI, nd, re starting a station;  Keith Robb of Cuyahoga Falls, OH, nd, re Noisy Concept doing an article on Kantako;  Geraldine Sopryeh of Chicago, IL, nd, needing information;  Joseph Kouad of Korhogo, West Africa (to Ron Sakolsky), 2 Nov 1993, re radio transmitter;  B.J.B of Louisville, KY, 2 May 1994, re starting a station;  Larry Stoley of Milwaukee, WI, 5 June 1996, re  his book Free Radio Broadcasting and interview for a chapter on Kantako; Sundiata Acoli of White Deer, PA, 8 Feb 1995, re information on BLR; Milt Shaw of KDIA Oakland, CA, 8 Jan 1996, re information on BLRSwartz, JoelItem 982941996-07-11199Scope and ContentsSending back a repaired ampKunz, Art and Vautrain, WillItem 1082951996-111910Scope and Contents(UIS students), re starting a station; stapled with 3 Nov 1996, re meeting with WUIS personnel on gaining student access on the station"Black Liberation Radio:  A Case Study of the Micro-Radio Movement"Folder 208296199220Scope and ContentsPaper given by Drs. Steven Shields and Robert Ogles at the Popular Culture AssociationPower Plays, Power WorksFolder 21829721Scope and ContentsMonograph by John Fiske, includes numerous mentions of KantakoPress releases, Black Liberation Radio newsletters, memos to supportersFolder 2282981990-199222Periodical articles on DeWayne Readus (later name Mbanna Kantako) and his radio stationFolder 2382991989, 199023Scope and Contents1 of 7"Black Liberation Radio"Item 18300231Scope and ContentsBy Michael Townsend and Husayn Al-Kurdi, written for unknown publicationX CommunicatorItem 28301232Scope and Contents"Black Liberation Radio," by Ron SakolskyMacrocosm USA:  Environmental, Political, and Social SolutionsItem 38302233Handbook with Directories (monograph)Item 48303234Scope and Contents"Radio Activist Mbanna Kantako:  In His Own Words," Sandi Brockway (ed.)"Mbanna Kantako and the Micro-Radio Movement"Item 58304235Scope and ContentsBy Townsend"Blind man telecasts defiance"Item 68305236Scope and ContentsAssociated Press release, unknown newspaper"Pirate Radio"Item 78306237Scope and ContentsFifth Estate (Detroit, MI newspaper)"Passion for Radio:  Radio Waves and Community" (press release for monograph)Item 88307238Scope and ContentsBruce Girard, ed., story by Ron Sakolsky;  Spanish version:  "El Regreso De La Comunidad A La Radio:  El Nacimiento del Moviemiento Microradial en los Estados Unidos" (published by AMARC);  English version:  "Zoom Black Magic Liberation Radio: Birth of the micro-radio movement in the USA"State Journal-Register, "FCC turns off Hay Homes radio station"Item 983081989-04-12239Scope and Contents"Readus promises to keep broadcasting until arrested"Illinois Issues, "Community Organizing Downstate:  Conflicts and Coalitions"Item 1083092310Scope and ContentsBy Cheryl Frank, June 1989.  Includes several paragraphs on conflicting approaches of Frank McNeil and Readus in tackling socio-political problems.Final Call, "Guerilla radio:  Underground radio station operator uses 'sneak attacks' to educate community"Item 1183101989-09-112311State Journal-Register, "Judgment sought against Readus for unlicensed radio broadcasting"Item 1283111989-11-102312Kurier (alternative German magazine that focuses on low-watt radio)Item 13831219902313Scope and Contents"Radio von  Unten:  WTRA Radio Springfield - Beginn einer Revolutionierung des Rundfunksystems der USA?"Illinois Times, "United States vs. WTRA:  From a Hay Homes apartment, Dewayne Readus and some kids operate a tiny radio station that can't be heard more than a mile away.  Why does the federal government want to shut it down?"Item 1483131990-012314Scope and ContentsBy Richard Shereikis (SSU professor), 3 copiesPeriodical articles on DeWayne Readus (later name Mbanna Kantako) and his radio stationFolder 248314199024Scope and Contents2 of 7Artpaper, "WTRA-FM:  One-Watt Radio"Item 183151990-01241Scope and ContentsBy TownsendPeople's Tribune, "Zoom Black Magic is on the air:  WTRA Radio won't be stopped"Item 283161990-02-12242Illinois State Fair Professional Art Exhibition pamphlet,Item 383171990243Scope and ContentsIncludes entry of "Dewayne Readus Activist" photographRock &amp; Roll Confidential, "Broadcast Confidential (column)"Item 483181990-02244Scope and Contentsre Zoom Black Magic link with Black Rose of Fresno, CAChicago Tribune, "Rights vs. privilege:  'Pirate radio' operators charge the  FCC with restricting free speech"Item 583191990-02-06245Fmedia, "Other Small-Print Happenings and the FM Industry News (column)"Item 683201990-04246In These Times, "Dewayne Readus:  radio rebel"Item 783211990-04247Democratic Communique, "WTRA Under Fire"Item 883221990248Scope and ContentsBy TownsendSound Choice, "Radio Activist Defies FCC"Item 983231990249Scope and ContentsBy David CiafardiniCultural Democracy, "Radio-Activity:  Community Animation You Can Do"Item 10832419902410Scope and Contents(Interview with Sakolsky), "Radio Activist Dewayne Readus:  In His Own Words" (remarks excerpted from the Chicago Guild meeting)Rock &amp; Roll Confidential, "Kids, Do Try This At Home"Item 1183251990-052411Scope and ContentsStapled with letter from editor Lee Ballinger to TownsendMother Jones, "Radio Free Radio"Item 1283261990-062412Scope and ContentsBy Rich ShereikisDetroit Metro Times, "Liberation Radio:  Who Says Your Community Can't Have Its Own Radio Station"Item 1383271990-062413Scope and ContentsBy Thom JurekWireless (WEFT Champaign, IL newsletter), "Pirate Community Radio in  Springfield"Item 14832819902414Columbia Journalism Review, "Making Radio Waves:  A Pirate in the Projects"Item 15832919902415Scope and ContentsBy Rich Shereikis;  included are negatives of the front cover of CJRZ Magazine, "Press Release"Item 16833019902416Scope and Contents(Readus and the FCC)State Journal-Register, "Jacksonville station manager says he'd like to help Kantako"Item 1783311990-08-092417Scope and ContentsBy Hilary SapersteinACE, "WTRA Semi-Clandestine in Springfield, Illinois"Item 1883321990-082418State Journal-Register, "Making Waves:  Radio renegade gets airplay of his own"Item 1983331990-08-082419Scope and ContentsBy SapersteinRadio and Records, "Illinois Radio Pirate Defies FCC"Item 20833419902420Scope and ContentsOn back side of this photocopy is LA Weekly, "Free Christian Slater," 24-30 Aug 1990 Playboy, "Newsbreaks" (one paragraph item comparing Christian Slater's movie to Readus, igniting a storm of mail), Sept 1990Daily Chronicle (DeKalb/Sycamore, IL), "Tiny station at odds with feds"Item 2183351990-09-232421Scope and ContentsAP release by Dennis ConradPeriodical articles on DeWayne Readus (later name Mbanna Kantako) and his radio stationFolder 258336199025Scope and Contents3 of 7St. Louis Post-Dispatch, "Making Waves:  Radio Pirate Snubs FCC"Item 183371990-09-16251Scope and ContentsBy Kathleen BestACE, "WTRA Update"Item 283381990-10252Scope and Contentsp. 20SSU Weekly (official campus newsletter), "Faculty/staff activities"Item 383391990-10-04253Scope and Contentsre Shereikis writing for various publications on ReadusAdult &amp; Continuing Education Today, "Hidden Hits"Item 483401990-10-22254Scope and ContentsColumn by John Ohliger, re Kantako vs. FCCVersion 90 (journal), "Revolution Radio:  Dewayne Readus and WTRA pump up the volume despite the FCC's fear of a black radio station"Item 583411990255Scope and Contentsp. 16, by Steve LeBlancPeriodical articles on DeWayne Readus (later name Mbanna Kantako) and his radio stationFolder 26503551990-199126Scope and Contents4 of 7Periodical articles on DeWayne Readus (later name Mbanna Kantako) and his radio stationFolder 2750356199127Scope and Contents5 of 7Periodical articles on DeWayne Readus (later name Mbanna Kantako) and his radio stationFolder 2850357199128Scope and Contents6 of 7Baur's Opera House ExhibitFolder 29755381989-199229Scope and ContentsSworn testimony and evidence of racist practices at Baur's Opera House.Sievers LetterFolder 3075539198730Scope and ContentsA letter exhibiting racist sentiments. Attached note from Townsend explains some of the peculiarities surrounding the letter.TRA - John Hay Tenant Rights Association LogoItem 1503581Scope and ContentsLaminated poster (tucked along side of box).Black Liberation Radio, Springfield, IL LogoItem 2503592Scope and ContentsLaminated poster (tucked along side of box).FREE WTRA LogoItem 3503603Scope and ContentsLaminated poster (tucked along side of box).Box 2Box 28342Periodical articles on DeWayne Readus (later name Mbanna Kantako) and his radio stationFolder 2983531992-199729Scope and Contents(7 of 7 folders)Social Anarchism, "Anarchy on the Airwaves:  A Brief History of the Micro-Radio Movement in the USA"Item 183901992291Scope and ContentsBy Ron Sakolsky, p.5, no.17Mondo, "Pirate Media"Item 283911993-11292Scope and ContentsBy Wes ThomasMEDIAforum (German), "Nachbarschaftsradio in den USA"Item 383921993-10293Scope and ContentsBy Harald KuhlOption ("Music Alternatives"), "Pirate Radio:  The FCC's War on Free Speech"Item 483931994294Scope and ContentsBy Jason FineAfterimage ("publication of the visual studies workshop")Item 583941994295Scope and Contents"The Revolution Will  Be Microwaved:  The FCC, Microwatt Radio, and Telecommunication Networks," by Greg Boozell (program director at Chicago Access Corporation)Nation, "Rebel Radio Versus the FCC"Item 683951995-02-20296Scope and Contents(Alexander Cockburn's Beat the Devil column),High Performance, "Black Liberation Radio:  Struggling For Air"Item 783961995297Z Magazine, "Challenging the Manufacture of Consent"Item 883971995-10298Scope and ContentsBy Steve Ongerth &amp; Radio Free BerkeleyRock &amp; Rap Confidential, "Radio Wars"Item 983981996-06299Scope and Contentsre California pirates;  mentions Napoleon Williams but not KantakoMediated Messages and African-American Culture (monograph)Item 10839919962910Scope and Contents"(Chapter 13) Empowering Voices:  KUCB and Black Liberation Radio," by Sharon Albert-Honore (includes section on Kantako)"Pirate Radio Kills the Ruling Class Stars," comic bookItem 11840019962911Scope and Contentsby Ken Wong?, Chicago, Illinois (photocopy)Transcript of interview of Kantako by Sue Gardner of CBC RadioItem 1284011997-012912Scope and ContentsToronto, Canada (printout of e-mail)Newpspaper clippingsItem 13840219972913Scope and Contentsre eviction of Kantako from the Hay Homes, from the Illinois State Journal-Register and Illinois Times (photocopies)"Kantako Raises Human Rights Issue as Hay Homes Slated for Demolition"Item 14840319972914Scope and ContentsArticle by Sheila Nopper of Toronto, CanadaThe Bleeding Edge, "The People's Choice: Afrikan Liberation Radio"Item 15840419962915"Radio's Renegade / Low-Watt 'Pirate' Fights F.C.C. Rules"Item 1684051997-12-082916Scope and ContentsNew York Times, re Stephen Dunifer of Berkeley, CA.Bibliographies of WTRA &amp; Black Liberation Radio ArticlesFolder 3084061989-199230Scope and ContentsIncludes a list of media activist resources and Association of Micro-Power Broadcasters (AMPB) Report #43.Micropower Email/Networking Contacts &amp; Mailing ListsFolder 31503712000-200131Athearn, Steve.  Micro TV.Folder 32503611992-10-1732Scope and ContentsLetter from Steve Athearn, Jobstown, NJ to Mbanna Kantako et al, re: building a low-power TV station; includes photographs and diagrams explaining the Micro-TV concepts.Newspaper and Periodical Articles on Human Rights RadioFolder 33503721988-199233Newspaper and Periodical Articles on Human Rights RadioFolder 34503731993-199534Newspaper and Periodical Articles on Human Rights RadioFolder 35503741996-199735Web and Periodical Articles on Human Rights Radio and Micro-Radio, 1998Folder 365036236Scope and Contents(1 of 3 folders)  Roughly chronological.Printouts from web sitesItem 18407361Scope and ContentsRadio Resistor's Bulletin
Wired News
San Francisco Liberation Radio 93.7 FM
Soundprint Media Center
www.radio4all.org
Free Radio Berkeley Update
Microradio News—Grassroots News Network Report
Black Liberation Radio Update
Decatur-Herald and Review
NYFMA
SHADOW 38 STEAL THIS RADIO!
www.freeradio.com
Grassroots News &amp; Media Conference &amp; Culture Jam
Toward Freedom Notebook
San Francisco Chronicle News
Philadelphia Inquirer OnlinePhotocopies from books, newspapers and periodicalsItem 28408362Scope and ContentsZ Magazine
Seizing the Airwaves: A Free Radio Handbook
Decatur Herald &amp; Review
Utne Reader
Radio World
VibeWeb and Periodical Articles on Human Rights Radio and Micro-Radio, 1998Folder 375036337Scope and Contents(2 of 3 folders)  Roughly chronological.
Printouts from websites:  Forum, www.radio4all.org, Free Radio Memphis, Micro Radio Speech, Black Cat Radio, Rougecom, SHADOW 38 STEAL THIS RADIO!, Free Radio Berkeley.Web and Periodical Articles on Human Rights Radio and Micro-Radio, 1998Folder 385036438Scope and Contents(3 of 3 folders)  Roughly chronological.
Printouts from websites:   NYFMA, SHADOW 38 STEAL THIS RADIO!, www.radio4all.org, Pirate Radio, Fine Print, Memphis Flyer, San Francisco Liberation Radio, Micro-Watt Radio, Afrikan Frontline Network.Web and Periodical Articles on Human Rights Radio and Micro-Radio, 1998-1999Folder 395037539Sakolsky, Ron and Dunifer, Stephen.  Seizing the Airwaves: A Free Radio Handbook, 1998Item 150376391Printouts of website articlesItem 250377392Newspaper and periodical articlesItem 350378393Web and Periodical Articles on Human Rights Radio and Micro-Radio, 1999Folder 405036540Scope and Contents(1 of 2 folders)  Roughly chronological.
Printouts from websites:  www.radio4all.org, Committee on Democratic Communications, Homeless People's Network, Rogue Radio Research, Emerging Micro Media, www.386haves.com, MetroActive Arts, www.we-2.com, Zone Blaster, New York Free Media Alliance, Radio Mutiny, 88.7 Lower East Side, Free Radio Gainesville, www.radfall.org, IWW International Radio Network.Web and Periodical Articles on Human Rights Radio and Micro-Radio, 1999Folder 415036641Scope and Contents(2 of 2 folders)  Roughly chronological.Printouts from web sitesItem 150379411Scope and ContentsCato Policy Analysis, Pirate Free Radio, Community Powered Radio, San Francisco Liberation Radio, Micro-Watt Radio, Hot Pirate Action, Free Radio Berkeley, Neighborhood Works; Community RadioPhotocopies from books, newspapers, and periodicals from The State Journal RegisterItem 250380412Web and Periodical Articles on Human Rights Radio and Micro-Radio, 2000Folder 425038142Web and Periodical Articles on Human Rights Radio and Micro-Radio, 2001Folder 435038243Web and Periodical Articles on Human Rights Radio and Micro-Radio, 2002-2007Folder 445038344NewsBank Inc., America's Newspapers, Web Articles from the State Journal-Register (Springfield, IL), 1998-2001Folder 455038445Scope and ContentsTopics include micro-radio and F.C.C. v. Mbanna Kantako.Web and Periodical Articles on Human Rights Radio and Micro-Radio, undatedFolder 465038546Various Writings on MicroRadioFolder 475038647Scope and ContentsArticles on Low Power Radio, Black Liberation Radio (BLR), Human Rights Radio (H.R.R.), Prometheus Radio Project, Unlicensed Radio, Inter-Regional Communications, Microradio.Periodical Articles pertaining to Mbanna KantakoFolder 485038748Web and Periodical Articles on Human Rights Radio and Micro-Radio, 1990-2000Folder 495038849Web and Periodical Articles on Micro-Radio, 1998Folder 505038950Scope and ContentsRoughly chronological.
Printouts from websites:  The Information Subway, National Lawyers Guild Committee on Democratic Communications, Weekly Alibi, Black Liberation Solidarity Page, Afrikan Frontline Network, www.radio4all.org, Institute for Economic Democracy, Cato Institute, Free Radio Press, NPR.Web and Periodical Articles on Micro-Radio, 1999Folder 515039051Scope and Contents(1 of 2 folders)  Roughly chronological.
Printouts from websites:  www.radio4all.org, Micropower Radio News, Mike Townsend article "The Trenches of Low-watt Radio", Metro Active, San Francisco Liberation Radio, The Free Forum Online, National Lawyers Guild Committee on Democratic Communications, Mojo Wire, Wall Street Journal, www.beatworld.com, www.sfbg.com, The Village Voice.Web and Periodical Articles on Micro-Radio, 1999Folder 525039152Scope and Contents(2 of 2 folders)  Roughly chronological.
Printouts from websites:  "Free Radio vs. the FCC: A Case Study of Micro Broadcasting," by Ted M. Coopman, Z Magazine, Znet, Free Radio Berkeley, Paper Tiger TV, Soundprint Media Center, National Lawyers Guild Committee on Democratic Communications, Jesse Drew, Macrocosm USA, Lake County Radio, Free Radio Network, www.freeradio.org, The Media and Democracy Congress, IWW International Radio Network, Alta Vista, Microradio Equipment Coalition, New York Free Media Alliance, Black Autonomy News Source, The A-infos Radio Project, Golden Gator Online, Community Radio.Web and Periodical Articles on Micro-Radio, 2000Folder 535039253Scope and ContentsRoughly chronological.
Printouts from websites:  San Francisco Liberation Radio, New York Times Online, The Nation.com, www.sfbg.com, National Lawyers Guild Committee on Democratic Communications, FCC, The Freedom Forum Online, The American Prospect Online, About.com, Common Dreams News Center, NPR.Web Articles printed from the San Francisco Liberation Radio website, 1998-2000Folder 545039354Photographs: Mbanna Kantako, Interviewees, Mike TownsendFolder 558285655Box 3Box 38409Chicago Guild meetingVideotape 184101990-01-19Scope and ContentsAlthough different part of meeting is shown (before # 16), Kantako &amp; Black Rose discuss genocide, police terrorism, free speech.Videotape 284111990-01-19Scope and ContentsTape One: WTRA Chicago Mtg: "19th century images of Blacks in Popular Culture". (15 min).
Tape Two: WTRA Chicago Mtg: Black face shows. (45 min).Williams, Napoleon - Decatur Police break-inVideotape 384121990Scope and ContentsIncludes WAND newscast (30 min)Tetso, Kogawa, "Meets Mbanna on Paper Tiger", Paper Tiger TVVideotape 48413Scope and Contents(30 min)
Tetso shows how to put together a transmitter
Mbanna Kantako shows how to put together a transmitter"From L.A. to John Hay", speakers at Sangamon State UniversityVideotape 584141992-06-04Scope and Contents(2 hrs)
Prof. Sidney Willhelm- "Economic History of Blacks; Genocide".
Kantako- "Springfield notes, History of Oppression &amp; Rights as Human beings.""Zoom Black Magic- Rough Cut &amp; Lay Offs"Videotape 68415ca. 1990Scope and Contents(15 min
Kantako gives tour of BLR; tape of shows-attorney
Kantako talks about state of nation, mainstream media"Nommo X: African Holocaust"Videotape 784161991Scope and Contents(2 hrs)
Part 1:  European Slave Trade, slave castles, slaves shipped to America, slaves in America, punishment &amp; torture, Belgium in the Congo (Zaire)-King Leopold slaughtered millions.
Part 2:  After slave trade-portrayal of blacks in ads, KKK, lynchings, tar &amp; feathering, burning down black people's homes as form of terror."Nommo X: African Holocaust"Videotape 88417Scope and Contents(2 hrs)
Part 3:   Wars and blacks that have fought for white causes in U.S., 50's &amp; 60's Schools; civil rights, police, assassination of black leaders, FBI-Hoover.
Part 4:   Dahmer killing blacks, King Alfred plan-60's, police, suppression of cancer cure, blacks in WW II, Jim Jones massacre and AIDS virus.Press conference for WTRA, John  Hay HomesVideotape 984181989-04-17Scope and ContentsMedia include: Channel 20, Channel 17, WSSR.  Kantako &amp; Associate answer reporter questions, WTRA back on air after FCC shut it down, calls police to arrest him, segment from Channel 20 news.Ward Churchill at SSU, 1990-04/19Videotape 1050291Scope and Contents(1hr)
"How to Start micro-radio"- later version of (#9) press conference 4/17/89. Kantako talks about micro-radio's significance in black community.WTRA Press Conference #1 &amp; 2, Hay HomesVideotape 118419Scope and Contents(1hr)
"How to Start micro-radio"- later version of (#9) press conference 4/17/89. Kantako talks about micro-radio's significance in black community.WTRA Police Station ProtestVideotape 1284201990-03-30Scope and Contents(1 hr)
WSSU (channel 17): Kantako talks to media, Gerald Clemons death by police, Karen Lambert, Marcus Kelley, police brutality, white oppression.Clemons/police protest vigil &amp; WAND Decatur news reportVideotape 1384211990-03-30Scope and Contents(30 min)Box 4Box 48423WTRA Press Conference, M.F. Version (Original), 1990-04-19Videotape 1450292Scope and ContentsMbanna Kantako press conference, 4/17/1989 (15 min.)Keyser, Kevin - Free Radio: A documentaryVideotape 1550293Mbanna Kantako at UIS, 1998-02-19Videotape 1650294Scope and ContentsDiscussion about formation and purpose of Human Rights Radio (60 min.)Kantako's R.A.P., 2001-05Videotape 1750295Scope and ContentsShows #5, 6, 7 &amp; 8Example of a small transmitter inside a video-cassette tape containerVideotape 1850296Scope and Contents88.1 FM radio transmitter with "Antenna out", "DC 12V", and "Audio in" connectors inserted through spine of a video-cassette tape container"Rebel Radio", Next TV, Toronto Canada, Raw Tape Shot May 2001Videotape 1950297Scope and ContentsSan Francisco Radio, Richard Edmondson, Pt. 1; San Francisco Radio, Richard Edmondson, Pt. 2; and Sarah Olson, Pt. 1"Rebel Radio", Next TV, Toronto Canada, Raw Tape Shot May 2001Videotape 2050298Scope and ContentsSan Francisco Radio, Light Pollution; San Francisco Radio, Alan Korn, Pt. 1; San Francisco Radio, Alan Korn, Pt. 2; and
Geocaching, Julie D'Angelo"Rebel Radio", Next TV, Toronto Canada, Raw Tape Shot May 2001Videotape 2150299Scope and ContentsFeaturing: San Francisco Liberation Radio DJs and Peter Franck, National Lawyers Guild.
NTV W 1127, NTV W 1128, NTV W 1129 San Francisco Radio"Rebel Radio", Next TV, Toronto Canada, Raw Tape Shot October 2001Videotape 2250300Scope and ContentsFeaturing: M. Kantako, M. Townsend, L. Johnson
NTV W 1258, NTV W 1259, NTV W 1260, NTV W 1261 Springfield, IL"Rebel Radio", Next TV, Toronto Canada, Raw Tape Shot May 2001Videotape 2350301Scope and ContentsFeaturing:  Stephen Dunifer, Free Radio Berkeley and Berkeley Liberation Radio; San Francisco Radio, Stephen Dunifer, Pt. 1 and Pt. 2"Rebel Radio", Next TV, Toronto Canada, March 2002Videotape 2450302Scope and ContentsNext TV Features: Rebel Radio on City TV, Toronto, Canada, March, 2002Box 5Box 58445"Notes on the Devils News"Audiotape 184241995-05-01Scope and ContentsSide A: (30 min) Show # 2,270; U.N. and Human rights, Hasara, McNeil, economic inequalities among races, Ralph Nader, prisons. "Last Day of Malcolm X Human Rights Club",  Kantako interviews SSU students about their experiences.
Side B:  Blank.Copy of Tape # 1Audiotape 28425Copy of Tape # 1Audiotape 38426"Notes on the Devils News"Audiotape 484271995-05-09Scope and ContentsSide A: (45 min) Show # 2,286;  U.N. and human rights, due process, police. "Fire at 1209 E. South St."- twin Barker babies die in suspicious murder.
Side B: (45 min) Show # 2,286; U.N. Human Rights Article 10. "Fire at 1209 E. South St." (continued)."The Jolly Roger Comedy Troupe"Audiotape 58428Scope and ContentsSide A: (45 min) The San Francisco Liberation Radio &amp; Radio Free Berkeley performs skits on: FCC, Policemen review movies- Geronimo, Earnest Saves Christmas, Rodney King beating, Lorena Bobbit story; restaurant scene; "Guilt trips 'R US" tours.
Side B: (20 min) Nazi apparel fashion shop, a kinder, gentler way of executing prisoners; Lillehammer 1994 Olympics, policeman talks about forfeiture; ruling class speaks out; community policing hotline.Zoom Black Magic Liberation RadioAudiotape 684291990Scope and ContentsSide A: (30 min) WJHU /NPR Radio, Baltimore Sound Print by Gary Caveno- Interview with M. Kantako about his past, police brutality, radio station's past, Dougie Thomas murder.
Side B: BlankA&amp;E Investigative ReportAudiotape 784301996-11-02Scope and ContentsSide A: (45 min) "Issues pertaining to Gov't Sponsored Lotteries."-Gambling, addiction, preying on the poor, effect on educational funding, cannibalizing the economy, strains on winners.
Side B: BlankSci-Fi Channel TV, 1996-08-19Audiotape 88431Scope and ContentsSide A: (40 min) Sci-Fi Channel TV, "She -Wolf of London"-serial killers.
Side B: (45 min) Discovery Channel TV, "What sex am I?"- Transvestites, transsexuals."AIDS as an Ethnic Weapon"Audiotape 98432Scope and ContentsSide A: (30 min) University of Wisconsin Radio, (John Fiske commentary)- Acknowledges BLR as source of "counter knowledge" on AIDS. Genocide tool for warfare against minorities. Different conspiracies include; 1970 military scientist speaks of wiping out certain races with disease  and chemicals; AIDS introduced into Africa through small pox vaccine via the WHO campaign; U.S. Army biological warfare program developed AIDS; NIH, CDC  use professor at Columbia University to introduce Hepatitis B vaccine, (which includes AIDS virus), and screening in Manhattan gay population in 1978. Carter's global 2000 plan; Kennan's 1947 views on Human rights &amp; U.S. hegemony.
Side B: Blank"Introspection"Audiotape 108433Scope and ContentsSide A: (40 min) Political poetry and rap. Deals with similar issues that Kantako speaks of ; race, capitalism, genocide, human rights.
Side B: (35 min)  Same as side A."Getting ready for AIDS, the mass media &amp; genocide"Audiotape 1184341995-02-23Scope and ContentsSide A: (45 min) Show #2,209, (John Fiske, Mike Townsend, and M. Kantako on BLR.)- Prelude to lecture at SSU. Professor Fiske speaks of white fear (anger) towards black people,  manifesting itself in conservative backlash, welfare reform, prison building,  gated suburbs, electronic surveillance, voting demographics, invisible oppression.
Side B: (45 min) Continuation of discussion with Fiske on issues such as failure of mass media, journalism schools, opinion polls, ESL, rap music.Audiotape 1284351996-08-08Scope and ContentsSide A: (45 min) Mbanna Kantako on HLR, show # 2,742 - "Inside the Marcus Garvey Liberation Camp 1996"- Reggae songs, interspersed throughout tape. Kantako introduces Camp and 5 UIS, LLCC students who learn and teach with black students; recorded live at the camp; teachers discuss activities- crafts, visit to the zoo.  Students discuss their activities (app 34 students). This school is modeled after Black Panther's School.
Side B: (45 min) Kantako gives physical dimensions of school in John Hay apartment, interviews students, teachers on their experiences, artwork projects, sewing clothes.Continuation of tape  # 12Audiotape 138436Scope and ContentsSide A: (45 min) Springfield Housing Authority throws class out of apt.  Woodworking- "Building brothers"; kickball game, discussion with Mike Townsend on aspects of camp. Students recite motto.
Side B: BlankSide A: Duplicate of  tape #12Audiotape 148437Side A: Blank; Side B: Duplicate of tape # 13, (side A)Audiotape 158438"Rites of Passage"Audiotape 1684391996Scope and ContentsSide A: ( 45 min) 11th Annual Ceremony for Garvey Liberation camp. Dia and students recite motto, teachers talk about each student;  Townsend speaks on Hay Homes being torn down.
Side B: (45 min) Continuation. Dia Kantako speaks; building brothers; presentation of gifts to Mbanna &amp; Dia; presentation of certificates to students, music.Duplicate of tape # 16Audiotape 178440"Rites of Passage"Audiotape 1884411993Scope and ContentsSide A: (20 min) Interviews with teachers, M. Townsend, music.
Side B: (20 min) Music, interviews with teachers on SHA, mayor, and aldermen"Rites of Passage" Duplicate of tape # 18Audiotape 198442"Marcus Garvey Liberation Camp 1996, Rites of Passage"Audiotape 2084431996-08-09Scope and ContentsDuplicate of tape # 18."Young Sisters at the Real Table"Audiotape 218444Scope and ContentsSide A: (30 min) Pt.1, 7/18/95. "African sisters to proud of."- "Dia Kantako"-  recorded live  at Marcus Garvey Liberation camp.  Students  participate in discussions about Dia, music.
Side B: (30 min) Pt.2, 8/1/95. "African Sisters to be proud of."-"Harriet Tubman."- students discuss the underground railroad leader; music.Box 6Box 650290Audiotape 22Audiotape 228446Scope and ContentsSide A: (45 min) Tilos R. 95.5 FM, "Unlicensed Radio in Budapest, Hungary."- Hungarian language, rock music-mostly U.S.; some English.
Side B: "Szokol Radio 92 mhz (Pirate)"- rock &amp; French rap, Hungarian language-. Some English.  "Fix radio (Another Pirate radio)"-Some English speaking, U.S. rock."We know ya"Audiotape 2384471996-10-09Scope and ContentsSide A: (45 min) Keidi Obi Awadu on HLR, #2,804, pt 5; "Rap cut," Awadu-Long Beach, Ca; chemical weapons, CDC &amp; LA County Public Health give vaccines to poor black children in 29 major cities known to cause AIDS- similar problems in Third World countries.  LA Times ran a story on this.  Vaccination injection problems.
Side B: (45 min) DNA test hoax, AIDS test hoax, prostate cancer test hoax, white concern over black population growth; Stockholm syndrome. Recording of Dia leading students in chant"The meaning of Amen"Audiotape 2484481996-09-12Scope and ContentsSide A: (45 min) M. Kantako on ALR, #2,624, ancient Egyptian History.
Side B: (45 min) Amen Ra and the creation of people all by himself through masturbation; resemblance of Amen Ra statue to Washington monument.Audiotape 2584491996-10-30Scope and ContentsSide A: (45 min) Mbanna K, &amp; Michael Townsend on HLR, #2,825 "Crossroads"- Discussion of democracy &amp; power. If wealth in U.S., $36 trillion, was spread equitably in a democratic fashion, each household would have $330,000.  But top 1% has majority of 36 trillion, bottom 50% of households has 4 % of U.S. wealth, wealth equals power in U.S. society. Elections convince powerless that they have equal power. Wealthy control who runs for office, 23,00 trade associations in Washington D.C.; 61,000 lawyers in Washington D.C, 3,000 registered lobbyists in Springfield; 91,000 lobbyists in Washington D.C. Elections legitimize injustice &amp; inequality.
Side B: (40 min) "Welfare Reform"- Middle class squeezed by upper class-city workers, nurses just as poor have already done. Destroying housing for the poor."Micro radio in the U.S.: Mahau Pheko on BLR"Audiotape 2684501994-08-08Scope and ContentsSide A: Produced by SF Liberation Radio broadcast Kantako interviews Pheko from 2/7/94.  She is coordinator for women's affair with Pan-Africanist Congress.  Helps women with getting books for libraries, and other programs to assist women in competing effectively in job market, became politically involved; gives South Africa history.
Side B: Part 2 of interview with Pheko, broadcast on SFLR on 8/8/94. Extended family in African history and white colonials that destroyed African family; death of black business and banks in U.S.; blacks working  for white businesses.Audiotape 2784511995-02-01Scope and ContentsSide A: "Bryan Harris on BLR, #2,187, Pimping Mother Africa p.31". "Mark of the Beast." Harris from Columbus, Ohio &amp; Kantako discuss "the best" that controls people; push for national ID card, with all kinds of personal info, &amp; black leaders cooperated with this movement.
Side B: Nation of Islam as coopted by society's powerful; "beast" electronic money.Audiotape 2884521994-07-24Scope and ContentsSide A: (45 min) Walter Southall on BLR, # 1,995. "Social Services Uncovered." Born in Chicago, went to EIU, worked there, approved highly by influential whites in administration, went to SSU; through contacts, became coordinator of youth activities at  Springfield, Sangamon County Community Action Agency-"didn't do a thing." Hired by Housing Authority security- says their attitudes towards tenants were hostile. Became "special program developer."
Side B: (45 min) SHA's main goal was to get rid of "undesirables" and not help other people; joined Ammani Co- run by Frank McNeil as contractor to SHA-they were a joke as well. Did not deal with lead-based paint. [Kantako calls this his most important interview.]Audiotape 2984531995-01-14Scope and ContentsSide A: (45 min) Zears on BLR, M. Townsend &amp; M. Kantako discuss public housing-dismantling of; residents thrown out, move in with relatives; purposely letting townhouses deteriorate.
Side B: (30 min) Welfare reform- whites blaming blacks, post WW II white middle class-boom and erosion after 1960's.Audiotape 3084541995-02-04Scope and ContentsSide A: (45 min) Keith McHenry on BLR, # 2,190. "Food Not Bombs." From S.F. Ca., K. McHenry gave away food in Boston in front of banks, etc, no arrests.  Arrested in San Francisco for giving food away without a permit.
Side B: Attraction of homeless to free food sites draws ire of downtown businesses, they enlist mayor and police to violently expel them from the area.  "Food Not Bombs" relies on micro broadcasters to get the word out.  Illegal to put up flyers about FNB in S.F. Frequent harassment of McHenry and volunteers.Box 7Box 750303Human Rights Radio, "Evolution to Revolution", 2002-02-01CD 150304Scope and ContentsIntroduction to "7 years of Sounds" hosted by Mbanna Kantako.  The program features pre-recorded voice and sounds set to reggae music.  Series #1, Side 0 (5:32)Human Rights Radio, "Evolution to Revolution", 1996-04-18CD 250305Scope and Contents"7 Years of Sounds", Mbanna Kantako.  Series #1, Side 1 (79:57)Human Rights Radio, "Evolution to Revolution", 1996-04-18CD 350306Scope and Contents"7 Years of Sounds", Mbanna Kantako.  Series #1, Side 2 (7:54)Human Rights Radio, "Evolution to Revolution", 1996-04-18CD 450307Scope and Contents"7 Years of Sounds", Mbanna Kantako.  Series #1, Side 3 (79:57)Human Rights Radio, "Evolution to Revolution", 1996-04-18CD 550308Scope and Contents"7 Years of Sounds", Mbanna Kantako.  Series #1, Side 4 (13:12)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #5, 2001-09-30CD 650309Scope and Contents"Human Rights Talk, Pt. 1" - Guests: Michael Hibbitt, Bay View Hunters Point, CA and Lavell Yohnson, Decatur, IL (28:27)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #6, 2001-10-01CD 750310Scope and Contents"Get Paid" - Guests: Sidney Willhelm, Buffalo, NY and Mike Townsend, Chatham, IL (35:05)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #7, 2001-10-07CD 850311Scope and Contents"Lets Look Black in the Past" (25:29)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #8, 2001-10-14CD 950312Scope and Contents"Dance with the F.C.C." - Guests:  Lavell Yohnson, Decatur, IL (30:28)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #9, 2001-10-15CD 1050313Scope and Contents"Secret Societies" (30:12)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #10, 2001-10-21CD 1150314Scope and Contents"Skull &amp; Bones" (29:47)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #11, 2001-10-22CD 1250315Scope and Contents"Pigs, Pt. 1" (30:45)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #12, 2001-10-28CD 1350316Scope and Contents"Propaganda" - Guest: Mike Townsend, Chatham, IL (32:38)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #13, 2001-10-29CD 1450317Scope and Contents"Before Deadly Force" (28:57)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #14, 2001-11-04CD 1550318Scope and Contents"No Not Egyptian" - Guest: Nko Uhuru, Durham, NC (30:24)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #15, 2001-11-05CD 1650319Scope and Contents"Dance with the F.C.C., Pt. 2, and Decatur P.D." - Guest:  Lavell Yohnson, Decatur, IL (29:39)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #16, 2001-11-11CD 1750320Scope and Contents"Meet Michael Hibbitt at 103.3 FM" - Guest: Michael Hibbitt, Bay View Hunters Point, CA (30:27)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #17, 2001-11-12CD 1850321Scope and Contents"The 14th Amendment" - Guest: Nko Uhuru, Durham, NC (32:24)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #18, 2001-11-17CD 1950322Scope and Contents"U.S. Propaganda" (30:34)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #19, 2001-11-18CD 2050323Scope and Contents"Before Deadly Force, Pt. 2" (31:39)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #20, 2001-11-19CD 2150324Scope and Contents"Modern Day Slavery in the USA" (32:09)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #21, 2001-12-01CD 2250325Scope and Contents"Reading is Real" - Guest: Hermain White, Richmond, VA (25:36)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #22, 2001-12-02CD 2350326Scope and Contents"U.S. Propaganda, Pt. 2" (32:44)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #23, 2001-12-03CD 2450327Scope and Contents"Dance with the F.C.C., Pt. 3, Back on the air in Decatur" - Guest: Lavell Yohnson, Decatur, IL (29:28)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #24, 2001-12-08CD 2550328Scope and Contents"De-Africanizing US Captives, Pt. 1" - Guest: Nko Uhuru, Durham, NC (33:21)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #25, 2001-12-09CD 2650329Scope and Contents"De-Africanizing US Captives, Pt. 2" - Guest: Nko Uhuru, Durham, NC (34:04)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #26, 2001-12-10CD 2750330Scope and Contents"De-Africanizing US Captives, Pt. 3" (33:04)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #27, 2001-12-15CD 2850331Scope and Contents"De-Africanizing US Captives, Pt. 4" (25:10)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #28, 2001-12-16CD 2950332Scope and Contents"U.S. Terror: Port Chicago" (33:45)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #29, 2001-12-17CD 3050333Scope and Contents"Dance with the F.C.C., Pt. 4, Update from the Trenches" - Guest: Lavell Yohnson, Decatur, IL (31:21)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #30, 2001-12-22CD 3150334Scope and Contents"At the Movies - The Matrix, Pt. 1" - Guest: Ken Collier, Chicago, IL (32:04)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #31, 2001-12-23CD 3250335Scope and Contents"At the Movies - The Matrix, Pt. 2" - Guest: Ken Collier, Chicago, IL (36:27)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #32, 2001-12-24CD 3350336Scope and Contents"The Land Grab" - Guest: Nko Uhuru, Durham, NC (33:09)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #33, 2001-12-29CD 3450337Scope and Contents"U.S. Terror, Pt. 2 - The Tuskegee Massacre" (32:45)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #34, 2001-12-30CD 3550338Scope and Contents"In the Name of Their God" - Guest: Nko Uhuru, Durham, NC (35:35)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #35, 2001-12-31CD 3650339Scope and Contents"Lets Make a Slave" - Guest: Nko Uhuru, Durham, NC (33:49)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #36, 2002-01-05CD 3750340Scope and Contents"In the Name of Their God, Pt. 2" (31:36)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #37, 2002-01-06CD 3850341Scope and Contents"There's Something Stinking and its Abe Lincoln" (29:09)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #38, 2002-01-07CD 3950342Scope and Contents"Dance with the F.C.C., Pt. 5 - Update from the Trenches, Pt. 2" - Guest: Lavell Yohnson, Decatur, IL (31:13)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #39, 2002-01-12CD 4050343Scope and Contents"The Constitution is a Crime" - Guest: Konnadi Kantako, Springfield, IL (31:39)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #40, 2002-01-13CD 4150344Scope and Contents"The Constitution is a Crime, Pt. 2" - Guest: Konnadi Kantako, Springfield, IL (34:19)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #41, 2002-01-14CD 4250345Scope and Contents"There's Something Stinking and its Abe Lincoln, Pt. 2 - 'The Civil War - What was it Good For?'" (30:16)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #42, 2002-01-19CD 4350346Scope and Contents"In Mankind's Beginning" (33:56)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #43, 2002-01-20CD 4450347Scope and Contents"In Mankind's Beginning, Pt. 2" (31:30)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #44, 2002-01-21CD 4550348Scope and Contents"European Law" (31:42)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #45, 2002-01-26CD 4650349Scope and Contents"European Law, Pt. 2" (30:31)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #46, 2002-01-27CD 4750350Scope and Contents"European Law, Pt. 3" (30:56)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #47, 2002-01-28CD 4850351Scope and Contents"Dance with the F.C.C., Pt. 6 - Update from the Trenches, Pt. 3" - Guest: Lavell Yohnson, Decatur, IL (30:14)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #48, 2002-02-02CD 4950352Scope and Contents"Pigs, Pt. 2" - Guest:  Konnadi Kantako, Springfield, IL (31:26)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #49, 2002-02-03CD 5050353Scope and Contents"What War on Drugs?, Pt. 1" (30:08)Kantako's Human Rights Patrol Series, #50, 2002-02-04CD 5150354Scope and Contents"The Making of Aunt Jemima" (31:48)Sort Stue "Viva Kantako Destroy Sony"CD 52698102011Scope and ContentsDanish band of Sort Stue
Includes folder with song lyrics, information from website, and personal comments.
Also, excerpts from the book, "DIY: The Rise of Lo-Fi Culture" by Amy Spencer (2008) regarding Mbanna Kantako.
Also two T-shirts for 25th anniversary of Human Rights Radio; Sort Stue Crew, CopenhagenHuman Rights Radio, "Notes on the Devil's News"CD 53755332002-2-9T.CC. Mbanna Kantako RadioCD 54755342012.1.2Box 8Box 850394Incoming Correspondence, General A-K, 1991-1993Folder 555039555Incoming Correspondence, General L-Z, 1990-1993Folder 565039656Incoming Correspondence, Media and Professional Organizations, 1989-1994Folder 575039757Incoming Correspondence, Legal, 1989-1994Folder 585039858Miscellaneous Letters, 1987-1993Folder 595039959Scope and ContentsWritten by various authors to various organizations.Email Correspondence, 1994-1995Folder 605040060Mailing Lists and Address LabelsFolder 615040161Correspondence Generated from Magazine Articles on how to start-up Micro-Radio Stations, 1990Folder 625040262Correspondence Generated from Magazine Articles on how to start-up Micro-Radio Stations, July 1990-November 1990; 1997Folder 635040363Legal Materials, 1989Folder 645040464Scope and Contents(1 of 2 Folders)  Roughly Chronological.FCC Notice to Dewayne Readus (Mbanna Kantako)Item 1504051989-04-16641Scope and ContentsWarning:  Unlicensed Radio Operation.Letter from U.S. Department of Justice, United States Attorney Central District of Illinois to Dewayne Readus (Mbanna Kantako)Item 2504061989-10-04642Scope and ContentsRequest to arrange discussion concerning alleged radio operation and payment of fee forfeitures.Notice to Compel Discovery filed by U.S. District Court, Central District of Illinois, Springfield DivisionItem 3504071989-12-19643Scope and ContentsCivil Case No. 89-3289 - Dewayne Readus, Defendant.  Includes Affidavit by James A. Lewis, Refusal of Readus to take oath to answer questions; Memorandum of Law in Support of Plaintiff; etc.Answer by Dewayne Readus to Civil Action No. 89329, U.S. District Court, Central District of Illinois, Springfield DivisionItem 450408644Legal Materials, 1991-1992, 2012Folder 655040965Scope and Contents(2 of 2 folders)  Roughly chronological.Memorandum from Peter Franck to Sally HarmsItem 1504101991-03-15651Scope and ContentsRe: Kantako case and NLG Convention.Letter from Peter Franck to Bob PerryItem 2504111991-03-18652Scope and ContentsRe:  Discussion of legislative approach to Kantako case.Memorandum from Ralph W. Hoenle and Michelle Schwartz to National Lawyers Guild Committee on Democratic CommunicationsItem 3504121992-05-19653Scope and ContentsRe:  Kantako case and International Human Rights.Letter from FCCItem 475536June 2011654Scope and ContentsA notice of unlicensed operation and a demand that the radio station must be discontinued.Federal Communications Commission, Applications and GuidesFolder 665041366FCC Low Power FM Radio:  Applicants GuideItem 150414661FCC Form 318:  Application for Construction Permit for a Low Power FM Broadcast StationItem 250415March 1990662Scope and ContentsIncludes instructions.FCC Form 318: Sample Initial Application and Sample Amended Application to Share PointsItem 350416663Filling Out the Non-Engineering Parts of FCC Form 318 or, How to Apply for a Low Power Radio StationItem 4504172000-04-16664Scope and ContentsDirections for the First-Time Applicant.   Prepared by the UCC, Office of Communication, Inc., Microradio Implementation Project.Technical Requirements for LPFM Station Operations and Guide to Filling Out Form 318 Section V: Engineering SpecificationsItem 550418ca. 2000665Scope and ContentsPrepared on behalf of The General Board of Global Ministries, The United Methodist Church.Correspondence, Human Rights Radio and F.C.C., May 1989-Nov. 1999Folder 675041967Correspondence, Human Rights Radio and F.C.C., Jan. 2000 - Dec. 2000Folder 685042068Correspondence, Human Rights Radio and F.C.C., Jan. 2001 - Dec. 2001Folder 695042169Correspondence, Human Rights Radio and F.C.C., Jan. 2002 - Apr. 2005Folder 705042270Correspondence between Janek Lowe and Mbanna KantakoFolder 7150423200271Scope and ContentsRe: Proposed movie project about pirate radio.  Includes Deal Memo and "Pump Up the Volume" storyline.Legal Materials, Correspondence and News Articles, 1989-1992Folder 725042472Scope and ContentsF.C.C. Case against Dewayne Readus (Mbanna Kantako).Legal Materials, Correspondence and News Articles, 1998-2000Folder 735042573Scope and ContentsF.C.C. Case against Dewayne Readus (Mbanna Kantako).  Includes Notice of Unlicensed Radio Operation from FCC to Kantako, Nov.-Dec. 1998).Legal Documents and Exhibits, 2000-2001Folder 745042674Scope and ContentsF.C.C. Case vs. Dewayne Readus (Mbanna Kantako).  Includes Pirate/Free Radio's "The Enforcement Action Database Table" article, 10-9-2001.Newsletters, Flyers, Brochures and Booklets pertaining to Micro-RadioFolder 755043375Teflon, Zeke.  "The Complete Manual of Pirate Radio", ndItem 150434751Scope and ContentsBooklet.Huron, Amanda and TriDish, Peter.  "So You Want to Apply for an Low Power FM Radio License...", 2000Item 250435752Scope and ContentsBooklet, with a section by Cheryl Leanza, Esq."You've Got a Right to Rock:  Don't Let Them Take it Away", 1990Item 350436753Scope and ContentsBooklet by the Editors of Rock &amp; Roll Confidential."How to find your Geographic Coordinates and How to find your Elevation Above Sea Level", ndItem 450437754Scope and ContentsFlyer."Not Your Granny's Recipe"Item 550438755Scope and ContentsFlyer advertisement for WUIS, NPR Station."Government Threatens Community Radio Station with Raid"Item 650439April 5, 1998756Scope and ContentsFlyer.Prometheus Radio ProjectItem 750440757Scope and ContentsIncludes newsletter, business advertisement, and brochure entitled "Freeing the airwaves from corporate control".Black Liberation Radio #2 flyerItem 850441758Scope and ContentsAdvertisement of a second station with a concentration on youth.Mayday Premiere, "Free Radio", 2000-05-01Item 950442759Scope and ContentsFlyer announcement of a video documentary to be shown at UIS.East Coast Microbroadcasting Conference, Philadelphia, PAItem 1050443April 3-5, 19987510Scope and ContentsBrochures (2)."A Radio Mutiny Hymnal of Sea Shanties"Item 1150444April 3-5, 19987511Scope and ContentsBrochure handed out at East Coast Microbroadcasting Conference, Philadelphia, PA."Welcome to the First East Coast Microbroadcasting Conference"Item 1250445April 3-5, 19987512Scope and ContentsEvents and schedules handout.Kits and Accessories from Free Radio BerkeleyItem 13504467513Scope and ContentsFlyer.Microradio Resources (Internet and Otherwise)Item 14504477514Scope and ContentsCompliments of Prometheus Radio Project, nd.Peoples Radio "Black Box" brochureItem 15504487515Scope and ContentsDescription of how and list of parts necessary to build a mini-FM transmitter (for an example of a mini-FM transmitter see MC 86, Box 4, Videotape 18).Phone Zap the FCC Monday December 15, 1997Item 16504497516Scope and ContentsFree my Radio campaign/article.Newsletter, "Rebel Radio", published by Friends of Radio Free Detroit, 1992-01-30Item 17504507517Scope and ContentsVol. 1, No. 1Newsletter, "Maximum Rock and Roll:  Pirate Radio Issue", June 1997Item 18504517518Newsletter, "Graffiti Times", published by S.E. Jones Publication, 1998Item 19504527519Association of Micro-Power Broadcasters (AMPB) Report #28, January 1999Item 20504537520Correspondence, 1989-2000Folder 765045476Scope and Contents(1 of 2 folders)  Roughly chronological.Correspondence, 1989-2000Folder 775045577Scope and Contents(2 of 2 folders)  Roughly chronological.Pamphlets, Memos, Press Releases, Posters and FlyersFolder 785045678Newsletters from various organizations and other microradio stationsFolder 795045779The KC Music Alliance NewsItem 150458791Scope and ContentsVol. 1, Issue 2, December 1992InteRadio the Newsletter of AMARC, World Association of Community Radio BroadcastersItem 250459792Scope and ContentsVolume 2, Number 1, 1989
Volume 2, Number 2, 1989
January 1990
Volume 5, Number 3, 1993
Volume 6, Number 2, 1994Reclaiming the Airwaves by Free Radio Berkeley &amp; the Free Communications CoalitionItem 350460793Scope and ContentsOctober 1993
May/June 1994Rebel Radio by Friends of Radio Free DetroitItem 450461794Scope and ContentsVol. 1, No. 1, ndThe Ely Fire FlyItem 550462795Scope and ContentsIssue 4, March 1991Radio Resistor's Bulletin by Friends of FreeForm Local 2 (FoFF2)Item 650463796Scope and ContentsDecember 1992
February/March 1993
#3 May-June 1993
#4 August-October 1993
#5 December 1993
#6 March 1994
#11 Summer 1995The Racine Courier.  "'Pirate' Station Informs, Springfield Listeners of its 'North Star'", May 25, 1991Item 750494797WTRA Newsletters, 1989-1991Folder 805046480Web ArticlesFolder 815046581Rodriguez, Luis J.  "Pirate Media!  Liberation Radio in America:  Arresting the Airwaves!"Item 1504661996811Scope and ContentsRock Out Censorship, Decatur, IL.Burghardt, Tom.  "Decatur Black Liberation Radio Under Attack!  SWAT Team Raids Home of Micro-Radio Broadcaster"Item 250467May 12, 1997812Scope and ContentsAntifa Info-Bulletin from news15.htm at www.nyct.net.Black Liberation Radio Solidarity PageItem 350468813Black Liberation Radio Background and HistoryItem 450469814About Black Liberation RadioItem 550470815Beloit Daily News.  "Rebellious rebel radio stations mean headaches for authorities"Item 650471February 10, 1997816Mid-Atlantic Infoshop News Kiosk.  "Black Liberation Radio in Decatur Raided Again"Item 750472April 8, 1997817Supriano, Sue.  "Black Liberation Radio Update:  Free Mildred Jones!!!  Keep Napoleon Williams out of Prison:  Support Black Liberation Radio, Decatur, Illinois"Item 85047321 Aug. 1997818Scope and Contentsblr.html at www.radio4all.org.Decatur Herald &amp; Review.  "Napoleon Williams Chronology", 1997Item 950474819Scope and ContentsCentral Illinois news.Burke, David.  "FCC cracking down on 'pirate' stations", 1997Item 10504758110Scope and ContentsDecatur Herald &amp; Review, Central Illinois news.Burke, David.  "I'm still saying, can you hear me?  Legal woes give an unhappy twist to the dream of a young boy playing with his first radio", 1997Item 11504768111Scope and ContentsDecatur Herald &amp; Review, Central Illinois news.Moore, Dave and Tyus, Billy.  "The voice of 'liberation':  Napoleon Williams' radio battle with authorities over his children has won him supporters and enemies", 1997Item 12504778112Scope and ContentsDecatur Herald &amp; Review, Special Edition.Newspaper and Periodical Articles on Micro-Radio, 1985-1996Folder 825047882Shields, Stephen O. and Ogles, Robert M.  "Black Liberation Radio:  A Case Study of the Micro-Radio Movement", March 1992Folder 835047983Scope and ContentsPresented at the 22nd Annual Meeting of the Popular Culture Association in Louisville, KY.Swegle, Lisa.  "Why an Alternative View is Needed in the Media", Fall 1991Folder 845048084Scope and ContentsStudent paper written for SSU Public Affairs Reporting Program.Wingfield, Susan.  "Two Republican Initiatives towards Cultural Hegemony through FCC Regulations", 1991Folder 855048185Scope and ContentsSan Diego State University.Williams, Patricia J.   "Metro Broadcasting, Inc. v. FCC: Regrouping in Singular Times", 1986Folder 865048286Scope and ContentsHarvard Law Review, [Vol. 104:468], pp. 525-546.Shields, Stephen O. and Ogles, Robert M.  "Black Liberation Radio:  A Case Study of the Micro-Radio Movement", Spring 1995Folder 875048387Scope and ContentsThe Howard Journal of Communications, Vol. 5, No. 3 (Spring 1995), pp. 173-183.Fiske, John.  "Testimony to the World Commission on Culture and Development", March 1995Folder 885048488Scope and ContentsPresented at the United Nations, March 14th and 15th, 1995.Boozell, Greg.  "Clearing the Air:  Habermas, The Information Superhighway and the Free Radio Movement", ndFolder 895048589Sakolsky, Ron.  "Frequencies of Resistance:  The Micropower Radio Movement Goes Global", ndFolder 905048690Scope and ContentsUnpublished manuscript.Albert-Honore, Sharon.  "Empowering Voices:  KUCB and Black Liberation Radio", 1996Folder 915048791Scope and ContentsMeditated Messages and African-American Culture, Contemporary Issues, edited by Venise T. Berry and Carmen L. Manning-Miller."Some Historic Perspectives on Civil Disobedience", ndFolder 925048892Zeller, George.  "The 1989 Pirate Radio Directory", 1989Folder 935048993Scope and ContentsTiare Publications.Periodical Articles on Radio Activity and Mass Communications, 1990-1996Folder 945049394Magazines, "Lies of Our Times", January 1991, and "CovertAction Quarterly", Fall 1997Folder 955049595Miscellaneous, 1994Folder 965049096Letter from Louis N. Hiken, attorney, to Philip Kane, Acting Engineer in Charge, FCCFolder 9750491June 28, 199397Scope and ContentsRe: In the Matter of Stephen P. Dunifer.Photocopy of Mbanna Kantako photographFolder 985049298Scope and ContentsPhotographer, date and location unknown.Photographs of Mbanna Kantako and his family, undatedFolder 995049699Scope and ContentsIncludes negatives.Photographs of Free Radio Personalities, ca. 1990Folder 10050497100Scope and ContentsPhotographs of David Barsamian, San Francisco Free Radio personalities, and other various free radio personalities at unknown locations, most undated.Mbanna Kantako VitaFolder 10150498101Academic Manuscripts and InterviewsFolder 10250499102Nopper, Sheila.  "Kantako Raises Human Rights Issue as Hay Homes Slated for Demolition", ndItem 1505001021Sakolsky, Ron and Dunifer, Stephen.  "Frequencies of Resistance:  The Micropower Radio Movement Goes Global", 1996Item 2505011022Scope and ContentsUnpublished manuscript.Boozell, Greg.  "Clearing the Air:  Habermas, The Information Superhighway and the Free Radio Movement", ndItem 3505021023Townsend, Michael.  "The FCC vs Human Rights (Radio)", ca. 1998Item 4505031024Shields, Stephen O. and Ogles, Robert M.  "Black Liberation Radio:  A Case Study of the Micro-Radio Movement", March 1992Item 5505041025Author unknown.  "Breaching the Matrix:  Why Human Rights Radio Had to Go", ndItem 6505051026Scope and ContentsMichael Townsend and Mbanna Kantako.Townsend, Michael.  Unpublished, untitled manuscript, ndItem 7505061027Scope and ContentsDiscusses the formation of Black Liberation Radio, its importance, and includes an example of Kantako's 24-hour programming schedule.Mbanna Kantako, 1997-02-26Item 8505071028Interview with Mbanna Kantako, ndItem 9505081029Black Liberation Radio Logos and Bumper Sticker, ndFolder 10350509103Human Rights Patrol Program List and photocopies of H.R.R. tape labelsFolder 10450543104Human Rights Violation Case 97 LM 3Folder 105513351997-02105Human Rights Radio 25th AnniversaryFolder 10675537November 2012106Scope and ContentsDocuments and printouts related to the 25th anniversary of Human Rights Radio.Kantako, Mbanna - Pirate Radio PioneerFolder 10777078April 25, 2013107Scope and ContentsArticle by Bruce Rushton in Illinois Times: "Pirate Radio Pioneer: Mbanna Kantake Won't Shut Up"
Includes comments from Mike Townsend, former UIS professor who was involved in the happenings on the east side of Springfield and the Hay Homes.  
Material gathered for article from UIS Special Collection MC 86: Michael Townsend, Micro-Radio Collection.Box 9Box 950512Restoring African People with Raw African Power Volume 37-48DVD 175535Kantako's R.A.P. 2001Videotape 2550513Scope and ContentsVolume 1 TRT - 28:22
Volume 2 TRT - 29:24
Volume 3 TRT - 29:04
Volume 4 TRT - 24:25Restoring African People (R.A.P.) with Raw African Power (R.A.P.)Videotape 2650514Scope and ContentsVolume 9 TRT - 28:05
Volume 10 TRT - 28:21
Volume 11 TRT - 28:23
Volume 12 TRT - 28:52Kantako's R.A.P. 2001Videotape 2750515Scope and ContentsVolume 13 TRT - 29:01
Volume 14 TRT - 28:50
Volume 15 TRT - 29:30
Volume 16 TRT - 29:26Kantako's R.A.P. 2001Videotape 2850516Scope and ContentsVolume 17 TRT - 27:38
Volume 18 TRT - 29:03
Volume 19 TRT - 28:59
Volume 20 TRT - 29:16Restoring African People with Raw African PowerVideotape 2950517Scope and ContentsVolume 29 TRT - 29:03
Volume 30 TRT - 29:42
Volume 31 TRT - 29:06
Volume 32 TRT - 28:42Restoring African People with Raw African PowerVideotape 3050518Scope and ContentsVolume 36 TRT - 29:15
Volume 37 TRT - 24:51
Volume 38 TRT - 29:28
Volume 39 TRT - 29:52Restoring African People with Raw African PowerVideotape 3150519Scope and ContentsVolume 41 TRT - 26:24
Volume 42 TRT - 26:12
Volume 43 TRT - 27:11
Volume 44 TRT - 25:28Restoring African People with Raw African PowerVideotape 3250520Scope and ContentsVolume 49
Volume 50
Volume 51
Volume 52Restoring African People with Raw African PowerVideotape 3350521Scope and ContentsVolume 60
Volume 61
Volume 62
Volume 63Restoring African People (R.A.P.) with Raw African Power (R.A.P.)Videotape 3450522Scope and ContentsVolume 66
Volume 67
Volume 68
Volume 69Restoring African People with Raw African PowerVideotape 3550523Scope and ContentsVolume 70 TRT - 28:28
Volume 71 TRT - 28:18
Volume 72 TRT - 29:20
Volume 73 TRT - 26:35Restoring African People with Raw African PowerVideotape 3650524Scope and ContentsVolume 74 TRT - 28:07
Volume 75 TRT - 26:35
Volume 76 TRT - 27:40
Volume 77 TRT - 25:06Restoring African People with Raw African PowerVideotape 3750525Scope and ContentsVolume 79
Volume 80
Volume 81
Volume 82Restoring African People with Raw African PowerVideotape 3850526Scope and ContentsVolume 87 TRT - 27:53
Volume 88 TRT - 24:32
Volume 89 TRT - 24:33
Volume 90 TRT - 29:56Box 10Box 1050527SlidesItem 535054253Scope and Contents35mm photo slides of Illinois Times "Radical Radio" article (2); two news articles on News Radio and FCC (4); and Mbanna Kantako broadcasting live on Human Rights Radio (3).Paper Tiger Television, "Low-Power Empowerment", ndVideotape 3950528Next TV Features: Rebel Radio on City TV, Toronto, Canada, March 2002Videotape 4050529Scope and ContentsShows #3 - #13.Free Radio: A Documentary by Kevin Keyser, San Francisco, CAVideotape 4150530Free RadioVideotape 4250531Scope and ContentsKevin Keyser Tape 1 TRT - 01:25:00Free RadioVideotape 4350532Scope and ContentsKevin Keyser Tape 2 TRT - 00:30:00Mbanna KantakoVideotape 4450533Kantako's Human Rights Radio:  Historical HighlightsVideotape 4550534Black Apocalypse, 1994-11-29Videotape 4650535Scope and ContentsFeaturing Sidney Willhelm and Mbanna Kantako.AIDS, The Mass Media, and Genocide, 1995-02-23Videotape 4750536Scope and ContentsFeaturing John Fiske and Mbanna Kantako.Tokyo Ngo Visit to Human Rights RadioVideotape 4850537February 9-10, 2002Scope and ContentsTape #1Tokyo Ngo Visit to Human Rights RadioVideotape 4950538February 9-10, 2002Scope and ContentsTape #2Jerry Landay, Micropower Teach In, 1998-02-07Videotape 5050539R.A.P. Raw #1, 2002-08-21Videotape 5150540Scope and ContentsMaxwell Camcorder videocassette (small).R.A.P. Raw #2, 2002-08-21Videotape 5250541Scope and ContentsMaxwell Camcorder videocassette (small).Box 11Box 1150544Stewart CraneAudiotape 31505461981-05-19SSU Towards ZeroAudiotape 32505471989-02-01Scope and Contents(60 min.)African Holistic HealthAudiotape 33505481990-03-31Scope and ContentsSides 1 &amp; 2.  Features Dr. Llaila Afrika.African Holistic HealthAudiotape 34505491990-03-31Scope and ContentsSides 3 &amp; 4.  Features Dr. Llaila Afrika.Terrance Jackson on WLIBAudiotape 35505501991-07-17No Mo X on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 36505511991-08-27Scope and Contents"African Holocaust, Part 2", show #714.No Mo X on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 3750552Scope and Contents"African Holocaust, Part 3".No Mo X on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 38505531991-08-29Scope and Contents(Sides A &amp; B)  "African Holocaust, Part 4", show #717.No Mo X on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 39505541991-08-30Scope and Contents(60 min. - Sides A &amp; B) "African Holocaust, Part 5", show #718.Muhammad Salaam on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 40505551991-10-06Scope and Contents(60 min.)  Show #754.Baba Kofi on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 41505561991-10-27Scope and Contents(90 min.) "Hallows-Eve", show #775.Muhammad Salaam on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 42505571991-11-03Scope and Contents(50 min.)  "Holy Khoran, Part 1", show #782.Muhammad Salaam on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 43505581991-11-10Scope and Contents(50 min.)  "Holy Khoran, Part 2", show #789.No Mo X on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 44505591991-11-11Scope and Contents(50 min.) Show #790.Muhammad Salaam on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 45505601991-11-17Scope and Contents(50 min.)  "Holy Khoran, Part 3", show #796.Muhammad Salaam on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 46505611991-11-24Scope and Contents(60 min.)  "Holy Khoran, Part 4", show #803.Barbara Justice on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 47505621991-11-25Scope and Contents(50 min.)  "AIDS and the Cure", show #804.Muhammad Salaam on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 48505631991-12-01Scope and Contents(50 min.)  "Holy Khoran, Part 5", show #810.No Mo X on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 49505641991-12-02Scope and Contents(60 min.)  "Remembering Bobbie Wright", show #811.Uncle L (New Jack Scholar) on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 50505651991-12-31Scope and Contents(60 min.)  Show #840.Nommo X on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 51505661992-01-01Scope and Contents(60 min., Sides A &amp; B) "The Origin of Lynching", show #841.Black Liberation Radio, Brothers at the real table, Part 4Audiotape 52505671992-01-19Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "From the leaf to the pipe", show #859.  Host Mbanna Kantako with guests Baba Kofi and Michael Diop.Black Liberation Radio, Brothers at the real table, Part 4Audiotape 53505681992-01-19Scope and ContentsDuplicate of audiotape #52.Black Liberation Radio, Brothers at the real table, Part 4Audiotape 54505691992-01-19Scope and ContentsDuplicate of audiotape #52.Black Liberation Radio, Brothers at the real table, Part 5Audiotape 55505701992-01-20Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Countering Counter Intelligence", show #860.  Host Mbanna Kantako with guests Baba Kofi, Greg K. Carr, Bryan Harris, and Del Jones.Zears Miles on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 56505711992-03-30Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "War talk, Part 1", show #930.Baba Kofi on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 57505721992-04-12Scope and Contents(80 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "African Origin of Easter", show #943.Zears Miles on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 58505731992-04-13Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "War talk, Part 2", show #944.Terrance Jackson on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 59505741992-05-11Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Putting it all together, Part 1", show #972.Zears Miles on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 60505751992-05-18Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "War talk, Part 3", show #979.Black Liberation Radio, Brothers at the real table, Part 7Audiotape 61505761992-06-08Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Countering Counter Intelligence", show #1,000.  Host Mbanna Kantako with guests Baba Kofi and Terrance Jackson.Uncle L and Bryan Harris on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 62505771992-06-17Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Secret Weapon Uncle Tom", show #1,009.Baba Kofi on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 63505781992-06-28Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "The fourth of they lie", show #1,020.Zears Miles on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 64505791992-08-10Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "War talk, Part 4 - Why go back to Africa?  Because we're intelligent", show #1,063.Terrance Jackson on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 65505801992-10-05Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Putting it all together, Part 5 - Banking", show #1,119.Zears Miles on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 66505811992-10-12Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "War talk, Part 5 - Denying the denial", show #1,126.Terrance Jackson on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 67505821992-11-30Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Philosophy of Liberation and the Art of War, Part 6", show #1,175.Black Liberation Radio, Brothers at the real table, Part 18Audiotape 68505831993-11-03Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Negro Watch", show #1,513.  Host Mbanna Kantako with guests Robert X and Randy Evans.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 69505841994-03-19Scope and Contents(60 min., Sides 1 &amp; 2) "Leave the Children Alone", show #1,649.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 70505851994-03Scope and Contents(60 min., Sides 3 &amp; 4) "Leave the Children Alone", show # unknown.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 71505861994-05-10Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B) "A Look in the Lodge", show #1,701.Bisa on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 72505871994-05-11Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B) "Brainwashing 2000", show #1,702.Darrell Ann White Marsh on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 73505881994Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Subtle Serpent", show #1,718.Linda Thompson on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 74505891994-06-06Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "D.C. Showdown", show #1,728.Shawn Morton on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 75505901994-07-01Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "The Millennium Factor", show #1,972.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 76505911994-07-10Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "The Real Cold War", show #1,981.Walter Southall on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 77505921994-07-24Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Social Services Uncovered, Part 1", show #1,995.Walter Southall on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 78505931994-07-31Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Social Services Uncovered, Part 2", show #2,002.Notes on the Devils NewsAudiotape 79505941994-09-17 &amp; 18Scope and Contents(90 min. total)

Side A, show #2,050:  National Geographic, 7-88, "When the Moors Ruled Spain"; State Journal Register - "Cilco pockets lightened"; and State Journal Register - "No drugs in hope students taken to hospital".

Side B, show #2,051: National Geographic, 7-88, "When the Moors Ruled Spain"; San Jose Mercury, 8-1-94, "Pirate radio supports battle of Taiwan police"; and CNN News, 9-17-94, "George Washington's Slaves".Notes on the Devils NewsAudiotape 80505951994-09-25 &amp; 26Scope and Contents(90 min. total)

Side A, show #2,058:  The Philadelphia Inquirer, 9-11-94, p. 6, 2A, "Wife drove Lincoln to Greatness".

Side B, show #2,059: CNN News, 9-26-94, "Locking down the Projects in Puerto Rico and the National Guard.Notes on the Devils NewsAudiotape 81505961994-10-15 &amp; 24Scope and Contents(90 min. total)

Side A, show #2,078:  "The Pigs Calling Mbanna Out".

Side B, show #2,087: "Mbanna Subpoenaed and Ordered to Testify".Bisa on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 82505971995-01-25Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Pick up the Pieces, Part 1", show #2,180.Notes on the Devils NewsAudiotape 83505981995-02-08 &amp; 09Scope and Contents(90 min. total)

Side A, show #2,194:  "Slave Patrol Scanner".

Side B, show #2,195: "Pigs Around the World".Notes on the Devils NewsAudiotape 84505991995-02-10 &amp; 14Scope and Contents(90 min. total)

Side A, show #2,196:  Channel 20 - "Evidence Room".

Side B, show #2,200: "Operation Cooperation".Notes on the Devils NewsAudiotape 85506001995-02-15 &amp; 16Scope and Contents(90 min. total)

Side A, show #2,201:  State Journal Register - "The Big Pinch".

Side B, show #2,202: Illinois Times - "Busting Big Time in Sangamon County, Illinois".Ron Sakolsky on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 86506011995-03-16Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "You get no Knowledge from going to College", show #2,230.Notes on the Devils NewsAudiotape 87506021995-04-21Scope and Contents(45 min.)

Side A, show #2,266:  "Horton Arrested for Making Fake Bomb Threats".

Side B: Blank.Notes on the Devils NewsAudiotape 88506031995-04-30Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  PBS, 4/25/95, - "The English Language", show #2,275.Boots &amp; Z-Roc on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 89506041995-05-31Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "The Coup - Genocide and Juice", show #2,307.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 90506051995-10-04Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B) "Satan Worshiping through the Centuries", show #2,433.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 91506061995-10-13Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B) "Satan's Associates", show #2,442.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 92506071995-10-21Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B) "Pigs, Part 2", show #2,451.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on Black Liberation RadioAudiotape 93506081995-11-03Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B) "The Land of the Free and the Home of the Slave", show #2,465.Box 12Box 1250609Notes on the Devils NewsAudiotape 94506101995-11-15Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Ebony's First Notes on the Devils News", show #2,475.Mbanna Kantako on A.L.R.Audiotape 95506111995-11-24Scope and Contents(90 min.) "Pigs, Part 3", show #2,484.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on A.L.R.Audiotape 96506121995-12-08Scope and Contents(90 min.)  "What War on Drugs?, Part 3", show #2,498.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on A.L.R.Audiotape 97506131995-12-15Scope and Contents(90 min.)  "The Land of the Free and the Home of the Slave, Part 2", show #2,505.Notes on the Devils NewsAudiotape 98506141996-01-21Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Long Term Employment is the Thing of the Past", show #2,542.Mbanna and Konnadi on A.L.R.Audiotape 99506151996-01-24Scope and Contents(90 min.)  "What War on Drugs?, Part 4", show #2,545.Mbanna Kantako on A.L.R.Audiotape 100506161996-02-07Scope and Contents(90 min.) "Witchcraft and Human Sacrifice", show #2,559.Mbanna Kantako on A.L.R.Audiotape 101506171996-02-20Scope and Contents(90 min.) "What War on Drugs?, Part 5", show #2,572.Notes on the Devils NewsAudiotape 102506181996-02-20Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Konnadi gets her First Traffic Ticket", show #2,572.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on A.L.R.Audiotape 103506191996-03-15Scope and Contents(90 min.)  "The Land Grab, Part 4", show #2,596.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on A.L.R.Audiotape 104506201996-03-22Scope and Contents(90 min.)  "Big Brothers Watching You", show #2,603.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on A.L.R.Audiotape 105506211996-04-05Scope and Contents(90 min.)  "Pigs, Part 4", show #2,617.Mbanna Kantako on A.L.R.Audiotape 106506221996-04-12Scope and Contents(90 min.) "The Meaning of Amen", show #2,624.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on A.L.R.Audiotape 107506231996-05-10Scope and Contents(90 min.)  "What War on Drugs?, Part 6", show #2,652.Bryan Harris on A.L.R.Audiotape 108506241996-05-22Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Pimping Mother Africa, Part 65" and "The Land of the Free and the Home of the Slave, Part 2", show #2,664.Mbanna Kantako on A.L.R.Audiotape 109506251996-05-24Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "The Ultimate Control:  Child Rape, Part 3", show #2,666.Shea Readus on B.L.R.Audiotape 110506261996-05-31Scope and Contents(90 min.)  "Social Services Uncovered, Part 4", show #2,673.Mbanna Kantako on H.L.R.Audiotape 111506281996-06-26Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "The 4 R's", show #2,699.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.L.R.Audiotape 112506271996-07-05Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "What is Education, Part 2", show #2,708.Mbanna Kantako on H.L.R.Audiotape 113506291996-07-12Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "What House of Life?", show # unknown.Real Brothers at the real tableAudiotape 114506301996-07-24Scope and Contents(90 min.)  Show #2,727.Box 13Box 1350631Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.L.R.Audiotape 115506331996-07-31Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Uncle Sam &amp; the Sun Worshipers, Part 1", show #2,734.Mbanna Kantako on H.L.R.Audiotape 116506341996-08-28Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "None of the Above", show #2,762.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.L.R.Audiotape 117506351996-09-04Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Uncle Sam &amp; the Sun Worshipers, Part 2", show #2,769.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.L.R.Audiotape 118506361996-09-25Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "What War on Drugs?, Part 7", show #2,790.Sheila Jones on H.L.R.Audiotape 119506371996-11-13Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Drug dealer, drug dealer, you can't hide", show #2,839.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.L.R.Audiotape 120506381996-11-20Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Unfair Welfare, Part 1", show #2,846.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.L.R.Audiotape 121506391996-11-27Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Unfair Welfare, Part 2", show #2,853.Mbanna and Konnadi on H.L.R.Audiotape 122506401996-01-24Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "The Land Grab, Part 5", show #2,860.Mimi Abramovitz on H.L.R.Audiotape 123506411996-12-05Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Under Attack and Fighting Back", show #2,861.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.L.R.Audiotape 124506421996-12-18Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Unfair Welfare, Part 3", show #2,874.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.L.R.Audiotape 125506431996-12-25Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Unfair Welfare, Part 4", show #2,881.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.L.R.Audiotape 126506441996-12-25Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "The Land Grab, Part 6", show #2,881.Notes on the Devils NewsAudiotape 127506461997-01-05Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "The Greeks and Sacrificing", show #2,892.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.L.R.Audiotape 128506471997-01-08Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Unfair Welfare, Part 5", show #2,895.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.L.R.Audiotape 129506451997-01-15Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "The Land Grab, Part 7", show #2,902.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.L.R.Audiotape 130506481997-01-15Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Unfair Welfare, Part 6", show #2,902.Mbanna and Konnadi on H.R.R.Audiotape 131506491997-01-29Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "What War on Drugs?, Part 8", show #2,916.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 132506501997-02-05Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Unfair Welfare, Part 7", show #2,923.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 133506511997-02-05Scope and ContentsDuplicate of audiotape #132.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 134506521997-02-13Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Unfair Welfare, Part 8", show #2,931.Box 14Box 1450632Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 135506531997-02-13Scope and ContentsDuplicate of audiotape #134.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 136506551997-02-13Scope and ContentsDuplicate of audiotapes #134 and #135.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 137506541997-03-19Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "The Land of the Free and the Home of the Slave, Part 4", show #2,965.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 138506561997-05-13Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "America the Perverted, Part 1", show #3,020.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 139506571997-05-15Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Pigs, Part 6", show #3,022.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 140506581997-05-27Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Unfair Welfare, Part 9", show #3,034.Keidi Obe Awadu on H.R.R.Audiotape 141506591997-05-28Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Elevating Science", show #3,035.Mbanna Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 142506601997-05-30Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "America the Perverted, Part 2", show #3,037.Mbanna Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 143506611997-06-03Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "There's Something Stinking and Its Abe Lincoln", show #3,041.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 144506621997-07-29Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Pigs, Part 9", show #3,089.Keidi Obe Awadu on H.R.R.Audiotape 145506631997-08-13Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Conspiracy Theories - Institutional Analysis", show #3,104.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 146506641997-08-14Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Pigs, Part 10", show #3,105.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 147506651997-08-19Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "The Land of the Free and the Home of the Slave, Part 5", show #3,110.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 148506661997-08-21Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "What War on Drugs?, Part 9", show #3,112.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 149506671997-09-17Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "The Land Grab, Part 9", show #3,139.Mbanna Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 150506681997-10-01Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Witches", show #3,153.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 151506691997-10-08Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Unfair Welfare, Part 10", show #3,160.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 152506701997-10-15Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Unfair Welfare, Part 11", show #3,167.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 153506711997-10-29Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Pigs, Part 11", show #3,181.Konnadi Kantako and EINUWR on H.R.R.Audiotape 154506721997-11-23Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "New World Order Review", show #3,206.Box 15Box 1550673Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 155506751997-11-26Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Pigs, Part 12", show #3,209.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 156506761997-12-16Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Pigs, Part 13", show #3,229.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 157506771997-12-23Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Pigs, Part 14", show #3,236.Human Rights RadioAudiotape 158506781997-12-25Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Raw African Power, Part 2", show #3,238.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 159506791997-12-30Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Unfair Welfare, Part 12", show #3,243.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 160506801998-01-06Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Punks Pimping the Impoverished", show #3,250.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 161506811998-01-06Scope and ContentsDuplicate of audiotape #160.Keidi Obe Awadu on H.R.R.Audiotape 162506821998-01-09Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Population Alimination", show #3,253.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 163506831998-01-13Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "The Land Grab, Part 10", show #3,257.Mbanna Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 164506841998-01-21Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "A Look in the Lodge, Part 2", show #3,265.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 165506851998-01-20Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Pigs, Part 15", show #3,264.Mbanna Kantako Live at UISAudiotape 166506861998-02-19Scope and Contents(90 min.)  "Human Rights vs. Civil Rights, Part 1 &amp; 2".Mbanna Kantako Live at UISAudiotape 167506871998-02-19Scope and Contents(60 min.)  "Human Rights vs. Civil Rights, Part 3 &amp; 4".Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 168506881998-02-24Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "The Land of the Free and the Home of the Slave, Part 6", show #3,299.Mbanna Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 169506891998-03-04Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides 1 &amp; 2)  "Co-pro-creation not masturbation", show #3,307.Mbanna Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 170506901998-03-04Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides 3 &amp; 4)  "Co-pro-creation not masturbation".Mbanna Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 171506911998-03-04Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides 5 &amp; 6)  "Co-pro-creation not masturbation".Human Rights RadioAudiotape 172506921998-03-06Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides 1 &amp; 2)  "Study Group", show #3,309.Human Rights RadioAudiotape 173506931998-03-06Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides 3 &amp; 4)  "Study Group", show #3309.Human Rights RadioAudiotape 174506941998-03-06Scope and ContentsDuplicate of audiotape #173.Box 16Box 1650674Human Rights RadioAudiotape 175506951998-03-06Scope and ContentsDuplicate of audiotape #172.Pat Gowens on H.R.R.Audiotape 176506961998-05-07Scope and Contents(90 min., Sides A &amp; B)  "Welfare Mothers, Part 1", show #3,371.Pat Gowens on H.R.R.Audiotape 177506971998-05-07Scope and Contents"Unfair Welfare, Part 2", show #3,371.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 178506981999-02-16Scope and Contents"The Media, Part 1", show #3,656.Mbanna and Dia Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 179506991999-02-23Scope and Contents"The Media, Part 2", show #3,663.Mbanna and Konnadi Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 180507001999-02-24Scope and Contents"Pimping Ain't Easy, Part 5" and "The Founding Felons G.W., Part 1", show #3,664.Mbanna and Konnadi Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 181507011999-03-10Scope and Contents"Pimping Ain't Easy, Part 6" and "There's Something Stinking and Its Abe Lincoln, Part 2", show #3,678.Walter Southall on Human Rights RadioAudiotape 182507021999-03-13Scope and Contents"The Streets of Springfield, Part 2", show #3,681.Mbanna and Konnadi Kantako on H.R.R.Audiotape 183507041999-03-10Scope and Contents"Pimping Ain't Easy, Part 7" and "There's Something Stinking and Its Abe Lincoln, Part 3", show #3,685.Walter Southall on Human Rights RadioAudiotape 184507031999-03-25Scope and Contents"War Talk, Part 1", show #3,683.Human Rights RadioAudiotape 185507052000-09-29Scope and ContentsF.C.C. RaidsHuman Rights RadioAudiotape 186507062001-08-27Scope and ContentsF.C.C. visit H.R.R. DecaturOVERSIZE cabinet 1OVERSIZE cabinet 150511Verbal Arts Festival 1992 poster - What is Censorship?Item 1505101Scope and ContentsMbanna Kantako of 107.1 FM Black Liberation Radio was a guest speaker during this festival on Thursday, April 23.
Located in Oversize Cabinet, Drawer 9Human Rights Radio 25th Anniversary PostersItem 27552220122Scope and ContentsFour posters celebrating the 25th anniversary of Human Right Radio. Located in Oversize Cabinet, Drawer 9.

