<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.87Archon Finding Aid Title MC.87UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:45:32 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC87. George C. Hoffman Papers, 1960-1991
    
      Hoffman, George C.
    
    MC.87
    94
    
      15.20 Cubic Feet
    
    1960-1991
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Springfield lawyer beginning practice in 1928; Chairman of the Springfield Committee for Higher Education (1960-1967); attorney for Sangamon State University on a retainer basis; and Springfield civic leader. Correspondence, memos, news clippings, reports, receipts, contracts, maps, and studies, chiefly 1965-1975, documenting the struggle to establish Sangamon State University and the university's legal transactions. The substance of the collection concerns higher education in Springfield, the acquisition of land for the campus, university governance, the physical development of the campus, and other university legal matters. Includes reports, correspondence, minutes and agendas of the Springfield Committee for Higher Education, a committee of business and professional figures who lobbied the State of Illinois for the establishment of a public, four-year college in Springfield (1960-1968); records regarding the acquisition and operation of the Clayville Rural Life Center (1972-1984); correspondence, reports, minutes and agendas of the SSU Foundation (1970-1989); programs, memos, minutes and agendas relating to CONVOCOM (an educational television service) and the development of its satellite technology (1970-1990);  correspondence and records regarding building contractors and the Gerald Schaflander case; correspondence, deeds, and maps regarding the purchase of lands for the SSU campus (1968-1983); and and news clippings, correspondence, and plans for the development of student housing (1970-1980).  
  
    Arrangement Note
Topical  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Series I was a gift from John Hoffman on 7/16/1998.  Series II was a gift from Fred Hoffman on 5/27/1998.  
  
    Related Materials
SEE ALSO: Oral History Collection:  H675IInes C. Hoffmann Memoir (Mrs. George Hoffman)  
  
    Records
    Papers
  
  Series 1Series 15537Box 1Box 15539Folder 1558719821Scope and ContentsContains news clippings and correspondence concerning Hoffmann's honorary
degree.Vocational and Technical Education in Illinois: Tomorrow's ChallengeItem 1554019601"A Study of the Proposal to Establish a Public Junior College in Springfield SchoolItem 255411961-062Scope and ContentsBy Dr. Donald W. Dunnan"Springfield Area Study-Higher Education"Item 355421963-013Scope and ContentsBy Dr. Robert M. Crane (2 copies)"College-Age Population Projections and Higher Education Enrollment Estimates in Illinois to 1980: Preliminary Report"Item 455431963-044Illinois School ProblemsItem 5554419655The Illinois Junior College SystemItem 6554519666Procedures for the Establishment of Public 2-Year CollegesItem 7554619667The Challenge of TomorrowItem 855471966-02-018"The Illinois Master Plan"Item 955481966-09-309Scope and ContentsBy Richard G. BrowneEndorsement of the Provisional Plan-Phase II of Board of Higher Education by Springfield Committee for Higher EducationItem 1055491966-1110"An Evaluation of the Need for A Senior College in Springfield"Item 1155501967-0311Scope and ContentsBy Robert Ferber (2 copies)Medical School Location AnalysisItem 1255511967-0412Location Analysis of Potential Medical School in Springfield AreaItem 1355521967-0813Education in the Health Fields for the State of Illinois: Volume 1Item 1455531968-0614Growth in Illinois Higher Education, 1962-68Item 1555541968-1215State of Illinois Board of Higher Education: Fourth Biennial Report, 1967-68Item 1655551969-0116Strengthening Private Higher Education in IllinoisItem 1755561969-0317Recommendations for Higher Education Operating Budgets, 1969-71Item 18555718Sangamon State University PamphletItem 195558197019Guide to Sangamon State University, 1970-71Item 20555920Fiscal Year 1972 Capital Budget-SSU, 6 August 1970Item 2155601970-09-0121Sangamon State University Internal Budget, 1970-71Item 22556122Sangamon State University Guide to Academic Programs, 1970-72Item 23556223Sangamon State University Progress Report on Academic ProgramsItem 2455631970-0924Interim University HandbookItem 2555641970-1025SSU Interim Facilities- Phase BItem 2655651970-12-1026Board of Regents Appropriations Requests for FY '72Item 2755661971-0427"A History and A Critique of Sangamon State University"Item 2855671972-0528Scope and ContentsBy Francis J. BudingerProgram-Commencement and Inauguration of the President Robert Clark SpencerItem 2955681972-06-1029Clayville Rural Life Center: Its First Two Years, 1975Item 30556930Student Housing-Sangamon State UniversityItem 3155701975-0931Sangamon State University Foundation, Report of the TreasurerItem 3255711975-09-18, 1980-09-24, 1981-09-3032Sangamon State University President's Report: 1970-75Item 33557233Norris L. Brookens LibraryItem 3455731976-0534Guide to the Faculty and Academic Requirements: SSU, 1976-77Item 35557435On-Campus Student Housing Feasibility StudyItem 3655751977-0436Robert C. Spencer PortraitItem 3755761978-10-2637Scope and ContentsPamphletStudent Housing Review Bond of 1979Item 38557738Scope and ContentsTranscriptSangamon State University (promotional brochure)Item 395578197939SSU-Board of Regents Student Housing Project ManualItem 4055791979-06-1140Public Affairs Center Dedication ProgramItem 41558019814119th Commencement ProgramItem 425582199042Untitled Report on Senior College in SpringfieldItem 43558343PAC GuideItem 44558444Need for Senior College PamphletItem 45558545Sangamon State University Campus and Springfield MapItem 46558646Box 2Box 25588Miscellaneous Materials—SSUFolder 155891976-19831SSUF Financial ProjectionsItem 1559011Board of Directors reportsItem 25591197912Clayville Rural Life CenterItem 3559213SSU Commencement ProgramsItem 4559314Scope and Contents11th (1982-05-16)
13th (1984-05-12)
15th (1986-05-17)
17th (1988-05-14)1974 "Technological Factors Affecting Illinois Coal Utilization"Item 5559415Newspaper ClippingsItem 655951987-198916SSU-OriginsFolder 255962Scope and Contents1972, 1982, 1985 Speeches and papers concerning SSU's origins and historySpringfield Committee for Higher EducationFolder 355971963-19693Scope and ContentsStatements and Correspondence about need for higher education in Springfield1962 Survey—Springfield Study of Higher EducationFolder 4559841967 Report of the Special Committee on New Senior Institutions to the Illinois Board of Higher EducationFolder 555991967-12-205Scope and ContentsIncludes 1968 Statement of the University of Illinois concerning the Report of the Board of
Higher Education Special Committee on New Senior Institutions, 1968-01-10Memos and ReportsFolder 656006Memos regarding "Strengthening Private Higher Education"Item 15601196961Illinois Board of Education Recommendations for Aid to Nonpublic InstitutionsItem 25602196962"Post-High School Technical Education: An Urgent Problem in Illinois?"Item 35603196163Proposed Model for SSUFolder 756047"A Proposed Model for Sangamon State University"Item 156051970-0171Scope and ContentsBy Sarah Anne Robinson, Ph.D."A Proposed Model for A Utopian University"Item 256061970-0472Scope and ContentsBy Sarah Anne Robinson, Ph.D.Bill to Create SSUFolder 8560719678Scope and ContentsSenate Bill 955 Lobbying efforts and EndorsementsSpringfield Higher EducationFolder 956081964-19789Statement to Committee T of the Board of Higher EducationItem 15609196891Correspondence regarding real estateItem 25610197792"The Lamp"Item 356111972-11-2893Newspaper Clippings regarding Springfield EducationFolder 1056121961-196710Scope and ContentsMany pre-SSU clippings, but some dating from the 1970s as wellIllinois Board of Higher Education Master Plan Committee ReportsItem 11561311Committee A-College EnrollmentsItem 1256141963-1212Committee B-Admission and Retention of StudentsItem 1356151963-1213Committee C-Faculty StudyItem 1456161963-1214Committee D-Collegiate ProgramItem 1556171963-1215Committee E-ResearchItem 1656181963-1216Committee F-Two-year collegesItem 1756191963-1217Committee G-Extension and Public ServiceItem 1856201963-1218Committee H-Vocational, Technical, Adult EducationItem 1956211963-1219Committee I-Physical FacilitiesItem 2056221963-1220Committee J-Illinois Financing of Higher EducationItem 2156231963-1221Committee L-Institutional Size and CapacityItem 225624196622Committee M-Demography and LocationItem 235625196623Committee N-Governing StructureItem 245626196624Committee O-Programs and ExperimentationItem 255627196625Committee P-Scholarship and Financial AidsItem 265628196626A Master Plan for Higher Education in IllinoisItem 27562927Scope and ContentsIllinois Board of Higher Education Master Plan, July 1964
Master Plan-Phase II, December 1966
Provisional Master Plan, March 1964
Master Plan-Phase III, May 1971Other Illinois Board of Higher Education ReportsItem 28563028Scope and ContentsFinal Recommendations of All Master Plan Committees, February 1964
A Master Plan-Phase II (Provisional Draft), September 1966
Reports on the Master Plan-Phase II, August 1966
Master Plan-Phase III Reports (Committee T-Public Administration, Committee U- Legal
Education)
Report on New Senior Institutions, February 1968Xeroxes of State Journal-Register newsclips about Springfield Senior CollegeItem 29563129Scope and Contents(2 copies)Box 3Box 35632SSU- Statements/contractsFolder 156331972-19841Invoices, contracts, agreements for legal services between SSU and Hoffman &amp; HoffmanItem 1563811SSU President's Report to the Board of RegentsItem 256391978-06-2212Springfield Committee for Higher EducationFolder 256341966-682Proposals by University of Illinois to establish a campus in SpringfieldItem 1563521Governance issuesItem 2563622Envelope of news clippings concerning governanceItem 3563723Medical School-Health Care EducationFolder 3564019673Desire for Creation of Law School-Correspondence, reportsFolder 456411969-19744SSU-Tax Exemptions-real estate, mortgage, assessmentFolder 556421973-19845SSU Creation; College-Public AdministrationFolder 656431967-19696Kathryn and Fred Patton papers-scholarships, parkFolder 756441978-19797SSU- Data Processing EquipmentFolder 856451978-19828Scope and ContentsAgreements, contracts for accountants, equipment, computersSSU- Real estate exemption certificatesFolder 956461986-19889SSU-University LitigationFolder 1056471979-198310SSU FoundationFolder 1156481977-198511Scope and ContentsReal estate matters; questions regarding SSUF's budgetSSU FoundationFolder 1256491972-197712Scope and ContentsLand deals; president's house projectSSU Foundation-Misc.Folder 1356501970-198613Scope and ContentsBylaws of SSU Foundation, 1978; real estate bequests, 1970-86SSU FoundationFolder 1456511975-198014Scope and ContentsProperty, accounts, leases, mortgagesBox 4Box 45652SSU Foundation-correspondence, resolutionsFolder 156531978-19791SSU Foundation-property-Lubin, et al.Folder 256541969-19782Performing Arts and Sciences FundFolder 356551981-19823SSU FoundationFolder 456561973-19764Scope and ContentsDevelopment-Clayville, housing, fountainsSSU Foundation Minutes (1970-1978) and Bylaws (1968-1981)Folder 556575SSU Foundation-Orchestra List, Public Affairs, Auditorium, ClayvilleFolder 656581981-19846SSU-Illinois Building AuthorityFolder 756611970-19727Scope and ContentsEasements, library, plat maps, land surveysSSU College Sites, ArchitectsFolder 856621967-19748Proposed college site; promotional literature from architects, engineers, soil consultantsItem 1566381SSU-Shepherd Road VacationItem 256641969-197782Development estimates, maps, land holdingsItem 3566583SSU-Springfield Sanitary District-agreementsItem 456661972-197984Appraisal Reports (10) Woodside TownshipItem 9565919689Blunk &amp; Blankmeyer; McClelland, Perry; Cox; Stout; Shepherd, Helen; Lubin; Charlson, Laura; McClelland, Charles Wesley; Shepherd &amp; ShepherdItem 10566010Scope and Contents(2 copies)Box 5Box 55667SSU Area DevelopmentFolder 1566819701Shepherd Road vacationFolder 2566919722SSU Legal Dealings (buildings and property)Folder 356701970-19723Scope and ContentsArchitects, utilities, furnishings, equipmentSSU-Zoning and Land UseFolder 456711969-19754SSU-Misc.Folder 556721970-19905Scope and ContentsProposal for Chamberlain School of LawSSU New Leases-Student HousingFolder 656731973-19766SSU Clayville Rural Life Center PlanningFolder 756741974-19767SSU-Curtis Hill ControversyFolder 856751973-19758Scope and ContentsHill was a graphic artist working for SSU; there were disagreements about reimbursement for his work.SSU Foundation-Conveyance of land to the University in discharge of debtFolder 956761974-19829SSU Foundation-Water Main to Pleasant PlainsFolder 1056771977-197910SSU-Clayville Planning IIFolder 1156781974-197811SSU "Friends of the Prairie Stars" Incorporation—Athletic AssociationFolder 1256791970-198012Box 6Box 65680SSU Foundation-Nuclear ResourcesFolder 156811974-19781Scope and ContentsNuclear Resources was a company involved with SSU in the Clayville Center projectSSUFolder 256821976-19802SSU-Food Service Agreements &amp; Liquor LicenseFolder 356831980-19823SSU-Student Housing—SCHAFolder 456841967-19764Application for Student Housing IIFolder 5568519795SSU Foundation—Housing Fund-DecemberFolder 656861978-19796SSU-Copies of agreements-HUD-related; bondsFolder 7568719797SSU-Academic Policy—President's reportsFolder 856881969-19738SSU-Lincoln Library MemosFolder 956891978-19809SSU-Student HousingFolder 1056901977-198010SSU-Pleadings Process AppearanceFolder 1156911968-196911Box 7Box 75692Student Apartment BuildingsFolder 156931976-19791SSU—Student Housing Application—Apartment House ProjectFolder 256941977-19792SSU—Downtown Center—Leland Builing—Capitol CampusFolder 356951972-19823SSU Foundation—YMCA Field Service BuildingFolder 456961977-19814SSU Origins—CONVOCOMFolder 556971981-19915SSU—Tax Assessments, ExemptionsFolder 656981969-19756SSU Foundation—Farm Income/TaxFolder 756991969-19897SSU-CILCO-GASFolder 857001970-19758Scope and ContentsLegal briefs and arguments re: CILCO's proposal for limits on its corporate customers' use.SSU-HousingFolder 9570119799Scope and ContentsInsurance—electrical, plumbing, construction; owner/contractor agreement; revenue bonds; project budgetSSU—Harland, Bartholomew, and Assoc.—Traffic EngineersFolder 1057021972-197310Scope and ContentsContract—SSU Street SystemBox 8Box 85703SSU-Surge BuildingFolder 157041973-19781Scope and ContentsPapers regarding legal questions when lien-lease agreement changed handsSSU-Surge Building-Raymur LeaseFolder 257051971-19772Scope and ContentsLease agreement, timelineSSU Board of Regents BRH Builder Interpleader CorrespondenceFolder 357061973-19763SSU Board of Regents BRH Builder Interpleader CorrespondenceFolder 457071974-19764Scope and ContentsBidding documentsSSU-Raymur Schools Corp., BRH briefs and memosFolder 557081973-19765SSU Interim Facilities (Part II), Ring Road, Partitions, etc.Folder 657091970-19726Scope and ContentsAgreements, contracts, insurance certificates, specs for Phase I, librarySSU Annexation—September 1972Folder 757101972-19747SSU Zoning Matters II—Coalition for Urban DevelopmentFolder 857111972-19788SSU—Downtown CenterFolder 957121973-19749Scope and ContentsCorrespondenceBox 9Box 95713SSU--Phase B Interim Facilities buildingFolder 1571419711Scope and ContentsAcademic Building; Library Additions—Contract DocumentsSSU—Legal Counsel for the Board of Regents- memos, etc.Folder 257151972-19772Equal Employment Opportunity/Affirmative Action—university constructionFolder 357161971-19733SSU—New Easements—charts, diagrams, agreements—housingFolder 457171970-19804SSU- Raymur Schools Corporation IIFolder 557181970-19785SSU 1973 financial statements (case of BRH Builders)Folder 657191974-19786Scope and ContentsContractsSSU Board of RegentsFolder 757201969-19737Scope and ContentsRegulations, governanceBox 10Box 105721SSU Foundation- permanent residence for PresidentFolder 157221972-19801Scope and ContentsLease, mortgage, specificationsInterim FacilitiesFolder 257231970-19712Scope and ContentsBids, specificationsSSU- Legal contracts with Murphy, Downing, Wofford and RichmanFolder 357241971-19723SSU-Legal MattersFolder 457251969-19704Scope and ContentsLibrary book purchase, land, student demonstrations, loyalty oaths, banking resolutionsSSU-Legal MattersFolder 557261970-19725Scope and ContentsCo-op bookstore, student unrest, student teaching, faculty contracts, litigation, band contracts, annexation to city, alleged possession of drugs by a faculty memberBoard of Regents RegulationsFolder 657271969-19726Scope and ContentsGoverning policy, bylawsSSU Labor ContractsFolder 757281969-19727SSU Day Care Center IncorporatedFolder 857291970-19728Capital Development Board—regulationsFolder 9573019729SSU—Interim Facilities ContractsFolder 105731197210Scope and ContentsMemos, blueprints, greenhouseSSU— Legal IssuesFolder 1157321970-197211SSU General Storage BuildingFolder 125733197212Scope and ContentsSpecifications, contracts, bidsSSU—Raymur Schools Corporation IIIFolder 1357341970-197413Box 11Box 115735SSU Raymur Schools Corporation LeaseFolder 1573619701SSU WSSR SatellitesFolder 2573719782ConvocomFolder 357381986-19873Scope and ContentsFinancial information, programmingConvocom—legal workFolder 457391983-19884ConvocomFolder 557401986-19875Convocom microwave bidsFolder 6574119796CONVOCOM Markley, et al.Folder 757421984-19857ConvocomFolder 857431982-19848WCIETCFolder 957441978-19799Scope and ContentsPublic relations, funding concernsSSU Radio and TV TowerFolder 1057451970-197410Convocom–microwave networkFolder 1157461979-198511ConvocomFolder 1257471981-198312ConvocomFolder 135748198513ConvocomFolder 1457491982-198514Scope and ContentsAgreements, schedulesBox 12Box 125750ConvocomFolder 157511975-19771Scope and ContentsPurchase of tower near Bluffs/microwave equipmentConvocomFolder 257521985-19882Scope and ContentsFund-raisingWCIETCFolder 357531976-19863ConvocomFolder 457541986-19884Scope and ContentsPolicies, correspondenceConvocomFolder 557551981-19875Scope and ContentsEquipment, bylaws, lease informationICH 1040 copiesFolder 657561985-19866Convocom—Bunn-O-Matic CorporationFolder 757571980-19877Scope and ContentsViewer surveys, financial statementsConvocom—Articles of Incorporation, AmendmentsFolder 857581984-19858Convocom—equipment listsFolder 957591983-19869ConvocomFolder 1057601980-198210Scope and ContentsFinancial reports, bidding documents, equipmentConvocomFolder 1157611986-199011Scope and ContentsAgendas, financial information, news releasesConvocomFolder 1257621977-1979; 198812Scope and ContentsVolunteer report; accounts; leases; specifications for TV transmitter, Vortman agreementBox 13Box 135763WCIETC Convocom lease terminationFolder 157641978-19801Scope and ContentsFunding agreements, legislative appropriationsSSU Convocom File IFolder 257651976-19782Scope and ContentsFunding, TV tower, legal concerns, Lovekamp memosWest Central Illinois TV Tower InsuranceFolder 357661976-19823Convocom-tower lease agreementFolder 4576719814WCIETC/Convocom Transmitter BidsFolder 5576819785Convocom-Spoon River property mapsFolder 6576919826Convocom termination file and reorganizationFolder 7577019807Convocom-Rock Island BroadcastingFolder 857711977-19788WCIETC/Convocom-Bureau of BudgetFolder 9577219789WCIETC/Convocom File II—correspondenceFolder 1057731976-197710ConvocomFolder 115774198211Scope and ContentsDistribution of microwave leasesConvocomFolder 125775198112Scope and ContentsSpecifications for microwave contract biddingConvocom-Spoon River College propertyFolder 1357761982-198313Series 2Series 25538Box 1Box 15777SSU-Board of Regents- SettlementsFolder 157781968-19721Properties AcquiredItem 157791968-197211Scope and ContentsMcClelland (2), Cox, Shively, Stout, ShepherdSite Cost Estimates for SSU and LLJCItem 2578012Shadid Contract (SSU Bookstore Contract)Folder 257811970-19722Scope and ContentsNebraska Book Company (SSU Bookstore, 1972-?)George CohenFolder 357821970-19713Scope and ContentsFormer Vice-President for Academic Affairs until July 7, 1970. Cohen was dismissed and then he sued the UniversityGerald SchaflanderFolder 457834Scope and ContentsControversial candidate for political studies department (1970). Legal complications arose from his "aiding and abetting an abortion."Policies during campus unrest/disruptions/demonstrationsFolder 5578419715Springfield Committee for Higher Education I-1,2Folder 657851964-19656Scope and ContentsPapers relating to development of a four year college in SpringfieldSpringfield Committee for Higher Education I-1,2Folder 757861964-19657Scope and ContentsPapers relating to development of a four year college in SpringfieldSpringfield Committee for Higher Education II- 1,2Folder 857871960-19648Scope and ContentsSurveys, news clippings, correspondence relating to condition of Illinois higher educationSpringfield Committee for Higher Education II- 1,2Folder 957881960-19649Scope and ContentsSurveys, news clippings, correspondence relating to condition of Illinois higher educationSSU-Volunteer WorkFolder 1057891970-197110Scope and ContentsGovernance papers and constitutionLaw School- 1,2Folder 1157901971-197711Scope and ContentsCenter for Legal Studies-articles, reports, surveys, correspondence on legal studies
and need for legal education in SpringfieldLaw School- 1,2Folder 1257911971-197712Scope and ContentsCenter for Legal Studies-articles, reports, surveys, correspondence on legal studies
and need for legal education in SpringfieldPassage of Senior College Bill 955Folder 135792196713Scope and ContentsRelating to higher education funding in
Illinois; Also 1950 "Report of the Study of the Structure of the State Tax-Supported System of Higher Education in Illinois"Papers Related to the Passage of SB 955-bill creating SSU-and need for senior collegeFolder 145793196714Scope and ContentsAlso 1966 Master PlanSpringfield Committee for Higher Education III- 1Folder 1557941965-0815Historic background of SSUItem 157951972151Senate Bill 1165 (budget for SSU)Item 257961969-1970152Springfield Committee for Higher Education III-2Folder 1657971965-0816Scope and ContentsSurvey of Springfield High Schools, 1966
Statement for a Four Year College in Springfield, 1965Survey of Springfield High SchoolsItem 157981966161Statement for a Four Year College in SpringfieldItem 257991965162Springfield Committee for Higher Education III- 2Folder 1758001965-0817Springfield Study of Higher EducationItem 158011964-08-27171Correspondence and articles regarding the need for a college in SpringfieldItem 258021965172Springfield Committee for Higher EducationFolder 1858031966-0318Scope and ContentsCorrespondenceCollegeFolder 1958041967-196919Scope and ContentsCorrespondence regarding SSU and whose system they will be placed underSpringfield Community College-need forFolder 2058051960-196120Box 2Box 25806Springfield Community College- Community College Fact-Finding CommitteeFolder 158071960-19611Scope and ContentsConcerns vote to establish junior collegeSpringfield College in IllinoisFolder 258081974-19772Correspondence and minutes of Lay Advisory BoardItem 1580921Papers concerned with funding and fund-raisingItem 2581022Springfield College in Illinois Financial AuditsFolder 358111973-19753Springfield College in IllinoisFolder 458121971-19744Scope and ContentsPromotional literature for potential donorsPossible Relation between Senior College and State GovernmentFolder 558131966-19675Scope and ContentsLegislative information and correspondenceCollegeFolder 658141967-19726Inaugural program for President SpencerItem 15815197261"Proposal for the Establishment by the University of Illinois of a New Institution of Higher Education in Springfield"Item 258161967-10-1662Lincoln Land Community College Ground-breaking Ceremony ProgramItem 35817197063CollegeFolder 758181967-19707Scope and ContentsCorrespondence regarding faculty candidates and SSU.CollegeFolder 8581919678Scope and ContentsLegislation and correspondenceCollegeFolder 958201966-19679Scope and ContentsSupport for founding of SSU-mainly correspondenceSpringfield Committee for Higher EducationFolder 1058211963-196610Scope and Contents"A Master Plan-Phase II"-Illinois Board of Higher Education, September 1966; CorrespondenceSpringfield Committee for Higher EducationFolder 115822196711Scope and Contents"The Need for a State Senior College in Springfield" by Robert Ferber (February 1967)Springfield Committee for Higher Education-Dr. Robert FerberFolder 1258231966-196712Scope and ContentsFerber papers and correspondence regarding surveyLots Exchange-Springfield Housing Authority-1Folder 1358241973-197613Scope and ContentsEastside Neighborhood Development ProgramLots Exchange-Springfield Housing Authority-2Folder 1458251968-197614Scope and ContentsEastside Neighborhood Development ProgramLots Exchange-Springfield Housing Authority-3Folder 1558261974-197615Scope and ContentsConcern about public housing on East side of SpringfieldBoard of Regents-Robert Shepherd Trial-Land AcquisitionFolder 1658271968-197116Scope and Contents1968 Triennial Atlas and Plat Book of Sangamon CountyBox 3Box 35828Sangamon State University FoundationFolder 158291968-19751Scope and ContentsMinutes, bylawsAppraisals-misc.Folder 258301968-19732MiscellaneousFolder 358311967-19733"Reflections on the Carnegie Commission on the Future of Higher Education in the United States"Item 158321973-0631Scope and ContentsUIUC President David D. Henry paperLow-rent Housing ManuaItem 258331968321967 House Bill 955 passageItem 3583433

