<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.90Archon Finding Aid Title MC.90UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:48:12 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC90. Jim Grubbs Armed Forces and Small Market Radio Collection, 1951-2001
    
      Grubbs, Jim
    
    MC.90
    97
    
      0.20 Cubic Feet
    
    1951-2001
    Date acquired: 01/10/2005
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Jim Grubbs, Assistant Professor of Communication at UIS, was a radio broadcaster for the Far East Network (FEN), stationed in Tokyo, Japan during the 1960s. Later Grubbs was an announcer for WSMI in Litchfield, Illinois.  In 1976, Grubbs and several other SSU employees and community members were granted a license for a station (98.7-WNNS) in Springfield.  He was recognized by Billboard Magazine as one of the outstanding small-market DJs in the United States in 1971. 

The collection includes audio CDs of broadcasts from the Far East  and Armed Forces Networks as well as broadcasts from small market radio stations.  The CDs from FEN and AFN document  the types of radio entertainment military personnel and their dependents listened to during their time in Japan and Alaska.  These broadcasts, dating from 1959 to 1971, include comedy, interviews, literature, a children's program, and music ranging from "Big Band" and Country to Top 20.  Also included is an oral history of Private Shelby Newhouse, one of the first FEN announcers.  Notable broadcasts include a 1972 interview with boxer Muhammed Ali, a 1960 broadcast featuring recordings by Elvis Presley, and a 1981 program detailing the history of WSMI in Litchfield, Illinois.

The CDs from the Illinois small market radio collections feature jingles, news, market reports, and music.  Also included is the "1971 Billboard Entry" that Grubbs submitted to Billboard Magazine.  
  
    Arrangement Note
By broadcast type and date  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Jim Grubbs  
  
    Audio CDs
  
  Audio CDsBox 13530FEN 0001 "Jazz Time"Item 13531ca. 19651Scope and ContentsAirman Burr Hoyle mixes a small amount of musical history into his commentary as he explores the range of jazz virtuosos from Jerry Mulligan, Stan Getz, Wes Montgomery on guitar, Clifford Brown on trumpet, and vocalists Mel Torme, June Christie, and the Four Freshman. 
Author: Airman Burr Hoyle. Playing time: 46:06FEN 0002 "Tokyo Calling"Item 235321965-01-102Scope and ContentsFeaturing music, comedy, interviews, and literature, at its best, "Tokyo Calling" was a vehicle for a potpourri of programming designed to capture the attention of young and old alike, women and men, military personnel, their dependents, domestic audiences, and the worldwide audience on shortwave. 
Author: Airman Burr Hoyle. Playing Time: 54:26FEN 0003 "Tokyo Calling"Item 335331965-03-073Scope and ContentsFeaturing music, comedy, interviews, and literature, at its best, "Tokyo Calling" was a vehicle for a potpourri of programming designed to capture the attention of young and old alike, women and men, military personnel, their dependents, domestic audiences, and the worldwide audience on shortwave.
Author: Airman Burr Hoyle. Playing Time: 53:20FEN 0004 "Tokyo Calling"Item 435341965-08-154Scope and ContentsFeaturing music, comedy, interviews, and literature, at its best, "Tokyo Calling" was a vehicle for a potpourri of programming designed to capture the attention of young and old alike, women and men, military personnel, their dependents, domestic audiences, and the worldwide audience on shortwave.
Author: Airman Burr Hoyle. Playing Time: 55:53FEN 0005 "Tokyo Calling"Item 535351960-07-105Scope and ContentsThis edition of "Tokyo Calling" comes from an earlier time period than FEN 0002 through FEN 0004 and illustrates that change in the format of the program over the years.
Author: Air Force Sgt. Jack Tyson. Playing Time: 1:13:34FEN 0006 "FEN 30th Anniversary Show"Item 635361975-09-126Scope and ContentsOn the 30th anniversary of the Far East Network in 1975, the Far East Network put together a one-hour retrospective featuring the history and highlights of the network.  Included is the formal Japanese surrender, Bob Hope broadcasts, the famous "monster who ate Tokyo" prank, the 1964 Olympics, and other network highlights.
Author: Air Force Sgt. Jim Dougherty. Playing Time: 59:30FEN 0007 "Bands of Japan"Item 73537ca. 19597Scope and Contents"Bands of Japan" was a weekly broadcast on the Far East Network featuring local Japanese "big bands" and was broadcast live from the officer's club in Sasebo, Japan.
Author: Army Sgt. Wayne Cummins. Playing Time: 29:35FEN 0008 "Let's Dance"Item 83538ca. 19598Scope and Contents"Let's Dance" was a show similar in style to "Bands of Japan."  The weekly broadcast featured local "big bands" and was broadcast live from Itazuke Naval Air Station, Japan.
Author: Airman 2nd Class Bill Hoffmeier. Playing Time: 25:19FEN 0009 "Operation Rumbleseat"Item 93539ca. 19599Scope and ContentsLt. Lapp recorded what is thought to be the first (if not only) show to be produced at super-sonic speed while a passenger in an F-100 fighter jet.
Author: Air Force Lt. Jim Lapp. Playing Time: 15:50.FEN 0010 "Oral History-Private Newhouse"Item 1035402001-01-0110Scope and ContentsThis is an oral history recorded by Private Shelby Newhouse who served as one of the first announcers for the Far East Network Tokyo station in 1952.  Newhouse recalls how he came to be a radio announcer and the conditions in post-war Japan.  He describes Tokyo studios and several incidents from the early days of the network.
Author: Army Private Shelby Newhouse. Playing Time: 16:09FEN 0011 "This is the Far East Network"Item 113541195111Scope and ContentsMerwin Smith was chief announcer, actor, and program director of FEN in 1952 when the station occupied studios in the NHK Radio Tokyo building in downtown Tokyo.  This presentation serves as a summary of early FEN activities.
Author: Merwin Smith. Playing Time: 23:45FEN 0012 "Enjoy Japan"Item 123542ca. 196012Scope and Contents"Enjoy Japan" was a weekly featured series broadcast on the Far East Network designed as a cross-cultural exchange aimed at both American military personnel and Japanese nationals.  The show featured music of Japan and discussed elements of Japanese culture.  The show's co-host was Hiroko Kubota who became a well-known writer in Japan.  This particular episode features Jizo-san (a mountain named for a guardian deity), Japanese superstitions, and the practice of "moon viewing."
Author: Sgt. Walt Sheldon and Hiroko Kubota. Playing Time: 54:54FEN 0013 "Sleepy Hollow"Item 1335431970-08-2913Scope and ContentsIn 1970, James Hilbrink of FEN-Tokyo conceived the idea of a weekly, locally produced, children's program to serve the dependents of personnel stationed in Japan.  The first broadcast aired on August 29, 1970.  Topics such as bike safety, the Boy Scouts, and even general safety tips were designed to fit comfortably within the "Sleepy Hollow" format.
Author: James Hilbrink, Tim Huguenard, and Kay Coughlin. Playing Time: 38:30FEN 0014 "FEN Daily Country Music Show"Item 143544ca. 197114Scope and ContentsDonator Paul Keane was a British Merchant Marine who listened to FEN regularly while in and around Japanese harbors.  He caught this country music show on his personal reel to reel tape recorder.
Author: Tim Huguenard. Playing Time: 18:19FEN 0015 "Top 20"Item 153545ca. 196215Scope and ContentsThis 1962 broadcast is typical of a series of Top 20 shows that aired, almost always on Saturday nights, over the users at FEN.  Cashman's notation at the end of the show that they were unable to present the number one Billboard song because they did not yet have it was a recurring problem at FEN.  Records had to be reviewed and distributed through the Armed Forces Radio and Television Service headquarters in California thus ensuring a delay in distribution.  Personal copies of records could not be played.
Author: Airman 1C George Cashman. Playing Time: 20:39FEN 0016 "Teenagers on Parade"Item 1635461960-09-1716Scope and ContentsPrograms aimed at teen listeners have been a mainstay on FEN throughout most of its history.  This broadcast comes from the Grant Heights Teen Club, located just outside of Tokyo.  With the cooperation of FEN, a full radio studio, known as "Radio T-E-E-N" was constructed in the teen club where regular Saturday morning broadcasts were originated.
Author: Dave Robertson &amp; Roy Goodwin. Playing Time: 1:07:40FEN 0017 "Teenagers on Parade"Item 173547ca. 1960-196117Scope and ContentsThis edition of "Teenagers on Parade" features a show that was produced in the FEN Tokyo studios rather than on location.
Author: Dave Robertson and Patty. Playing Time: 1:03:21FEN 0018 "Muhammad Ali Interview"Item 1835481972-03-3118Scope and ContentsSports was an integral part of FEN programming.  This 1972 clip features a background story and interview with Muhammad Ali the day before his fight with Mac Foster at the Tokyo Buddakan on April 1, 1972.
Author: Marine Cpl. Tim Secker and Air Force Sgt. Art Burnett. Playing Time: 10:26FEN 0019 "Teenagers on Parade"Item 1935491961-07-2219Scope and ContentsThis episode of "Teenagers on Parade" features two additional hosts.  This is a "telescoped" rather than full version of a very poor quality tape.
Author: Sandy Cooper, Dave Robertson, and Wayne. Playing Time: 10:40FEN 0020 "Feature Artist (Elvis Presley)"Item 203550ca. 196020Scope and ContentsPrior to the broadcasts over FEN from the Grant Heights teen club, high-school aged students created their own "closed circuit" station known as "Radio T-E-E-N."  The studio was directly connected to the speaker systems via telephone wires at various base locations including the swimming pool.  Bill McCain is one of the individuals directly responsible for the creation of Radio T-E-E-N.
Author: Bill McCain. Playing Time: 18:58FEN 0021 "Teen Scene Discotheque"Item 2135511968-06-2221Scope and ContentsIn the summer of 1968, "Teenagers on Parade" evolved into a live show aired from pool side at South Camp Drake near Tokyo, Japan called "The Teen Scene Discotheque."  While this tape may appear to be of poor quality, it is very close to the sound of the original broadcast.  A standard telephone line was used to carrying the signal from poolside to the main study with a resultant "tinny" sound.
Author: Gary Griffin, Kay Nishioka, Jim Grubbs, and "The Green Apples." Playing Time: 55:00FEN 0022 "Fun Dial"Item 2235521968-06-2022Scope and ContentsLike "Teenagers on Parade," "Fun Dial" has been through a number of incarnations over the years.  During the 1960s and early 1970s, it served as the Far East Network's daily outlet for Top 40 music.  This session features the network's non-commissioned officer in charge (NCOIC) Sgt. Don Mooring.
Author: Air Force MSgt. Don Mooring. Playing Time: 55:00FEN 0023 "Teenagers on Parade"Item 2335531966-01-0123Scope and ContentsThis is a New Year's Day special edition on "Teenagers on Parade" that features a review of music from 1965.  This was Paul Sheffield's first show.
Author: Chris Bergstead and Paul Sheffield Playing Time: 55:26FEN 0024 "Teenagers on Parade"Item 2435541967-07-1524Scope and ContentsThis show was the first "Teenagers on Parade" for Tim Synder.  Synder was also a voice in several Japanese anime cartoons of the period including "Speed Racer."
Author: Suzanne Stevens and Tim Synder. Playing Time: 56:01AFN 0001 "Armed Forces Network Alaska PAMS Series 42 Jingles"Item 253555ca. 197125Scope and ContentsThese jingles were produced by the PAMS Corporation for the Armed Forces Network Alaska.  A number of these jingles were adapted and used on the Far East Network as well.
Author: PAMS Singers. Playing Time: 15:09SMI 0001 "WSMI Jingles"Item 263556ca. 197026Scope and ContentsThis is a series of 13 jingles produced by Pepper-Tanner for WSMI and WSMI-FM in Litchfield, Illinois.  They represent typical jingles used in small market radio during the period.
Author: Pepper Tanner Singers. Playing Time: 3:57SMI 0002 "31 Years of WSMI and You Featuring John Marty and Jim Grubbs"Item 273557ca. 198127Scope and ContentsThis CD features a number of programming elements from WSMI, Litchfield, Illinois, including Nelson Boswell Commentary, Bond County (Illinois) news, market reports, and a country music program.  This recording was captured over-the-air in Springfield, Illinois and includes "31 Years of WSMI and You."  John Marty produced a series of featured highlighting WSMI personalities during the station's history.
Author: John Michael Marty. Playing Time: 42:32SMI 0003 "1971 Billboard Entry"Item 2835581971-07-0128Scope and ContentsThis recording is the master copy of an entry submitted to the annual Billboard Magazine radio competition in 1971.  It features Jim Grubbs, known on the air as Jimmy Junior, during the Rock Revolution.  Grubbs was awarded recognition by Billboard Magazine as one of the outstanding small-market DJs in the country for 1971.  The show includes a number of personalized local commercials that typify WSMI's approach to integration of programming and advertising.
Author: Jim Grubbs. Playing Time: 46:08SMI 0004 "1972 Billboard Entry"Item 2935591972-05-1529Scope and ContentsThis is Grubbs's 1972 Billboard Magazine competition entry.
Author: Jim Grubbs. Playing Time: 46:08NNS 0001 "WNNS Demo Program" Midwest BroadcastingItem 303560197630Scope and ContentsDuring the 1970s Sangamon State University employees including Mark Erenburg, Carl Flipper, Cleve (Corky) Hill, and Jim Grubbs, along with several community members, applied for, and were ultimately granted a license for FM frequency 98.7 MHz in Springfield, Illinois.  The corporation was named Midwest Broadcasting and the station eventually became WNNS.  This recording was created for the company as a demonstration of proposed programming and programming technique.
Author: Jim Grubbs and Mark Erenburg. Playing Time: 57:54

