<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.91Archon Finding Aid Title MC.91UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:48:14 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC91. Don Springer Historical Financial Documents Collection, 1717-1967
    
      Springer, Don
    
    MC.91
    98
    
      0.20 Cubic Feet
    
    1717-1967
    Date acquired: 00/00/2003
  
  
    MC91. Don Springer Historical Financial Documents Collection: 1717-1967
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Historical financial instruments, such as bonds, stock certificates, treasury notes, checks and a land patent, many bearing decorative engraved vignettes and associated with prominent events and persons in financial and political history.

 Some of the items include: a 1782 bond issued by France's King Louis XVI, secured by taxes on alcohol and salt, which were bitterly resented by the common people and contributed to the outbreak of the French Revolution; a 1795 certificate for stock in the Company of the Philadelphia and Lancaster Turnpike, signed by the Company's president, William Bingham; a bond issued by the government of Mexican Emperor Maximilian I in 1864; a bearer bond of the Compagnie Universelle du Canal Interocéanique de Panama, which was organized in 1880 to build a sea-level canal across the Isthmus of Panama; a bearer bond issued by the French government in 1899 to finance the construction of a railroad from Addis Ababa in Ethiopia to the port of Djibouti; a 1967 check signed by oil tycoon J. Paul Getty; a 1794 Pennsylvania land patent issued to William Bingham, signed by Governor Thomas Mifflin and assigned to William Morris (Mifflin and Morris both signed the Declaration of Independence); a 1777 Massachusetts treasury note, printed by Paul Revere and issued to finance the state's operations during the American Revolution; and an elaborately engraved 1758 certificate for  stock in the Royal Trade Company of Barcelona.  
  
    Arrangement Note
By series and Chronological  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Don Springer  
  
    Accruals and Additions
Gifts made annually, 2003-2012  
  Gift of 2003Series 11161Louis XVI, King of France, 1754-1793.  Bond, "Rentes Viagère sur une ou deux Têtes à différens Derniers"Item 1116217821Scope and ContentsBond issued in accordance with a 1782 edict of King Louis XVI, providing the bearer an annuity in exchange for loans to the royal treasury. Bankrupted by years of war with Britain as well as by its military support of the United States during the American Revolution, France aggressively sought to finance its huge national debt. These bonds were secured by taxes on alcohol and salt, which were bitterly resented by the common people and contributed to the outbreak of the French Revolution in 1789.The bonds offered a substantial return (9-12% per annum) but in the end only worsened France's debt.
 
The document is printed, with added handwriting and signatures, and headed with an official ink stamp ("Expeditions pour le Roi").   1 leaf, 14" x 20," framed.Empire of Mexico. Bond for Public Foreign Mexican DebtItem 2116318642Scope and ContentsBond for 50 British pounds or 1260 francs against the Mexican national debt, issued by the government of Emperor Maximilian I.Archduke Maximilian, from the Austrian House of Habsburg, was installed as the Emperor of Mexico by the troops of the French Emperor Napoleon III in 1863, but was deposed and executed in 1867.This bond, bearing coupons for an annual dividend of 3 pounds (three of which are clipped), was one of many issued in Paris and London by Maximilian's regime as an attempt to raise 200 million francs to defray the cost of France's military support. The issue was poorly subscribed and the loan's failure helped seal the downfall of Maximilian.  1 item, 12" x 17Gould, Jay, 1836-1892. Stock Certificate, Missouri, Kansas, and Texas Railway CompanyItem 3116418813Scope and ContentsCertificate for 100 shares of capital stock in the Missouri, Kansas, and Texas Railway Company issued to Jay Gould, dated 17 June 1881.Gould was one of the first and most famous of the railroad "Robber Barons." He was the president and director of many railroad and telegraph companies, including the MKT, whose trains had the distinction of being a favorite target of the Dalton Gang.The certificate includes a decorative engraving of cattle and a cowboy.  1 item, 11.5" x 8."Insull, Samuel, 1859-1938. Stock Certificate, Louisville and Northern Railway and Lighting CompanyItem 4116519074Scope and ContentsCertificate for 37 shares of common stock in the Louisville and Northern Railway and Lighting Company issued to F. R. Willey of Pomona, California, dated 12 September 1907 and signed by the company's treasurer and its president, Samuel Insull.Insull, once Thomas Edison's personal secretary, headed a succession of electric trolley and utility companies, including Commonwealth Edison, and created a notorious "bubble" of financial speculation in the 1920s that burst after the stock market crash of 1929. "Insull Stock" became a symbol of financial ruin during the Great Depression.The certificate features engravings of an Edison electric streetcar and two Edison light bulbs. 1 item, 11" x 8."Getty, Jean Paul, 1892-1976. Bank Draft, to John Bell &amp; CroydenItem 5116619675Scope and ContentsCheck dated 18 October 1967 for nine shillings and ten pence, drawn on the Chase Manhattan Bank of London. The payee is John Bell &amp; Croyden, a London pharmacy. The check bears the signature of the payer, J. Paul Getty, a famous oil tycoon and one of the richest men of his time. The check shows the cancellation stamp of Barclay Bank Ltd.  1 item, 8' x 4", framed.Gift of 2004Series 21167Company of the Philadelphia and Lancaster Turnpike. Stock certificateItem 6116817956Scope and ContentsCertificate for $743 of stock in the Company of the Philadelphia and Lancaster Turnpike, issued to Joseph Walker of Philadelphia in 1795. Signed by the Company's president, William Bingham.The Company of the Philadelphia and Lancaster Turnpike was organized in 1792. The first President and Manager was William Bingham (1752-1804), the richest man in America and founder in 1781 of the Bank of North America, the first bank organized in the U.S. The Lancaster Pike was the first major paved road in America, built with a roadbed of crushed stone following a method developed by the Scottish engineer John MacAdam.Printed and handwritten on vellum. The certificate bears an engraved vignette of a Conestoga wagon approaching a turnpike, and is said to be one of the first American stock certificates featuring a vignette.  8.5" x 7.5"Russia. Nicholas Railroad.  BondItem 7116918697Scope and ContentsBond for 120 rubles/500 francs/20 pounds sterling, one of 550,500 bonds issued by the Russian government in 1869 to finance the Nicholas Railroad, named after Czar Nicholas I (d. 1855), in whose reign Russia's rail network was first planned and began construction.The bond bears an engraving of the Russian Imperial Double Eagle. The recto contains Russian text, and the verso contains French and English text.   12" x 15," framed.Cedar Rapids, Iowa Falls and Northwestern Railway Company.  BondItem 8117018848Scope and ContentsBearer bond for $1000 with 80 coupons, issued in 1884 to finance construction of the Cedar Rapids, Iowa Falls and Northwestern Railway Company. This railway was under the control of the Burlington, Cedar Rapids and Northern Railroad, and extended from Spirit Lake, Iowa into southern Minnesota and was completed to Sioux Falls, South Dakota in 1886.The bond is not signed or endorsed. 14" x 10", 3 sheets.Compagnie Universelle du Canal Interocéanique de Panama. BondItem 9117118869Scope and ContentsBearer bond for 500 francs of the debt of the Compagnie Universelle du Canal Interocéanique de Panama, which was organized in 1880 to build a sea-level canal across the Isthmus of Panama. The president of the company was Ferdinand de Lesseps (1805-1894), who had successfully constructed the Suez Canal. The Panama project was beset with financial, geological and labor problems, and its workers were ravaged by tropical diseases. In 1889 the company was liquidated, and de Lesseps and his son were charged and convicted of embezzlement. However, the work completed by the French made possible the later completion of the Panama Canal by the United States in 1914.The bond includes decorative engravings of allegorial figures representing the continents, and the engraved signature of Ferdinand de Lesseps.   7" x 6.5", framed.Carthage and Adirondack Railway Co. BondItem 101172189210Scope and ContentsMortgage bond for $1000, issued in New York City, December 1, 1892. Vertical format without coupons. Features engraved vignettes of a steam engine and a buck with antlers. Signed and attested by A. G. Cox (president) and Allen Cox (secretary). The Carthage and Adirondack Railway Co. was founded in 1883 and was acquired by the New York Central and Hudson Valley Railroad in 1913.   10.5" x 15", framed.Northern Alabama Coal, Iron and Railway Co. BondItem 111173189911Scope and ContentsBearer bond for $1000 issued in 1899 by the Northern Alabama Coal, Iron and Railway Co. Vertical format with engraved vignettes of coal miners and steam engines, and including two sheets of coupons (one clipped). Signed and attested by John Carlson (secretary) and E. Zimmerman (president). 
Eugene Zimmerman (1843-1914) of Cincinnati founded several railroads, and helped construct the Chesapeake and Ohio railroad bridge there. In 1905 J.P. Morgan acquired stock in a railroad headed by Zimmerman, who loaded the company with debt and obligations, causing Morgan to lose $12 million on the deal. 9.5" x 14", 3 sheets.Compagnie Impériale Chemins de Fer Éthiopiens. BondItem 121174189912Scope and ContentsBearer bond with 48 coupons issued by the French government in 1899 to finance the construction of a railroad from Addis Ababa in Ethiopia to the port of Djibouti in the French colony of Somali Coast. The project was a joint venture with the government of Emperor Menelik II (1844-1913), who did much to expand and modernize Ethiopia.The Imperial Ethiopian Railway Company was formed in Paris in 1896, and work began on the railroad at Addis Ababa soon after. This bond reflects an increase of the capitalization of the company to 18 million francs in 1899. The construction of the railroad was complicated by difficult mountainous and desert terrain, and in 1904 construction ceased and the company was liquidated in 1907.The elaborate engraving on the bond, by the illustrator L. Bombled, shows Menelik II inspecting the railway with his entourage and a caravan of camels.   25" x 16".Gift of 2005Series 31175Massachusetts ("State of Massachusetts-Bay"). Treasury NoteItem 131176177713Scope and ContentsTreasury note issued to Jireh Swift for the receipt of nineteen pounds and six shillings by the "State of Massachusetts-Bay," dated 1 December 1777. Massachusetts Treasurer Henry Gardner witnessed the note.Beginning in 1775, Massachusetts was the first state to issue loan certificates to finance its operations during the American Revolution. The state issued this series of notes, which paid lenders 6 per cent interest, in order to borrow £100,000. The notes were engraved and printed by Paul Revere (although his name does not appear on them), and bore the warning "DEATH TO COUNTERFEIT THIS."  9" x 6".Great Republic Gold and Silver Mining Company. BondItem 141177186714Scope and ContentsBearer bond for £50 to finance the first mortgage of the Great Republic Gold and Silver Mining Company, incorporated in 1867. The bond, bearing seven per cent interest and maturing in 1873, includes twelve coupons, one of which is clipped. At the time this bond was issued, the Great Republic Gold and Silver Mining Company of Norfolk, Virginia operated five gold and silver mines in Nevada.The bond includes engraved vignettes showing the goddess Liberty with the U.S. Capitol in the background, Queen Victoria, Abraham Lincoln, and smelting machinery.  13" x 16."Oregon and Transcontinental Company. Stock CertificateItem 151178188215Scope and ContentsCertificate for 1000 shares of common stock in the Oregon and Transcontinental Company, issued to Henry Villard. The certificate is signed by the Company's Treasurer Joseph Simon and Vice-President Anthony Johnson II and is dated 2 November 1882.Henry Villard (1835-1900) was a prominent German-born financier and entrepreneur, who played a central role in the development of railroads in Oregon and the Pacific Northwest. During the Civil War he was a newspaper journalist, and met Lincoln on many occasions. Later, he was a partner of Thomas Edison, and played an important role in the development of General Electric. Villard at various times acted as president of several Pacific Northwest railroads, president of Edison General Electric, owner of the New York Evening Post, and was the founder of North American Company. The Oregon and Transcontinental Company, founded in 1871, was a holding company for the Northwest train and steamship lines of which Villard was president.The engraved vignette on the certificate shows two Native Americans on a hilltop observing the distant approach of locomotives and steamships.  11" x 7".Gift of 2006Series 41179Commonwealth of Pennsylvania. PatentItem 161469179416Scope and ContentsPatent for a 1,100 acre tract in Northumberland County, Pennsylvania known as "Rochester," sold to William Bingham in exchange for a warrant issued to Robert Gilmore in 1792 plus a payment of five pounds, eleven shillings and six pence. The document, printed and handwritten on vellum, is dated 30 October 1794 and was signed and witnessed by Pennsylvania Governor Thomas Mifflin on 15 December 1794.William Bingham (1752-1804) was known in his time as the richest man in America and in 1781 founded the Bank of North America, the first bank organized in the U.S. (See item 6 above).The vellum document bears the Pennsylvania state seal and on the back shows the assignment of the land by Bingham to Robert Morris and John Nicholson in 1795. Robert Morris is known as the "financier of the American Revolution" and was a signer of the Declaration of Independence, as was Thomas Mifflin. 20.5" x 10.5"Australasian Pacific Mail Steam Packet Company. Stock CertificateItem 171180185217Scope and ContentsCertificate for a £20 share in the Australasian Pacific Mail Steam Packet Company issued to Thomas Baring of Bishopgate Street, London, dated 12 October 1852. Engraved with an embossed seal.Thomas Baring (1799-1873), a longtime member of Parliament, belonged to the dynasty that operated London's famous Baring Bank from 1762 to 1995. Baring Bank was long a major force in international finance: it helped finance the Union during the Civil War, financed many U.S. railroads, and finally fell in an massive embezzlement scandal in 1995.The Australasian Pacific Mail Steam Packet Company, formed in 1852, was absorbed in 1861 by the Royal Mail Steam Packet Company, which operated until 1972.   8.25" x 6.5".Parrot Silver and Copper Company. Stock CertificateItem 181181189918Scope and ContentsCertificate for common stock in the Parrot Silver and Copper Company of Montana. Dated 2 March 1899, the certificate was issued to F. M. Tucker &amp; Co. for ten $10 shares of capital stock. The back shows the assignment of five shares to Frank Seabury on 4 March 1899.The Parrot mine was opened near Butte, Montana in 1864 and was named after R.R. Parrot, a local attorney. By 1889 the Parrot Silver &amp; Copper Company was removing 260 tons of copper/silver ore a day. While the Parrot Silver &amp; Copper Company continued to operate the mine, it became part of the Amalgamated holdings (associated with William Rockefeller of Standard Oil) in 1899. During the period of primary production, 1884 to 1910, miners extracted almost 300 million pounds of copper from the Parrot Mine.The certificate bears a vignette of a parrot. 11.25" x 7.25".Parrot Silver and Copper Company. Stock certificateItem 191182190919Scope and ContentsCommon stock certificate, dated 31 March 1909, issued to Richardson Hill for five $10 shares of capital stock and the back shows the assignment of the shares to John W. May on 28 June 1909.The certificate features an elaborate engraved border. 11.5 x 8.25".Gift of 2007Series 51183Fernandina and Jacksonville Railroad Co. BondItem 201184188020Scope and ContentsBearer bond in the amount of $1000 in the Fernandina and Jacksonville Railroad Co. of Florida. The bond is signed by the company's president, J. W. Fellows and the secretary, E. N. Dickerson, Jr. On the verso, the bond is certified with signatures of three trustees, including Edward H. Harriman. Harriman (1848-1909) was a leading figure in the development and finance of railroads and a shrewd stock market investor. His involvement in the expansion of major railroads, such as the Union Pacific, Illinois Central, and Chicago and Alton railroads, and successful financial struggles with rivals such as J. P. Morgan and J. J. Hill, earned him the popular title of "Napoleon of the Rails."The bond bears a small but detailed engraved vignette of a steam locomotive, and elaborate border, and 40 unclipped coupons. 1 folio, 23" x 14 1/2"Wilmington and Northern Railroad Company. Mortgage BondItem 211185188721Scope and ContentsBond for $500 issued in 1887 to finance a $1 million mortgage of the Wilmington and Northern Railroad. The bond is signed by the company's president, Henry Algernon DuPont.DuPont (1838-1826), a member of the prominent DuPont family of Delaware, initially pursued a military career, attending West Point and serving bravely in the Shenandoah Valley campaign during the Civil War. He left military service in 1875, and became involved in his family's business interests, acting as president of the Wilmington and Northern from 1879 to 1899. He later served two terms in the U.S. Senate, 1906-1917.The bond bears finely detailed engraved vignettes of steam locomotives, a seaport,and cattle, and an elaborate border. The verso shows transfers of the bond to 1918; the second leaf shows extensions from 1927 to 1972. 2 leaves, 13" x 10"Northern Pacific Railroad Company. Stock CertificateItem 221186189622Scope and ContentsCertificate for ten shares of common stock connected with the reorganization of the Northern Pacific Railroad Company by the firm of J. P. Morgan and others in 1896. The Northern Pacific Railroad was chartered in 1864 to build a line from Lake Superior to the Pacific Coast. The railroad was granted 57 million acres to construct the line through the northern Great Plains and Rockies – terrain General William T. Sherman described as "bad as God ever made, or any one could scrape up this side of Africa."  By 1871 the line was being surveyed through Sioux lands in the Black Hills, and Sitting Bull and others attacked the surveyors and white settlers and caused the dispatch of federal troops to the area. These incidents led to the Black Hills War and the defeat of Custer by Sitting Bull at Little Bighorn in 1876. Despite these and additional financial setbacks, the Northern Pacific Railroad was completed in 1883. Sitting Bull delivered a bitter speech at the opening ceremonies. The railroad fell into receivership in 1893 and was reorganized soon after by J.P. Morgan and others.The certificate bears a small vignette of a young woman holding a feather and pillow. 10 ¾" x 7 ½"International Mercantile Marine Company. Stock CertificateItem 231187190823Scope and ContentsCertificate for ten shares of common stock in the International Mercantile Marine Company, founded by J. P. Morgan in 1902 and the parent company of the White Star Line. The sinking of White Star's great passenger liner Titanic on its maiden voyage in 1912 caused Morgan one of the greatest losses of his financial career. The bond bears an engraved red border and a vignette of an allegorical goddess holding scales, flanked by globes showing the Western and Eastern hemispheres. 11 1/2 " x 8"Also included is a facsimile of the New York Tribune of 16 April 1912, reporting the sinking of the Titanic.Marconi Wireless Telegraph Company. Stock CertificateItem 241188192024Scope and ContentsCertificate for fifty shares of capital stock in the Marconi Wireless Telegraph Company, issued to Keybourn and Croft on 19 September 1919. 

Italian radio pioneer Guglielmo Marconi founded the Wireless Telegraph and Signal Company in 1897, which was renamed the Marconi Wireless Telegraph Company in 1900. Marconi and his company made the first trans-Atlantic radio transmissions in 1901-02. In 1919 the U.S. Navy seized the assets of the British Marconi Wireless Telegraph Co. in order to keep radio technology in American hands. The assets were assigned to the newly-formed company RCA (Radio Corporation of America), whose president, David Sarnoff, had started as a Marconi radio operator.

The certificate bears a green engraved border and a vignette of an allegorical goddess holding scales, flanked by globes showing the Western and Eastern hemispheres and transmission towers. (The vignette is almost identical to the one in item 23 above.) 12" x 8"Mission Development Company. Stock CertificateItem 251189195425Scope and ContentsCertificate for one share of common stock in the Mission Development Company, dated 26 November 1954. The certificate bears the printed signature of the company's president, oil tycoon J. Paul Getty.The Mission Development Company was created in 1945 to leverage Getty's takeover of a rival, Tidewater Oil. After Getty succeeded in gaining control of Tidewater, he merged Mission Development into Getty Oil.The certificate bears a vignette of an allegorical goddess with sword, shield, and a cornucopia spilling coin. 12" x 7 3/4".Gift of 2008Series 66728Real Compania de Comercio Establecida en Barcelona. Stock CertificateItem 266735175826Scope and ContentsCertificate for 250 pesos of stock in the "Real Compania de Comercio Establecida en Barcelona" (Royal Trade Company of Barcelona) issued to Don Pedro Sahavedra Barnuevo of Valencia on 3 July 1758. The "Real Compania de Comercio" was established in 1755, under royal patronage. It was founded with a capitalization of 1,000,000 pesos comprised of 4,000 shares at 250 pesos each, of which only 1,785 were purchased by investors. The company was granted a monopoly on trade with Santo Domingo, Puerto Rico and Venezuela's Isla Margarita. Trade with these islands was relatively poor, and the company could not pay dividends to investors until 1771. The company was finally absorbed by the Spanish Royal Trading Company, Filipinas in 1785.The engraved certificate, in Spanish, is printed on vellum, and signed by directors of the company, with an ornate paper seal at the bottom. The uncolored engraving features a prospect of the city and harbor of Barcelona, with sailing ships. The decorative border includes cherubs, sea monsters, and a trident. The heading includes the seals of Spain and Catalonia, and religious figures, including the Virgin and Christ child, saints, and a pope and friar. On the bottom margin are the names of the artist, Emmanuel Tramullas, and engraver/printer, Ignatius Valls. 11.75" x 15.5" (Source: Howard Shakespeare, "The Spanish Royal Trading Companies." Journal of the International Bond &amp; Share Society, Spring-Autumn 1989.)Gift of 2009Series 734725Board of Directors for the Muscovite Trade (Directie van de Moscovische handel).  BondItem 2734726171727Scope and ContentsBond for 1000 Guilders issued to Toon der Duses by the Directie van de Moscovische handel (Board of Directors for the Muscovite Trade.) This bond was related to an effort to raise 65,000 Guilders to advance trade with Russia, authorized by the States General of the United Netherlands and the City of Amsterdam. The bonds were secured by a 0.5% duty on goods imported or exported to Russia and were to be repaid within six months at a rate of 4% interest.England had a head start developing trade with Russia with the founding of the Muscovy Company in 1555, but it was the Dutch who dominated Russian trade throughout the 17th century. Holland desperately needed masts, lumber, hemp and other materials produced in Russia to build and maintain its naval and merchant fleets. In 1697-98 and again in 1717 the reformist Tsar Peter the Great visited the Netherlands, which he viewed as the model of a modern seagoing power. Peter not only favored Dutch commerce, but he employed large numbers of Hollanders in the building and training of his fleet and in the construction of waterways and roads in Russia. The Board of Directors for the Muscovite Trade was formed by the Dutch government at the time of Peter's first visit. This bond coincides with Peter's 1717 visit, during which he and the Netherlands reaffirmed their commercial ties.The document, dated 4 May 1717,  is printed in Dutch on the front of a bifolio (8" x 12 3/4") and bears an embossed seal with the lion of the United Netherlands, and the signatures of the Board of Directors: Egbert Thesing, Arnoldus Dix, Christoffel Brants, Nicolaas Warin, and Leonard Van Hoesen. The reverse notes two interest payments made on the bond in 1718.One of the Directors, Christoffel Brants (1664-1732) was particularly friendly with Tsar Peter. The Brants family had longstanding trading connections with Russia, and Christoffel, who supplied muskets to Peter during his victorious military campaigns against Swedish forces in 1707-09, was awarded a Russian peerage  in 1717. Brants's house in Amsterdam, where he received Peter as a guest, still stands and is a historic site.Gift of 2010Series 850192Imperial India Company (Keijserlijche Indische Compagnie) Stock Certificate, 1723.Item 285019328Scope and ContentsA stock certificate dating from 1723 for shares in the Imperial India Company (also known as the Ostend Company), based in the Austrian Netherlands (modern day Belgium). One of the earliest printed stock certificates ever issued. The Imperial India Company was created soon after Austria gained control of parts of Belgium in 1713. It was intended to compete with the long-established Dutch East India Company for trade with China, India, and the African coast. Although the company was quite successful (particularly in the China tea trade), Holy Roman Emperor Charles VI suspended it in 1731 in exchange for Dutch recognition of his daughter Maria Theresa as his heir. After receiving this recognition, Austria allowed the company to be rolled into the Dutch East India Company.

    This certificate, no. 3734, documents the receipt of 250 gulden, the first payment for a total of 1000 gulden in capital stock, from "The Lady," widow of Joan Michiel Mainone of Cologne on 17 August 1723. The certificate is signed by four directors of the Imperial Indian Company and shows three further payments in 1723-25.

    Printed and handwritten paper document, 7 3/4" x 12 1/2." Includes an engraving of the the Habsburg crest.Gift of 2011Series 957976Banque Territoriale Stock CertificateItem 2957977180429Scope and ContentsA stock certificate issued by the Banque Territoriale of Paris to Jean Baptiste Etienne De la Place for the amount of 1000 francs. The document is dated according to the French Revolutionary calendar as 15 Brumaire, Year 12 (i.e. 6 November 1804). The Banque Territoriale was founded in 1798 and failed in 1803-04, when its assets were assumed by Chavagnac and Co. The certificate is witnessed with the signature of Pierre Samuel Du Pont de Nemours, Administrature-regent of the Banque.

Du Pont (1739-1817), after early training as a watchmaker and in medicine, became a noted economist. He served briefly as inspector general of commerce under King Louis XVI, and helped negotiate the 1783 Treaty of Paris, which ended the American Revolution. He was a moderate supporter of the French Revolution and served in the National Constituent Assembly, but strove to save King Louis and Marie Antoinette from execution. He narrowly escaped the guillotine during the Reign of Terror (1792), and later served in the government of the Directory but fell out of favor for suspected royalist sympathies. In 1799 he and his family emigrated to the United States, where he became a close friend of Thomas Jefferson and founded, with his sons, a gunpowder foundry in Delaware. In 1802 he returned to France and helped negotiate the Louisiana Purchase, and later helped plot the exile of Napoleon to Elba. After Napoleon's return to power in 1814, Du Point returned to the U.S. and remained until his death. He and his sons are recognized as the founders of the huge Du Pont chemical corporation.

Printed and handwritten paper document, 7 ½" x 10." The verso shows a small printed seal with writing documenting the payment of dividends.Gift of 2012Series 1074722United States Steel Corporation. BondItem 17472319011Scope and ContentsA bond for $100,000 in gold, issued to Andrew Carnegie by the United States Steel Corporation and dated 14 June 1901. J. P. Morgan and Elbert H. Gary founded U. S. Steel in February, 1901 by combining steel operations owned by Andrew Carnegie with Gary's Federal Steel Company and several smaller companies . It was capitalized at $1.4 billion, making it the world's first billion-dollar corporation. 

With Charles Schwab as intermediary, Morgan and Carnegie negotiated the sale of Carnegie's steel holdings. Carnegie's initial offer was $400 million, which he soon increased to $492 million, a price which Morgan accepted. Carnegie demanded payment not only in cash but in 5% gold-mortgage bonds such as this one. Carnegie apparently wanted the gold-backed bonds because he suspected Morgan's new company would fail. Reportedly, when Morgan and Carnegie shook hands to seal the deal, Morgan remarked, "Mr. Carnegie, I want to congratulate you on being the richest man in the world."

The capitalization of U.S. Steel at the time of its first stock offering (26 February 1901) was 7% of the total Gross National Product of the United States at the time and probably, proportionally, the largest Initial Public Offering (IPO) in American history. In its first full year of operation, U. S. Steel already made 67 percent of all steel produced in the United States and was a major player in the world steel industry through most of the twentieth century.

The bond features a red engraved border and a vignette showing a steel mill and train yard. 13" x 9 ½."

