<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>MC.92Archon Finding Aid Title MC.92UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:48:17 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    MC92. Robert P. Crawford Chicago City Hall Radio Collection, 1968-2003
    
      Crawford, Robert P.
    
    MC.92
    99
    
      0.40 Cubic Feet
    
    1968-2003
    Date acquired: 11/20/2004
  
  
    Scope and Contents
The Robert P. Crawford Audio Archives contains 58 hours and 47 minutes of tape recorded radio broadcasts, copied onto 63 audio CDs. Robert P. Crawford (b. 1936) was the City Hall Correspondent for WBBM radio in Chicago from the 1960s until his retirement in 2001. The central figures are six Chicago mayors from Richard J. Daley to Richard M. Daley. There are 2148 separate speeches, news conferences, and interviews. There is also an "Archives Preview" disk narrated by Crawford. The collection is divided into seven series:

Series I: The Richard J. Daley Years (1968-76, 7 CDs) features a variety of topics including Daley's secret to winning elections, his handling of the anti-war riots during the 1968 Democratic National Convention, and the controversial "shoot to kill order" Daley issues to police to deal with arsonists during the riots that followed the slaying of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.

Series II: The Michael Bilandic Years (1976-79, 1 CD) focuses on his administration's perceived failure to provide adequate snow removal after a record blizzard in January, 1979.

Series III: The Jane Byrne Years (1979-83, 7 CDs) gives insight to Chicago's first woman Mayor and such issues as the Firefighters Union strike in 1980, public housing reform, and nepotism. 

Series IV: The Harold Washington Years (1983-87, 5 CDs) features Washington's political battles with the "Vrdolyak 29" majority in the City Council, his efforts to end Machine-style control of city government and his pursuit of political reform. 

Series V: The Eugene Sawyer Years (1987-89, 1 CD) features Sawyer's conflict between the Democratic Machine and members of the Washington Coalition.

Series VI: The Richard M. Daley Years (1989-2001, 12 CDs) features issues including the 1996 Democratic National Convention, school reform, and race relations in Chicago. 

Series VII: Politicians and Other Figures series (29 CDs) features speeches, commentaries and news conferences given in Chicago between 1982 and 2003 by 175 figures from government, religion, the law, civil rights, and sports. Included are three debates from the 1983 campaign for Mayor of Chicago, debates from the 1992 and 1998 races for the U.S. Senate in Illinois, and items by President Bill Clinton, Illinois Governors Thompson, Edgar and Ryan, Senator Paul Simon, Congressman Harry Hyde, Nelson Mandela, and many others.

The original tapes of the above items are housed in Special Collections at the University of Illinois at Chicago. The University Archives at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign also holds copies of the tapes and CD copies.  
  
    Arrangement Note
By series and date  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
None  
  
    Source of Acquisition
Robert P. Crawford  
  
    Existence and Location of Originals
Original tapes housed at Special Collections, University of Illinois at Chicagohttp://www.uic.edu/depts/lib/specialcoll/services/rjd/findingaids/Crawfordf.html  
  
    Related Materials
The original tapes of the above items are housed in Special Collections at the University of Illinois at Chicago.

The University Archives at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign also hold copies of the tapes and CD copies.http://www.uic.edu/depts/lib/specialcoll/services/rjd/findingaids/Crawfordf.html  
  
    Audio CDs
  
  Richard J. Daley Years (1968-1976)Series 14050tape side #1, Time: 10:48CD 14051Scope and ContentsBiographical pieces on Mayor Richard J. Daley, narrated by Robert P. Crawford, 1976tape side #1A, Time: 39:35CD 24052Scope and ContentsBiographical pieces on Mayor Richard J. Daley, narrated by Robert P. Crawford, 1976News Conference with Daley re handling of riots connected with slaying of Martin Luther King Jr , 1968-04-20Speech regarding the controversial appointment of the son of Alderman Thomas Keane, 1971-08-21News conference re Democratic primary election losses, 1972-03Mayor Richard J. Daley talks to members of his family, friends, staff members, and the news media on the occasion of his 70th birthday, 1972-05-15Daley attacks the so-called "Singer 59" group that was holding caucus meetings to select an independent slate of delegates to replace Daley's Chicago delegates at the 1972 Democratic National Convention, 1972-06-26Speech by Daley to a labor rally in support of Democratic Presidential candidate George McGovern, 1972-09-10Daley addresses a rally of Democratic Party precinct captains on the eve of the March primary elections, 1974-03tape side #2, Time: 52:08CD 34053Scope and ContentsDaley expresses his love for Chicago on the occasion of his 19th anniversary in office, 1974-04-20Daley addresses the State Street Council's annual meeting, 1/28/1975-01-28Daley addresses members of the Cook County Democratic Organization, 1975-02-03tape side #3, Time 37:29CD 44054Scope and ContentsContinuation of Mayor Daley's speech to members of the Cook County Democratic Organization, 2/3/1975Mayor addresses rally of Democratic Party precinct Captains, 2/10/1975News conference: Mayor tells reporters not to believe everything they read in the newspaper, 1975-02Mayor Daley addresses a labor rally, 1975-02-07tape side #4, Time: 34:04CD 54055Scope and ContentsContinuation of Mayor Daley's address to a labor rally, 1975-02-07Mayor addresses a meeting of the Chicago Convention and Tourism Bureau re reports of a pessimistic mood in the country, 1975-03Mayor talks of his favorite day of the year, St. Patrick's Day, in his City Hall Office reception area, 1975-03News conference responding to protests accusing the Chicago Police Department of engaging in illegal spying, 1975-03-25Daley responds to the release of internal Police Department documents revealing illegal spying on individuals and groups, 1975-03-26Daley delivers a victory statement after winning election to a 6th term as Mayor of Chicago, 1975-04-01News conference in which Daley criticizes the Democratic National Committee for turning the site selection process for national party conventions into a bidding process, 1975-04-15Daley's inaugural address, 1975-04-18Daley defends the Chicago Board of Education, 1975-01-22tape side #5, Time: 13:19CD 64056Scope and ContentsNews conference in which Daley demands evidence that the father of his son John's fiancée is linked to organized crime, 1975-04-23Daley talks of his ambitious plan to form a not for profit organization to rehabilitate and replace housing in poor neighborhoods, 1975-04-23Daley addresses delegates to the Illinois Democratic Party Convention, 1975-06-06News conference in which Daley states that reports of police spying on law-abiding citizens and groups are overblown, 1975-06-06Daley at the annual United States Conference of Mayors, 1975-07-05News conference where Mayor Daley gives account of greeting President Richard Nixon at O'Hare airport, 1975-07-10Daley addresses a joint session of the Illinois General Assembly, 1975-10-23Daley responds at a news conference to newspaper disclosures that Illinois Bell was tapping the telephones of City Hall politicians, 1975-11-20At a news conference, the Mayor discusses the interference of the courts in the fight over which Chicago delegation would be seated at the Democratic National Convention in 1972, 1974-12-11Daley addresses a labor luncheon, 1976-02-11Daley addresses a rally of Democratic Party precinct captains, 1976-02-20Daley addresses members of the Cook County Democratic Party, 1976-03-29tape side #6, Time: 25:37CD 74057Scope and ContentsDaley addresses members of the Cook County Democratic Party, 1976-03-29Daley denounces the Woodward/Bernstein book on Richard Nixon's last days as President, 1976-03-03Daley responds to a proposed referendum to enforce residency requirements for all city employees, 1976-05-04Daley spells out his position on abortion, UndatedIn a speech to a labor union audience, Daley criticizes Martin Luther King,  Jr., 1966News conference in which Daley responds to criticism of Chicago police, UndatedDaley rejects charges from his critics that Chicago remains one of the most racially intolerant urban areas in America, Undated.Michael Bilandic Years (1976-79)Series 24058tape side #1, Time: 22:40CD 14555Scope and ContentsMayor Michael Bilandic reacts to the decision of a Federal Grand Jury not to return indictments after an investigation into the handling of taxicab fare increases by his office and the City Council, 1979-01-22Bilandic defends the response of his Administration to the Blizzard of '79, 1979-01-15The Mayor boasts that his Administration has the best snow removal operation in the history of the City, 1979-01-16The Mayor admits that there were some parking lots which were not plowed despite notice from the City that they had been cleared for use, 1979-01-18Mayor Bilandic defends his Administration's handling of the Blizzard of '79 during a City Council meeting, 1979-01-19Mayor Bilandic defends a contract that was given to one of his former aids, Ken Sain, to design a new snow removal plan for the City before the Blizzard of 79 took place, 1979-01-29In an exchange with reporters, Mayor Bilandic reacts to charges that his Snow Command Chief Peter Schivarelli has ties to organized crime, 1979-01-30In an exchange with reporters, the Mayor continues his defense of former top City Hall administrative aid Ken Sain in the face of accusations, 1979-01-31Mayor Bilandic kicks off his reelection campaign in a speech to supporters and reporters, 1979-02-08Mayor Bilandic finally admits at a news conference that the highly controversial study Ken Sain did on snow removal and which critics had branded a "sweetheart contract" was not perfect, 1979-02-05With his job approval ratings sinking, Mayor Bilandic goes before a luncheon meeting of Democratic Party precinct captains and gives a bizarre speech, 1979-02-14Mayor Bilandic finally admits that he made mistakes during his Administration's critical snow removal efforts after the Blizzard of 79, 1979-02-22Incumbent Mayor Michael Bilandic concedes defeat to his upstart challenger Jane Byrne on the evening of the Democratic Primary for Mayor of Chicago, 1979-02-27George Dunne, Cook County Democratic Party Chairman, talks to reporters about the defeat of Mayor Bilandic, UndatedBilandic delivers a tearful farewell to members of the City Council after his primary defeat, 1979-03-28Jane Byrne Years (1979-83)Series 34059tape side #1, Time: 23:57CD 14564Scope and ContentsByrne explains how the patronage system would work under her if she is elected as Mayor, 1979-03-08Byrne elaborates on her contention that there may be a 150 million dollar deficit in outgoing Mayor Michael Bilandic's budget, 1979-03-19State Senator Richard M. Daley reads a formal resolution by the Democratic Party endorsing Jane Byrne for Mayor in the general election, 1979-03-12In an exchange with reporters during the general election campaign, Byrne is questioned about new contracts for policemen and firemen, 1979-03-16Byrne talks to the party faithful about the importance of winning the April 3rd general election, 1979-03-26During a campaign rally at Roosevelt University, Byrne says teachers should be required to live in the City just like City employees, 1979-03-22Jane Byrne delivers her inaugural address after being sworn in as the first woman Mayor in the history of Chicago, 1979-04-16At her first news conference, Mayor Byrne states that she warned ward superintendents in the Streets and Sanitation Department to get neighborhoods cleaned up or be fired, 1979-04-17In an exchange with reporters, the Mayor says she has not changed her mind about a new Police Superintendent, 1979-04-19Jane Byrne delivers her victory speech on the night she becomes the first woman Mayor of Chicago, 1979-04-03Rally song that was composed for Jane Byrne and which was sung often at campaign gatherings, 1979-03-27Byrne comes close to tears in a tribute to the late Mayor Richard J. Daley, 1979-03-27Mayor Byrne offers her version of how Sharon Gist Gilliam was fired as Consumer Services Commissioner, 1979-04-20At a news conference, Mayor Byrne startles reporters with a claim that records in her office and in the office of former political patronage chief Tom Donovan are missing, 1979-04-20Mayor Byrne declares war on Latin street gangs, 1979-04-23The Mayor backs off of her promise to pick an outsider as her new Police Superintendent, 1979-04-23The Mayor announces she has suspended Deputy Street Commissioner Pat O'Conner, 1979-04-23At a news conference, Byrne says she is going to shake up the Board of Health, 1979-04-24The Mayor accuses a reporter of bad manners, 1979-05-01The Mayor angrily defends her appointment of the girlfriend of her top aide Paul McGrath to her staff, 1979-05-02Byrne claims that long time Chicago Park District Superintendent Ed Kelley had no quarrel with all future Park District patronage appointments going through her office when the two met privately the day before, 1979-05-02The Mayor responds to the claim of Park District Superintendent Ed Kelley that he never agreed to direct future patronage appointments through her office, as she claimed, 1979-05-03The Mayor tells reporters she does not engage in name calling, 1979-06-22The Mayor denies she meant to be critical of President Jimmy Carter at a U.S. Conference of Mayors meeting when she called the Carter Administration "insensitive," 1979-06-20Byrne tells reporters that President Carter is going to have to ask her for an endorsement of his reelection bid, 1979-06-22The Mayor declares that Pat Murphy is her choice for Police Superintendent during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 1979-06-10The Mayor attacks Illinois Democratic House Speaker William Redmond and Majority Leader Mike Madigan, 1979-06The Mayor explains why she stripped former Mayor Michael Bilandic and his family of police bodyguard protection, 1979-07-13During an exchange with reporters, Byrne defends the costly renovation of her office in a time of tight budgets, 1979-08-01The Mayor says she may end the Daley's policy of paying city trade union employees industry rates because of shoddy work, 1979-08-02The Mayor promises to put stronger spending controls in her first budget, 1979-08-01Byrne complains about the leak to the press about the gambling debts of her Revenue Director Tim Degnan, 1979-07-30The Mayor says that Deputy Police Superintendent Sam Nolan will be the new Public Safety Director with authority over both the Police and Fire Departments, 1979-07-30The Mayor remarks that women (including herself) change their minds, 1979-07-30Byrne denies she promoted Sam Nolan to the post of Public Safety Director in order to get rid of him as a candidate for Police Superintendent, 1979-07-30Byrne denies that her appointment of Mike Sneed as her Press Secretary was nepotism, 1979-08-21The Mayor accuses the former Bilandic Administration of disorganization and poor record keeping, 1979-08-21Byrne declines to hold the Board of Education responsible for poor school conditions, 1979-08-22The Mayor levels sharp criticisms at the School Board, 1979-08-29Mayor Byrne threatens to strong-arm landlords if they gouge tenants with exorbitant rents, 1979-08The Mayor explains why she wants city inspections centralized, 1979-08The Mayor opposes the use of surveillance tactics to catch inspectors taking payoffs, 1979-08Mayor Byrne delivers a statement in support of integrating neighborhood schools in response to a school bussing proposal put forward by the U.S. Department of Health, Education , and Welfare, 1979-08tape side #2, Time: 21:11CD 24889Scope and ContentsContinuation of Byrne talking about neighborhood schools, 1979-08Mayor Byrne tells reporters she told trade union leaders there would be layoffs, 1979-09-17During a feud with the trade unions, the Mayor suggests she does not need the support or money of big labor, 1979-09-13The Mayor declares her support for the political patronage system in Chicago, 1979-09-26The Mayor expresses anger at a column that appeared in local newspapers criticizing her husband Jay McMullen, 1979-09-26Byrne takes First District Police Commander Paul McLaughlin to task for his high visibility with the news media, 1979-10-12The Mayor tells reporters she will respect the wishes of the Democratic Party Organization and not back a slate of delegates committed to a particular candidate for President at the 1980 National Convention, 1979-10-12The Mayor reveals her plan for the creation of a merit pay plan in 1981, 1979-10-12Byrne has a tense encounter with the press, 1979-10-10In a speech at a big Democratic Party fundraiser, the Mayor warns Senator Ted Kennedy that if he challenges President Jimmy Carter for the 1980 Democratic Party nomination there will be a party blood bath, 1979-10-15The Mayor stops short of a formal endorsement of President Jimmy Carter in a speech, 1979-10-10The Mayor defends the hiring of her daughter Kathy to a $17,000/ year job at the Chicago Transit Authority, 1979-10-15Byrne denies reports that she tried to coerce a city worker into running against Richard M. Daley for 11th Ward Democratic Committeeman in exchange for saving his job, 1979-10-10Byrne boasts that half the new subway she is proposing to place under the Stevenson Expressway will be in operation before she runs again for reelection, 1979-10-12The Mayor denies that she is systematically purging 11th ward residents from the City payroll in retaliation against Richard M. Daley, 1979-10-16The Mayor again defends the hiring of her daughter Kathy at the Chicago Transit Authority, 1979-10-19The Mayor tells reporters how she overheard a conversation between police officers about her complaints on traffic not moving well during the Chicago marathon, 1979-10-22The Mayor defends herself against charges of nepotism in the face of a disclosure that a second friend of her daughter Kathy's has been hired as a mayoral aide at $12,000/year, 1979-10-23The Mayor tells reporters how she tried unsuccessfully to help President Jimmy Carter "rev" up his standing in the polls, 1979-10-29The Mayor tells reporters why she thinks the decision of Senator Ted Kennedy to challenge President Carter for the 1980 presidential nomination will not split the Party, 1979-10-29The Mayor says the local Democratic Party "got left at the gate" in two previous election years because it endorsed a candidate too late, 1979-10-29The Mayor tells reporters that letters of political backing are no longer required to get a job in her Administration, 1979-10-25The Mayor claims she is not really at odds with Park District Superintendent Ed Kelley, 1979-10-25The Mayor praises ward committeemen and says that she doesn't plan to get involved in many races for committeemen in 1980, 1979-10The Mayor says the parks need new leadership that the condition of the parks is the issue, and not patronage, 1979-09Byrne claims that the Mayor of Chicago should take precedence over the Superintendent of the Parks, 1979-09Byrne rises to the defense of Bill Hart, a powerful Street Department Ward Superintendent, claiming he did a good job of snow removal in his ward during the Blizzard of '79 even though he was in a hospital bed, 1979-09The City Controller Clark Burris refutes Mayor Byrne's claim that the City had a deficit, 1979-04-27The Mayor vows not to have a repeat of the snow removal problems of 1978-79 which set the stage for her upset victory over then Mayor Michael Bilandic in the Democratic mayoral primary in February of 1979, 1979-11-01Byrne talks about the lack of public support for the Carter White House as she endorses Senator Ted Kennedy for the 1980 Democratic presidential nomination, 1979-10-30Mayor Byrne fires her Revenue Director Jerry Cannon one day after his political boss, State Senator Richard M. Daley, refused to join the Mayor in endorsing Senator Ted Kennedy for President.  Cannon openly criticized his political firing by Byrne, 1979-11-06The Mayor defends and gives a vote of confidence to her budget director Don Haider, her Corporation Counsel William Quinlin, her Streets and Sanitation Commissioner Jim Donovan, a top aide John Surane, and Police Chief Joe DeLeonardi, 1979-11-08tape side #3, Time: 21:58CD 34895Scope and ContentsSteve Smith, Senator Ted Kennedy's national campaign manager, tells reporters that Mayor Byrne will be calling the shots in the Illinois primary campaign, 11/13/1979State Senator Richard M. Daley speaks out against an early endorsement of Kennedy by the Cook County Democratic organization at a party meeting, 11/5/1979Byrne fires a broadside at major banks in the City and why they like President Jimmy Carter, 11/12/1979Mayor Byrne makes it clear she will demand full financial disclosure from the Board of Education before guaranteeing any loans to the Board, 11/20/1979Vice President Walter Mondale takes note of Mayor Byrne's absence from a big political fundraising dinner in Rosemont for President Jimmy Carter, 12/6/1979They Mayor says she welcomes a criminal investigation into the possible misuse of funds at the Chicago Board of Education, 12/6/1979The Mayor tells reporters that if she had known about the secret 25 thousand dollar a year salary the late Mayor Richard J. Daley was getting from the local Democratic Party she would have used that as an issue against Mayor Bilandic, 12/6/1979Byrne break with the policy the late Mayor Richard J. Daley used of entering labor disputes between public agencies and unions to win settlements quickly, 12/17/1979Deputy Corporation Counsel Dan Pascalle reveals that Controller Ray Coyne had proposed the City not wipe a 29 million dollar property tax error off the books because the City could use the money, 1/17/1980The Mayor says that her task force proposal to close more than 10% of the public schools would not result in more layoffs of teachers, 2/5/1980The Mayor says there is no way the City will cave in to the 10% pay increase demand of the Firefighters Union, 2/5/1980Angry members of the Chicago Firefighters Union chanting in front of Mayor Byrne's City Hall office waving fists and placards in the face of a strike threat, 1/31/1980On the second day of the strike, the Mayor argues with one striker on the picket lines in front of City Hall, 2/15/1980Mayor Byrne assures the people there is enough manpower available to adequately protect the city on the first day of the strike, 2/14/1980Mayor Byrne's husband Jay McMullin tells reporters it is true that his wife has been talking too much to reporters, 1/18/1980Loyal Fire Lieutenant Kevin King and Battalion Chief William Foran let it all out during a City Hall interview with reporters on why they do not want strikers back in the fire houses, 2/22/1980On the second day of the strike, the Mayor tells reporters of her intention to fill the jobs of strikers with quickly trained recruits, 2/15/1980Byrne defends her controversial decision to keep a 29 million dollar property tax error on the books as a basis of what she calls "enrichment," 2/1980Byrne weaves a web of intrigue in which she accuses Richard M. Daley of being behind the hardcore of striking firemen who she thinks are keeping other firemen on the picket lines, 3/3/1980A crowd of unruly striking firemen yells at aldermen after a City Council special session to deal with the ongoing firefighters strike, 2/26/1980Byrne objects to her newly appointed school board meeting to elect a president before members have even been sworn in, 5/16/1980Mayor Byrne stakes out a formal policy position in favor of the Mayor officially getting involved in the running of the public schools, 5/19/1980This is Mayor Byrne's outspoken husband Jay McMullin during the height of the scandal over alleged mob influence in the Chicago Police Department, 4/24/1980Suggestions in the media and from some allies of Mayor Byrne tell Jay McMullin, the Mayor's husband, that he should resign from his job as a city worker, 4/24/1980Byrne tells reporters the charges of alleged mob influence in the Police Department do not phase her, 4/25/1980The Mayor tells reporters she does not think Bill Griffin and Mike Bradley, her two top staff aides, had dirty hands in the police department/mob influence controversy generated by Chicago Tribune columnist Bob Wiedrick, 4/23/1980The Mayor says she is not going to let race be the sole determining factor in who she picks for membership on the Board of Education, 6/5/1980Byrne gives her views on what the value of Cable TV service in Chicago would be, 6/11/1980tape side #4, Time: 23:23CD 45027Scope and ContentsContinuation of Byrne talking about the value of Cable TV, 6/11/1980This is a lengthy exchange between the Chicago Tribune's City Hall Reporter Bob Davis and other reporters on the day he was supposed to leave City Hall after Mayor Byrne had ordered him out of the Press Room, 6/23/1980The Mayor's husband Jay McMullin talks about the Chicago Tribune, 6/23/1980The Mayor's husband and Press Secretary Jay McMullin admits the whole purpose of the confrontation was to attract public relations attention to the Mayor's case against the Tribune, 6/24/1980Mayor Byrne describes for reporters what she considered to be the worth of having her husband serve as her Press Secretary, 7/2/1980The Mayor claims there are "hundreds" of neighborhoods in Chicago clamoring for public housing and she can't see any of them wanting to turn it down, 7/10/1980The Mayor makes a rare admission that she broke one of her campaign promises by granting a consulting contract to a firm that had donated more than one thousand dollars to her political fund, 7/15/1980Byrne tells reporters to start reporting the positive aspects of her Administration or else she will not hold news conferences, 10/2/1980The Mayor denies she retaliated against Richard M. Daley by firing two cabinet members who reportedly were supporting his campaign for Cook County States Attorney, 10/1/1980Byrne says that all the federal aid President Carter poured into Chicago during the campaign should help him in the City but that it will take a lot of hard work to win the state anyway, 9/29/1980Byrne tells reporters during a news conference that she wants an open and free election on union representation in the police department, 10/14/1980The Mayor's Press Secretary explains why the Mayor attacked Senator Richard M. Daley, 10/9/1980Democratic Party Chairman George Dunne shows reluctance to take action against a ward boss who openly backed Carey for reelection, 10/13/1980Mayor Byrne launches a surprise attack against Senator Richard M. Daley in the heat of the campaign, 10/21/1980Standing behind her accusation that Senator Richard M. Daley was engaged in racist tactics, the Mayor responds to media demands for more proof by offering up a shopping center development she claims Daley killed in the Stockyards area as an example of how he blocks permits for racial reasons, 10/23/1980During a news conference, the Mayor begins with a rather humorous exchange in which she tells her husband to stay out of an exchange between her and a reporter in which she was scolding for not raising his hand before asking a question, 10/29/1980At a news conference, the Mayor defends herself against charges by L. Patrick Green that he was the only Deputy Commissioner denied a pay raise in her new budget because he was a cousin of "Sis" Daley, 11/24/1980In an exchange with reporters, the Mayor refuses to offer justification for her planned expansion of the City Department of Investigations, 11/14/1980The Mayor says that stealing on the City's Building Department Permit Desks is now up to eight or nine million dollars during the taping of WBBM's "At Issue" program, 11/25/1980State Senator Richard M. Daley responds to Mayor Byrne's charge that he was engaged in racist tactics with the help of allies in the City Building Department, 10/28/1980Byrne insists to reporters that the City did have deficits as she had claimed since taking office, 12/3/1980The Mayor responds to a newspaper poll showing a decline in her popularity, 12/9/1980Byrne denies having knowledge of a city ordinance dumping the civil service system, 1/14/1981Mayor Byrne attacks Cook County Assessor Tome Hines during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 3/13/1981tape side #5, Time: 18:08CD 55029Scope and ContentsContinuation of Byrne's appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 3/13/1981Mayor Byrne staunchly defends her controversial Senior Budget Advisor Edwin Yeo, 3/1981The Mayor talks at a community meeting in Cabrini Green, 4/3/1981Byrne speaks out against a Board of Education school desegregation plan and its forced bussing component, 4/3/1981Byrne talks about how the School Board, in her judgment , has failed to improve its financial cash flow, 4/7/1981Byrne fires back at School Superintendent Ruth Love, 4/7/1981The Mayor tells reporters that a study of 1980 census tracts by the City Planning Department suggests the need to create one and maybe two Latino wards in the city, 4/7/1981The Mayor tells reporters how she will use her apartment at the Cabrini Green public housing project and how she has also established apartments at other housing projects, 4/23/1981Mayor Byrne endorses the second school desegregation plan presented to a federal judge, 5/1/1981The Mayor puts forth her argument on why she will not accept less than an oil tax to fund mass transit, 5/27/1981
The Mayor explains how her proposed 4% service tax to fund a City run CTA would be applied if the City were to take over the CTA, 6/10/1981The Mayor offers justification for using a 4% service tax as the vehicle to finance the CTA, 6/17/1981Byrne says she does not fear a political backlash against her in 1983 during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 7/10/1981The City Council gets involved in the debate over Mayor Byrne's effort to win more state aid for the CTA, 7/20/1981The Mayor defends her decision to make Tony Frato her new City Controller, 9/24/1981The Mayor gives reporters an early glimpse of the strategy she will use in her campaign for reelection, 9/24/1981The Mayor insists to reporters that she never expressed an interest in running for Cook County Democratic Party Chairman, 10/23/1981Byrne, in a speech to the Chicago Television Academy, tells her audience she thinks she is being treated fairly by the news media but what she hates is media negativism, 10/29/1981Cook County Democratic Party Chairman George Dunn complains that he does not have very much input on party affairs because Mayor Byrne runs the show, 11/11/1981During her Budget Message to the City Council, Mayor Byrne says that there will be no property tax increase in her 1982 budget, 11/12/1981Byrne tells a special U.S. Conference of Mayors meeting in Chicago that President Reagan's policies should be given a chance to work, 11/13/1981Mayor backs away from the idea of a surcharge on suburban riders of the CTA during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 1/22/1982The Mayor complains to reporters that the news media are making an event out of the weather, 2/2/1982The Mayor makes an unprecedented appearance before the City Council's Police Committee, 2/3/1982Mayor says she does not think a smaller hotel in the north loop would hurt development there, 2/4/1982tape side #6, Time: 26:53CD 65129Scope and ContentsThe Mayor concedes to reporters that she has a problem with side street plowing, 2/9/1982Mayor Byrne attends the St. Valentines Day Ball for senior citizens at the Conrad Hilton Hotel, 2/1982Mayor Byrne claims in an exchange with reporters that two thirds of the political money she has raised from the beginning of her tenure in office went to charity, 3/4/1982The Mayor stands firm in support of Chicago Housing Authority Chairman Charles Swibel, 3/19/1982The Mayor once again defends Chicago Housing Authority Chairman Charles Swibel, 3/25/1982The Mayor tells reporters that public housing in Chicago is never going to be a country club, 3/25/1982The Mayor alludes to "fat cat realtors" who, she claims, just want to sell off public housing and put the poor out on the streets, 4/2/1982Mayor Byrne issues and Executive Order barring People's Gas Co. from getting City permits to shut off the service of customers who have not paid their bills, 3/31/1982Mayor Byrne charges that the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) is seeking consultant studies to find ways for the government to get out of public housing, 4/1/1982Mayor Byrne defends a "sweetheart" contract she awarded to her two former top aides, Bill Griffin and Mike Bradley, 5/21/1982Mayor Byrne once again sternly defends her involvement in public school affairs and says she will continue to do it so long as the full faith and credit of the City are behind the financial bailout of the Board of Education, 5/17/1982Mayor Byrne denounces the rejection of the Equal Rights Amendment by the Illinois House as a disgrace, 6/23/1982Byrne reveals to reporters that one of her political rivals is under federal investigation by the FBI, 6/11/1982The Mayor lays out her case on how she has been treated as Mayor, 6/24/1982The Mayor flashes her wit as a City Hall news conference as she tries to disarm possible controversy over how she will handle the plowing is side streets during the coming winter, 11/9/1982Byrne uses the strategy of trying to pretend she is not a candidate in reelection mode as she releases part of a new budget containing goodies to attract voters, 11/8/1982Mayor Byrne defends her three new white appointees to the Chicago Housing Authority Board to oversee a public housing system that is 95% black, 7/24/1982Byrne unveils her reelection year budget for 1983, 11/12/1982The Mayor tries to justify her claim that the City was just about "bankrupt" when she took over as Mayor, 11/12/1982Mayor Byrne announces her candidacy for reelection, 11/22/1982Byrne addresses Democratic Party slate makers on the day she won endorsement in a split vote, 11/23/1982The Mayor says she considers discussions about her hiring of an outside consultant to change her image during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 11/24/1982At a news conference, Mayor Byrne says that she has told the School Board to get moving and sell off the 21 properties it owns to generate the money needed to rehabilitate schools that are still in use, 1/4/1983tape side #7, Time: 5:23CD 75132Scope and ContentsContinuation of the news conference, 1/4/1983At a news conference, the Mayor says that the Reagan Administration's plan to take care of unemployment is low on their list, 1/10/1983In the heat of her reelection campaign, the Mayor denies that street gang members are working for her, 2/4/1983On the campaign trail in the 17th Ward, the Mayor tells a black audience her opponents have no issues to talk about so they get personal, 2/9/1983Mayor Byrne launches an attack on the Sun Times for allegedly engaging in person, vitriolic, attacks against her and her husband, 2/16/1983Mayor Byrne concedes defeat in the primary election to Congressman Harold Washington during a news conference at City Hall, 2/23/1983Byrne stuns the political world by announcing that she will run for mayor in the general election as a write-in candidate, 3/16/1983In conceding defeat for the third time since her election as mayor in 1979, this time in the primary for Circuit County Clerk, Jane Byrne says the people have spoken and that she can take the hint, 3/15/1988Harold Washington Years (1983-87)Series 44060tape side #1, Time: 28:29CD 15134Scope and ContentsDuring a mayoral campaign appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, Washington states that he would replace most, if not all, of the top (cabinet) people in City government (the Byrne Administration), 2/18/1983Washington talks about the issue of race, the school board in Chicago, Rev. Jessie Jackson, and Vice President Walter Mondale at his first news conference after winning the Democratic Mayoral Primary two days earlier, 2/24/1983During the general election campaign for mayor, Washington states that he supports the concept of Chicagofest, 3/4/1983Washington says Governor Thompson's budget is a "scare budget," 3/3/1983Washington says he promised a group of business leaders in a private meeting that he would not use Home Rule to hike local taxes if the Legislature failed to vote for an increase in the state income tax, 3/3/1983During the general election campaign for mayor, Washington sets out his stand against patronage, 3/8/1983Washington talks about the role of women in government, 3/8/1983Washington speaks at a labor breakfast, 3/9/1983At a labor union luncheon rally during the general election campaign, Washington delivers a controversial attack on what is left of the old Democratic Machine, 3/30/1983Washing blasts hate literature which surfaced late in the campaign suggesting he was a child molester (This would later be called the best and most important speech of the campaign), 4/7/1983Harold Washing delivers his victory speech to a crowd of enthusiastic supporters at Donnelly Hall after winning election as the first black Mayor in Chicago history, 4/12/1983Harold Washington delivers his inaugural address, 4/29/1983Mayor Washington explains his position on the May 2nd City Council meeting he abruptly adjourned but which the rival Vrdolyak 29 majority block then took over to pass its own reorganization plan, 5/6/1983The Mayor tells reporters he has shed his big Cadillac limousine in favor of a small Oldsmobile 98, 5/16/1983During a City Council Committee of the Whole hearing on the Mayor's Community Development Program, the Mayor tries to get things off to a civil start by delivering the invocation himself, 5/26/1983Mayor unveils his Transition Team report on reform of city government, 6/3/1983This passage demonstrates Mayor Washington's love affair with the English language, 6/6/1983In an exchange with reporters, the Mayor sets forth a more cautious view on collective bargaining than he offered while seeking union support during the election campaign, 6/7/1983On the occasion of his endorsement of Labor Leader Charles Hayes to succeed him in Congress from Chicago's First District, he says he is not a political boss and is not going to put the heat on for Hayes, 6/15/1983The Mayor tells reporters he is not prepared to accept the layoff of policemen and/or firemen to balance the City Budget, 6/15/1983The Mayor tells a group of black protesters that private firms which do business with the City will have affirmative action programs, 6/17/1983The Mayor says a federal civil rights suit will be filed because there was a "conspiracy" by the Vrdolyak 29 to deny the Council's black members and their constituents an equal voice in Council affairs, 6/22/1983The Mayor unveils a "Budget Reform Ordinance," 6/22/1983The Mayor says the despite a campaign pledge opposing higher property taxes; he will study a tax increase now after the Legislature refused to go for a tax package that would have given Chicago substantial revenue, 6/30/1983The Mayor unveils an Executive Order providing for public access to city records, 7/5/1983In an interview marking his first 100 days in office, the Mayor says he is looking into the possibility of casino gambling for Chicago to raise revenue, 8/9/1983tape side #2, Time: 26:32CD 25135Scope and ContentsThe Mayor says he would never consider moving into a Cabrini Green public housing project the way Mayor Jane Byrne did to lead the fight against gangs, 8/11/1983The Mayor explains why he is vetoing an ordinance backed by the Vrdolyak 29 that sought to give civil service protection to some eight thousand trade union and laborers union city employees, 8/18/1983The Mayors says he will not mediate the teachers union-school board contract dispute even is he is asked to do so, 9/14/1983The Mayor expands on his call for the dumping of Ed Vrdolyak as Cook County Democratic Party Chairman, 9/15/1983Statement from the Mayor further explaining why Ed Vrdolyak must go as Cook County Democratic Party Chairman, 9/29/1983
The Mayor says tongue-in-cheek he wants to apologize for a comment he made about Ed Vrdolyak the day before, 9/30/1983Mayor gives a speech to a group of minority businessmen, 10/7/1983The Mayor says that his effort to being more blacks and Hispanics into City government will not be at the expense of whites, 10/20/1983The Mayor denounces former Police Superintendent Richard Breczyck'a candidacy for Cook County State's Attorney during the taping of WBBM's "At Issue" program, 11/18/1983The Mayor defends the 6% tax he proposed on business rents to help shore up his first (1984) budget, 11/15/1983The Mayor endorses a 1992 world's fair in Chicago, 10/31/1983The Mayor summarizes for reporters the key off the record remarks he made to nearly one thousand business leaders at a closed meeting of the Economic Club of Chicago, 1/16/1984The Mayor gives a speech to the Broadcast Advertising Club, 1/19/1984The Mayor defends his top political advisor Clarence McClain even though he resigned after his arrest record on vice charges was made known, 11/23/1984The Mayor backs off on calling Clarence McClain a worthy advisor and starts referring to him as just a friend, 12/1/1984The Mayor attacks Ronald Reagan for doing a bad job as President, 2/1/1984The Mayor tells reporters it is true that there is a downside to the probability that more city employees will join unions as a result of the state's new collective bargaining law, 2/6/1984The Mayor delivers a speech to the Chicago Crime Commission, 2/9/1984Mayor Washington delivers a speech to a predominately black student audience at the University of Illinois Circle Campus, 2/21/1984The Mayor defends his choice of a Japanese bank for involvement in a new 259 million dollar borrowing plan, 2/27/1984The Mayor rules out any chance of peace with Ed Vrdolyak after the March Primary in the interest of trying to deliver Illinois into the Democratic column in November, 3/1/1984The Mayor tells a group of Chinese American businessmen that he is disturbed that someone would even imply that there is a conspiracy to block the Park Board appointments he will be sending to the City Council, 3/13/1984The Mayor delivers a speech to a mostly black student audience at the Loop College four days before the primary election, 3/16/1984The Mayor reflects on his first year in office, 4/11/1984The Mayor delivers his first "State of the City" address to the League of Women Voters, 4/12/1984In connection with a dispute over how to apply the Shakman ban on political hiring and firing to some 900 middle management jobs in the city government, the Mayor says he moved to get rid of some junior executives, not because of politics, but because on incompetence and sabotage, 4/27/1984The Mayor jokes about the attempt by Alderman Ed Burke to oust him from office for filing his ethics statement three weeks late, 5/25/1984The Mayor has an interview with WBBM on the anniversary of his first year in office, 5/2/1984The Mayor says his Administration has done well on the whole so far considering that he was forced to inherit a payroll populated with an inordinate number of saboteurs, 6/1/1984The Mayor makes it clear he would not favor a boycott of the 1984 national elections by blacks, 7/9/1984The Mayor denounces the City Council's rival Vrdolyak 29 majority block, 7/10/1984tape side #3, Time: 22:51CD 35136Scope and ContentsContinuation of the Mayor denouncing the City Council's rival Vrdolyak 29 majority block, 7/10/1984The Mayor raps City Council Financial Committee Chairman Ed Burke during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 10/4/1984The Mayor speaks at a luncheon meeting of the Chicago Academy, 10/3/1984The Mayor announces his second plan to fight street gang violence, 12/3/1984The Mayor challenges the City Council's Vrdolyak 29 majority block during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 12/7/1984Mayor Washington unveils a new court ordered city hiring plan to comply with the Shakman ban on political hiring and firing, 2/7/1985The Mayor says an ethics law for the City should preclude any city official from putting wives and other relatives on the payroll, 1/22/1985In an exchange with reporters, the Mayor says the involvement of the Vrdolyak camp in leaking a bugging tape to the Chicago Tribune of a conversation he had with a 3rd Ward aldermanic candidate proves Vrdolyak and his allies are just fumblers and bumblers, 2/25/1985The Mayor takes a shot at Illinois Senate Republican Minority Leader James "Pate" Philip, 3/4/1985The Mayor takes a shot at Alderman Ed Burke, 3/18/1985The Mayor takes a shot at Brad Reynolds, head of the U.S. Justice Department's Civil Rights Division, during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 3/22/1985The Mayor takes another shot at one of his political enemies, Alderman Ed Burke, and what he says is the Alderman's downbeat attitude about the City, 3/28/1985The Mayor replies to a statement New York Mayor Ed Koch made about race relations in Chicago, 3/28/1985Mayor announces an executive order to award 30% of city contracts to firms owned by minorities and women, 4/3/1985The Mayor responds to an attack by former Mayor Jane Byrne, 4/29/1985The Mayor attacks the Vrdolyak 29 in the City Council for once again trying to assert control over policy changes in the police and fire departments, 5/23/1985The Mayor colorfully chides Republican Governor Jim Thompson for failing to produce the GOP support needed to bring a World's Fair to Chicago in 1992, 6/21/1985The Mayor fires an opening attack on the mayoral candidacy of former Mayor Jane Byrne, 9/9/1985Mayor Washington says he is satisfied that the bidding process on the O'Hare people mover system was handled properly, UndatedThe Mayor defends a litmus test of loyalty his political operatives are requiring candidates to meet, 11/10/1985The Mayor blasts the demand of Alderman Ed Burke for City Council oversight controls on the big O'Hare expansion program as "gangersterism" and "blackmail," 11/14/1985The Mayor challenges his arch rival Ed Vrdolyak to run against him for Mayor in 1987, 11/15/1985The Mayor hotly denies that a former campaign aid, Lee Miller, has enough influence to steer contracts to pals, 11/15/1985The Mayor attacks Alderman Ed Vrdolyak for pushing a resolution that demands the Mayor denounce Minister Louis Farrakhan for his statements about Jews, 11/18/1985At a news conference, the Mayor says the Chicago Sun Times should have apologized for having accused his Administration of mishandling bids on the people mover project at O'Hare airport, 11/21/1985The Mayor gives a briefing on the U.S. Attorney's Operation Incubator corruption probe, 1/7/1986During a City Council meeting, the Mayor joins the "Refrigerettes" in a cheer as the Mayor and aldermen pay tribute to the Chicago Bears for winning the National Football Conference crown, 1/16/1986The Mayor gives a briefing on the U.S. Attorney's Operation Incubator corruption investigation, 2/7/1986The Mayor deplores the leaks in the U.S. Attorney's Operation Incubator corruption probe, 2/10/1986The Mayor gives an appearance on the Channel 2 "Newsmakers" program, 2/14/1986The Mayor accuses Alderman Ed Burke and the City Council Finance Committee he chairs of trying to obstruct the goals and will of his new Council majority, 5/9/1986The Mayor comments to reporters on his political goal in the wake of winning narrow control of the City Council by virtue of his tie-breaking vote, 5/7/1986The Mayor says he does not see any real massive public backlash occurring against the record 80 million dollar property tax increase he engineered, 5/21/1986The Mayor tells reporters that any Democrats who do not support his call for a city income tax down in Springfield cannot count on his political support at election time, 5/24/1986The Mayor denies that his seizing of control of City Council committees was a power grab, 6/6/1986The Mayor comes out against mandatory drug testing for city employees, 8/14/1986
The Mayor defends his right to fight a referendum backed by rival Machine regulars to change the rules for mayoral elections, 8/18/1986tape side #4, Time: 55:11CD 45137Scope and ContentsThe Mayor says he should be praised for ordering the internal Sullivan anti-corruption investigation of his Administration, 10/23/1986The Mayor calls on the press to quit quoting his arch rival Ed Vrdolyak on Ethics legislation, 10/26/1986The Mayor talks about his new revised ethics ordinance, 11/6/1986The Mayor talks about his political opponents bring up his past during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 11/14/1986The Mayor delivers a speech to students at Northeastern University, 1/15/1987The Mayor talks to reporters after signing ethics legislation into law, 2/1987The Mayor makes no apologies over reports he plans to dump rival Machine types from City Council committee chairmanships when he reorganizes the Council, 4/3/1987Mayor wins a clear mandate in the General Election and becomes the first Mayor to win reelection to a second consecutive term since Richard J. Daley, 4/8/1987The Mayor denies he dumped southwest side aldermen like Ed Burke, Mike Sheahan, and John Madrzyk from leadership posts because he ran badly in their wards, 4/16/1987The Mayor refuses to accept blame for admitted mismanagement at the CHA, 5/6/1987The Mayor criticizes Roosevelt University urbanologist Pierre de Vise for charging that the Mayor's hiring policies are too heavily weighted in favor of clacks, that they make a mockery of fairness and constitute a violation o f civil rights law, 5/26/1987The Mayor blasts the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development for a report which sharply criticizes the management team he sent to the Chicago Housing Authority to reform the agency, 5/28/1987The Mayor takes Governor Jim Thompson to task for failing to line up Republican support behind his tax program and then trying to blame him for the program's lack of support, 6/18/1987The Mayor talks about the decision of his arch rival Ed Vrdolyak to switch to the Republican Party after resigning as Cook County Democratic Party Chairman, 6/19/1987The Mayor scoffs at suggestions that he go to Springfield to lobby in person for tax increases, 6/19/1987The Mayor defends his decision to fire Patrick Quinn as City Revenue Director, 6/26/1987The Mayor fires back at critics who say his criticism of the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development is not helping to bring about a compromise that would prevent a HUD takeover of the CHA, 7/22/1987The Mayor blames the failure of the City Revenue Department to make a crackdown on parking ticket scofflaws work on Circuit Court Clerk Morgan Finley, 8/13/1987The Mayor denies that he and his budget aides used phony inflated estimates of gas tax revenues to show the city budget was balanced when the Mayor was seeking reelection, 8/25/1987
The Mayor criticizes aldermen who voted against a school property tax levy, 10/30/1987The Mayor says he opposes a total kind of full blown decentralization of the public school system as part of any school reform plan, 10/9/1987The Mayor gives a briefing on his record 2.7 billion dollar budget for 1988, 10/15/1987The Mayor defends his decision to allow the Cubs to play 18 night games at Wrigley Field, 11/13/1987Mayor Washington addresses Cook County Democratic Party leaders for only the second time since being elected Mayor in 1983, 11/18/1987The Mayor responds to attempts by arch rival Ed Vrdolyak as a Circuit Court Clerk candidate on the Republican ticket to make the race a referendum on the Mayor, 11/19/1987During the 1987 campaign for mayor, Washington mocks Democratic challenger and former Mayor Jane Byrne for wishing for another show storm so he will be defeated, UndatedDuring the 1987 campaign for mayor, Washington denies he was behind the heckling of challenger Jane Byrne at one of her campaign appearances, UndatedDuring the 1987 campaign for mayor, Washing attacks his Republican opponent Ed Vrdolyak, UndatedDuring a question and answer session with a mostly black student audience at Loop College, the Mayor says he will be tough in cracking down on crime and street gang violence, 2/21/1985Mayor Washington speaks to students at Loop College in observance of Black History Month, 2/21/1985Mayor Washington delivers his Second Inaugural Address after winning a second term, 5/4/1987tape side #5, Time: 29:34CD 55138Scope and ContentsMayor Washington enthusiastically sings the song "Chicago" along with the band at the celebration of his reelection to a second term, 4/4/1987The Mayor delivers his victory speech on the night of election to a second term, 4/4/1987Mayor Washington delivers his second inaugural address after winning a second term, 5/4/1987Eugene Sawyer Years (1987-89)Series 54061tape side #1, Time: 13:56CD 15139Scope and ContentsSawyer delivers his first news conference after being elected Acting Mayor by the City Council in a stormy all night session, 12/3/1987Acting Mayor Sawyer speaks at a luncheon meeting of about 500 Catholic businessmen, 1/8/1988Sawyer refers to the name "mumbles" that critics have given him because of his speaking style during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 1/29/1988At a news conference, Sawyer vows to put the court ordered Shakman protections against political patronage hiring into the City Personnel Code, 2/3/1988Acting Mayor Sawyer says that Paul Simon could face retaliation from black voters when he seeks reelection to the Senate in 1990 because of his decision to keep control of his delegates to the Democratic National Convention rather than urging them to support Rev. Jessie Jackson for the presidential nomination, 4/12/1988Sawyer declares his opposition to the proposed home equity program, 4/12/1988Sawyer explains why it took him so long to fire aid Steve Cokely in the wake of revelations that Cokely was delivering anti-Semitic, anti-Christian lectures to supporters of Minister Louis Farakhan, 5/5/1988Sawyer says he will not tolerate another teachers strike in an interview on radio station WVON, 6/1/988Sawyer defends a meeting at which pledges to raise money for his campaign were extracted from members of his cabinet, 1/5/1989Sawyer declares again that he listed a controversial 30 thousand dollar finder's fee from a zoning case 10 years earlier on his income tax return during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 1/5/1989Sawyer defends his shakeup of the City Council's leadership saying he had to put some people in power who were going to advance his agenda, 7/13/1988Acting Mayor Eugene Sawyer delivers his first public statement after losing the primary election in a landslide to Richard M. Daley, 3/13/1989Acting Mayor Eugene Sawyer brings his brief 16 month tenure to a close with a farewell speech to the City Council at his final meeting, 3/29/1989Richard M. Daley Years (1982-2001)Series 64062tape side #1, Time: 36:23CD 15140Scope and ContentsRichard M. Daley announces his candidacy for Mayor, 11/4/1982Daley speaks on WBBM's "At Issue," 1/6/1983Daley accuses Mayor Jane Byrne of breaking her word to take part in a political campaign debate, 1/11/1983At a news conference, Daley vows to revamp the Corporation Counsel's Office if he is elected Mayor, 1/26/1983Daley accuses Mayor Jane Byrne of "double-crossing" members of the Firefighters Union, 2/3/1983News conference in which Daley blasts Chicago Housing Authority Chairman Charles Swibel, 2/7/1983tape side #2, Time: 58:20CD 25141Scope and ContentsDaley delivers his victory speech at his election night headquarters after winning the General Election for Mayor, 4/4/1989Daley takes the oath of office as Chicago's 45th Mayor, 4/24/1989Daley's first inauguration speech as Mayor of Chicago, 4/24/1989Daley announces 22 of his key Cabinet members, 4/21/1989Daley vows to not to dictate to other elective offices like a political boss, 4/20/1989Daley defends his decision to eliminate only one Council committee, 4/26/1989News conference in which Daley states that the City faces a serious budget shortfall, 4/27/1989Daley says he does not want the new $50,000 stretch limo that was purchased for the Mayor before he took office, 5/1/1989Daley speaks on WBBM's "At Issue" Program where he talks about the issues of race, school reform, random drug testing, and public policy, 5/4/1989Daley defends his decision to bring in outsiders to head the Streets and Sanitation and Economic Development Departments, 5/8/1989Daley speaks out in opposition to proposed legislation that would impose a $2-a-month head tax on suburbanites who work in Chicago, 5/8/1989Daley reveals his management style, 5/8/1989News conference in which Daley announces the firing of the entire Board of Health and a new direction for health care, 5/9/1989Daley states he is opposed to the New York approach of distributing free needles to drug users to prevent the spread of AIDS, 5/9/1989Daley defends his offering of tax breaks to Sears to encourage the company to stay in Chicago and keep six thousand jobs in the City when the Sears Tower is sold, 5/9/1989News Conference in which Daley announces the creation of an Inspector General position, 5/11/1989Mayor Daley announces a unique agreement with the private sector to have an Arthur Anderson executive serve as Revenue Director for one year on loan, 5/2/1989Daley defends his decision not to renew a policy allowing the City Council's Finance Committee to review major city contracts, 5/24/1989Daley explains his choices for the Interim School Board to implement school reform, 5/25/1989Daley announces a crackdown on loafing by city workers, 6/1/1989Daley mocks the owners of the Chicago Bears for threatening to move the team to Arlington Heights, 6/29/1989tape side #3, Time: 28:13CD 35142Scope and ContentsDaley states he is personally opposed to abortion, but that the decision should be made by a woman in consultation with her doctor, 7/10/1989Daley supports the use of wiretaps and eavesdrop devices to detect violations of the law by politicians and others, 7/13/1989In a controversial remark, Daley states that if the CHA (Chicago Housing Authority) cannot pay its overdue water bill, then meters should be installed to limit residents to one shower a day, 8/9/1989Daley opposes the levy of taxes to build a stadium for the Bears because the team only plays about 11-12 home games, 8/9/1989Daley apologizes for his August 9 remark, 8/14/1989Daley lashes out at critics in the black community who claim that racially-motivated police brutality has been on the increase since he was elected Mayor, 9/11/1989Daley criticizes the Bush Administration's strategy on drugs, 9/6/1989Daley defends a controversial deal to give United Airlines 20 acres of prime land at O'Hare Airport, 9/29/1989Daley expresses concern for the findings of a study showing that ethnic isolation in Chicago is feeding racism, 9/29/1989Daley rejects a call by City Council reformers to revive legislation creating an Inspector General, 10/2/1989Daley attacks black groups for saying Police Superintendent Leroy Martin is working to reduce police brutality, but he (the Mayor) is not, 10/2/1989Daley chides critics of local school advisory councils, 10/10/1989At a news conference, Daley vows to keep politics out of contracts and jobs at O'Hare Airport, UndatedDaley reacts to the arrest of a man accused of threatening his life in a call to 911, 10/31/1989Daley outlines a new ordinance giving the Consumer Services Department more power to deal with deception and fraud in the marketplace, 10/25/1989Daley insists he will stay out of the primary elections to avoid being seen as a Boss, 10/23/1989Daley talks to children at a West Side grade school about gangs and drugs, 10/24/1989Daley declares his opposition to a proposal by Alderman Bill Henry to require food sellers to show proficiency in English, 12/12/1989Daley responds to union policemen engaging in a ticket-writing slowdown job action to protest the Mayor's inaction regarding contract arbitration, 11/15/1989Daley reveals he will begin negotiations after January 1, 1990 with Bears President Mike McCaskey on a new stadium, 12/21/1989Daley tells the School Board to drop the tactics of threatening deficits to get more help from Springfield, 1/19/1990Daley says he is determined to collect on overdue parking tickets, 2/14/1990Daley says he will accept responsibility for any shortcomings on snow removal after a 10-inch snowfall, 2/15/1990Daley affirms his support for a proposed third major airport, 2/15/1990Daley responds to criticism from former Mayoral opponent Ed Vrdolyak on his third airport plan, 2/22/1990Daley rejects a call by three state legislators for a public referendum on his third airport plan, 2/23/1990Daley criticizes waste, inefficiency, and mismanagement in the City's health care insurance program, 2/26/1990Daley explains why he refuses to get involved in Democratic Party primaries, 3/22/1990Daley defends his Education Deputy Lourdes Monteagudo and her decision to enroll her daughter in a suburban private school, 3/27/1990Daley defends his plan for a third airport to the Economics Club of Chicago, 4/12/1990tape side #4, Time: 24:07CD 45143Scope and ContentsDaley attacks a Sun Times article which claims that minority hiring in higher positions in his Administration is down by 25% since the previous November, 4/11/1990Daley encourages local TV stations to accept ads in a city campaign against AIDS which mention condoms, 5/3/1990Daley defends extensive background checks on school board nominees which delayed their appointments, 5/11/1990Daley defends the slow pace of selecting school board appointees, 5/8/1990Daley explains why he is opposed to a constitutional amendment that would require a 60% vote in the Illinois Senate and House for the approval of tax measures, 5/1/1990Daley says he will support extension of the temporary two year 20% increase in the State Income Tax only if it is tied to property tax relief, 5/21/1990Daley responds angrily to questions regarding whether his father could have done more to steer city contracts to firms owned by minorities and women, 5/22/1990Daley reacts to a newspaper story that the City is no longer bothering to ticket dog owners for failing to pick up the waste left by their animals, 5/30/1990Daley blurts out in reply to a question about why he left a City Council meeting before a debate on South African sanctions, 7/2/1990In a moment of frustration over the refusal of the Bush Administration to provide more funding for the war on drugs, he says the City doesn't have the power to stop drugs, 7/4/1990Daley tells reporters not to blame him for a racially motivated incident that occurred in a tavern called Fat Albert's, 8/31/1990Daley says the black postman who had a dog sicked on him in Bridgeport by a Hispanic resident was not his mailman, 8/31/1990Daley accuses the news media of preparing to do a hatchet job on him for being at his Grand Beach, Michigan summer house when a major power blackout occurred on the City's west side, 7/30/1990At a Chicago TV Academy luncheon, Daley says the press is correct about his protectiveness of his family, 5/24/1990Daley gets into a test exchange with his defeated challenger in the last Mayoral election, Alderman Timothy Evans, at a City Council hearing on the city's high murder rate, 9/26/1990Daley says he is a proponent of the death penalty on the even of the execution of convicted murderer Charles Walker at Stateville Prison, 9/11/1990Daley responds to the indictment of long time First Ward Abraham Fred Roti and other First Ward political figures and whether this proves there is a link between organized crime and City Hall, 12/19/1990In announcing that he will run for reelection, Daley denies being afraid to debate his more articulate challengers, 12/10/1990Daley explains why he opposes City Council hearings on taxicab industry corruption, 1/11/1991Daley explains why he thinks a proposal to limit the Mayor of Chicago to two consecutive four year terms is a bad idea, 1/11/1991Daley says he thinks the City Council ought to change the policy of paying the legal fees of aldermen under criminal investigation up to the point of indictment, 12/21/1990Daley tells members of the Rotary Club that he will fight the efforts of Governor Jim Edgar to shift more general welfare costs to the City, 3/12/1991Daley defends his controversial intervention into the dispute over who should be the next Chancellor of the University of Illinois at Chicago, 3/7/1991Daley says in his victory speech for mayor that the victory was a milestone because it shattered the myth that with an election must come bitterness and name calling, 4/2/1991Daley has a question and answer session with reporters after his election victory speech, 4/2/1991Daley insists the investigation his office launched into the loafing scandal in the First Ward Sanitation Department has been thorough and that is shows the commitment he made to protect the taxpayers and their money, 5/30/1991Daley insists that he has respect for the Laborers Union, 5/30/1991Mayor Daley takes the oath of office for the second time, 5/6/1991Daley gives his inaugural address, 5/6/1991Daley blasts the Detroit Pistons for refusing to shake hands after losing four straight in the playoffs to the Chicago Bulls, 5/31/1991Daley says the proposed domed stadium for the Bears cannot be built, 4/10/1991In discussing the controversy over the proposed renewal of the Civil Rights Act in Congress and the issue of racial quotas, the Mayor says he supports racial quotas, 6/6/1991Daley defends his much criticized strategy of operating quietly behind the scenes in the protracted negotiations over a state budget compromise, 7/18/1991Daley raps the Illinois General Assembly for refusing to make the local share of the State Income Tax Surcharge permanent, 7/18/1991Responding to critics who say he is not exercising leadership in a Springfield stalemate over a new State Budget, Daley suggests that any stronger role would again raise accusations that he is trying to be a Boss, 7/8/1991Daley responds to charges from some gay activists that his Administration had not done enough in the war against AIDS, 8/8/1991Daley insists he has no secret remap plan of his own on remapping City wards to comply with the 1990 Census, 8/9/1991Daley says he will not deviate from his plan to take Sundays off to be with his family, 8/9/1991At a news conference, Daley says the School Board has to face reality in closing a shortfall, 8/9/1991Daley says he firmly believes that if property taxes are raised it will move more middle class taxpayers out of Chicago as well as more businesses, 8/14/1991tape side #5, Time: 23:15CD 55144Scope and ContentsDaley says that drug sweeps by the police are necessary, 8/14/1991Daley says the City is not going to use land it wants from the military at O'Hare Airport to build additional runways, 8/14/1991Daley says he warned the School Board members when he appointed them that is was going to be a very tough job that would require them to make very difficult decisions, 8/16/1991Daley says when he was States Attorney nobody wanted to listen to him when he warned that gangs were a criminal, not a social problem, 8/29/1991Daley says the drug violence in Chicago is getting just like Columbia, 8/29/1991Commenting on health care, Daley says millions of dollars were lost to the taxpayers because of fraud, mismanagement, and sloppy procedures, 10/3/1991Daley releases a study of the Police Department at a news conference, 10/9/1991Daley says he has no regrets over having sought to win the power to remove the City Treasurer from pension boards, 11/7/1991Daley says with sarcasm in his voice that he does not believe reports about Miriam Santos' poor attendance at pension board meetings, 11/8/1991Daley suggests that City Treasurer Miriam Santos has been ungrateful, 11/6/1991Daley announces a new controversial franchise agreement with Commonwealth Edison, 10/22/1991Daley suggests that City Treasurer Miriam Santos was looking for publicity with her charge that his top aides were interfering in the operations of her office, 11/1/1991Daley jokes that he is wondering where his father is to help him get out of a threatened school strike, 11/14/1991Daley talks about all the problems he is facing at a particularly troubling time in his tenure, 11/5/1991Daley comments on his decline in the popularity polls, 11/1991Daley talks of his serious consideration of gambling as a new source of revenue, 11/5/1991Daley rejects the charge of the Legislative Black Caucus (in Springfield) that his effort to give the School Finance Authority more oversight authority over the School Board was a racially motivated power grab, 11/8/1991Daley delivers his budget message to the City Council, 10/15/1991Daley puts in another pitch for his proposed third airport in the Lake Calumet region, 12/12/1991
Daley says the boast that he halted a subpoena to Joey Auippa when he was States Attorney was false, 1/8/1992Daley breaks down during in availability in his City Hall Conference room as he talks about the unauthorized party his son Patrick had, 3/2/1992Daley blasts the news media for spending more time reporting on his son's party than on a police officer who was killed in the line of duty, 3/9/1992Daley continues his tirade against the press for playing up his son's party, 3/2/1992Daley talks about the moral question of gambling, 4/2/1992Daley holds a briefing about the flood that was caused when a tunnel under the Chicago River was compromised, 4/17/1992Daley talks about the anti-gang initiative being proposed in the City Council, 5/20/1992Daley denies calling National Democratic Party Chairman Rob Brown and pressuring him into denying City Treasurer Miriam Santos a delegate seat at the Convention, 5/27/1992Daley responds to a vote by the U.S. Senate to ban sports betting in most states, 6/3/1992Daley talks of the violence and looting that accompanied the Bulls's Championship celebration, 6/15/1992Daley says it is a joke to let lawbreakers who caused trouble during the Bulls celebration out of I-Cards, 6/16/1992Daley reacts to the U.S. Supreme Court decision in a Pennsylvania abortion case, 6/29/1992Daley and Governor Edgar announce an agreement on a proposed third airport in the Lake Calumet region, 2/21/1992Daley endorses the concept of a gambling casino/entertainment complex in Chicago, 3/24/1992Daley announces the firing of the City's Acting Transportation Commissioner John LaPlante, 4/14/1992Daley blasts minority Republicans in the Illinois Senate for killing his Lake Calumet airport plan, 7/1/1992Daley accuses Governor Jim Edgar of not doing enough to get Republican votes for a third airport in the Lake Calumet region, 7/2/1992Daley insists he has no plans to run for Governor in 1994, 9/22/1992Daley announces sweeping reform of the Police Department, 7/22/1992Daley raps Governor Edgar for vowing to veto any casino bill that he (Daley) proposes, 9/25/1992Daley belittles Governor Edgar saying that in place of land based casinos he is willing to consider a land based theme park but only in conjunction with riverboat casinos, 12/1/1992Daley announces a new plan to crack down on gang violence at Cabrini Green and in public housing in general, 10/19/1992Daley defends his leadership after a year of setbacks that included the loop flood, a bridge disaster, and his failure to get a third airport and gambling casinos, 12/16/1992tape side #6, Time: 23:30CD 65145Scope and ContentsDaley reacts to the conviction of former First Ward Alderman Fred Roti, 1/15/1993Song that was recorded about Mayor Daley's frustrating fight to bring casino gambling to Chicago, Undated.Daley talks about his love for his job, 2/10/1993Daley endorses a new runway at O'Hare Airport, 3/23/1993Daley defends his proposal to create cul-de-sacs to wall off certain neighborhoods from violent crime, 2/22/1993Daley unveils a proposal to impose a 5% cap on property tax increases or to limit increases to the rate of inflation, whichever is less, 1/25/1993Daley refuses to take sides in the property tax feud between Alderman Jim Laski and Laski's political boss Congressman Bill Lipinski, 2/19/1993Daley unveils his experiment in community policing, 2/2/1993Daley responds to reports that many police officers are not volunteering for community policing because they oppose it, 3/24/1993At a City Hall news conference, Daley backs off under City Council pressure from a 12-million dollar property tax increase to pay for a new police contract, 2/19/1993At a joint news conference with Governor Edgar, Daley contends that he and Edgar actually do agree on a number of issues, 3/12/1993Daley explains why he did not let go of City Clerk Walter Kozubowski from the ticket in 1991, 4/6/1993On the key question of why he did not check further with his sources at the U.S. Attorney's Office to determine if the charges being probed against Kozubowski were serious enough to warrant dumping him from the ticket, Daley says to do that would violate grand jury secrecy, 4/19/1993Daley defends his decision to plan for a move out of Bridgeport to more upscale surroundings, despite his long family history there, 4/2/1993Daley says it serves no purpose for some state legislators and others to go around "browbeating" Chicago schools, 4/21/1993Daley defends his reform proposals on teacher union work rules, 4/21/1993Daley says he hops suburban and downstate GOP lawmakers and Governor Edgar are not fighting more aid for Chicago schools because so much of the system is black, 4/22/1993Daley warns the Teachers Union and School Board there is no pot of gold down in Springfield to bail out the schools, 4/30/1993Daley blasts the Chicago Crime Commission's opposition to his plan for up to five riverboat casinos in Chicago due to fears of more crime, 5/10/1993Daley refuses to discuss tradeoffs in exchange for Governor Edgar and the Republicans signing on to his floating casino plan, 6/3/1993Daley defends the pay scales for Chicago public school teachers, 6/15/1993Daley talks about the importance of Congressman Dan Rostenkowski to the state of Illinois, 7/20/1993Daley appoints Federal Prosecutor Tom Scorza as interim City Clerk, 6/1993Daley gives a major speech to the Chicagoland Association of Commerce and Industry, 6/29/1993Daley talks about his dissatisfaction with the job President Clinton is doing, 6/16/1993Daley raps the Phoenix Suns and team star Charles Barkley for belittling his police security preparations in the event of street trouble if the Bulls won another championship. 6/23/1993Daley defends what the Police did during the 1968 Democratic National Convention Riots, 8/26/1993Daley concedes that the borrowing plan he proposed to bail the Chicago schools out of trouble again is one nobody likes, not even him, 9/7/1993Cut of protesters singing outside of Mayor Daley's City Hall Office as they demand more action by Daley to resolve a budget crisis and to keep the schools open, 9/13/1993Daley rejects Republican demands for a Chicago referendum in 1995 on increasing property taxes for the public schools, 9/20/1993Daley rips an attempt by street gangs to use a new movement called "21st Century Vote" to move into the political arena, 10/13/1993Daley criticizes teachers Julian High School who walked off the job, 10/19/1993Daley says a decision by the Principal and Assistant Principal at Englewood High School to let the school be used for a gang leader awards ceremony shows you what is happening in our schools, 10/27/1993Daley raps Governor Edgar's record on the day Edgar announces his run for reelection, 11/9/1993Daley responds to criticism from labor unions after he goes against them and endorses the North American Free Trade Agreement, 11/10/1993Daley criticizes how long the federal grand jury investigation into Dan Rostenkowski's personal and campaign finances is taking, 2/15/1994Daley criticizes a front page series of articles in the Chicago Tribune documenting why families are fleeing to the suburbs, 12/1/1993Daley delivers a speech on his anti-crime package, 1/11/1994Daley speaks at a school in the Robert Taylor Homes area, 3/20/1994Daley raps the failure of the system to hold judges accountable for bad performance, 2/10/1994Daley criticizes the so-called feeding frenzy of speculation about whether Congressman Dan Rostenkowski might agree to a plea bargain deal and resign, 6/5/1994Daley reveals for the first time in a Q and A with reporters that he got controversial gifts from Dan Rostenkowski that the FBI allege were illegally charged to taxpayers and that the FBI interviewed him about that and his relationship with the Congressman, 6/3/1994During a news conference, Daley says Dan Rostenkowski is a friend of his and he is not going to walk away, 6/31/1994Daley triggers controversy with the statement that scattered site public housing has to be moved out to the suburbs, not just built in the city, 4/19/1994Daley angrily defends the Police Department after a west side Alderman Dexter Watson turned a drug bust news conference into criticism of the department, 6/2/1994Daley openly expresses reservations about President Clinton's health plan saying the employer mandates Clinton wants could cost the nation jobs, 6/28/1994Daley defends President Clinton in the face of declining voter job approval ratings, 6/16/1994Daley defends the job that National Democratic Party Chairman Dave Wilhelm has done, 6/22/1994Daley attacks Bob Woodward's book on Bill Clinton as gossip, 6/16/1994Daley sarcastically congratulates Indiana riverboat interests and the state's Governor for doing their jobs well and getting riverboats there, 6/30/1994Daley denies that his lobbying efforts on behalf of Chicago riverboats were half-hearted and a case of too little too late, 7/7/1994Daley raps Governor Edgar for a lack of leadership in the issue of Chicago riverboats, 7/7/1994Daley claims the Governor retracted his agreement to seek a Senate vote on a Chicago riverboat gambling bill right after the primary, 7/12/1994Daley denies that his moral leadership was called into question, 8/3/1994tape side #7, Time: 25:29CD 75146Scope and ContentsDaley defends his support for a jobs contract with the Chicago Urban League that will funnel funds to a group with ties to street gangs (21st Century Vote), 7/20/1994As he looks ahead to Chicago hosting the 1996 Democratic National Convention, Daley defends the City's actions during the riots associated with the Democratic Convention in 1968, 7/20/1994Daley rips White House Deputy Chief of Staff Harold Ickes for working behind the scenes to force out National Democratic Party Chairman David Wilhelm, a close Daley ally, 7/20/1994Daley bristles at reminders of 1968 on the day of the official announcement that Chicago has been chosen as the site for the 1996 Democratic National Convention, 8/4/1996Daley talks about the shocking case of an 11-year old boy who is wanted for shooting three people, one fatally, while involved in gang initiation, 8/31/1994Daley lashes out at U.S. Senator Paul Simon for his criticism of the law and order provisions in a new federal anti-crime bill, 8/31/1994Daley disagrees with a group of black alderman who went to the Art Institute and took the painting down of Harold Washington in women's underwear, 9/21/1994Daley asks reporters to please tell Governor Edgar that Chicago is still part of Illinois, 9/21/1994Daley defends Democratic Gubernatorial candidate Dawn Clark Netsch in the face of charges from Governor Edgar that she is allegedly soft on crime, 9/26/1994Daley denounces suburban pleasure boat owners for wanting the City to open bridges for their boats at any hour of the day or night, 9/29/1994Daley says the School Board should look at the idea of privatizing management of schools, 10/5/1994Daley raps Governor Edgar for making light of Dawn Clark Netsch's opposition to the death penalty, 10/5/1994Daley says current tax sentencing rules are actually more costly than the tougher one he proposed in his crime package, 11/9/1994Daley talks about the landslide Republican victories in the off-year elections, 11/9/1994Daley rejects the proposal for more frequent garbage collections to attack dirty alley problems, 11/1/1994Daley tells Democratic leaders they should be in charge of getting crime legislation passed in Springfield, 11/16/1994Daley responds to the controversy over the way Connie Chung of CBS sandbagged the mother of U.S. House Speaker Newt Gingrich in an interview, 6/5/1995Daley says the "Contract With America" that the Republicans came up with is great, 1/6/1995Daley speaks out against the idea of dividing the Chicago school system into about 10 different districts, 1/18/1995Daley addresses a group of black ministers who endorsed him, 1/18/1995Daley tells reporters not to blame the City Council committee ghost payroller scandal on him, 2/9/1995Daley criticizes leaders of the National Democratic Party in Washington for viewing democratic mayors as special interests, not as the eyes and ears of the party on urban problems, 2/10/1995Daley explains his philosophy about political campaigns, 2/22/1995Daley denies that he offered former Illinois Attorney General Roland Burris a high paying job if he would not run against him, 3/8/1995Daley comes down hard on the teacher/coach of the Steinmetz high school academic decathlon team for encouraging his team to cheat, 3/28/1995Daley defends the endorsement he received from indicted former alderman and state legislator Joe Kotlarz, 3/28/1995Daley defends his refusal to debate his opponents in the primary and general election campaigns, 3/28/1995Daley raps the so-called turncoats who move out of Chicago to the plush suburbs and who turn around and criticize the City they came from as if there was something wrong with Chicago, 3/29/1995Daley says on the morning after his reelection victory that he knows his father would be proud of him to have won three times in this day and age, 4/4/1995Daley says he would still like to have riverboat gambling in Chicago, 4/10/1995
Daley raps City Council opponents of pay raises, 4/11/1995Daley reveals a bi-city airport pact with Gary, 4/14/1995Daley says it didn't matter if Chicago could not accept something because the Governor and Republican leaders intended to do it anyway, 4/14/1995Daley discusses the hypocrisy of state legislators who speak against pay raises and then lobby behind the scenes breathlessly to try and get them, 4/14/1995Daley says he is willing to take responsibility for any retaliation Chicago suffers (from Springfield) as a result of his airport dealing with Gary, 4/14/1995Daley says he thinks the instances of ghost payrolling that cropped up on City Council committees are very isolated, 5/3/1995Daley delivers his victory statement at his campaign night headquarters after defeating Roland Burris in the General Election to win a third consecutive term as Mayor of Chicago, 4/4/1995Daley claims the City Council is one of the most effective legislative bodies in the country, 4/28/1995Daley says he is willing to take the responsibility no one else in the state wants for reforming Chicago's public schools, 5/10/1995Daley rips the liquor industry for defending the worst taverns in the City, 5/17/1995Daley talks about the lobbying effort to defeat a planned Republican takeover of O'Hare (in Springfield), 5/17/1995tape side #8, Time: 23:37CD 85147Scope and ContentsIn a lengthy exchange with reporters, Daley denies he is in a snit with the media after several days of terse responses to questions, 6/13/1995Daley reacts to attempts in the City Council to limit off color programming on cable TV to certain adult hours, 6/14/1995Daley says community leaders who want more say over empowerment zones (special development zones) want to put their hands in the "old cookie jar" because there is 100 million dollars involved there, 6/14/1995Daley says the option of operating public schools year round needs to be evaluated, 6/14/1995Daley says in the wake of the indictment of School Board President Sharon Grant for not paying taxes that he is going to have future Board appointees sign affidavits saying they paid their taxes, 6/27/1995Daley voices support for the U.S. Supreme Court decision allowing random drug testing for student athletes in public schools, 6/27/1995Daley says the disclosure that the City was about to make a five million dollar loan to a movie studio developer with mob ties was a minor incident that was corrected, 6/28/1995Daley announces members of his School Reform Team, 6/29/1995Daley reacts to the guilty plea entered by School Board President Sharon Grant on federal income tax charges, 7/6/1995
Daley says the switch to a nonpartisan contest for Mayor of Chicago won't mean much because voters are much more independent now and less party conscious than ever before, 7/7/1995Daley talks about baseball, 7/7/1995 and 7/12/1995Daley plays down the seriousness of the great killer heat wave that struck Chicago and which ended up with more than 500 deaths, 7/14/1995Daley rips Commonwealth Edison for failing to adequately respond to power outages caused by the killer heat wave, 7/17/1995Daley says one of the big overriding problems during the heat wave was the refusal of senior citizens to leave their apartments and go to cooling centers, even when the City offered some assistance, 7/17/1995Daley admits the City could have done a better job responding to the killer heat wave, 7/17/1995Daley questions the figures being put out by the Cook County Medical Examiner on heat-related deaths, 7/19/1995Daley says people have a right to criticize the Mayor after his Administration was criticized for responding too little too late to the killer heat wave, 7/20/1995Daley says he has no complaints about the criticism he took in the media for his handling of the heat wave, 7/20/1995Daley defends the wife of Congressman Mel Reynolds during the Congressman's trial, 8/9/1995Daley defends a new city ordinance allowing the City to seize and control dangerous dogs, 9/12/1995Daley reacts to the acquittal of O.J. Simpson after his long trial, 10/3/1995Daley defends a police department decision ordering a Catholic police officer to guard an abortion clinic against his beliefs, 9/21/1995Daley defends the ruling of a hearing officer for the City Human Relations Commission that the Boy Scouts cannot deny employment to a gay applicant, 9/21/1995Daley defends a plan to create six alternative schools to deal with troublemaker kids, 9/15/1995Daley responds to Bears president Mike McCaskey's statement that his grandfather George Hallas would have advised him to move the team to Indiana if he gets a better deal than Soldier Field, 10/26/1995Daley says that railroads have a responsibility to improve safety after a tragic fatal train-school bus accident in Fox River Grove, 10/26/1995Daley defends his Soldier Field renovation plan to keep the Bears in Chicago, 10/18/1995Daley states that the moving of football teams is all about money, 11/6/1995 and 11/7/1995Daley explains why he proposed a measure to let the City immediately close bars that lose licenses for serious violation instead of being allowed to stay open pending appeal, 11/1/1995Daley gives a statement about the way NFL team owners only care about the money, 11/14/1995Daley explains why he refuses to sweeten the pot to get the Bears to stay in Chicago, 11/22/1995Daley says he is irritated over what he claims was a demand by the Bears for a 26 million dollar annual profit guarantee backed by city taxes, 12/5/1995Daley responds to criticism from the Bears that he is hampering negotiations by going public all the time with comments on various issues, 12/12/1995Daley says he is not going to get into a bidding war with an Indiana stadium group, 12/13/1995Daley says everyone realizes we can no longer fund public schools out of the property tax, 12/14/1995Daley says he is very disappointed over the corrupt conduct exposed in the Federal Government's "Operation Silver Shovel" investigation, 1/10/1996Daley acknowledges that his Inspector General does not have the resources the Government has to root out corruption, 1/11/1996Daley raps the Illinois Supreme Court for striking down the City's anti-loitering ordinance and for saying membership in a street gang was not illegal, 1/17/1996Daley comments on the indictment of the former Dean of the City Council Anthony Laurino on ghost payrolling and obstruction of justice charges, 1/17/1996Daley accuses the Republican majority on a U.S. Senate Committee probing Whitewater of trying to make a political football out of Hillary Clinton, 1/17/1996Daley says that the City of Chicago is not going to bear the cost of a McCaskey dome for the Bears, 1/17/1996Daley defends the request his Administration is submitting to the Federal Court asking for relaxation of a consent decree limiting police spying on groups and individuals, 1/18/1996Daley says there has to be a regional tax for the "McCaskey Dome," 1/18/1996Daley talks about school reform, 1/19/1996Daley comments that there are more important issues that the Whitewater scandal, 1/19/1996Daley talks about the corruption in the school system, 1/23/1996Daley says the Bears have not really killed his Soldier Field renovation plan because they have yet to send him a letter saying so, 2/5/1996Daley talks about his disappointment over the Urban League entering into an agreement with 21st Century Vote (a gang-linked group) to promote voter registration in light of all the good things the League has done, 2/20/1996tape side #9, Time: 23:02CD 95148Scope and ContentsAt a news conference, Daley announces his meeting with Governor Edgar about a domed stadium plan for the Bears, 3/2/1996Mayor Daley and Governor Edgar talk to the media after their meeting on a domed stadium for the Bears, 3/8/1996Daley reacts to Governor Edgar's proposal for a referendum on a tax swap for public schools, 3/21/1996Daley explains why he thinks the Democratic National Convention should be altered so that one of the four days is set aside just for entertainment, 3/26/1996Daley criticizes President Clinton's executive order "One Strike and You're Out" (out of public housing), 3/28/1996Daley praises Commerce Secretary Ron Brown after his death in a plane crash, 4/3/1996Daley denies that the "Operation Silver Shovel" federal corruption investigation will give the City a negative reputation, 4/17/1996Daley says he does not agree with critics who say corruption in the City Council has become institutionalized, 4/19/1996Daley talks about how he cannot vouch for the integrity of everyone in the City Council or in City Government, 4/23/1996Daley talks about the conflict of interest CTA Chief Robert Belcaster got into when he purchased stock in a company doing business with the CTA, 5/6/1996At a news conference, Daley complains the School Board has been allowing too many exemptions under its residency policy and that it must change, 5/6/1996Daley defends his unveiling of a massive plan to tear down high rises at Cabrini Green, 6/27/1996Daley talks about the Clinton White House's choice to request FBI background files on people from the Reagan and Bush administrations, 6/29/1996Daley defends the lottery system the City set up for protest groups to use set aside areas for demonstrations during the upcoming Democratic National Convention in Chicago, 7/18/1996Daley reacts to the "Operation Silver Shovel" indictment of Alderman Jessie Evans, 7/16/1996Daley says the Democrats should adopt a platform that gives everyone a "piece of the action" at the National Convention, 6/11/1996Daley urges the news media to give full coverage to convention protest groups during the Democratic National Convention, 7/30/1996Daley understands that there are some groups planning protests during the Democratic Convention who will try to provoke the police, 8/2/1996Daley says he will need to work 24 hours a day during the National Convention, 8/23/1996At a news conference, Daley talks about how the media blamed his father for the riots during the 1968 Democratic National Convention, 8/25/1996Daley talks about the successful Democratic Convention, 8/30/1996Daley backs President Clinton's controversial signing of the welfare reform bill crafted mostly by conservative republicans, 8/20/1996Daley talks about trying to get local businesses around the city to clean up their properties, 8/20/1996Daley says it is a complete lie that he used his clout with the Clinton Administration to get the FAA to not oppose the closing of Meigs Field, 9/26/1996
Daley speaks to Rotary Club members, 9/24/1996Daley says he favors elimination of commemorative holidays from the school calendar, 9/25/1996Daley mocks plans for a fundraiser for O.J. Simpson, 9/25/1996Daley says the media should stop speculating about secret agendas for his proposed park at Meigs Field, 9/30/1996Daley talks about the growing court fight over Meigs Field, 10/2/1996Daley mocks Governor Edgar's attempt to attract private funding for a third airport near Peotone, 10/10/1996Daley comments on the press who was leaking information about city employees who were not paying back parking tickets, taxes, and water bills), 10/23/1996 and 10/24/1996Daley presents city employees with an ultimatum to pay off their city debts, 10/30/1996Daley mocks the threatened Republican takeover of Meigs Field, 11/18/1996Daley mocks talk of a tradeoff with the Republicans (in Springfield) in the Meigs Field controversy to end the feud, 11/21/1996Daley insists that at the end of the five year deal with Governor Edgar on Meigs Field, the facility will become a park, 1/6/1997Daley rips the GOP majorities in the Illinois Senate and House for passing a bill that brings straight ticker voting to an end in Illinois, 1/8/1997Daley appoints the City's first ever domestic violence coordinator, 1/12/1997Daley talks about the police corruption scandal in the Austin District, 1/14/1997 and 2/7/1997Daley says it is time for the City Council to start considering some of the reforms he has recommended and to undertake serious reforms in the wake of more scandal, 2/25/1997Daley talks about his overnight stay in the White House Lincoln bedroom, 2/26/1997Daley rips State Police Director Terry Gainer for suggesting a rise in serious accidents on area expressways can be traced to too much drinking at "Taste of Chicago" and other city festivals, 2/26/1997Daley says he is not opposed to nepotism on City Council committees so long as the relatives of the alderman involved do the work, 2/26/1997Daley defends his decision to extend medical benefits to the live-in partners of gay and lesbian city employees, 2/27/1997Daley mocks members of the CHA police force at Cabrini Green for fleeing the scene during a shooting spree at the housing project, 3/1/1997Daley defends his decision to ask a federal judge to relax a consent decree imposing tough spying limits on the Police Department, 3/7/1997Daley talks about the three white teenagers who allegedly beat up a 13-year old black youth in his native Bridgeport, 3/25/1997Daley says he is excited about the way the Police Department uncovered corruption in the Austin District and two other police districts, 3/18/1997tape side #10, Time: 14:05CD 105149Scope and ContentsDaley talks about the ethics law reform, 6/18/1997Daley says the major political parties just cannot dictate the slating of candidates anymore, 8/21/1997Daley says he will not endorse candidates, 8/22/1997Daley talks about policemen, 10/1/1997Daley says he is very upset and mad over the revelations about his City Council floor leader Pat Huels concerning alleged conflicts of interest, 10/16/1997, 10/21/1997, and 10/27/1997Daley talks about the fact that when you are a public official, you really have few real friends, 10/30/1997Daley insists he is not a king (despite his power), 11/4/1997The Webb Commission unveils its report recommending reforms after police scandals, 11/6/1997Daley rips Linda Tripp for taping her telephone conversations with Monica Lewinsky without Monica's knowledge, 1/23/1998Daley gets emotional as he denies the charge of Tribune columnist John Kass that he referred to the Italian Queen of the St. Patrick's Day parade as a "dego," 3/31/1998Daley defends his decision to give a demoted hack a good paying job at O'Hare Airport, 7/17/1998Daley talks about Clinton's affair with Monica Lewinsky, 9/10/1998Daley defends the City's anti-gang loitering law, 12/9/1998Daley says the City Council ought to vote up or down on pay raises for members, not give the job to commissions, 12/2/1998Daley says that the city has an uphill fight against street gangs, 11/17/1998Daley announces a major lawsuit against the gun industry, 11/12/1998Daley explains during the blizzard of 1999 why city cannot plow side streets, 1/5/1999Daley defends expansion plans at O'Hare, 2/4/1999Daley criticizes the high costs of the Ken Starr investigation into Whitewater and the Clinton-Lewinsky affair, 2/8/1999Daley speaks on his campaign trail as he seeks reelection, 2/11/1999Daley responds sarcastically to demands that he apologize to the families of two young boys who were falsely accused of the murder of 11-year old Ryan Harris, 2/10/1999Daley rejects the notion that he has amassed too much power, 2/22/1999Daley explains why he was able to capture a surprising 45% of the black vote, 2/24/1999
Daley explains why he won the reelection, 2/24/1999Daley defends the power he has been able to build as Mayor, 3/1/1999Daley takes the oath of office for the fourth time, 3/1/1999tape side #11, Time: 15:32CD 115150Scope and ContentsContinuation of Daley taking the oath of office for the fourth time, 3/1/1999Daley defends his crackdown on health and sanitation violations in restaurants, 3/10/1999Daley says there will be no retaliation by City Hall against Marshall Field's for the decision to shut down production of Frango mints and move the operation to Pennsylvania, 3/18/1999Daley defends the five police detectives who investigated the Ryan Harris murder and ended up falsely accusing and charging two young boys, ages seven and eight, 3/18/1999Daley has exchange with reporters about why ComEd Chief John Roe was not present to join in announcing a City-ComEd agreement on upgrading the city's electrical system, 3/23/1999Daley defends the huge 12-billion dollar public works program proposed by Governor Ryan, 5/11/1999Daley says the police department owes a full explanation to the public and to the families of two unarmed black motorists who were shot to death by police after separate chases, 6/15/1999 and 6/16/1999Daley appoints a new 10 member reform board at the Chicago Housing Authority, 6/21/1999Daley defends the 76 million dollar package of taxes, fee, and fines in his year 2000 budget, 10/5/1999Daley denies that his tax laden budget is a sign he is preparing to retire during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 10/15/1999Daley takes a swipe at Clinton housing aide Harold Lucas, 11/4/1999Daley says his Administration's disappointing performance in steering more minority contracts to black-owned firms is a concern to him, 11/17/1999Daley talks about the roots of racist behavior in Chicago firehouses, 11/18/1999Daley scolds five members of the City Council for voting against his appointment of James Joyce as Fire Commissioner, 12/16/1999Daley claims there was a thorough investigation by his Administration into a controversial janitorial contract that was awarded to members of the politically-connected Duff family, 1/4/2000At a news conference, Daley says that he has worked hard to protect his and the city's reputation, 1/10/2000Daley defends his new second version of a gang loitering ordinance, 1/11/2000Daley says he does not object to the U.S. Attorney looking into the questionable contracts his Administration awarded to the politically-connected Duff family, 1/13/2000Daley says he thinks people are tired of politics and just want politicians to get things done, 2/2/2000Daley delivers his State of the City speech to the League of Women Voters, 1/19/2000Daley insists that the new gang loitering law passed by the City Council will be enforced "very, very delicately," 2/3/2000
Daley praises Governor George Ryan for being a doer, not a talker, 2/3/2000Daley says he had nothing to do with the federal investigation that led to City Treasurer Miriam Santos' indictment and conviction, 2/9/2000Daley claims he does not hand out city contracts in exchange for political campaign contributions, 2/17/2000Daley points the finger of responsibility at the supervisors in charge after reports a prostitute was allegedly having sex with firemen in a firehouse on Cumberland Avenue, 3/1/2000Daley says he knows nothing about the prostitute who claims she was servicing a lot of firemen at a lot of Chicago firehouses, 3/2/2000Daley hotly denies his tough health inspections at city restaurants are retaliation because the owners have dared to criticize his policies, 3/8/2000Daley denies that people close to him were working on his orders to try and oust Ed Kelly as the veteran Democratic Committeeman of the 47th Ward, 3/15/2000Daley says he does not want anyone throwing his name out to obtain favors, 3/23/2000Daley tells reporters during a briefing outside of his City Hall Office that he feels much better (after his scare with an attack of high blood pressure), 4/10/2000Daley defends the proposal to put up an honorary street sign on the north side to honor Playboy Magazine founder Hugh Hefner, 4/11/2000Daley insists he has a good relationship with former City Treasurer Miriam Santos, 4/17/2000Daley comments on his daughter Nora's wedding, 4/20/2000tape side #12, Time: 6:01CD 125151Scope and ContentsDaley says he knows nothing about election fraud in the Florida presidential battle between Al Gore and George Bush, 11/9/2000Daley defends his controversial plan to renovate Soldier Field at a cost of 583 million dollars, 1/9/2001Daley denies telling his Public Schools CEO Paul Vallas he should run for governor, 1/10/2001Daley blasts President Clinton's decision to pardon fugitive financier Marc Rich after his ex-wife donated millions to Clinton's campaigns, 1/23/2001Daley discusses the need to wipe some old ordinances off the books, 1/24/2001Daley says he thinks Bill Clinton was a great president but says he really left many of his biggest supporters disappointed, 1/24/2001Daley again questions a proposed third airport near Peotone, 2/6/2001Daley criticizes President Clinton's decision to pardon a California drug dealer whose family donated millions to the Democratic Party, 2/13/2001Daley says he will not give up trying to get the Illinois General Assembly to pass stronger gun control legislation, 2/8/2001Daley says he wants his school reform team leaders to try new ideas to improve the reading skills of the kids, 3/1/2001Daley defends contract cronyism at O'Hare Airport, 3/20/2001Daley praises his outgoing public schools CEO Paul Vallas after six years heading up his reform effort, 6/7/2001Daley says he is resigned to the need for extensive public hearings on his O'Hare expansion plan, 6/31/2001Daley says George Ryan has been a very good Governor, 7/11/2001Daley responds to a question about whether he fears closer scrutiny of the Daley family is his brother Bill decided to run for Governor, 8/28/2001Daley says there is no way he would ever run for Governor, 8/30/2001Daley talks about the tough security precautions his Administration put in place after the 9-11 terrorist attacks on the World Trade Center in New York, 9/13/2001Daley supports the FAA in keeping Meigs Field closed, 9/19/2001Daley abandons his support for a plan that would have allowed the Bears to sell naming rights to Soldier Field as part of a huge renovation project, 10/1/2001Daley responds to complaints about the City's new emergency preparedness, 10/2/2001Daley calls for a halt to the long debate over who won the state of Florida in that last presidential contest, 11/12/2001Politicians and Other FiguresSeries 74063tape side #1, Time: 25:30CD 15260Scope and ContentsGeorge Hagopian (30th Ward Alderman) replies to the heated debate on Mayor Jane Byrne's ward remap plan, 11/9/1981John Marcin (35th Ward Alderman) asks if the Byrne remap plan is the Mayor's way of telling the Polish voters "to hell with them," 11/9/1981Charles Swibel (Jack of all trades advisor and political fixer for several mayors) openly admits the City library system is political and always has been during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 9/24/1981Lawrence Bloom (5th Ward Alderman) sharply denounces Mayor Byrne's ward remap plan charging the neighborhoods would get shafted to create political fiefdoms, 11/13/1981John Marcin (35th Ward Alderman) denounces Mayor Byrne's ward remap plan, 11/13/1981John Marcin (35th Ward Alderman) attacks other aldermen for being willing to let mayor Byrne dictate to them while she is drunk with power, 11/13/1981Ed Vrdolyak (Alderman) defends Mayor Byrne's ward remap plan, 11/13/1981Martin Oberman (43rd Ward Alderman) rips Mayor Byrne's remap plan as dictatorship, 11/13/1981Martin Oberman (43rd Ward Alderman) points out that Byrne was abandoning her promise to end Machine control of Chicago, 11/13/1981Martin Oberman (43rd Ward Alderman) attacks the major pay raises for city executives proposed by Mayor Byrne, 12/18/1981Lawrence Bloom (5th Ward Alderman) attacks the pay raises for city executives proposed by Mayor Byrne, 12/18/1981John Marcin (35th Ward Alderman) asks since when does the Mayor have the right to hand out goodies to her loyalists when it is the taxpayer's money she is using, 12/18/1981Aldermen Terry Gabinki and Martin Oberman get into a heated argument typical of the years when Jane Byrne was Mayor, 2/10/1982Martin Oberman (43rd Ward Alderman) fired criticism at Mayor Byrne for making what he considered dictatorial rulings from the Chair, 2/10/1982Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) voices support for Mayor Byrne's new handgun control ordinance on the day the Council passes the measure, 3/19/1982Marian Humes (8th Ward) calls Mayor Byrne's legislation a "con game," 3/19/1982Martin Oberman (43rd Ward Alderman) speaks out in defense of Mayor Byrne's proposed handgun control legislation, 3/19/1982Timothy Evans (4th Ward Alderman) speaks in support of Mayor Byrne's handgun control legislation, 3/19/1982Richard Mell (33rd Ward Alderman) speaks out against the handgun proposal, 3/19/1982Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman) says he reserves the right to change his endorsement of Mayor Byrne to somebody else later in the next mayoral election, 3/25/1982Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman) says all the grand jury investigations into his affairs have not been funny or nice but that it happens to all politicians, 3/25/1982Vito Marzullo (25th Ward Alderman) defends the gifts of money and valuables that were accepted by Governor Jim Thompson, 4/30/1982Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) denounces People's Gas for ripping off consumers while people can't pay their bills, 5/5/1982William Griffin (former top aide to Mayor Byrne) defends the 98 thousand dollar sweetheart contract his consulting firm got to improve public relations in the City Health Department, 5/20/1982Rob Warden (editor of the Chicago Lawyer publication) criticizes Mayor Byrne for having fought the release of her transition papers, UndatedCharles Swibel (Jack of all trades advisor to several mayors) defends his refusal to quite his post as Chairman of the Chicago Housing Authority, 6/22/1982Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Cook County Democratic Party Chairman) responds to Alderman Alan Streetor's charge that Mayor Byrne is offering money for votes to try and defeat him in the 17th ward aldermanic runoff election, 6/28/1982Don Rose (well-known consultant to political independents) talks about Mayor Byrne's chances of being reelected as being grim, UndatedHarry Fink (a political unknown who sought the endorsement of the Cook Country Democratic Party for Mayor) tells regular Democrats during Party slatemaking hearings that should be slated as the Party candidate for Mayor, 11/23/1982Sheila Jones (member of the Socialist Workers Party) seeks the endorsement of the Party for Mayor, 11/23/1982Vito Marzullo (25th Ward Alderman and boss of the Ward he has headed for years) calls for loyalty and unity behind the Mayor, 11/23/1982
Robert Shaw (Alderman and outspoken member of the City Council's black caucus) reveals at Democratic Party slatemaking hearings that he is endorsing Mayor Byrne for reelection, 11/23/1982Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) endorses Mayor Jane Byrne for reelection and calls for her slating by the Party, 11/23/1982George Dunne (Cook County Board President) says it is ironic Mayor Byrne is out to get him because when he was Democratic Party Chairman he once blocked an effort by ward bosses to get her during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 12/16/1982Martin Oberman (43rd Ward Alderman) talks to reporters after winning a rare victory in the courts in which the Court of Appeals ruled he had a right to see the Hay Study on higher pay for city executives and Mayor Byrne's contingency fund expenditures, 1/13/1983Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) blasts Adlai Stevenson III for charging as he endorsed Richard M. Daley for Mayor that Mayor Byrne's top fund raiser Charles Swibel had offered him substantial campaign funds is he would endorse Byrne, 2/7/1983Adlai Stevenson III (Illinois U.S. Senator) endorses Richard M. Daley for Mayor, 2/7/1983Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) praises members of the Democratic Machine and says they are where it's at, 2/16/1983Ed Quigley (City of Chicago Sewer Commissioner and the rough, tough, long time boss of the west side 27th Ward) denies in the face of years of strong evidence that vote fraud exists in his ward, 3/2/1983Bob Healey (President of the Chicago Teachers Union) takes a witty shot at Republican mayoral candidate Bernard Epton and Epton's call for a freeze on teacher salaries, 3/9/1983Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) takes note of reports Mayor Byrne is going to become a TV commentator when she leaves office, 4/13/1983Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) battles with Mayor Harold Washington for control of the City Council, 5/6/1983tape side #2, Time: 26:08CD 25261Scope and ContentsMarian Volini (38th Ward Alderman) appeals for reason and compromise as the only member of the Washington camp to attend the session, 5/6/1983Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) blasts Mayor Washington for abruptly gaveling to adjournment a 5/2/1983 meeting, 5/6/1983Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) calls on Mayor Washington to "come on here" and he says the City Council has to get together, 5/6/1983Terry Gabinski (32nd Ward Alderman) voices frustration over the fact that the political warfare between his block ("Vrdolyak 29") and the "Washington 24" over control of the Council has resulted in no business being done, 5/11/1983William Henry (West Side Alderman) says he has seen Daley, Bilandic, and Byrne all sit in the Mayor's chair and have requests be respected, 5/11/1983Timothy Evans (4th Ward Alderman) denounces the attempts of the "Vrdolyak 29" to conduct City Council business against Mayor Washington's wish for a recess, 5/11/1983Mayor Washington/Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) tangle over a parliamentary ruling in a scene typical of the wrangling that marked the early feud between the new Washington Administration and old guard Democrats in the "Vrdolyak 29," 5/11/1983Mayor Washington/Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) clash over parliamentary procedure, 5/11/1983Mayor Washington/ Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) Washington threatens to clean the City Council chambers if members of the "Vrdolyak 29" do not sit down and be quiet, 5/11/1983Mayor Washington says to loud cheers: "Mr. Vrdolyak, I've never run from anybody, including you, in my life," 5/11/1983Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) answers Mayor Washington's remark about never running from anybody, 5/11/1983Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) denies that the actions of his forces in putting through their own system of committees in the City Council was a conspiracy to deny Council blacks their equal voice, 6/22/1983Roman Pucinski (41st Alderman) accuses blacks in the "Washington 21" block of walking out on Council reorganization, 6/22/1983Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) calls the Mayor anti-Catholic and says he is either ignorant or stupid, 6/24/1983Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) takes a low shot at Mayor Washington's opposition to allowing increased class sizes as part of cuts at the School Board to prevent a property tax increase, 6/24/1983Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) responds to the statement by Mayor Washington that he ought to be dumped as Party Chairman, 8/10/1983Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) critiques Mayor Washington's first 100 days in office, UndatedEd Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) says during the taping of WBBM's "At Issue" program that the "Vrdolyak 29" agree there should be more layoffs in the 1984 budget, 9/30/1983Burton Natarus (42nd Ward Alderman) speaks in support of his resolution calling for a study to determine if a bulletproof shield should be installed in the Council Chambers to protest aldermen, 9/28/1983Martin Oberman (43rd Ward Alderman) looks over at Alderman Bernard Stone and says, "If you'll shut up Bernie we can have some order," 9/28/1983Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman), Mayor Washington, Martin Oberman (43rd Ward Alderman) This passage features an angry floor fight between the "Vrdolyak 29" and "Washington 21" forces over budget reform, 9/28/1983Bernard Stone(50th Ward Alderman)goes after Deputy School Superintendent for Finance Harry Strasberg during City Council Finance Committee hearings on the School Board's property tax levy, 10/11/1983Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Cook County Democratic Party Chairman) explodes in fury at a Council meeting over Mayor Washington's veto of a new soccer field in his ward, 10/20/1983Richard Mell (33rd Ward Alderman) says that he was once a rubber stamp in the Council and that there is nothing wrong with admitting it, 10/20/1983Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Cook County Democratic Party Chairman) issues a veiled warning to Mayor Washington that his veto of a soccer field in his ward is going to bring retaliation against Washington supporters on projects in their wards, 10/20/1983Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) denounces Mayor Washington's chief political advisor Clarence McClain, 11/30/1983Timothy Evans (4th Ward Alderman) denounces the Party ticket put together by the County Democratic Party and which gave Mayor Washington's supporters only token participation, 11/28/1983Burton Natarus (42nd Ward Alderman) defends video games as the City Council prepares to pass tougher licensing controls on game rooms, 1/11/1984Richard Mell (33rd Ward Alderman) takes a swipe at independent alderman David Orr for opposing an ordinance applying stricter controls over billboard and sign advertising in the City, 1/20/1984Terry Gabinski (32nd Ward Alderman) calls Alderman David Orr "a creep" for implying that he was putting in the fix for big outdoor advertising firms, 1/20/1984Roman Pucinski (41st Ward Alderman) speaks out against a proposed borrowing plan involving a Japanese bank, Mitsubishi, 2/22/1984George Hagopian (30th Ward Alderman) voices dislike for the borrowing plan involving the Japanese bank, 2/22/1984Mayor Washington/Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) The Mayor warns the City Council he will no longer tolerate personal attacks, 2/24/1984George Hagopian (30th Ward Alderman) rants and raves against the failure of Chicago banks to want to try and outbid a Japanese bank in a City borrowing plan, 2/24/1984Anna Langford (16th Ward Alderman) denounces the "Vrdolyak 29" majority for proposing to send the Mayor's borrowing plan back to Committee, 2/24/1984Mayor Washington/Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) A very funny exchange between the two arch rivals at a City Council meeting, 3/8/1984Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) says in a speech after turning back a challenge by Mayor Washington's forces and winning reelection as Party Chairman that he does not give into threats or intimidation, 4/2/1984William Smith (Promoter) says Chicago still suffers from the negative image of being home for the mob, 6/21/1984Bernard Stone (50th Ward Alderman) draws cheering from spectators at a City Council meeting with an attack on the School Board for triggering an increase in property taxes for a bond issue that the Council can do nothing under state law, 12/18/1984Michael Shakman (Attorney and father of the historic court-ordered ban on political hiring and firing) praises a new hiring plan for the City of Chicago, 2/7/1985Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) denies any knowledge of the bugging of a conversation between Mayor Washing and a 3rd Ward Aldermanic candidate, James "Skip" Burrell, 2/20/1985Mayor Washington/Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) both allude to the budding incident at the Mayor's apartment involving 3rd Ward Aldermanic candidate James "Skip" Burrell, 3/20/1985Adlai Stevenson III (U.S. Senator and candidate for Governor of Illinois against incumbent Jim Thompson in 1986) raps Governor Thompson for trying to portray him as a wimp and sap during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 9/25/1985Fred Roti (1st Ward Alderman and reputed political fixer for the Mob) rises to the defense of Chicago Port Authority Executive Gilbert Cataldo, 10/10/1985Jerome Orbach (46th Ward Alderman) speaks in support of a resolution opposed by Mayor Washington that would have the Mayor and Council condemn Minister Louis Farrakhan for his controversial negative remarks about Jews, 11/26/1985Burton Natarus (42nd Ward Alderman) breaks with the Mayor on the Farrakhan resolution during a City Council debate, 11/26/1985Dorothy Tillman (3rd Ward Alderman) speaks against the resolution condemning Farrakhan and calls Alderman Ed Vrdolyak "wickedly great" for proposing a resolution just to embarrass Mayor Washington, 11/26/1985Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) responds to Alderman Tillman, 11/26/1985Sheila Jones (Midwest Director of the Lyndon LaRouche right wing extremist group) announces her candidacy for Mayor and raps Mayor Washington, 3/27/1986Adlai Stevenson III (U.S. Senator and candidate for Governor of Illinois) defends the decision he made to not campaign against the LaRouche extremists in the primary, 4/4/1986Timothy Evans (4th Ward Alderman and Mayor Washington's new City Council floor leader) voices joy over the Mayor finally getting 25 of his 38 stalled appointments approved, 5/9/1986Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman), Timothy Evans (4th Ward Alderman and Mayor Washington's floor leader), Mayor Washington  An exchange between the three leaders at a special session of the City Council as Burke complains about the Washington forces, 5/9/1986Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) says he will stay on as Party Chairman despite party losses that cost his majority block control of the City Council, 5/8/1986William Henry (24th Ward Alderman) raps the Vrdolyak forces for not wanting to support Mayor Washington's tax proposals, 5/14/1986Bernard Stone (50th Ward Alderman) raps Mayor Washington's forces for backing tax increases, 5/14/1986Martin Oberman (43rd Ward Alderman) blasts the Vrdolyak forces for voicing concern about the impact of Mayor Washington's proposed tax increases on "the little guy," 5/14/1986Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) hints at campaign strategy for the 1987 mayoral campaign by referring to Mayor Washington as "the master taxer," 5/14/1986Cardinal Joseph Bernadine (Head of the Chicago Catholic Archdiocese) says at a news conference that while Bingo and Las Vegas nights have recreational plusses they ought to be phased out as sources of church revenue in the parishes that have them, 5/21/1986Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) denounces Mayor Washington and his majority allies in the City Council for pushing through a plan that eliminates nine Council committees and gives the Mayor control of all the rest, 6/6/1986tape side #3, Time: 29:29CD 35262Scope and ContentsJuan Soliz (25th Ward Alderman) raps Mayor Washington for calling him "Vrdolyak's boy," 6/6/1986Ed Kelly (Superintendent of the Chicago Park District) says that if Mayor Washington tries to put him in a corner there's no way he will be humiliated during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 6/20/1986Iola McGowen (member of the Park Board) explains why she is sticking with Superintendent Ed Kelly and not joining Mayor Washington's effort to strip Kelly of his powers, 6/20/1986Corneal Davis (Preacher, former state legislator and member of the Chicago Board of Elections) delivers an impassioned speech against and Election Board ruling declaring a runoff between Luis Gutierrez and Joe Torres in the 26th ward aldermanic election fight, UndatedEd Burke (14th Ward Alderman) rises in a meeting of the City Council Finance Committee to back Committee approval of an amendment to an arbitrator's ruling on a new contract for firefighters, UndatedBernard Stone (50th Ward Alderman) warns the voters will retaliate against Council members who vote for Mayor Washington's historic 80 million dollar property tax hike, 9/24/1986Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) blasts the Mayor's attempt to pass the package of property and gas tax hikes without going to committee first, 9/24/1986Burton Natarus (42nd Ward Alderman) explains why he voted against the property tax hike portion of the plan earlier but then went on to vote for it at this meeting, 9/24/1986Martin Oberman (43rd Ward Alderman) fires back at Alderman Burke's complaints about Mayor Washington not following proper procedures, 9/24/1986Roman Pucinski (41st Ward Alderman) declares that passage of the property tax/gas tax plan will result in people referring to Mayor Washington as "high tax Harold," 9/24/1986Ed Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) loses his cool during a heated exchange on the tax issue, 9/24/1986Bernard Stone (50th Ward Alderman) blasts Washington ally Alderman Luis Gutierrez, 9/24/1986Jesus Garcia (22nd Ward Alderman) raps former Mayor Jane Byrne for taking Spanish lessons to try and get votes in the Latino community during another run for mayor, UndatedTom Sullivan (former U.S. Attorney for the Northern District of Illinois) tells reporters that it is pretty obvious there might well have been real improprieties in City Government, UndatedEd Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) says his campaign for Mayor has been irreparably harmed by charges in the Sun Times that he met twice with mob kingpin Joseph Ferriola presumably to gain political help, UndatedTed Kennedy (U.S. Senator) sings a Hispanic song before a Hispanic campaign audience with Mayor Washington beaming at his side, UndatedEd Burke (14th Ward Alderman) talks about the betrayal of his own allies who defected to Mayor Washington in the fight over City Council reorganization, UndatedArthurene McGee testifying at a City Council committee hearing on a critical city loan to the near bankrupt Chicago Housing Authority, UndatedThis is a natural sound of a band playing "My Kind of Town, Chicago Is," UndatedEd Smith (28th Ward Alderman) speaks in favor of the restoration of bulk garbage pickups in the City, 5/10/1987Burton Natarus (42nd Ward Alderman) speaks out in opposition to a proposal that would severely restrict the operations of mobile sandwich trucks, 6/1987Joy Noven, an angry parent, denounces the continuing Chicago teachers' strike of 1987, UndatedGeorge Hagopian (30th Ward Alderman) denounces school conditions during a City Council Finance Committee hearing on the 698 million dollar school property tax levy, 10/28/1987Richard Mell (33rd Ward Alderman) criticizes Mayor Washington's budget and his plan to hire 1700 more people during a news conference, 10/29/1987Victor Vrdolyak (10th Ward Alderman who succeeded his brother Ed in the post) speaks out against the school property tax levy, 10/30/1987Lawrence Bloom (5th Ward Alderman) breaks with the other members of Mayor Washington's leadership team to oppose the school property tax levy, 10/30/1987Dorothy Tillman (3rd Ward Alderman) chastises some of her colleagues for threatening to vote against the school tax levy for petty reasons, 10/30/1987Burton Natarus (42nd Ward Alderman) says the key to reviving the School Board is accountability, not control, 10/30/1987Edward Burke (14th Ward Alderman) contests the argument by the Washington Administration that the City Council must approve the school property tax levy by law or face a court order to do so, 10/30/1987Robert Shaw (9th Ward Alderman) rants and raves in favor of his proposed legislation to require restrooms in all gas stations that would be available to the general public, 10/28/1987Burton Natarus (42nd Ward Alderman) speaks in favor of restrooms in gas stations, 10/28/1987Anna Langford (16th Ward Alderman) speaks out in opposition to the gas station restroom ordinance, 10/28/1987Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) raps his colleagues for looking so silly debating bathrooms in gas stations when there are more important issues to deal with, 10/28/1987Paul Kendall (President of Citizens United for Baseball in the Sunshine (CUB)) criticizes the Mayor's decision to permit 18 night games at Wrigley Field, UndatedMorgan Finley (Cook County Circuit Court Clerk) proclaims his innocence after being indicted in the U.S. Attorney's "Operation Incubator" probe of political corruption, 11/16/1987
Mike Madigan (Speaker of the Illinois House) explains during a Democratic Party slatemaking meeting why he thinks it would be wrong to slate former Mayor Jane Byrne for Circuit Court Clerk, 11/16/1987Ed Vrdolyak leads up to the official announcement that he is jumping to the Republican Party, 9/16/1987Ernest Jones (20th Ward Alderman) makes a startling assertion during City Council budget hearings that women workers create costly absenteeism because of their monthly periods, 11/23/1987Richard Mell (33rd Ward Alderman) bursts from a caucus meeting to shout that we have a new Mayor meaning Alderman Eugene Sawyer, 12/1/1987Natural sound of the turmoil that surrounded the City Council's marathon meeting to elect a successor to the late Mayor Washington, 12/1/1987Luis Gutierrez (26th Ward Alderman) speaks in behalf of Alderman Timothy Evans (Mayor Washington's floor leader) to the new Acting Mayor, 12/1/1987tape side #4, Time: 33:24CD 45263Scope and ContentsWilliam Henry (24th Ward Alderman) speaks in support of Alderman Eugene Sawyer to be the new Acting Mayor, 12/1/1987Dorothy Tillman (3rd Ward Alderman) speaks in support of Alderman Timothy Evans to be the new Acting Mayor, 12/1/1987Dorothy Tillman (3rd Ward Alderman) gives a speech against the election of Alderman Eugene Sawyer as Acting Mayor by the City Council is put to music, 12/1/1987Jerome Van Gorkum (Managing Director of the Chicago Housing Authority) tells a City Council Committee that a shortage of federal public housing aid is not the fault of the U.S. Dept of Housing and Urban Development, 1/10/1988Patrick O'Connor (40th Ward Alderman) takes the critics of Acting Mayor Eugene Sawyer to task for using a selective memory of the Washington agenda to try and suggest Sawyer is straying from the agenda on the issue of taxicab reform, 1/27/1988Richard Mell (33rd Ward Alderman) charges that the Evans forces were against Acting Mayor Eugene Sawyer's taxi reform plan only because of sour grapes over Alderman Evans losing the battle for Acting Mayor to Sawyer, 1/27/1988Cardinal Joseph Bernadine (Head of the Chicago Catholic Archdiocese) denies that a controversial church statement which appears to condone the use of condoms as a part of an education campaign on AIDS was poorly written during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 1/22/1988William Beavers (7th Ward Alderman) defends the political patronage system, 2/3/1988George Dunne (Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) says that media saturation coverage of the party primaries is turning off the voters, 3/18/1988Paul Kandall (Chairman of CUB) complains that the deal leaves the Wrigleyville neighborhood "screwed," 2/28/1988Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) revives the old Black Sox scandal to support his argument against Mayor Sawyer's compromise plan allowing eight night games in 1988 and 18 thereafter for 15 years, 3/25/1988Bernard Hansen (44th Ward Alderman) rises to oppose the Mayor's compromise on lights at Wrigley Field, 3/25/1988Timothy Evans (4th Ward Alderman) rises to oppose the Mayor's compromise on lights at Wrigley Field, 3/25/1988Irwin Jann (Lawyer for the Tobacco lobby) and Ernest Jones (20th Ward Alderman) Jann calls the proposal for clean indoor air nonsense.  Jann draws the wrath of Alderman Jones, 4/8/1988Ernest Jones (20th Ward Alderman) contends there should be a holiday declared for the late Mayor Harold Washington, 4/14/1988Fred Roti (1st Ward Alderman) gets incensed over Alderman Jones' remark about the holiday for late Mayor Washington, 4/14/1988Ernest Jones (20th Ward Alderman) winds up the argument by saying let us just name one of our own black boys with the kinky hair to an honor, a holiday for Washington, 4/14/1988George Dunne (Cook County Board President and Chairman of the Cook County Democratic Party) rejects Better Government Association charges that he traded jobs for sex with lesbians, 5/1/1988President Ronald Reagan blows Illinois Attorney General Neil Hartigan's name while giving thank yous at the beginning of a speech before the Strategy Forum in Chicago, 5/4/1988Bobby Rush (2nd Ward Alderman) demands that the Art Institute of Chicago take down a student painting that shows the late Mayor Washington in women's underwear, 5/11/1988Anna Langford (16th Ward Alderman) demands that the offensive painting of Harold Washing be taken down, 5/11/1988Jean Mayer (Head of a Coalition pushing a guaranteed home equity plan to protect homeowners in neighborhoods undergoing racial change) rips aldermen for opposing or delaying a vote on the proposal, 5/9/1988Steve Cokely (Administrative aide in the Administration of Mayor Eugene Sawyer) talks on the day he cleaned out his desk and left City Hall after being fired for his anti-Semitic, anti-Christian remarks, 5/6/1988William Beavers (7th Ward Alderman) speaks out in opposition to the proposed new Clean Indoor Air Act which limits smoking in most public places to certain designated areas, 5/25/1988tape side #5, Time: 29:06CD 55264Scope and ContentsDanny Davis (29th Ward Alderman) expresses support for the Clean Indoor Air Act even though he is a smoker, 5/25/1988Ed Smith (28th Ward Alderman) rises to support the Clean Indoor Air Act, 5/25/1988Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) says smoking stinks and he is for ending it, 5/25/1988John Madrzyk (13th Ward Alderman) speaks against the proposal as a confirmed smoker, UndatedAnna Langford (16th Ward Alderman) rips into Vice Mayor David Orr during a debate in which Orr was dumped from his post on a 31 to 15 vote, 5/25/1988William Beavers (7th Ward Alderman) rips into David Orr and says his picture does not belong in the gallery of mayors, 5/25/1988David Orr (49th Ward Alderman) responds to his dumping from the post of Vice Mayor by saying that the Machine is not dead, 5/25/1988Dorothy Tillman (3rd Ward Alderman) speaks out against the proposed home equity guarantee legislation being pushed by a citizens coalition to protect the value of homes in racially changing neighborhoods, 6/8/1988Anna Langford (16th Ward Alderman) says there are already laws on the books to prevent panic peddling and block busting so home equity guarantees are no necessary, 6/8/1988Richard Mell (33rd Ward Alderman) speaks in favor of the proposed home equity ordinance, 6/8/1988Luis Gutierrez (26th Ward Alderman) steps forward as the only Hispanic alderman to support the proposed home equity ordinance, 6/8/1988William Krystyniak (23rd Ward Alderman) rises to support the home equity ordinance, UndatedMichael Sheahan (19th Ward Alderman) says City Controller Ronald Picur should be fired for failing to reach an earlier agreement with city pension funds on paying medical benefits of city retirees, 6/30/1988George Hagopian (30th Ward Alderman) speaks out against a Human Rights ordinance which calls for a ban on discrimination against gays and lesbians/ 9/14/1988Burton Natarus (42nd Ward Alderman) speaks in support of the proposed Human Rights ordinance, 9/14/1988William Beavers (7th Ward Alderman) is an opponent of gay rights who says during the City Council debate that God made Adam and Eve, not Adam and Steve, 9/14/1988Anna Langford (16th Ward Alderman) blasts mayoral candidates Ed Burke and Lawrence Bloom for urging no vote on the school property tax levy, 10/26/1988Lawrence Bloom (5th Ward Alderman) blasts rival candidate and Alderman Timothy Evans for riding the late Mayor Washington's coattails during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 11/23/1988Ernest Jones (20th Ward Alderman) objects to passage of a resolution that urges aldermen to quit questioning committee witnesses about race, religion, ethnicity, gender, etc., 11/16/1988Richard M. Daley (Cook County State's Attorney) says he will give back any campaign contribution over 1500 dollars from any lawyer or law firm that has done business with his office, 1/5/1989Richard M. Daley (Cook County State's Attorney) and Avis Lavelle (Campaign Press Secretary) This passage demonstrates how Lavelle would break off questions from reporters to Daley when they started to get into sensitive, controversial subjects, 1/5/1989Avis Lavelle (Campaign Press Secretary for Daley) moves in to protect State's Attorney Daley from too much questioning during the campaign of 1989, 1/4/1989Ed Smith (28th Ward Alderman) triggers an outburst when he refuses to accept the plum of a City Council committee chairmanship being offered to him by Mayor Eugene Sawyer in a shakeup of Council committees, 7/13/1988Terry Gabinski (32nd Ward Alderman), Ed Smith (28th Ward Alderman) Alderman Gabinski somewhat sarcastically congratulates Alderman Smith for a very kind gesture in allowing someone else to have the chairmanship he turned down, 7/13/1988During the City Council meeting, pandemonium breaks out as spectators and aldermen argue back and forth on the merits of the power play by Mayor Eugene Sawyer, 7/13/1988Robert Shaw (9th Ward Alderman) gets so confused in the midst of all the confusion that he forgets what ward alderman Terry Gabinski is from, 7/13/1988Timothy Evans (4th Ward Alderman) warns that Mayor Sawyer's power play marks the sunset of the short Sawyer reign, 7/13/1988Danny Davis (29th Ward Alderman) says he cannot wait for February 28th to come so he can help vote Mayor Sawyer out, 7/13/1988Total confusion reigns in the City Council as aldermen nearly come to blows over Mayor Sawyer's reorganization shakeup, 7/13/1988Bobby Rush (2nd Ward Alderman) accuses Mayor Sawyer of letting himself be buffaloed and led down a primrose path by enemies of the late Mayor Washington, 7/13/1988William Henry (24th Ward Alderman) defends Mayor Sawyer's reorganization shakeup of committees, 7/13/1988Dorothy Tillman (3rd Ward Alderman) rises to protest the loss of her committee chairmanship, 7/13/1988Danny Davis (29th Ward Alderman) says the shakeup was an evil sinister plot, 7/13/1988Edwin Eisendrath (43rd Ward Alderman) rips into the granting of an O'Hare Airport concession contract to Martha Tucker, a black resident of Mayor Sawyer's home ward, 1/18/1989Luis Gutierrez (26th Ward Alderman) says the way the O'Hare concession contract was granted to a minority in his case made a sham out of the process, 1/18/1989Luis Gutierrez (26TH Ward Alderman) and William Henry (24th Ward Alderman) get into an argument over the O'Hare concession contract the Mayor awarded to a member of his own ward, 1/18/1989Anna Langford (16th Ward Alderman) rips into Alderman Gutierrez, accusing him of being a hypocrite because he was a former supporter of Washington, 1/18/1989Ernest Jones (20th Ward Alderman) supports the award of the contract to a member of Mayor Sawyer's ward, 1/18/1989Burton Natarus (42nd Ward Alderman) tried to immediately bury ethics reform legislation in a subcommittee, 2/8/1989David Orr (49th Ward Alderman) finally gets the floor after much trying to talk about the proposed reforms, 2/8/1989David Orr (49th Ward Alderman) and Burton Natarus (42nd Ward Alderman) get into an exchange over a move to bury ethics reform legislation in a subcommittee, 2/8/1989Gus Savage (Chicago Congressman) brands Cook County State's Attorney Richard M. Daley as a born and bred racist, 2/18/1989George Hagopian (30th Ward Alderman) says is any military personnel put the American flag on the floor like the Art Institute they would have been shot for treason and would have deserved it, 3/8/1989William Krystyniak (23rd Ward Alderman) says the decision of the Art Institute to allow the exhibit (with the flag on the floor) is an insult, 3/8/1989Terry Gabinski (32nd Ward Alderman) speaks in favor of landmark City Council legislation which for the first time would require aldermen to disclose any interest they have in a zoning matter under consideration, 3/8/1989Burton Natarus (42nd Ward Alderman) attacks Alderman David Orr for demanding an amendment which would prevent any Council member from acquiring an interest in a matter that was approved by the Council for three years after that approval, 3/8/1989George Hagopian (30th Ward Alderman) refers to the Art Institute board members as "goodie two shoes" for defending a flag on the floor exhibit, 3/16/1989Danny Davis (29th Ward Alderman) shows off his eloquence as he speaks of the importance of the flag as a symbol of hope for a better nation, 3/16/1989Ed Vrdolyak (Republican candidate for Mayor) predicts that Richard Daley will refuse to take part in campaign debates, 3/10/1989Raymond Figueroa (31st Ward Alderman) blasts many of his colleagues who praised outgoing Mayor Eugene Sawyer at his last City Council meeting, 3/29/1989Ed Smith (28th Ward Alderman) opposes a 16% increase in water rated recommended by the newly elected Mayor Richard M. Daley, 4/26/1989tape side #6, Time: 25:18CD 65265Scope and ContentsTimothy Evans (4th Ward Alderman) rises to oppose Mayor Daley's committee reorganization plan, 4/26/1989Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) tries to set the tone for the new Richard M. Daley Administration, 4/26/1989Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) says Mayor Daley should get a janitor down to mop up all the tears as the Council prepares to approve a cut of more than a million dollars in spending for committees, 5/10/1989David Orr (49th Ward Alderman) responds to a complaint that a provision in the legislation which bars employees in six department from engaging in political activity is overly harsh, 5/10/1989Robert Shaw (9th Ward Alderman) objects to a key provision in the proposed new ethics law charges, 5/10/1989Luis Gutierrez (26th Ward Alderman) supports the changes in ethics laws and say that the decision of Mayor Daley to push the tough new provisions successfully refutes the claims of Daley's campaign opponents that he would try to turn back the clock, 5/10/1989Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) agrees in the Council debate on tougher ethics reforms that some of the provisions are unreasonable, 5/10/1989George Dunne (President of the Cook County Board of Commissioners) and Carl Hansen (veteran suburban Republican member of the Board) Dunne tells Hansen to "shut up" during a heated debate on the affiliation plan between County, University of Illinois, and Michael Reese hospitals, 6/27/1989
Fred Roti (1st Ward Alderman) responds to the discovery of a secret FBI camera which was found hidden under a seat cushion at Counselor's Row Restaurant and trained on the corner table where Roti, his friends, and first was political bosses sit and dine, 6/30/1989Timothy Evans (4th Ward Alderman) calls the 25 million dollar property tax rollback Mayor Daley is promising in his 1990 budget shortsighted and politically inspired, 7/19/1989Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) tried to blame rising property taxes on the Washington Administration at its allies, 7/19/1989Ed Smith (28th Ward Alderman) says the truth is that both the old Machine forces and those loyal to Washington voted for property tax increases, 7/19/1989Robert Shaw (9th Ward Alderman) opposes giving an Inspector General the power to probe aldermen and says he objects to proponents suggesting aldermen are the only crooks in town, UndatedSharon Sharp (Illinois Lottery Director) defends the state sponsored lottery games in the face of criticism that they encourage more illegal gambling and corrupt public morals, 8/22/1989Dorothy Tillman (3rd Ward Alderman) agrees with a resolution to hold public hearings on alleged police brutality, 9/13/1989Danny Davis (29th Ward Alderman) says the problem of police brutality goes much deeper than just a few cops, 9/13/1989Keith Caldwell (8th Ward Alderman) says he favors bringing back the "rack and pillory" to punish cops who engage in brutality against any citizens, 9/13/1989Anna Langford (16th Ward Alderman) claims brutality declined under Mayor Washington but now it is open season on "niggers" again, 9/13/1989Jim Thompson (Illinois Governor) refuses to accept any responsibility for bringing about property tax relief, 8/14/1989Harry Carey (Cubs baseball announcer) displays the great play-by-play skills Harry brought to the microphone and it also shows the great enthusiasm he had for the game, UndatedKeith Caldwell (8th Ward Alderman) says the public perception is that every guy in blue cannot be trusted to not use excessive force, 10/4/1989Burton Natarus (42nd Ward Alderman) says all the indictments of previous aldermen proves the current system works well as it is, 10/4/1989Raymond Figueroa (31st Ward Alderman) supports giving the Inspector General (IG) the power to investigate aldermen, 10/4/1989Danny Davis (29th Ward Alderman) opposes giving the IG the power to investigate aldermen saying he resents the implication that somehow all aldermen are a bunch of crooks, 10/4/1989Ernest Jones (20th Ward Alderman) opposes allowing the IG to investigate aldermen because of a fear that power would be abused, 10/4/1989John Pakk (Citizen) claims while testifying that he was a victim of police brutality, 9/28/1989Leroy Martin (Chicago Police Superintendent) defends his decision to defend Mayor Daley on the way he has handled police brutality, 10/10/1989
Ed Smith (28th Ward Alderman) and Lemuel Austin (34th Ward Alderman) Smith gets into a heated exchange with Austin (Chairman of the City Council's Budget Committee) after Austin accused him of failing to show up for a hearing he had asked for on garbage collection problems in his ward, 10/26/1989Bob Martin (Head of Chicago's Gang Intervention Program) says the recruitment techniques of street gangs have improved, 10/24/1989William Shaw (9th Ward Democratic Committeeman) says we just have to teach white folks a lesson at the close of Democratic Party slatemaking where the Party's Executive Committee chose a slate for Cook County elections which upset blacks, 12/16/1989Sheila Jones (A disciple of right wing extremist leader Lyndon LaRouche) says we are going to take to the streets and the State Election Board better get down on its knees and pray to God, 1/24/1990Rick Garcia (Leader of an organization of gay Catholics) blasts Mayor Daley's plan to give gays and other special interest groups more of a voice by putting them under the City Human Relations Commission, 1/19/1990Mary McDonald (Suburban Republican member of the Cook County Board) calls rival Democratic commissioner John Stroger " a pimple on the fundament of mankind" for suggesting she wasn't sincere about wanting to help the poor receive proper trauma care (At Cook County Hospital), 1/16/1990Jim Edgar (Illinois Governor) says he could support an increase in the state income tax, if the money were used to provide property tax relief, 1/19/1990Jim O'Grady (Cook County Sheriff) delivers a statement saying he does not believe disclosures of a mob boss on tapes played in federal court, 2/9/1990Jim Dvorak (Cook County Republican Party Chairman) denies the boasts of a mob figure that he made payoff of 10 thousand dollar a month to Dvorak to protect gambling operations while Dvorak was Undersheriff, 2/9/1990William Banks (36th Ward Alderman) defends the decision to put State Representative James De'leo on his City Council Zoning Committee payroll, 1/29/1990Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) notes that once before the Health Department was run by a non-doctor under Richard J. Daley because the Commissioner at the time, Murray Brown, was a chain smoker who liked to drink a lot, 3/21/1990tape side #7, Time: 26:14CD 75266Scope and ContentsLuis Gutierrez (26th Ward Alderman) defends Lourdes Monteagudo, Mayor Daley's Deputy for Education, in the face of demands that she be called to account at a hearing on her remark that not one Chicago high school was good enough for her daughter to attend, 4/6/1990Glenn Carr (City of Chicago Personnel Director) defends Mayor Daley's record on hiring minorities, 4/11/1990Burton Natarus (42nd Ward Alderman) says it is getting a little absurd the way people are trying to outdo each other on reform, 6/27/1990Robert Shaw (9th Ward Alderman) protests the refusal of the Council to pass tough new sanctions against South Africa, 6/27/1990Dorothy Tillman (3rd Ward Alderman) says the refusal to pass tough sanctions on South Africa is an insult to black America and Mandella should not come here because Chicago is not ready for him, 6/27/1990
Marlene Carter (15th Ward Alderman) accuses the Council of playing parliamentary games with the lives of millions of South Africans by refusing to pass tough sanctions, 6/27/1990Timothy Evans (4th Ward Alderman) and Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) tangle during a meeting of the City Council's Finance Committee, 7/28/1990Larry Gorski (Mayor Daley's advisor on the disabled) says the new Americans With Disabilities Act will actually save taxpayers money, not cost them more, 7/25/1990Lemuel Austin (34th Ward Alderman) delivers a stirring defense on Mayor Daley's legislation to set aside a certain percentage of city contracts for minorities in the face of an effort by a black colleague, 7/31/1990Clarence Wood (Director of the Commission on Human Relations) gets testy and says the problem of racial tension starts right in the Mayor's press conference room with a predominately white media that does not know how to report a power blackout on the west side with sensitivity, 7/30/1990Lemuel Austin (34th Ward Alderman and Chairman of the City Council's Budget Committee) angrily strikes back at a fellow African American colleague, Alderman Robert Shaw, 10/28/1990Bill Henry (24th Ward Alderman) files his nomination petitions on the last day he again makes the charge that federal indictment against him was timed to destroy him as a black political leader, 12/17/1990Jane Byrne (former Mayor of Chicago) chides Mayor Daley for his refusal to engage in campaign debates, 12/14/1991Fred Roti (1st Ward Alderman) reacts to the federal criminal indictment returned against him, 12/19/1990Jane Byrne (former Mayor of Chicago) announces her candidacy for Mayor again in the Democratic Primary, facing off against Mayor Richard M. Daley, 11/12/1990Tom Cullerton (38th Ward Alderman) offers unusual praise for Republican Governor Jim Thompson during ceremonies honoring Thompson for his record 14-years of service, 1/11/1991Jim Thompson (Governor of Illinois) reflects on his love of Chicago as a kid who grew up on the city's west side, 1/11/1991Dick Phelan (Cook County Board President) presides over his first Board meeting, a stormy affair in which he makes frequent use of the gavel as he tries to gain control and prevent a hostile coalition from filling key committee chairmanships with its own people, 12/10/1990John Stroger (Chairman of the Cook County Board's Finance Committee) pointedly advises Phelan that Board members have to have respect for each other, 12/10/1990Dick Phelan (Cook County Board President) and John Stroger (Chairman of the Board Finance Committee) have an argument, 12/10/1990Dick Phelan (Cook County Board President) says he is bitterly disappointed over the failure of the Democratic majority to back his own reorganization plan, 12/10/1990John Stroger (Chairman of the Cook County Board's Finance Committee) responds to the complaint from President Phelan that the Democratic majority on this Board has let him down, 12/10/1990Dick Phelan (Cook County Board President) responds to John Stroger's speech with one of his own in which he charges that the three Democrats who joined the Republican minority on the Board to block his reform organization plan indicates to him that Stroger is not interested in reform, 12/10/1990Demonstration.  This is one of the several street protests which took place over the decision of the Bush Administration to launch the Persian Gulf War against Iraq, 1/15/1991tape side #8, Time: 27:55CD 85267Scope and ContentsDemonstration.  A couple of supporters and opponents of the Persian Gulf War get into a face to face heated debate over the wisdom of the war with Iraq, 1/15/1991Franklin Brandon (Marine deserter) asks when are we going to learn that wars like the ones in Vietnam and Iraq do not work, 1/15/1991Bill Davis (National Coordinator for Vietnam Veteran Against the War) says the fact that poor young people are once again being asked to sacrifice is what he calls particularly appalling, 1/15/1991Irene Dolan (Chicago resident) says she is just sick at the decision to go to war, 1/15/1991Vietnam War veteran criticizes the anti-war protests in the Daley Plaza, 1/15/1991Danny Davis (former Alderman, former County Board member and at this moment a candidate for mayor of Chicago) tries to get media attention for his campaign by taking part in the protest against the Persian Gulf War, 1/15/1991Dick Phelan (President of the Cook County Board) contends in this frank statement that his first budget is good, 1/22/1991Jane Byrne (former Mayor and now running for mayor again) complains about being called a political spoiler saying it's sexist during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 2/15/1991Lemuel Austin (34th Ward Alderman) reacts to his very close victory for reelection after nearly paying the price for his endorsement of Mayor Daley, 2/24/1991Dan Quayle (Vice President of the United States) tries to knock down the notion that President Bush might dump him from the '92 ticket in favor of General Colin Powell, 3/13/1991Phil Rock (President of the Illinois State Senate) sings Irish songs in the State of Illinois Center lobby on St. Patrick's Day with Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) is at the piano, 3/16/1991Patrick Huels (11th Ward Alderman) defends the Daley Administration's switch on how to get aldermen to attend committee meetings from a tough approach of not allowing passage of any matter that didn't pass with a quorum to simply making attendance records public, 3/20/1991Fred Roti (Former 1st Ward Alderman) reacts to the charges that 37 1st Ward sanitation workers were loafing and filing false time sheets by saying that as far as he is concerned they always did the job, 3/25/1991Eugene Pincham (Candidate for mayor) says distorted Democratic Party priorities and the way they shortchange the poor is going to enhance criminal behavior among the have-nots during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 3/28/1991Timothy Evans (4th Ward Alderman) says he wants his rivals to know that when he opposed them it was based on principles, not on personalities during farewell remarks at his last City Council meeting, 4/12/1991Anna Langford (16th Ward Alderman) talks about the days when she and Marylou Hedlund were elected as the first women members of the Council during farewell remarks at her last City Council meeting, 4/12/1991
Roman Pucinski (41st Ward Alderman) talks about the old days as a reporter covering City Hall in his farewell remarks after being defeated for reelection, 4/12/1991Ricky Hendon (27th Ward Alderman) speaks in support of his package of measures to curb street sex, especially in the west side ward, 6/12/1991John Steele (6th Ward Alderman) criticizes a Daley Administration plan to grant a multi-million dollar break to the politically corrected bus firm that has exclusive rights to shuttle people between O'Hare and downtown, 6/12/1991Ed Smith (28th Ward Alderman) blasts the consultant hired by the Daley Administration for saying that Com Ed's transmission system was highly reliable despite major blackouts the previous summer, 6/18/1991Burton Natarus (42nd Ward Alderman) talks with City Controller Walter Knorr on the quality of Chicago's water as part of an effort to justify the rate increase Mayor Daley proposed, 6/26/1991William Beavers (7th Ward Alderman) gets into a testy exchange with Barbara Silvestre of the Chicago Lung Association over a proposed amendment to a law banning cigarette vending machines in all places but taverns which would also ban remote controlled machines, 6/26/1991Robert Shaw (9th Ward Alderman) tells the story of how he was propositioned on the way to work by three prostitutes during a meeting of the City Council's Police Committee on legislation to toughen penalties for street prostitution, 7/11/1991Ed Smith (28th Ward Alderman) complains that those who are not allies of the Daley Administration are going to be wiped out in a remap of city wards if the Daley majority in the Council does not agree to fair rules to guide the process, 8/9/1991Richard Mell (33rd Ward Alderman) says the complaining by critics and suspicions by Mayor Daley allegedly has a secret map of redrawn wards are symptoms of a deeper concern which is political survival, 8/9/1991Miriam Santos (City Treasurer) says people in the Daley Administration have to understand she is going to run an efficient, effective office and no one will stand in her way, 11/7/1991John Madrzyk (13 Ward Alderman) and Rickey Hendon (27th Ward Alderman) get into a heated exchange at a City Council Budget Committee hearing on Mayor Daley's "Bad New Budget," 11/13/1991Bernard Stone (50th Ward Alderman) denounces the Mayor's Human Relations Commission Director Clarence Wood, 11/15/1991Richard Phelan (President of the Cook County Board) rips the former administration of George Dunne for running County Government like a general store, 10/22/1991tape side #9, Time: 25:01CD 95268Scope and ContentsRickey Hendon (27th Ward Alderman) denounces the new franchise agreement the Daley Administration reached with Commonwealth Edison for its failure to provide bill relief, 11/20/1991Tim Degnan (Mayor Daley's Patronage Chief) defends himself against charges by City Treasurer Miriam Santos that he and two other Daley aides ordered her to grease the skids for Administration allies seeking lucrative pension loan deals, 11/26/1991Ed Bedore (Mayor Daley's Chief Financial Officer) defends himself in the Santos case, 11/26/1991Frank Kruesi (Mayor Daley's Top Policy Advisor) says he is still at a loss to explain why City Treasurer Miriam Santos think he, Tim Degnan, and Ed Bedore are interfering in the operations of her office, 11/26/1991Rickey Hendon (27th Ward Alderman) complains at a City Council meeting about an effort by the Daley forces to head off adding an amendment to the City's new franchise deal with Commonwealth Edison, 11/27/1991Lemuel Austin (34th Ward Alderman) argues against the affirmative action amendment on contracts to the City's franchise deal with Commonwealth Edison, 11/27/1991William Beavers (7th Ward Alderman) objects to the unions putting heat on him to back off on the Commonwealth Edison amendment, 11/27/1991Robert Shaw (9th Ward Alderman) protests the effort of the Daley forces to pass their version of a ward remap plan, 10/28/1991Rickey Hendon (27th Ward Alderman) tells the Mayor that by trying to push through his version of a ward remap plan he is forcing blacks who want to be moderates and compromise to be radicals again, 10/28/1991Bobby Rush (2nd Ward Alderman) says if the Mayor's ward remap plan was really an "equity" map it would not be passing with 24 white votes, only two black votes, and no Hispanic votes, 10/28/1991Lawrence Bloom (5th Ward Alderman) blasts the Mayor for breaking his own promise to be fair to all in the ward remap process, 10/28/1991Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) makes the point that a soft drink tax to replace 74 million dollars in lost franchise fees from the City's deal with Commonwealth Edison would not work, 10/30/1991Ed Smith (28th Ward Alderman) says there needs to be a crackdown on violent crime, 9/11/1991Dorothy Tillam (3rd Ward Alderman) blasts the attempt by Mayor Daley's majority forces to remove a tough affirmative action amendment from the City's franchise agreement with Com Ed after the company rejected it, 12/11/1991Rickey Hendon (27th Ward Alderman) blasts women aldermen who voted to strike the affirmative action amendment requiring Edison to give 30% of all business to companies owned by minorities and women, 12/11/1991Lawrence Bloom (5th Ward Alderman) raps the Mayor for turning his back on his own minority set aside ordinance by wanting to exempt Edison from it, 12/11/1991Ed Smith (28th Ward Alderman) encourages aldermen to not "trapudate" their responsibility, 12/11/1991Robert Shaw (9th Ward Alderman) says a vote to remove the affirmative action amendment from the agreement would be like the time Jefferson Davis tried to recruit blacks to fight for the Confederacy, 12/11/1991Patrick O'Connor (Alderman and Chairman of the Council's Education Committee) says if the schools are not improved Chicago will have a population of uneducated, uncivilized young people who cannot get a job, 11/11/1991Matt Rodriguez (Chicago Police Superintendent) says that the Rodney King riots in Los Angeles were part of a problem that has been festering for a long time, 5/7/1992Richard Phelan (Cook County Board President) defends his proposed countywide sales tax saying he does not enjoy doing it, that no politician in his right mind enjoys it, 5/4/1992Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) tells about the advice an embattled Superintendent once gave to his successor during the City Council's meeting to confirm Matt Rodriquez as the new Police Supt, 5/20/1992Gus Savage (2nd District Chicago Congressman) explains why he thinks Jews are calling him anti-Semitic, 3/11/1992Avis Lavelle (Mayor Daley's Press Secretary) tells how she feels as she departs her job to reportedly become press spokesperson for Democratic Presidential candidate, Governor Bill Clinton of Arkansas, 6/4/1992Matt Rodriquez (Chicago Police Superintendent) defends his decision to use a measured response in dealing with the looters and troublemakers during the celebration that followed the Bulls second straight NBA championship, 6/15/1992John Steele (6th Ward Alderman) questions how well Mayor Daley's proposed anti-loitering law will work, 6/17/1992Robert Shaw (9th Ward Alderman) says if the anti-loitering ordinance passes it will cause havoc in the city because some cops will surely abuse it, 6/17/1992William Banks (36th Ward Alderman) defends the anti-loitering proposal saying it is time to consider the rights of the many, not the rights of the few, 6/17/1992Dorothy Tillam (3rd Ward Alderman) charges that the anti-loitering measure is an attempt to put another law on the books to harass black and Hispanics, 6/17/1992Ed Smith (28th Ward Alderman) rises to support the anti-loitering proposal in a shark break with his black colleagues in the Council, 6/17/1992Lemuel Austin (34th Ward Alderman) decries the parents who let their kids sell drugs because it helps pay the rent, 6/17/1992Shirley Coleman (16th Ward Alderman) rises to complain during the City Council's debate on the proposed anti-loitering law, 6/17/1992Charles Gamble (Retired Captain in the Chicago Fire Department) testifies that for years the Fire Department has been sweeping racial discrimination problems under the rug, 7/24/1992Richard Mell (33rd Ward Alderman) says that his colleagues are a bunch of hypocrites for proposing a resolution denouncing Cincinnati Reds owner Marge Schott for the same kind of racial and ethnic slurs that they utter behind the scenes, 12/9/1992Burton Natarus (42nd Ward Alderman) says something has to be done about all the nasty bicycle messengers in the loop who do not obey the laws, 7/7/1992Bobby Rush (2nd Ward Alderman) defends an anti-crime measure in the face of constitutional questions being raised by some colleagues, 7/7/1992Matt Rodriquez (Chicago Police Superintendent) talks about the police reforms recommended by the consulting firm of Booze-Allen, 7/22/1992Richard Phelan (President of the Cook County Board) says the attacks against him for ordering resumption of abortions at County Hospital have not been easy to stomach, but he says his conscience is clear, 9/18/1992Jim Edgar (Governor of Illinois) talks about the heart problem that doctors discovered and which led to him undergoing an angioplasty procedure to reopen clogged arteries near his heart, 10/16/1992James Laski (23rd Ward Alderman) explains how he was kicked out of the 23rd ward Democratic organization by his ward boss, Congressman Bill Lipinski, for refusing to support Mayor Daley's controversial proposed property tax increase, 2/5/1993Richard Phelan (Cook County Board President) denies charges he is steering lucrative bond issue business to campaign contributors, 4/12/1993Jim Edgar (Governor of Illinois) tells reporters he would not oppose a statewide referendum on land based casino gambling even though he is personally opposed to the idea, 4/9/1993John Steele (6th Ward Alderman) blasts Mayor Daley's proposal to put a cap on property taxes in Chicago, 3/8/1993Joe Moore (49th Ward Alderman) blasts the proposed tax cap measure as being as phony as a three dollar bill, 3/8/1993Jim Edgar (Governor of Illinois) tells reporters he is not anti-Chicago any more than Mayor Daley is anti-Illinois, 3/12/1993Jim Edgar (Governor of Illinois) sums up his attitude on bailing out Chicago's public schools, 4/27/1993Michael Madigan (Speaker of the Illinois House) tells reporters he thinks that floating casinos in Chicago are only a matter of time, 4/30/1993Thomas Scorza (Former Assistant U.S. Attorney in Chicago) tells members of the City Council's Rules Committee he is withdrawing as Mayor Daley's choice for interim City Clerk, 7/12/1993Richard Munoz (22nd Ward Alderman) defends a new group called 21st Century Vote, whose membership is loaded with known gangbangers, for trying to get into the political arena, Undatedtape side #10, Time: 28:32CD 105269Scope and ContentsDexter Watson (27th Ward Alderman) says there is no way he will vote to remove city sanctions on companies doing business with South Africa, UndatedCardinal Joseph Bernadine (Head of the Chicago Catholic Archdiocese) responds to demands for radial church reform by saying he has managed to provide much more involvement within the framework of a church hierarchy which, as everyone knows, is not a democracy, 11/9/1993Gary LaPielle (Chairman of the Illinois State Democratic Party) says the Party has to face reality and realize that endorsement do not mean what they used to, 11/30/1994Paul Simon (Illinois U.S. Senator) says he is concerned that promises by the major networks to cut back on TV violence will not be kept in the long run, 12/17/1994Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) speaks in favor of a highly controversial City Council resolution extending bereavement leave (3 days) to "domestic partners," 12/15/1993Brian Doherty (41st Ward Alderman) attacks the bereavement resolution, 12/15/1993
Dan Rostenkowski (5th District Chicago Congressman and Chairman of the House Ways and Means Committee) claims that the wife of his ally, Alderman Terri Gabinski, was not a ghost payroller, 2/15/1994Alan Streeter (17th Ward Alderman) criticizes the refusal of the Council to pay the legal fees for him and other aldermen who got sued after they tore down an offensive painting of Harold Washington at the Art Institute, 2/22/1994Dorothy Tillman (3rd Ward Alderman) denounces the Council for refusing to pay her legal fees, 2/22/1994Bobby Rush (Chicago Congressman) defends his role when he was an alderman in tearing down the unflattering painting of Harold Washington, 2/22/1994George Clements (Catholic priest respected for his involvement in the inner city and its problems) criticizes the ACLU for its opposition to police sweeps at Chicago Housing Authority buildings to flush out weapons, 3/31/1994Harvey Grossman (Legal Director of the ACLU) defends his organization's opposition to police weapons sweeps of CHA apartments without warrants, 3/31/1994George Clements (Catholic priest respected for his involvement in the inner city and its problems) defends his one church, one addict program in the face of questions that working with a state funded agency violates the separation of church and state doctrine, 5/23/1994Jim Edgar (Governor of Illinois) speaks to the issue of whether the threatened end to Congressman Dan Rostenkowski's reign as powerful House Ways and Means Committee Chairman could hurt the State's legislative agenda, 5/25/1994John Stroger (Chairman of the Cook County Board's Finance Committee) says that the gangs must be prevented from infiltrating the political process, 1/14/1994Dexter Watson (27th Ward Alderman) and Lorraine Dixon (8th Ward Alderman) This is a sequence of a fight between Dexter Watson and Ted Mazola (1st Ward Alderman) with Lorraine Dixon, who was presiding as President ProTem, demanding for order, 4/13/1994Jim Edgar (Governor of Illinois) defends allowing his state trooper bodyguards to cut the grass at his log cabin home in Sherman, Illinois near Springfield, 6/9/1994Jim Edgar (Governor of Illinois) insists Lieutenant Governor Bob Kustra was not pushed out, 6/28/1994Michael Madigan (Democratic Speaker of the Illinois House) says the complaints that Mayor Daley's lobbying effort in Springfield have left a lot to be desired are off base, 7/8/1994Bob Kustra (Illinois GOP Lieutenant Governor) defends his flip-flop decision to drop plans to resign and become a talk show host after Governor Edgar underwent heart bypass surgery, 7/18/1994Lawrence Bloom (5th Ward Alderman) attacks a Daley Administration plan to funnel 45 thousand dollars in job funds to a group (21st Century Vote) that is linked to a major street gang, 8/2/1994Shirley Coleman (16th Ward Alderman) defends jobs money being funneled to 21st Century Vote, even though her ward covers the gang infested high crime area of Englewood, 8/3/1994Anthony Laurino (39th Ward Alderman) delivers a long farewell speech in the City Council talking about how he always proudly delivered his ward for Mayor Daley's father and how he always fought a good fight, 8/4/1994Tom Harris (Spokesman for 21st Century Vote) denies that his organization is political in nature, 8/3/1994
David Wilhelm (National Democratic Party Chairman) makes the official announcement that Chicago has been chosen to hose the 1996 Democratic National Convention, 8/4/1994Matt Rodriquez (Chicago Police Superintendent) says the mistakes made by police during the '68 convention will not be repeated, 8/5/1994tape side #11, Time: 23:04CD 115270Scope and ContentsRickey Hendon (Democratic State Senator from Chicago) complains that Mayor Daley will just put a bunch of negro yes men on as oversight panel to supervise the awarding of contracts and jobs to minorities at the 1996 Democratic National Convention, 8/17/1994Jim Edgar (Governor of Illinois) tells reporters he is feeling great and that his recuperation is on schedule after his heart bypass surgery, 8/18/1994Mel Reynolds (Democratic Congressman from Chicago's 2nd District) denies all the charges in a 20 count indictment against him that accuses him of having sex with a minor, 8/22/1994John Buchanan (10th Ward Alderman) accuses Inspector General Alexander Vrstouris to his face of being a sham because he has exceeded the authority given to his office, 10/21/1994Bobby Rush (Democratic Congressman from Chicago's 1st District) blasts the Mayor for being a non-education mayor, 11/1/1994Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) predicts that neither Joe Gardner nor Roland Burris will stand a chance against Mayor Daley in the 1995 city elections during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 12/4/1994Dawn Clark Netsch (Democratic candidate for Governor of Illinois) claims during a speech to a senior citizens group that Edgar is secretly planning to increase taxes on food and medicine to make up for a huge budget deficit, 10/14/1994Jim Edgar (Governor of Illinois) says during his campaign for reelection that he is not ready to raise any taxes "at this time," 9/30/1994Dawn Clark Netsch (Democratic candidate for Governor of Illinois) claims that the Governor's plan to deal with skyrocketing Medicaid costs is coming unraveled and we are left with a huge gap in the budget, 10/3/1994Jim Edgar (Governor of Illinois) insists the State is not going to run out of money in March, despite a big Medicaid deficit, 10/3/1994Dawn Clark Netsch (Democratic candidate for Governor of Illinois) says she is personally opposed to the death penalty, 9/13/1994Jim Edgar (Governor of Illinois) details his most effective campaign strategy against his Democratic opponent, 9/22/1994Penny Severns (Democratic candidate for Lt. Governor of Illinois) criticizes Governor Jim Edgar's record on crime, 9/22/1994Jim Edgar (Governor of Illinois) rejects the complaint of his Democratic opponent that his portrayal of her as soft on crime is an insult to women, 9/23/1994Ed Smith (28th Ward Alderman) speaks in support of Mayor Daley's budget plan, 11/16/1994John Stroger (New President of the Cook County Board) thanks Mayor Daley for putting his winning campaign on track during his inauguration address as the new County Board President, 12/5/1994John Daley (New Chairman of the Cook County Board's Finance Committee) defends his role as the new Chairman amid questions it puts too much power into the hands of the Daleys again, 12/5/1994Dawn Clark Netsch (former candidate for Governor of Illinois) tells reporters she was the only candidate in the last Governor's race who was brave enough to talk frankly about a need for higher taxes to fund education properly, 1/5/1995Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) claims he and his top aide knew nothing about a ghost payroller on his City Council Finance Committee staff, 2/6/1995Larry Horist (the bitter loser of the Republican primary race for mayor of Chicago) says Mayor Daley is a fine guy but is a captive of an ancient political machine, 1/18/1995Dexter Watson (27th Ward Alderman) blasts Mayor Daley during a City Council budget debate, 11/18/1994John Stroger (President of the Cook County Board) accepts responsibility for the hiring of a lawyer of his staff who turned out to be somebody who had been disbarred, 1/3/1994Roland Burris (Independent candidate for mayor of Chicago) puts the blame on Mayor Daley for the Democrats losing control of both the Illinois House and Senate in the 1994 elections, 3/10/1995James "Pate" Philip (President of the Illinois Senate) takes issue with the contention of Democrats that Chicago was treated unfairly when a decision was made to allow riverboat gambling in Illinois during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 4/7/1995Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) calls Mayor Daley's agreement with the city of Gary, Indiana for another airport a plan of unique and historic proportions that may trigger legal challenges all the way to the U.S. Supreme Court, 4/15/1995William Beavers (7th Ward Alderman) attacks Illinois Republican Senate President James "Pate" Philip for backing legislation to have the State take over control of O'Hare airport, 4/15/1995Robert Shaw (9th Ward Alderman) claims that Illinois Republican State Senate President James "Pate" Philip is trying to "neuter" Chicago with an attempted takeover of O'Hare airport, 4/15/1995Bernard Stone (50th Ward Alderman) says he is not about to be thrown into economic slavery by "the Pharaoh of Wooddale" (James "Pate" Philip), 4/15/1995John Buchanan (10th Ward Alderman) accuses Illinois State Senate President James "Pate" Philip of engaging in a power grab, 4/15/1995Ted Mazola (1st Ward Alderman) rises to support the other item on the agenda, a pay hike for aldermen and other elected officials, including the Mayor, 4/15/1995Dexter Watson (27th Ward Alderman) calls the proposed pay raise for aldermen a disgrace, 4/15/1995Billy Ocasio (26th Ward Alderman) says he cannot accept the pay raise for himself when the average income in his ward is only 23 thousand dollars a year, 4/15/1995Dorothy Tillman (3rd Ward Alderman) says she does not hide her face as an alderman, 4/15/1995James "Pate" Philip (President of the Illinois Senate) mocks Mayor Daley's lack of clout in the Illinois General Assembly during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 4/7/1995
Jim Edgar (Governor of Illinois) warns that Mayor Daley's unilateral airport alliance with the city of Gary, Indiana, undermines the trust and confidence needed to strike deals on airport issues, 4/21/1995Michael Madigan (Democratic Speaker of the Illinois House) denounces a Republican bill that gives Mayor Daley more power over the public schools in Chicago but no money to carry out reforms, 5/16/1995Bill Clinton (President of the United States) calls for a broader ban on lethal types of ammunition, 6/30/1995John Stroger (President of the Cook County Board) responds to a new law passed by the State Legislature which makes the race for Chicago Mayor a nonpartisan contest, 7/7/1995Jim Edgar (Governor of Illinois) defends placing his signature on a bill turning mayoral elections in Chicago into nonpartisan contests, 7/7/1995Jim Thompson (former Governor of Illinois) says he's often been accused of having an "edifice complex" but he just thinks it is important that great cities have symbols of their greatness during the dedication of the renovated Navy Pier, 7/12/1995Daniel Alvarez (Chicago Commissioner of Human Services) says one of the big reasons so many elderly people dies was that they neglect themselves, 7/17/1995Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) defends Mayor Daley's ties to a family involved in the development of a housing project, 8/2/1995Gery Chico (President of Mayor Daley's Reform Board of Education) explains why he called the current level of academic achievement in Chicago's high schools "baloney," 9/21/1995tape side #12, Time: 23:14CD 125271Scope and ContentsLynn St. James (Chief Education Officer for the Chicago Board of Education) takes the middle ground in the controversy over a decision to start testing children at the kindergarten level, 9/21/1995Paul Vallas (Chief Executive Officer of the Chicago Public Schools) says his office is no longer going to wait till "hell freezes over" to deal with the problem situations in the schools, 9/21/1995Ed Smith (28th Ward Alderman) calls on the City Council to impose a transaction tax on the major currency exchanges to offset a property tax increase, even though such a move would be illegal, 10/12/1995Mike McCaskey (President for the Chicago Bears) says he thinks his grandfather, George Hallas, would have advised him to go for a better deal elsewhere in he could not get a satisfactory one to keep the Bears in Chicago, 10/25/1995John Buchanan (10th Ward Alderman) says something stinks about the attempt of a politically connected cable TV firm, 21st Century, to win a franchise with the City of Chicago, 10/26/1995Matt Rodriquez (Chicago Police Superintendent) says the Police Department is trying to set a proper tone for the 1996 Democratic National Convention during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 11/4/1995Burton Natarus (42nd Ward Alderman) says one of the most important causes of rats in the City is dog feces, 11/15/1995Virgil Jones (15th Ward Alderman) reveals the FBI interrogated him during the U.S. Attorney's Operation Silver Shovel investigation of City Council corruption, 1/8/1996William Beavers (7th Ward Alderman) tells reporters he has no idea who John Christopher (the FBI undercover mole in the Operation Silver Shovel probe of City Council corruption) is and says he never met with him, 1/8/1996Sam Burrell (29th Ward Alderman) reveals he had lunch with FBI undercover mole John Christopher back in 1991, 1/8/1996Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) cautions that just because somebody is named as a target in the probe does not mean they are guilty, 1/8/1996
Patrick Huels (11th Ward Alderman and Mayor Daley's City Council Floor Leader) contends the U.S. Attorney's Operation Silver Shovel investigation of Council corruption will not cripple city government, 1/9/1996Lorraine Dixon (8th Ward Alderman) concedes that City Council corruption makes it very hard for the City Council to be taken seriously, 1/9/1996John Steele (6th Ward Alderman) says that the appearance of more corruption in the City Council pains him greatly, 1/9/1996William Banks (36th Ward Alderman) says there is no need to expand the powers of the Inspector General so the IB could investigate City Council corruption, 1/9/1996Bernard Stone (50th Ward Alderman) opposes expanding the powers of the Inspector General to include the authority to investigate City Council members, 1/9/1996Joseph Moore (49th Ward Alderman) says the best way to restore some semblance of public trust in the office of alderman is to allow the City's Inspector General to investigate charges of misconduct by City Council members, 1/9/1996Jessie Evans (21st Ward Alderman) says is at a crossroads in his career where decisions have to be made during the Operation Silver Shovel corruption investigation, 1/9/1996Percy Giles (37th Ward Alderman) insists he has done nothing wrong even though he is a target in the federal Operation Silver Shovel corruption investigation, 1/9/1996James Laski (Chicago City Clerk) laments to being identified as a target in the federal investigation of ghost payrolling after all the publicity his records being subpoenaed were given, 1/10/1996Ricardo Munoz (22nd Ward Alderman) admits that he got a campaign contribution from one of the companies that was being run by John Christopher, 1/10/1996Ray Suarez (31st Ward Alderman) says what angers him about the federal Operation Silver Shovel probe of City Council corruption is the way the government used undercover moles to "entrap" aldermen, 1/10/1996Ambrosio Medrano (25th Ward Alderman) talks with reporters the day after he entered a guilty plea to taking bribes in the federal Operation Silver Shovel case, 1/11/1996Miguel Santiago (Democratic member of the Illinois House) repeatedly refuses to comment on his involvement in the federal ghost payrolling investigation, 1/19/1996William Lipinski (Democratic Congressman from the 3rd District) says he thinks the Clinton White House handled the whole Whitewater investigation extremely poorly during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 1/26/1996Raymond Frias (12th Ward Alderman) says he will not comment on the Operation Silver Shovel investigation, 2/4/1996Luis Gutierrez (Democratic Congressman for Chicago's 4th District) responds to reports he might be a target in the federal Operation Silver Shovel corruption investigation, 2/4/1996Henry Hyde (Illinois suburban Republican Congressman and Chairman of the House Judiciary Committee) says there is always a danger of a political backlash when a special prosecutor calls the First Lady before a Federal Grand Jury as Kenneth Starr did with Hillary Clinton in the Whitewater investigation, 2/2/1996Jim Edgar (Governor of Illinois) proposes a domed stadium for the Bears, 2/8/1996Jim Compton (President of the Chicago Urban League) defends a League decision to join 21st Century Vote (a group police said had links to street gangs) in a voter registration effort, 2/14/1996Jim Edgar (Governor of Illinois) endorses a study commission plan for a public referendum on a constitutional amendment to alter the way public schools are funded and which would lead to an increase in the state income tax, 3/21/1996William Beavers (7th Ward Alderman) says it was a violation of political manners for Alderman Alan Streeter to wear a wire and rat on his City Council colleagues in the federal Operation Silver Shovel probe of corruption in the Council, 4/18/1996Michael Flager (Pastor of St. Sabina Catholic Parish and known for his activist involvement in a variety of community issues) criticizes the snitching by some aldermen on one another in the Operation Silver Shovel corruption investigation, 4/18/1996Bernard Stone (50th Ward Alderman) says with reference to some aldermen wearing a wire to catch other aldermen in the Operation Silver Shovel corruption investigation that everyone has got to do what they think is right, 4/18/1996Richard Mell (33rd Ward Alderman) reacts to the U.S. Attorney's office having his ethics statement subpoenaed in connection with the Operation Silver Shovel corruption investigation, 4/17/1996Eugene Schulter (47th Ward Alderman) says the bad thing about having his ethics statement subpoenaed by the government in the Operation Silver Shovel corruption investigation is the impact on your family, 4/17/1996John Buchanan (10th Ward Alderman) says he does not mind the Government issuing a subpoena for his ethics statement, 4/17/1996Jim Burns (U.S. Attorney for the Northern District of Illinois) admits there have been some leaks of information in the two federal investigations into City Council corruption and ghost payrolling in local governments, 4/24/1996Bernard Stone (50th Ward Alderman) calls the Mayor's argument that he needs subpoena power in the prosecution of misdemeanor offenses against the City a "pile of crap," 7/1/1996Jim Edgar (Governor of Illinois) says the Republican Party's nominee to be, Senator Bob Dole, should be given the kind of platform he wants at the GOP National Convention, 6/14/1996Rev. Jessie Jackson (Head of Operation Push) attacks General Colin Powell for taking advantage of Democratic civil rights gains, then joining the Republicans who would tear them down, 6/27/1996Jim Edgar (Governor of Illinois) says he is amazed President Clinton refuses to come right out and say he is going to pardon his friends who were convicted in the Whitewater scandal, 10/9/1996James Laski (Chicago City Clerk) says the Daley Administration knew it had a scofflaw scandal on its hands 10 days before it leaked out, 10/23/1996John Buchanan (10th Ward Alderman) denounces the proposal by Mayor Daley to eliminate Good Friday as an official City holiday, 1/8/1997Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) defends the decision of Mayor Daley's City Council majority block to retain the law firm of Jenner and Block as its lawyer in the City Council ward remap case, 2/25/1997John Daley (Cook County Board Finance Committee Chairman) defends the Board's selection of attorney James Houlihan to replace Tom Hynes as County Assessor even though he was a vocal critic of the late Mayor Richard J. Daley, 3/18/1997Rev. Hyram Crawford (Firebrand Black Minister) responds to the hearing on Mayor Daley's plan to extend health benefits to the live-in partners of gay and lesbian city workers, 3/19/1997Brian Doherty (41st Ward Alderman) speaks out against the move to extend health benefits to the live-in partners of gay and lesbian city workers saying the legislation does not meet the criteria for fostering the public welfare, 3/19/1997Thomas Murphy (18th Ward Alderman) speaks out in strong opposition to the gay and lesbian live-in partner health benefit extension, 3/19/1997Dorothy Tillman (3rd Ward Alderman) opposes the gay and lesbian live-in partner health benefit extension, 3/19/1997Ed Smith (28th Ward Alderman) opposes the gay and lesbian benefits extension, 3/29/1997Carol Moseley Braun (first black woman member of the U.S. Senate) says she does not know why there were so many stories about problems with her campaign fund and the Federal Election Commission investigation, 4/7/1997Henry Hyde (6th District Republican Congressman from Illinois and Chairman of the House Judiciary Committee) complains about cafeteria Catholics who sample only what they want from the Church during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 4/11/1997Ed Burke (14th Ward Alderman) says he is withdrawing from litigation in which his clients challenge the City budget and tax levies he helped pass because on conflict of interest questions raised by the media, 5/29/1997tape side #13, Time: 25:41CD 135272Scope and ContentsEd Burke (14th Ward Alderman) says he is withdrawing from litigation in which his clients challenge the City budget and tax levies he helped pass because on conflict of interest questions raised by the media, 5/29/1997Thomas Murphy (18th Ward Alderman) criticizes Alderman Ed Burke, 6/11/1997Francis George (Archbishop and new Head of the Chicago Catholic Archdiocese) says that from time to time he will speak out on issues of moral important by he will not try to tell aldermen (and the Mayor) how to run the city, 4/16/1997Jim Edgar (Governor of Illinois) says he feels very comfortable with the plan he proposed on school funding reform during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 6/15/1997Richard Mell (33rd Ward Alderman) sketches out the high points of the ethics reforms that Mayor Daley and most aldermen agreed to pass in the wake of the Council corruption scandal, 6/18/1997Robert Shaw (9th Ward Alderman) objects to passage of a package of tough ethics reforms, 6/20/1997Dorothy Tillman (3rd Ward Alderman) claims the Council is being held hostage by reform, 6/20/1997Sam Burrell (29th Ward Alderman) says he has a hard time coming to grips with voting ethics reforms, 6/20/1997John Buchanan (10th Ward Alderman) opposes the ethics reform package, 6/20/1997Joe Moore (49th Ward Alderman) supports the package of ethics reform, 6/20/1997Jim Edgar (Governor of Illinois) talks about his decision to retire at the end of his second term during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 8/21/1997Jessie Evans (21st Ward Alderman) tells reporters it is his firm belief a discovery (investigation) should take place to determine the possibility of ethical misconduct by prosecutors in his case, 9/7/1997Jim Ryan (Illinois Attorney General) says that after careful consideration he has decided not to run for the U.S. Senate, 9/9/1997John Buchanan (10th Ward Alderman) says the latest City Council scandal that prompted the resignation of 11th Ward Alderman Patrick Huels is going to put all Council members in a glasshouse and he says we deserve to be in it, 10/21/1997Tom Allen (38th Ward Alderman) talks about the ethics reform package, 10/29/1997Dan Webb (former U.S. Attorney in Chicago and Chairman of the Webb Commission on Police Corruption) announces the Commission's recommendations for Police Department reforms, 11/6/1997Terry Hillard (Chicago Police Superintendent) talks after Mayor Daley announces him as the new Superintendent, 2/18/1998Dorothy Tillman (3rd Ward Alderman) criticizes an audience of taxi drivers for not serving the black community, 12/10/1997Ed Smith (28th Ward Alderman) criticizes a group of firemen at a firehouse party who were caught on video tape making racist remarks, 1/14/1998Virgil Jones (15th Ward Alderman) says the firehouse video tape shows a certain mindset of white supremacy in the Fire Department, 1/14/1998Dan Rostenkowski (Chicago Democratic Congressman and Chairman of the House Ways and Means Committee) admits he violated the law in a statement to reporters after he entered a plea of guilty to corruption charges, UndatedDan Rostenkowski (former Chicago Congressman) says the Government has an awful lot of money when they come after you during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 7/5/1998Glen Poshard (Democratic Congressman from Southern Illinois and the Democratic candidate for Governor of Illinois) complains about being held to an unfair standard by Party liberals who opposed his candidacy, 8/9/1998George Ryan (Illinois Secretary of State and Republican candidate for Governor of Illinois) denies allegations he pressured Secretary of State Employees to contribute to his campaign and that such pressure was at the heart of a licenses for bribes scandal in his office, 10/7/1998Henry Hyde (Illinois GOP Congressman and Chairman of the House Judiciary Committee) says the people hold the ultimate solution to the outcome of impeachment proceedings involving President Clinton, 10/15/1998Helen Shiller (46th Ward Alderman) complains the Council is only taking another baby step for ethics reform, 12/2/1998Bobby Rush (Chicago Congressman) announces his candidacy for Mayor against incumbent Richard M. Daley at a rally of supporters, 11/23/1998Carol Moseley Braun (Democratic U.S. Senator from Illinois and the first black woman to serve in the Senate) gives a speech during her unsuccessful campaign for reelection, 10/27/1998Terry Levin (Spokesman for the City of Chicago's Streets and Sanitation Department) discusses the massive cleanup after a big blizzard in 1999 during an exchange with reporters, 1/5/1999Miriam Santos (Chicago City Treasurer) reads a statement bitterly reacting to her criminal indictment by a Federal Grand Jury on charges of shaking down people who did business with her office for campaign contributions, 1/27/1999Henry Hyde (Illinois GOP Congressman and Chairman of the House Judiciary Committee) reflects on his handling of the impeachment proceedings against President Clinton during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 2/28/1999Henry Hyde (Illinois GOP Congressman and Chairman of the House Judiciary Committee) gives a speech to the City Club of Chicago, 3/22/1999tape side #14, Time: 21:28CD 145273Scope and ContentsHenry Hyde (Illinois GOP Congressman and Chairman of the House Judiciary Committee) gives a speech to the City Club of Chicago, 3/22/1999Janet Williams (Spokesperson for the Chicago Lung Association) defends the right of restaurant patrons to snitch on owners who do not obey health and sanitation regulations, 3/29/1999Jerry Springer (Nationally syndicated talk show host) defends the fighting that frequently breaks out on his program, 6/4/1999George Ryan (Governor of Illinois) denies he broke a no tax increase campaign pledge by supporting higher liquor and vehicle taxes to help pay for his 12 billion dollar public works program, 5/15/1999Terry Hillard (Chicago Police Superintendent) denies he railroaded the cops accused of wrongdoing in two fatal shootings of two unarmed black motorists by saying before the investigation was completed that they had violated Department rules, 6/16/1999A street musician sings his protest against a proposed ordinance imposing more stringent regulations on street musicians because they are allegedly becoming a nuisance, 7/1/1999Rev. Jessie Jackson (Head of the Rainbow Push Coalition) talks about wanting to help the Mayor end abuses in the City's minority contract awarding process, 1/4/2000Miriam Santos (former Chicago City Treasurer) asks where the fairness and equity is in the way women are treated in the justice system at her first news conference since her conviction was overturned and she was released from prison, 2/7/2000George Ryan (Governor of Illinois) says he is angered about the licenses bribes scandal that occurred while he was Secretary of State because the investigation has overshadowed the good things he has done as Governor, 2/7/2000Miriam Santos (former Chicago City Treasurer) This is the incriminating phone conversation the FBI secretly taped between then City Treasurer Santos and a banker who was doing business with the City, UndatedGeorge Ryan (Governor of Illinois) gives his combined State of the State and Budget Address to the Illinois General Assembly, 2/2/2000George Ryan (Governor of Illinois) says he knows reporters have a job to do but that he is just not going to answer any more questions about the licenses for bribes scandal that occurred on his watch as Secretary of State, 2/7/2000Thomas Murphy (18th Ward Alderman) challenges the contention of critics that Mayor Daley's new anti-loitering law is unconstitutional, 2/16/2000Dorothy Tillman (3rd Ward Alderman) speaks out in opposition to Mayor Daley's new version of an anti-loitering ordinance, 2/16/2000Freddrenna Lyle (6th Ward Alderman) speaks out in opposition to Mayor Daley's second version of an anti-loitering ordinance, 2/16/2000George Ryan (Governor of Illinois) explains why he still favors the death penalty even though he made headlines nationwide by ordering a moratorium on executions pending further study after 13 death row inmates were found to be innocent, 3/9/2000John Johnson (Special Agent in Charge of the Chicago Office of the FBI) talks about Operation Silver Shovel's undercover mole John Christopher, 3/17/2000Scott Lassar (U.S. Attorney in Chicago) defends the use of a conman and ex-convict like John Christopher as an undercover mole to catch targets in the act of taking bribes, 3/17/2000George Ryan (Governor of Illinois) explains why he thinks the Secretary of State's office will probably always be plagued with corruption, 4/14/2000Miriam Santos (Chicago City Treasurer) arrives for her first day at work after winning her old job back as City Treasurer when her conviction was overturned, 4/17/2000Carrie Austin (34th Ward Alderman) says someone has to pay for the past sins of slavery during a City Council debate on a resolution to pay reparations to the descendents of slaves, 5/17/2000Bernard Stone (50th Ward Alderman) apologizes to his black colleagues in the Council for doing nothing to fight racism and slavery, 5/17/2000Bill Clinton (President of the United States) addresses a rally in the Palmer House and comments on irregularities in the counting of votes in Florida that favored George W. Bush, 1/9/2000George Ryan (Governor of Illinois) rejects the call by the Willis family (the Rev. Dwayne Willis and wife) that he will resign, 1/29/2000Peter Fitzgerald (Republican U.S. Senator from Illinois) says he thinks the people of Illinois are hungry to end the entrenched culture of insider deals in Springfield, UndatedPaul Vallas (Chief Executive Officer for the Chicago Public Schools) makes his resignation as Mayor Daley's school reform chief official, 6/7/2001Paul Vallas (former Chief Executive Officer for the Chicago Public Schools) explains the real reason why he resigned during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 6/8/2001Dick Simpson (University of Illinois at Chicago Political Science Professor and former Chicago Alderman) explains what is wrong with the kind of pinstripe contract corruption going on under Mayor Daley during an appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 3/22/2001George Ryan (Governor of Illinois) talks about why he ordered a moratorium on executions, a move for which he won worldwide praise, 8/8/2001George Ryan (Governor of Illinois) defends his decision to veto a bill that would have denied funding to poor women seeking abortions, a veto that infuriated the right wing of the Illinois Republican party, 8/8/2001George Ryan (Governor of Illinois) announces that he will not seek reelection to a second term in 2002, 8/8/2001tape side #15, Time: 44:25CD 155274Scope and ContentsGeorge Ryan (Governor of Illinois) says he is pardoning four Death Row inmates who, together, had spent 60 years facing death for murders they did not commit in a major speech at DePaul University Law School three days before leaving office, 1/10/2003tape side #16 and #17, Time: 60:30CD 165275Scope and ContentsGeorge Ryan (Governor of Illinois) announces during a major speech at Northwestern University Law School that he is commuting the sentences of every inmate on death row, 1/11/2003tape side #18 and #19, Time: 60:37CD 175276Scope and ContentsRod Blagojevich (Governor of Illinois) gives his inaugural address after being sworn in as the first Democratic Governor of Illinois in 26 years, 1/13/2003Rod Blagojevich (Governor of Illinois) delivers his first State of the State address to a joint session of the Illinois General Assembly, 3/12/2003tape side #20 and #21, Time: 60:00CD 185277Scope and ContentsThe first debate between Mayor Jane Byrne, Cook County State's Attorney Richard M. Daley, and Congressman Harold Washington in the hotly contested Democratic Campaign for Mayor of Chicago in 1983, 1/18/1983tape side #22 and #23, Time: 60:00CD 195278Scope and ContentsThe second debate between Mayor Jane Byrne, Cook County State's Attorney Richard M. Daley, and Congressman Harold Washington in the hotly contested Democratic Campaign for Mayor of Chicago in 1983, 1/27/1983tape side #24 and #25, Time: 60:00CD 205279Scope and ContentsThe debate in the General Election Campaign for Mayor of Chicago in 1983.  The candidates were the Democratic nominee, Congressman Harold Washington, and the Republican nominee, State Senator Bernard Epton, 3/21/1983tape side #26 and #27, Time: 60:00CD 215280Scope and ContentsDebate between the candidates for the U.S. Senate from Illinois during the 1992 General Election Campaign.  The candidates were Republican nominee Richard Williamson and Democratic nominee Carol Moseley Braun, 10/12/1992tape side #28 and #29, Time: 60:00CD 225281Scope and ContentsDebate between the three contenders for the Democratic nomination for Governor of Illinois during the 1994 primary campaign.  The candidates were State Senator Dawn Clark Netsch, former Illinois Attorney General Roland Burris, and Cook County Board President Richard Phelan, 2/15/1994tape side #30 and #31, Time: 60:00CD 235282Scope and ContentsThe pivotal debate between Illinois Democratic U.S. Senator Carol Moseley Braun and her Republican challenger, State Senator Peter Fitzgerald, during the 1998 General Election Campaign.  The debate took place on a special one hour edition of WBBM's "At Issue" program, 10/18/1998tape side #32 and #33, Time: 62:30CD 245283Scope and ContentsNelson Mandela, Head of the African National Congress and future President of South Africa, addresses a luncheon meeting of religious leaders in Chicago on his long battle to end apartheid in his country, 7/6/1993South African Archbishop and Nobel Peace Prize winner Desmond Tutu addresses a UNICEF awards luncheon in Chicago, 6/14/1994Former Chicago Democratic Congressman and House Ways and Means Committee Chairman Dan Rostenkowski addresses the City Club of Chicago on the state of politics and government in Washington, 4/16/1998tape side #34 and #35, Time: 52:45CD 255284Scope and ContentsIllinois Democratic U.S. Senator Paul Simon announces that he will not seek reelection in 1996, ending a long career in politics that began with his election to the Illinois House in 1954, UndatedIllinois Democratic U.S. Senator Paul Simon speaks during a farewell interview on WBBM's "At Issue" program, 12/20/1996tape side #36, Time: 30:00CD 265285Scope and ContentsIllinois Republican Governor Jim Edgar makes a farewell appearance on WBBM's "At Issue" program on the day before retiring after eight years in office and 30 years in politics, 1/10/1998tape side #37, Time: 43:50CD 275286Scope and ContentsFormer Illinois Republican Governor Jim Thompson, the longest serving Governor in state history (14 years) addresses the Civic Federation of Chicago, talking about the current state of politics in American, 6/25/1998tape side #38, Time: 29:30CD 285287Scope and ContentsReverend Jessie Jackson, President of the Rainbow/Push Coalition, talks about "Black on Black Crime" during a regular Saturday meeting at the Coalition's Chicago headquarters, 11/27/1993tape side #39, 19:05CD 295288Scope and ContentsReverend Willie Barrow, Deputy Director of Operation Push, addresses the gathering after being inducted into the Chicago Senior Citizens Hall of Fame during ceremonies in the City Council chambers, 5/9/1995Veteran Independent Democratic 5th Ward Alderman Lawrence Bloom delivers a prepared statement to the media after his indictment on federal corruption charges, 7/8/1997Democratic Cook County Circuit Court Clerk Aurilia Pucinski, member of one of Chicago's most well known Polish families that had been involved for years in Democratic Party politics, announces she is switching to the Republican Party to run for the presidency of the Cook County Board, 12/11/1997Democratic Presidential Candidate Jimmy Carter addresses Illinois Democrats at a fundraiser shortly before the start of the Democratic National Convention in 1976 where he won the Party's nomination for President, UndatedCrawford's original inventories and other documentationBox 15289Richard J. Daley Years, 1968-1976Folder 152901Michael Bilandic Years, 1979Folder 252912Jane Byrne Years, 1979-1988Folder 352923Harold Washington Years, 1983-1987Folder 452934Eugene Sawyer Years, 1987-1989Folder 552945Richard M. Daley Years, 1982-2001Folder 652956Politicians and Other Figures, 1981-2003Folder 752967Summary of Collection and Correspondence about CollectionFolder 852978Audio CDsBox 25298Scope and ContentsSee series 1-7 for a detailed listing of the contents of the audio CDs.Archives Preview, Time: 7:22CD 15299Scope and ContentsPiece on the Crawford Audio Archives, narrated by Crawford, n.d.

