<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>O.M570Archon Finding Aid Title O.M570UIS Archives/Special CollectionsArchives/Special Collections LIB 144One University Plaza, MS BRK 140Springfield, IL 62703-5407twood1@uis.eduURL: This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on 2018-06-06 16:50:03 -0400.undother_unmapped
  
    
      English
    
    
      UIS Archives/Special Collections
    
    Miami Land Claims in Illinois: Interview and Memoir
    
      Miami Land Claims in Illinois
    
    
      Yow, Tim
    
    
      Bisbee, Matt
    
    
      Eaton, Pauline
    
    
      Greenberg, Ken
    
    
      Leonard, Floyd (Chief)
    
    
      Olds, Julie
    
    
      Porter, Rich
    
    
      Wilmot, Tom
    
    
      Cramer, Andrew W.
    
    O.M570
    1692
    
      7.00 items
    
    Dummy Date
    Tapes
    et al.
  
  
    Scope and Contents
Members of the Miami Nation,  Illinois land owners and farmers, and others discuss a controversial lawsuit filed in 2000 by the Miami Nation against 15 landowners on ancestral Miami lands in the Wabash Basin in east-central Illinois.  Chief Leonard and Olds, leaders of the Miami Nation of Oklahoma, discuss the history of their tribe, their claim to 2.6 million acres of land in Illinois, disputed treaties, "blood quantums," tribal cultural centers, and the casino controversy. Eaton, Greenburg and Yow, eastern Illinois farmers and landowners, discuss their families' histories on the disputed land, and their opposition to the Miami claim. Bisbee, press secretary to Republican  congressman Tim Johnson of Champaign, discusses a proposed bill to shelter Illinois landowners from Miami claims and direct future lawsuits directly to the Federal government. Porter, a former TV news director, discusses his organization of opposition to the construction of a possible Miami gambling casino near Paxton, Illinois. Wilmot, a real-estate and casino developer, briefly responds to questions regarding the merits of the Miami claim.The Miami Nation dropped the suit in 2001, but may refile it in the future. Cramer conducted the interviews in Oklahoma and Illinois as research for his 2002 UIS history master's thesis, "Nations Divided: The Battle Over the Miami Land Claim in Illinois." (see J54/50/4311).6 tapes, 270 mins., 80 pp.
Interviews by Andrew W. Cramer, 2001
RESTRICTED: No legal releases.  
  
    Conditions Governing Access
RESTRICTED: No legal releases.  
  

